<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Lisa Smith</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/080916earpiece-1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/CtXQpjjWEAEMHmu.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-27-13_39_52-Was-Hillary-Wearing-an-Earpiece-During-Last-Nights-Presidential-Forum_-»-Alex-J.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-27-13_40_13-Was-Hillary-Wearing-an-Earpiece-During-Last-Nights-Presidential-Forum_-»-Alex-J.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>There’s a lot that could be discussed about last night’s debate, like the unfair debate moderator asking questions to help Hillary, but that’s not the main concern right now. There is one thing that has baffled many…. Hillary didn’t appear to be her usually stupid coughing self! She was so ready with answers and detailed facts. Almost just as bizarre was that not once did she sputter or reach for a glass of water. This is so odd that it has everyone and their grandma talking! The latest question swirling around on social media are the pictures that appeared to show Hillary with some kind of flesh-colored device embedded inside her ear…is that an earpiece she is wearing? Or just something fashionable for old ladies? Twitter may have figured out the answer…do you see it?  It certainly wouldn’t be the first time Hillary had to use a device for help. What do you think? Could it be a trick of light and shadows? A puffy zipper, perhaps? Or was Hillary actually hiding a “Cough prevention machine” in her hideous feminist pantsuit?  Hillary Clinton’s campaign is fervently denying that she was wearing an earpiece. Fox News reported that “Clinton spokesman Nick Merrill said what is seen in the photo is merely a reflection of the TV lights or a flash.” While we aren’t sure what was going on inside Hillary’s little head last night, we do have a very interesting email posted by Woods from Clinton and Huma Abedin that the WikiLeaks archive released, “Did u take your earpiece or do I need to get it?”  Woods had a hidden sense of humor that escaped him on twitter…“She can’t even #lie without help from a gaggle of other #liars through an earpiece.”  Then Woods added: “She literally can’t help herself. She’s the kind of sociopath who will lie even if the truth were more beneficial.” Of course, we don’t have actual proof of the earpiece, it could have just been a hearing aid. Hmmm no one has talked about Hillary wearing an earpiece in the past when she fumbled through her speeches. Some claim it’s merely a reflection of studio lights. We’ll let you be the judge. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>174</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>480</end>
        <start>175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>724</end>
        <start>481</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>779</end>
        <start>725</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>780</end>
        <start>780</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1038</end>
        <start>781</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1039</end>
        <start>1039</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1121</end>
        <start>1040</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1260</end>
        <start>1122</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1509</end>
        <start>1261</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1510</end>
        <start>1510</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1658</end>
        <start>1511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1659</end>
        <start>1659</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1677</end>
        <start>1660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1794</end>
        <start>1678</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1996</end>
        <start>1795</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2078</end>
        <start>1997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2079</end>
        <start>2079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1003</end>
        <start>979</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1259</end>
        <start>1146</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1508</end>
        <start>1460</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1657</end>
        <start>1574</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1793</end>
        <start>1679</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1794</end>
        <start>1678</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>People Noticed Something Odd About Hillary’s Outfit at the Debate Last Night</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/people-noticed-something-odd-hillarys-outfit-debate-last-night/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
