<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/700594-navy-sailor-proudly-refuses-to-stand-for-anthem-then-navy-veterans-lower-the-boom-on-her-protest/">
        <end>31</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Military-1-e1474893170316.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/08/681673-colin-kaepernick-blasted-for-refusing-to-stand-for-national-anthem-over-oppression-of-black-people/">
        <end>1026</end>
        <start>1010</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/690195-a-navy-sailor-just-took-kaepernicks-protest-to-next-level-disrespects-flag-during-national-anthem/">
        <end>1125</end>
        <start>1114</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/usampwtfm/?fref=ts">
        <end>1181</end>
        <start>1146</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/700451-police-release-graphic-bodycam-video-of-keith-scott-shooting-but-new-images-may-be-more-revealing/">
        <end>1556</end>
        <start>1540</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/24/navy-investigating-second-sailor-who-refused-to-stand-for-national-anthem/">
        <end>1572</end>
        <start>1558</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Military1.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.military.com/daily-news/2016/09/23/navy-publishes-guidance-warning-sailors-not-protest-anthem.html">
        <end>2712</end>
        <start>2698</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Yet another black female sailor declared that she would sit during the National Anthem. Janaye Ervin posted on Facebook her intentions and declared the Navy was punishing her for exercising her constitutional rights. The military is a realm unto its own. It is governed by military law and procedure. This woman has served in the Navy for eight years… she damn well knows that and is using a Marxist/terrorist tactic… she’s using our own freedoms against us. Ervin is in violation of Navy regulations. They require all uniformed personnel to stand at attention and face the ensign while the anthem is played. You do not get an exception because you are black. As John Bloomer pointed out, anyone has a right to protest, but action conducted as a protest does not grant immunity from the law or a pass on any social consequence. The discipline within the naval ranks is warranted on her actions or lack thereof.  From the Independent Review Journal: The national anthem protests — inspired by 49ers quarterback Colin Kaepernick — were just gathering steam when the first American military member raised eyebrows by joining in. Facebook community, US Army Military Police WTF Moments, posted video of the sailor, who said that she would not stand for the anthem “until the U.S. proves that they’ve got my back as a black woman”:   Although the Navy did speak to the sailor in the video, officials made it clear that she would not be separated from the service for her actions. Last week, as tensions increased following two highly publicized police shootings, another sailor came forward to say that she would be sitting out the national anthem as well:  Ervin also said that she intended to “support and defend the Constitution of the United States and to spread freedom and democracy around the world.” But she would do well to heed the observation of fellow African American Martin Baker who was reminded of something he was told in training: “I was told in basic training the simplest of phrases: we are here to preserve and defend democracy, not practice it. When you put the uniform on, you must put aside your personal feelings and remember at that moment you are a direct representative of the United States of America. You are, if need be, the advanced diplomacy of the American way of life. If at any time you feel you cannot stand and represent our flag and our nation even in something as simple as the anthem, you forfeit the right to wear that uniform.” That is exactly right and it goes right to the heart of her transgression. Ervin’s actions could also be considered ‘political speech’, which is also against military regulations. Because of these two incidents, the Navy has issued new guidelines: According to Navy Regulation 1205, personnel in uniform must stand at attention and face the flag when the national anthem is played. Navy active-duty personnel in civilian clothes will face the flag, stand at attention, and place their right hand over their heart. Additionally, Sailors will receive training on the appropriate usage of social media, and must not use it to discredit the Naval Service, and should be reminded it could potentially be used as evidence against them. While military personnel are not excluded from the protections granted by the First Amendment, the US Supreme Court has stated that the different character of our community and of the military mission requires a different application of those protections.” Neither of the sailors has been discharged… yet. But the new guidelines state that such actions will be punishable under Article 92 of the UCMJ and will be considered serious offenses — grounds for involuntary separation from the service. As they should. Don’t enlist if you can’t follow the military’s rules, regulations and laws. And if you can’t bring yourself to stand for the National Anthem, perhaps you should also find a different country where you have no issues with patriotism. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>458</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>910</end>
        <start>459</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>911</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>948</end>
        <start>912</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1125</end>
        <start>949</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1326</end>
        <start>1126</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1327</end>
        <start>1327</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>1328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1474</end>
        <start>1329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1475</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1652</end>
        <start>1652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2540</end>
        <start>1653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2645</end>
        <start>2541</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2713</end>
        <start>2646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2979</end>
        <start>2714</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3195</end>
        <start>2980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3452</end>
        <start>3196</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3941</end>
        <start>3453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3942</end>
        <start>3942</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1324</end>
        <start>1261</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1801</end>
        <start>1691</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2464</end>
        <start>1945</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>699</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3452</end>
        <start>2714</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Navy Sailor PROUDLY Sits During National Anthem In Uniform – Navy Veterans Set Her STRAIGHT! [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/america/navy-sailor-proudly-sits-national-anthem-uniform-navy-veterans-set-straight-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
