<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/LesThePrez/status/779106921576067074">
        <end>525</end>
        <start>519</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/allistree/status/779072075440934913">
        <end>577</end>
        <start>571</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wcax.com/story/33163463/uvm-raises-black-lives-matter-flag">
        <end>685</end>
        <start>673</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8056">
        <end>913</end>
        <start>857</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8162">
        <end>1460</end>
        <start>1417</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The University of Vermont’s Burlington campus is flying a Black Lives Matter flag alongside both the American and state flags. The flag is being sponsored by the UVM Student Government Association, the president of which called the flag a way “to show symbolic support for our community.” The University of Vermont’s Burlington campus is flying a Black Lives Matter flag alongside both the American and state flags. Several students from the school took to social media to express their support for the move, with some saying the school is “winning for this” and another noting that since the school is supportive of the movement, “we should be too.” One local news outlet is reporting that the flag is being sponsored by the school’s Student Government Association (SGA), whose president called the move a way to “show symbolic support for our community.” [RELATED: KU library pushed BLM propaganda on students]  “The Student Government Association is sponsoring the flag at this time to show symbolic support for our community when so many are struggling with the violence and search for justice in this country,” SGA president Jason Maulucci wrote in a statement. “It is fitting that the flag flies adjacent to the recently engraved benches that pronounce the values of Our Common Ground—Respect, Integrity, Innovation, Openness, Justice, and Responsibility.” The flag apparently appeared on campus the day after… Read the rest of the story at Campus Reform  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>126</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>288</end>
        <start>127</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>415</end>
        <start>289</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>650</end>
        <start>416</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>856</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>913</end>
        <start>857</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1362</end>
        <start>914</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1416</end>
        <start>1363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1460</end>
        <start>1417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1461</end>
        <start>1461</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1607</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1681</end>
        <start>1608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>287</end>
        <start>244</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>557</end>
        <start>541</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>649</end>
        <start>632</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>287</end>
        <start>247</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1114</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1361</end>
        <start>1168</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1643</end>
        <start>1631</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BLM Flag and American Flag Fly SIDE-BY-SIDE at University of Vermont</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36974/blm-flag-and-american-flag-fly-side-by-side-at-university-of-vermont/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
