<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tiffiny Ruegner</author>
    <mainText>Holy cow, I started crying when I read this post. Mark Ross had just found out that his sister had been killed in a car accident by some dumb punk. His number 1 priority was to get to his mom to comfort her a couple states away. He had a friend drive him even though his friend had a suspended license. In Ohio, they were pulled over for a traffic violation and Ross was thinking, “We’re going to jail,” because his friend was driving illegally and he had a warrant out for his arrest.   The State Trooper had the car towed so they were stranded. Ross, breaking into tears explained to the other police officer who showed up, Sgt. David Robison, that his sister was just killed and he was trying to get to his mom to comfort her. Instead of arresting him, Sgt. Robison offered to drive him 100 miles (as far as he could go) to drop him closer to family. Just as Robison was dropping him off, he asked if he could pray for him. Ross’ Facebook post explains the moment, “He REACHES OVER AND BEGAN PRAYING OVER ME AND MY FAMILY.” Ross then goes on to explain to his friends that, “Everybody knows how much I dislike Cops, but I am truly Grateful for this Guy. He gave me hope.” The one thing you can get from this story is that ALL Lives Matter and true humanity doesn’t see color. This cop helped a young man who was in pain because THAT is humanity and THAT is what police officers do. They are not trained to do it, it is in their blood. Most people join the police force because they want to help people. I am grateful for this Christian man who helped a young man gain hope and comfort. This nation doesn’t need a movement of Black Lives Matter or Any Lives Matter… this nation needs more Christian people doing their duty as Christians to succor the weak or weary. Our national campaign shouldn’t be #BLM but #WWJD. We all need to remember when we go to work, the grocery store or drive down the street… what would Jesus do, what would he do for YOU? What HAS Jesus done for your family? How can you reciprocate Jesus’ love and be more like Him who suffered every inhumanity there was and then rose above it all? Thanks Mark Ross for giving me my perspective back. I’m grateful you posted this. God Bless your family in this time of need. Here’s his selfie with the Sgt. This is what he wrote about it: At 3am I got a phone call stating that my sister had been killed in a car accident due to some young dumb punk! I haven’t slept and instantly got on the road. Of course we were speeding, trying to get back to Detroit. And we got pulled over in Ohio. I knew I was going to Jail due to a petty warrant. The police called Wayne county and they refused to come get me because of the distance. I explained to the officer that my sister had died and that I needed to get to my mother asap. I broke down crying and he saw the sincerity in my cry. He REACHES OVER AND BEGAN PRAYING OVER ME AND MY FAMILY. He offered to bring me 100 miles further to Detroit because they towed the vehicle. Everybody knows how much I dislike Cops but I am truly Greatful for this Guy. He gave me hope   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>485</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>486</end>
        <start>486</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>487</end>
        <start>487</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1026</end>
        <start>488</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1505</end>
        <start>1027</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2241</end>
        <start>1506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3080</end>
        <start>2242</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3081</end>
        <start>3081</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3082</end>
        <start>3082</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3083</end>
        <start>3083</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>402</end>
        <start>382</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1025</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1173</end>
        <start>1078</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>This Black Man Hates Cops, Then His Sister Was Killed And Something Changed…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/black-man-hates-cops-sister-killed-something-changed/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
