<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/wow-eagles-players-raise-black-power-fist-national-anthem/">
        <end>24</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Eagles?src=hash">
        <end>1618</end>
        <start>1611</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/lLW8ZoYUUn">
        <end>1645</end>
        <start>1619</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JClarkCSN/status/778028203822551040">
        <end>1694</end>
        <start>1676</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://profootballtalk.nbcsports.com/2016/09/19/three-eagles-raise-fists-during-national-anthem/">
        <end>2010</end>
        <start>1974</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I’ve pretty much decided to boycott the NFL. There are some great players and coaches there, but until Commissioner Goodell gets his head out of his butt and puts a stop to dissing the National Anthem, the military and the police, I want nothing to do with them. If you love your country, I would hope you love it more than the NFL and football or any other sport… what these whining, wealthy athletes are doing is not only unpatriotic, it is racist and incendiary in nature. They are spoiling for a race war. Three Philadelphia Eagles players raised their fists in the sign for Black Power at their game in Chicago on Monday night during the National Anthem. It was disgraceful and I think I’ve had just about enough of this crap. Ever since Colin Kaepernick started this cop-hating gesture by sitting and then kneeling during the National Anthem, it has had me furious. I’ve seen it spread to colleges and high schools. I’ve seen it infect other sports as well. It should not be tolerated by these teams… it’s just that simple. It doesn’t help that Barack and Michelle Obama have done it as well… it is a radical, racist gesture and unacceptable. I accept it no more than I would accept a Nazi salute – they are both disgusting and hateful. Even Sports Illustrated has bowed to Black Lives Matter. From Gateway Pundit: It’s an Obama world. Last week NFL players were sitting during the National Anthem. Now they’re raising the Black Power fist. On Monday four Eagles players raised the black power fist during the National Anthem.   Malcolm Jenkins and few teammates with fists in air during National Anthem. #Eagles pic.twitter.com/lLW8ZoYUUn — John Clark CSN (@JClarkCSN) September 20, 2016    Eagles defensive end Steven Means, strong safety Malcolm Jenkins and defensive back Ron Brooks all raised their fists. The rest of the Eagles, and all players on the Bears, stood at attention. The players who did the radical salute should all be shunned for this behavior and they should be ashamed of themselves. Especially since just days ago a black man ambushed a female police officer in her patrol car in Philadelphia, shooting her eight times. Her vest saved her, but the guy shot five others, killing one, before he was brought down. Doing the Black Power salute only makes all of that worse and inflames racial and police tensions even more. These players live in the freest country in the world, where they have made millions and live privileged lifestyles. Yet they hate America, her military and the police who protect their sorry asses. Obama took a colorblind society and turned it into a race war waiting to happen. Now, everything is about race and you have Black Lives Matter, the New Black Panthers and the Nation of Islam getting away with racial incitement and violence threatened and realized. These players deserve far more than a boycott. They deserve to be banned from their sports over this. There should be consequences for stoking the fires of racial animosity and the hatred of American heroes.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>509</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1299</end>
        <start>510</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1320</end>
        <start>1300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1341</end>
        <start>1321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1404</end>
        <start>1342</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1532</end>
        <start>1447</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1533</end>
        <start>1533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1534</end>
        <start>1534</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1645</end>
        <start>1535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1694</end>
        <start>1646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1695</end>
        <start>1695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1696</end>
        <start>1696</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1697</end>
        <start>1697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2348</end>
        <start>1698</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2812</end>
        <start>2349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3020</end>
        <start>2813</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3021</end>
        <start>3021</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3022</end>
        <start>3022</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>756</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1694</end>
        <start>1535</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WOW: Eagles Players Raise Racist Black Power Fist During National Anthem, Hate Our Vets</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/wow-eagles-players-raise-racist-black-power-fist-national-anthem-hate-vets/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
