<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8173">
        <end>1012</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Clemson University freshmen may no longer publicly display Harambe-related memes because they “add to rape culture” and can be “a form of racism.” The ban was allegedly inspired by an incident that occurred last week, but administrators are refusing to divulge any details. A Clemson administrator sent an email to Resident Advisors (RAs) Friday instructing them to demand that freshman remove all Harambe references from dorm hallways and windows. The administrator claimed Harambe’s death has been used to “add to rape culture” and can be “form of racism.” An RA further added that any student who disobeys these instructions will be “in trouble.” “All Harambe references are no longer allowed within our community.” “We are no longer allowing any reference to Harambe (or any other spelling) to be displayed on doors, halls, billboards, or windows,” the instructions state. “Harambe should not be displayed in a public place or a place that is viewed by the public… Read the rest of the story at Campus Reform  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>146</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>273</end>
        <start>147</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>448</end>
        <start>274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>649</end>
        <start>449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>718</end>
        <start>650</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>719</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1012</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>1013</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1159</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1233</end>
        <start>1160</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>114</end>
        <start>95</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>145</end>
        <start>128</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>114</end>
        <start>95</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>145</end>
        <start>130</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>648</end>
        <start>637</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>717</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>851</end>
        <start>720</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1195</end>
        <start>1183</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clemson BANS Memes Featuring Dead Gorilla Harambe…Promotes “Rape Culture” and “Racism”</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37061/clemson-bans-memes-featuring-dead-gorilla-harambe-promotes-rape-culture-and-racism/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
