<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Hannah Bleau (Red Dawn)</author>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/19/politics/donald-trump-racial-profiling/">
        <end>91</end>
        <start>37</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/trump-racial-profiling-cnn.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>CNN recently ran an article titled, “Donald Trump defends racial profiling in wake of bombs.” Now, let’s first ignore the fact that once again, CNN is more upset over how we talk about the terror suspect and his religious affiliation than the fact that he allegedly set off bombs intended to hurt people and shot at cops during his capture. CNN claims Trump “reiterated his support for the controversial practice of racial profiling by police amid increasing threats to the homeland.” Translation: Donald Trump is a RAAAAAAACIST!  But here’s the thing. Trump never even mentioned racial profiling. He was praising Israel’s extraordinary vetting methods, which involves profiling, especially at the airport. And guess what? It works for them. “Our police are amazing. Our local police — they know who a lot of these people are. They are afraid to do anything about it because they don’t want to be accused of profiling and they don’t want to be accused of all sorts of things,” Trump said. “You know, in Israel they profile. They’ve done an unbelievable job, as good as you can do. But Israel has done an unbelievable job, and they’ll profile. They see somebody that’s suspicious, they will profile. They will take that person and they’ll check out,” he continued. “Do we have a choice? Look what’s going on. Do we really have a choice? We’re trying to be so politically correct in our country. And this is only going to get worse.” Profiling doesn’t necessarily mean racial profiling. CNN completely made that up, because they want to advance the false narrative that Trump’s a giant racist. CNN even admitted that Trump didn’t actually say “racial” profiling in that very article. Trump did not say on what attributes he would encourage police to profile possible suspects, but it’s illegal for police to subject US persons to disparate treatment based on their race or other protected status. So Trump “did not say on what attributes he would encourage police to profile possible suspects,” but in the VERY FIRST PARAGRAPH, CNN definitively claims that he “reiterated his support for the controversial practice of racial profiling by police.” They made a claim and basically debunked it two paragraphs later. In what world is that considered fair and balanced reporting?</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>484</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>529</end>
        <start>485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>530</end>
        <start>530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>741</end>
        <start>531</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>988</end>
        <start>742</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1431</end>
        <start>989</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1591</end>
        <start>1432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1681</end>
        <start>1592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1894</end>
        <start>1682</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2144</end>
        <start>1895</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2272</end>
        <start>2145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Chicks On The Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>92</end>
        <start>37</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>483</end>
        <start>359</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>975</end>
        <start>743</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1430</end>
        <start>1265</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>64</end>
        <start>58</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1774</end>
        <start>1688</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2143</end>
        <start>2059</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1894</end>
        <start>1682</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>CNN Caught Adding A Word To Donald Trump’s Comments To Make Him Look Bad</title>
    <uri>http://www.chicksontheright.com/cnn-caught-adding-word-donald-trumps-comments-make-look-bad/?utm_source=RWN&amp;utm_medium=RWN&amp;utm_campaign=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
