<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>iPatriot</author>
    <links href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2012-05-30/the-democratic-roots-of-the-birther-movement">
        <end>674</end>
        <start>668</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ipatriot.com/happening-left-chooses-birther-issue/">
        <end>1837</end>
        <start>1791</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In the past 3 or 4 days, the old Obama “Birther Claims” are again making headlines. This time is that candidate Donald Trump is attempting to close the door on it by saying that Barack Benito Milhous Hussein Obama (ht: Mark Levin) was born in the United States – period. You know it – the claim that Obama was born in Kenya and therefore not eligible to be president – the claim that was first implicitly floated by the Hillary Clinton campaign in 2007 and 2008. Yes, that one. It wasn’t Donald Trump who originally fired up the birther train. He just took it to ridiculous heights. It was actually a political stunt by Hillary Clinton’s chief strategist Mark Penn who wrote in 2007: “His [Obama] roots to basic American values and culture are at best limited. I cannot imagine America electing a president during a time of war who is not at his center fundamentally American in his thinking and his values.” Penn also suggested how the campaign might take advantage of this. “Every speech should contain the line that you [Hillary] were born in the middle of America to the middle class in the middle of the last century,” he advised Clinton. “And talk about the basic bargain as about [sic] the deeply American values you grew up with, learned as a child, and that drive you today.” He went on: “Let’s explicitly own ‘American’ in our programs, the speeches and the values. He doesn’t … Let’s add flag symbols to the backgrounds [of campaign events].” So they’ve chosen the one straw man they can go to war against. A topic so utterly pointless at this time, the only question to be asked is – what is the point? Almost eight years into Obama’s reign and it’s being brought up again. There is no point, other than as a distraction – which is the point. Anything to get Clinton out of the… Read the rest of the story at www.iPatriot.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>270</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>477</end>
        <start>271</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>582</end>
        <start>478</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>908</end>
        <start>583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1453</end>
        <start>909</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1790</end>
        <start>1454</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1837</end>
        <start>1791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1838</end>
        <start>1838</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1984</end>
        <start>1839</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2058</end>
        <start>1985</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>54</end>
        <start>40</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>907</end>
        <start>685</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1122</end>
        <start>977</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1283</end>
        <start>1145</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1452</end>
        <start>1298</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2020</end>
        <start>2008</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Why are the Obama “Birther Claims” Making Headlines AGAIN?</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36892/why-are-the-obama-birther-claims-making-headlines-again/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
