<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Oliver Willis</author>
    <links href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/donald-trump-african-american-communities_us_57e1b099e4b0e28b2b50d74c">
        <end>169</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump has again made a huge mistake while referring to life experienced by many black Americans every day. The screw-up in question came as Trump seriously argued that the lives of blacks today are worse than they were during slavery and in the Jim Crow segregation era.  Speaking at a rally in Kenansville, North Carolina, Trump again stumbled in an apparent attempt to endear himself to black voters. “We’re going to make our country safe again. We’re going to rebuild our inner cities because our African-American communities are absolutely in the worst shape that they’ve ever been in before,” he said. “Ever, ever, ever.” The comment, made in a city named for a slave owner, is objectively untrue, and completely ignores that black people were once subjected to slavery and Jim Crow laws. While the media has largely viewed Trump’s weird racial comments as a sign that he is “reaching out” to black voters, polls have actually shown that he is poised to do worse with that group than Mitt Romney or John McCain. Black voters have had an inherent distrust of Trump, which has been amplified thanks to his promotion of the racist “birther” conspiracy there for years.Trump also called for the death penalty for the Central Park 5, long after it had been proven that the young black men involved with the case had been proven innocent. Lately, Trump has argued that the black community in America is a desperate, infantile mess, relying on government welfare in order to simply get by. The image Trump has been spreading has not been for black audiences, but instead have been targeted to a conservative base, high on the idea that ethnic minorities always have their hands out. Black voters have found Trump’s description of them insulting, particularly coming as the community has made huge strides forward. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>277</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>278</end>
        <start>278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>409</end>
        <start>279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>647</end>
        <start>410</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>814</end>
        <start>648</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1043</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1368</end>
        <start>1044</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1711</end>
        <start>1369</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1844</end>
        <start>1712</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1845</end>
        <start>1845</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>279</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Says Blacks Are In Worse Shape Than During SLAVERY (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/21/trump-says-blacks-are-in-worse-shape-than-during-slavery-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
