<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Greg Campbell</author>
    <links href="http://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/community/broward/article102396747.html">
        <end>1087</end>
        <start>1017</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Here’s the thing: one does not have to love America. This is a free country and if one feels the need to disrespect this nation, there are not – nor should there be – legal consequences.   However, let’s be very clear: there is no law that mandates that people should be able to say whatever they want, whenever they want and remain free from encountering consequences. If I told my boss to shove it, it would be wrong for me to end up in jail for the supposed crime. However, is it not fair that I should be fired or otherwise demoted or reprimanded? Similarly, the NFL has the authority to punish the ingrates who refuse to stand for the national anthem. They have chosen not to and thus, many are choosing to boycott the NFL, including this author. Others are making consequences clear: as several Miami Dolphin players continue to demonstrate their hatred for the country that affords them the opportunity to make millions upon millions of dollars doing what they love, a police union in Miami has weighed in and asked Sheriff deputies to not perform security details for the players anymore until such a time that they begin to show a little gratitude towards this nation. Jeffery Bell, the president of the International Union of Police Associations, Local 6020, said: “We’ve asked the deputies and the Broward Sheriff’s Office not to do the details anymore.” The union has asked police units to stop providing protection for the players at a time when fans and former fans have begun to vent their outrage towards the players. Some have even taken to burning Dolphins gear. “I respect their right to have freedom of speech. However, in certain organizations and certain jobs you give up that right of your freedom of speech temporary while you serve that job or while you play in an NFL game,” Bell said. If these ingrates are so convinced that blacks are being persecuted by police – a central premise in the platform of Black Lives Matter – then they should not receive the benefit that these supposed bigots afford. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>186</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>187</end>
        <start>187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>188</end>
        <start>188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>369</end>
        <start>189</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1177</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1274</end>
        <start>1178</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1365</end>
        <start>1275</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1580</end>
        <start>1366</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1811</end>
        <start>1581</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2025</end>
        <start>1812</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2026</end>
        <start>2026</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1364</end>
        <start>1276</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1799</end>
        <start>1582</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1365</end>
        <start>1275</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1811</end>
        <start>1581</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Police Union Asks Deputies To Not Escort Dolphins Until The Team’s Players Stand For Anthem</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/police-union-asks-deputies-not-escort-dolphins-teams-players-stand-anthem/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
