<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Donald Trump will not be fazed by the presence of another brash billionaire businessman, Mark Cuban, in the front row of the upcoming debate, the Republican nominee's campaign asserted Friday. Cuban, a Hillary Clinton supporter who has repeatedly criticized Trump, tweeted Thursday night that he would be in attendance at what he termed the "Humbling at Hofstra," in reference to the debate's site at the Long Island university. Story Continued Below "I just think it’s worth noting that this is one of those things that could get inside somebody’s head. And Mark Cuban, sitting right there in front of him," Fox Business host Maria Bartiromo said during a discussion with national spokeswoman Katrina Pierson. Pierson objected to that assessment, remarking, "No one can get in Donald Trump's head. No one can get in Mr. Trump’s head." "He's going to be focused and he’s gonna be ... focused on talking to the American people," Pierson said. "It doesn't matter who's in the front row. Mr. Trump is gonna make his case at Monday night." Campaign manager Kellyanne Conway mocked Clinton's invitation of Cuban later on the same network, calling it "a typical Monday night for Hillary Clinton spending it with billionaires who don't particularly care for Donald Trump." Conway added, "What's he gonna do -- make funny faces at Donald Trump?"</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>192</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>428</end>
        <start>193</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>450</end>
        <start>429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>710</end>
        <start>451</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>835</end>
        <start>711</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1035</end>
        <start>836</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1265</end>
        <start>1036</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1337</end>
        <start>1266</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Pierson on Cuban at debate: 'No one can get in Donald Trump's head'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/mark-cuban-debate-trump-react-228577?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
