<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Greg Campbell</author>
    <links href="http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/congressional-black-caucus-demands-nationwide-crackdown-law-enforcement/">
        <end>941</end>
        <start>916</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It would be foolish to pretend that all police officers are upstanding professionals. Just like any profession, there are many, many dedicated professionals and yes, there are some bad ones as well. Police officers are people and sometimes they make mistakes and sometimes they’re just plain bad people of low moral character.   However, in a profession that requires people to literally put their lives on the line for the good of society, I feel comfortable asserting that while there are some bad apples to be found, the vast, vast majority of police officers in America are dedicated professionals worthy of respect and who should be offered a degree of freedom from unnecessarily second-guessing life-and-death decisions that must occur in a millisecond. But don’t tell that to the Congressional Black Caucus… The caucus is demanding that radicalized and openly-corrupted Attorney General Loretta Lynch step in to target police officers to help prevent officers throughout the country from reacting with deadly force to black men and women who pose immediate dangers. Of course, the caucus does not frame the discussion in exactly that way, but that is the effort all the same. Referring to recent high-profile killings of armed black men posing immediate dangers to police officers, Rep. Maxine Waters, D-CA, read the letter to the Attorney General outside the Department of Justice as the adoring media dutifully nodded in agreement. “The world is watching and we cannot continue to ignore these killings,” she grandstanded with the caucus standing in solidarity. The letter urges Lynch to “aggressively pursue investigations, indictments and prosecutions through the Office of Civil Rights against any and all law enforcement officers who harm or kill innocent unarmed black men, women and children.” Of course, such a demand seems reasonable… if they’re truly innocent people. However, in many recent high-profile cases of blacks being killed by officers of varying ethnicities, the quickly-fabricated narrative concerning the conduct of the deceased radically differs from the reality of the situation that emerges after radicalized social justice warriors have already furthered a fictitious narrative that supports their manipulative media narrative. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>326</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>327</end>
        <start>327</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>328</end>
        <start>328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>759</end>
        <start>329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>814</end>
        <start>760</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1072</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1182</end>
        <start>1073</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1440</end>
        <start>1183</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1570</end>
        <start>1441</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1808</end>
        <start>1571</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2262</end>
        <start>1809</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2263</end>
        <start>2263</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1512</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1807</end>
        <start>1598</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Congressional Black Caucus Now DEMANDING Crack Down On Police Officers Nationwide…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/congressional-black-caucus-now-demanding-crack-police-officers-nationwide/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
