<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rodney Lee</author>
    <links href="http://americantoday.news/george-soros-i-am-a-god-i-created-everything-i-control-america-and-hillary-clinton/">
        <end>216</end>
        <start>209</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Soros believes that he is God and that he controls America!  Interesting opinion as he is an atheist! Well, he has been doing a pretty good job at trying to control America and that is FOR SURE! AmericanToday reports: George Soros claims he is a god and “the creator of everything,” however the billionaire globalist also warns he is a “self-centred” god who believes “normal rules do not apply” to him. “I fancied myself as some kind of god …” he wrote. “If truth be known, I carried some rather potent messianic fantasies with me from childhood, which I felt I had to control, otherwise they might get me in trouble.“ When asked by Britain’s Independent newspaper to elaborate on that statement, Soros doubled down: “It is a sort of disease when you consider yourself some kind of god, the creator of everything, but I feel comfortable about it now since I began to live it out.“ “Next to my fantasies about being God, I also have very strong fantasies of being mad,” Soros once confided on British television. “In fact, my grandfather was actually paranoid. I have a lot of madness in my family. So far I have escaped it.” Soros has made his wealth on the backs of millions in poverty, yet he is the king of decrying how unfair America is because of its greatness. He has, in fact, created more poverty around the world than he could ever complain about!  Why doesn’t he just give away his money to the poor, and live as he would like others to live? Because he is just another far left hypocrite who cares about no one except George Soros. Ugly he is, on the inside and out! It is OK! Someday George, you WILL know who God is! Philippians 2:9 Therefore God also has highly exalted Him and given Him the name which is above every name, 10 that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, of those in heaven, and of those on earth, and of those under the earth, 11 and that every tongue should confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.     </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>101</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>194</end>
        <start>102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>217</end>
        <start>195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>403</end>
        <start>218</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>881</end>
        <start>404</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1125</end>
        <start>882</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1357</end>
        <start>1126</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1358</end>
        <start>1358</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1543</end>
        <start>1359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1630</end>
        <start>1544</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1962</end>
        <start>1631</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1963</end>
        <start>1963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1964</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1967</end>
        <start>1966</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>281</end>
        <start>255</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>349</end>
        <start>337</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>394</end>
        <start>369</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>443</end>
        <start>405</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>456</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1124</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>881</end>
        <start>218</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1125</end>
        <start>882</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>George Soros: ‘I Am A God, I Created Everything, I Control America And Hillary’ George Soros has finally lost the last tiny bit of mind he had left!</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/09/21/soros-god-created-everything/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
