<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/big-government/2016/09/20/terrorist-trump-slams-hillary-award-palestinian-terrorists-wife/">
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1425</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton’s totally tone deaf Clinton Foundation will be honoring a Palestinian teach. The problem arises when you learn that she is married to a terrorist. Hanan an-Hroub will be speaking at a Clinton Global Initiative event to honor her for a teacher award. The event takes place in New York. How’s that for location? Read the story below.  As Written By Joel Pollack for Breitbart: Donald Trump is criticizing Hillary Clinton over the fact that the Clinton Foundation is honoring a Palestinian teacher whose husband is a convicted terrorist on Tuesday evening. Hanan an-Hroub is scheduled to speak at a Clinton Global Initiative event in New York after winning a $1 million teaching award from another charity that donates to the Clinton Foundation. Her husband, Omar al-Hroub, spent 10 years in an Israeli prison for his role in a 1980 bombing that killed six Israelis. The event is going ahead as planned, in spite of the recent Islamist terrorist bombings in New York and New Jersey, which injured dozens. The Wall Street Journal noted Tuesday: Omar al-Hroub was convicted on charges that he was an accomplice in a deadly bombing attack in Hebron that killed Israelis walking home from Friday night Sabbath prayers. According to an Associated Press account at the time, Omar al-Hroub was a chemist who provided chemicals needed for making the bombs. Trump campaign spokesman Jason Miller said …. Full Story Here: Palestinian Terrorist’s Wife to Address Clinton Foundation</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>347</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>348</end>
        <start>348</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>390</end>
        <start>349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>569</end>
        <start>391</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>879</end>
        <start>570</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1017</end>
        <start>880</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1056</end>
        <start>1018</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1361</end>
        <start>1057</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1407</end>
        <start>1362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1424</end>
        <start>1408</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1361</end>
        <start>1057</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1408</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREITBART: Palestinian Terrorist’s Wife to Address Clinton Foundation</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/breitbart-palestinian-terrorists-wife-to-address-clinton-foundation/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
