<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kosar</author>
    <links href="http://www.washingtonexaminer.com/hillary-clintons-lead-collapses-just-before-debate/article/2602814">
        <end>329</end>
        <start>320</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2016-09-26/national-poll">
        <end>352</end>
        <start>345</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/3KWOl2ibaW">
        <end>1518</end>
        <start>1495</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TrumpTrain?src=hash">
        <end>1531</end>
        <start>1520</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MAGA?src=hash">
        <end>1537</end>
        <start>1532</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/4kQX4pmt0I">
        <end>1564</end>
        <start>1538</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/780377077518364673">
        <end>1620</end>
        <start>1602</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Media outlets have made it official: Just before tonight’s first 2016 presidential debate, Republican presidential candidate Donald J. Trump is leading! Democrats were recently ready to measure the drapes in the White House. But according to Bloomberg Politics, Clinton’s once seemly insurmountable lead has officially “collapsed.” As Bloomberg reports: Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton are locked in a tied two-way race for the presidency as they head to Hofstra University in New York on Monday night for one of the most highly anticipated debates in modern politics. The Republican and Democratic nominees each get 46 percent of likely voters in a head-to-head contest in the latest Bloomberg Politics national poll, while Trump gets 43 percent to Clinton’s 41 percent when third-party candidates are included. Clinton faces higher expectations as tens of millions of people tune in for a television spectacle that could reach Super Bowl viewership levels. About half, 49 percent, say they anticipate the former secretary of state will perform better, while 39 percent say that for Trump, a real-estate developer and former TV personality And, Hillary has lost support among women and younger Millennial voters: Ann Selzer, the Iowa-based pollster who oversaw the survey, said there are signs that Clinton’s margins with women and young voters have eroded over the past three months, helping to explain Trump’s gains. New national Bloomberg poll just released – thank you! Join the MOVEMENT: https://t.co/3KWOl2ibaW. #TrumpTrain #MAGA pic.twitter.com/4kQX4pmt0I — Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) September 26, 2016  In addition, pollsters noted that more of Trump’s voters are excited to vote for him than Hillary voters are about voting for her. It’s clear that Hillary Clinton’s ongoing criminal activity, the questionable ways she became wealthy, and her ongoing health struggles have doomed a campaign that once looked invincible. The Clinton political machine that used to control the message through the liberal media in the 1990s simply can’t hide from today’s alternative media. Hillary Clinton is being exposed, and voters are paying attention. This is what Hillary Clinton’s poll numbers look like today: What do you think about Hillary Clinton’s collapse in the polls? Please leave us a comment (below) and tell us what you think.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>153</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>332</end>
        <start>154</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>333</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1142</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1215</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1421</end>
        <start>1216</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1565</end>
        <start>1422</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1621</end>
        <start>1566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1622</end>
        <start>1622</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1753</end>
        <start>1623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2160</end>
        <start>1754</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2221</end>
        <start>2161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2348</end>
        <start>2222</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2349</end>
        <start>2349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2350</end>
        <start>2350</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Political Insider</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>330</end>
        <start>320</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>354</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1420</end>
        <start>1215</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1620</end>
        <start>1421</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Site Navigation Once Leading in the Polls, HILLARY CLINTON HAS COLLAPSED!</title>
    <uri>http://www.thepoliticalinsider.com/leading-hillary-poll-collapsed/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
