<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>The first general election debate between Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump averaged 84 million viewers across 13 channels, according to data from Nielsen, making it the most watched presidential debate in modern history. Until last night, the most-watched debate in history was the 1980 debate between Jimmy Carter and Ronald Reagan. That debate averaged just over 80 million viewers. With a few networks still to be counted by Nielsen, and the 80 million figure not including anyone who watched online, last night's debate will end up with more people watching than any prior presidential debate. In 2012, the first debate between Mitt Romney and Barack Obama averaged 70 million viewers. In 2008, the first debate between John McCain and Obama averaged 53 million viewers. On cable news, Fox News led the way with more than 11 million viewers. NBC led the broadcast networks with more than 18 million people tuning in. The ratings put the debate in rare company. Of TV programs that drew an average of more than 80 million viewers, most were NFL Super Bowl broadcasts, with the others were the finales of M.A.S.H. and Cheers. Of course, the debate aired on a dozen TV networks and streamed online, whereas the Super Bowl and M.A.S.H. only aired on one channel each. The numbers do not include anyone watching on PBS, Univision or non-rated TV channels like C-SPAN, nor does it include anyone that streamed the debate online. Data from Facebook, YouTube and other digital sources suggests that millions more people watched the debate live online. All told, Fox News averaged 11.4 million viewers, including 3.5 million in the key adults 25-54 demo. CNN averaged 9.8 million viewers, including 4.4 million in the demo, and MSNBC averaged 4.9 million viewers, including 1.6 million in the demo. NBC averaged 18.1 million viewers, ABC 13.5 million viewers, CBS 12.1 million viewers and the PBS NewsHour 2.96 million viewers. Among the business channels, Fox Business Network averaged 673,000 viewers, while CNBC averaged 520,000 viewers.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>220</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>774</end>
        <start>221</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>920</end>
        <start>775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1267</end>
        <start>921</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1547</end>
        <start>1268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2035</end>
        <start>1548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>First Trump-Clinton debate is the most-watched debate of all time</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/on-media/2016/09/first-trump-clinton-debate-smashes-ratings-records-228788?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
