<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kosar</author>
    <links href="http://wncn.com/2016/09/19/small-nc-town-prepares-for-trump-rally-clinton-postpones-chapel-hill-event/">
        <end>576</end>
        <start>569</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/778238281196662784">
        <end>2156</end>
        <start>2138</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton has just postponed a high-dollar fundraiser, indefinitely! The event, called “lunch with Hillary Rodham Clinton” invited donor levels between $2700 and $100,000 to attend. No reason was given for the change of event, originally scheduled to take place at the home of Michael Warner and Betty Craven. Clearly, Hillary Clinton’s serious health issues are why her campaign is imploding! This indefinite postponement couldn’t come at a worse possible time, as the campaign reportedly spent $50 million just last month trying to defeat Donald Trump. As WNCN reports: A small Eastern North Carolina town is preparing for Donald Trump’s appearance Tuesday just as a Hillary Clinton event in Chapel Hill on Tuesday was postponed. Trump will hold a rally in Kenansville Tuesday just two weeks after making a stop in Greenville. The rally will be held at the Duplin County Event Center and it is likely to be the largest event ever held in Kenansville, with a population of about 855. Duplin County Schools announced on Monday they would be closing at noon Tuesday in anticipation of Trump’s visit. High amounts of traffic are expected in the area, school officials said. Meanwhile, Clinton campaign officials said Monday afternoon that a Tuesday fundraiser in Chapel Hill was postponed. The Clinton event was billed as “lunch with Hillary Rodham Clinton” and had four donation levels to attend. Those contribution levels were described as $100,000, which featured “chair reception with Hillary,” $33,000, which included a “host reception with Hillary,” $5,000, which included “preferred seating” and $2,700. While Hillary was unable to make an appearance, Trump is planning rallies in Kenansville, just weeks after a stop in Greenville. While Kenansville has a population of 855, the Trump rally at the Duplin County Event Center will likely be the largest event they have ever held. 10,000 supporters are expected. Donald Trump made sure to point out Hillary cancelling a fundraiser: Hillary Clinton is taking the day off again, she needs the rest. Sleep well Hillary – see you at the debate! — Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) September 20, 2016  Reporters are standing by to see if Hillary Clinton’s plans this week in Florida will also be cancelled without explanation. What do you think Hillary Clinton is hiding? Please leave us a comment (below) and tell us.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>75</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>316</end>
        <start>76</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>561</end>
        <start>317</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>578</end>
        <start>562</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>738</end>
        <start>579</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>835</end>
        <start>739</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>836</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1178</end>
        <start>992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1294</end>
        <start>1179</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1402</end>
        <start>1295</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>1403</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1923</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1992</end>
        <start>1924</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2101</end>
        <start>1993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2157</end>
        <start>2102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2158</end>
        <start>2158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2283</end>
        <start>2159</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2375</end>
        <start>2284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2376</end>
        <start>2376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2377</end>
        <start>2377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Political Insider</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>127</end>
        <start>94</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>127</end>
        <start>94</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1501</end>
        <start>1472</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1558</end>
        <start>1530</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1601</end>
        <start>1584</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1614</end>
        <start>578</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2156</end>
        <start>1992</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Site Navigation Hillary Clinton Just Cancelled, AGAIN!</title>
    <uri>http://www.thepoliticalinsider.com/hillary-health-cancelled-again/?source=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
