<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Posted by John Prager on 26 Sep 2016</author>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2016/09/26/new-york-boy-asks-obama-in-letter-if-syrian-refugee-omran-daqneesh-can-live-with-him.html">
        <end>329</end>
        <start>271</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-03-00.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-09-41.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-08-30.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-06-47.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-05-52.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-04-11.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_4-03-40.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-26_1-08-41.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It’s night-impossible to spend five minutes in a Fox News comment thread without coming across something that would give even a Klansman pause to say “hey man, can you tone it down? That’s a bit too racist.” But buried within the Stupid Part of America’s criticisms of a kind, 6-year-old New York boy who wrote to President Obama to ask if a little Syrian boy  who was rescued from a building that had been hit by an airstike was a comment from one of Trump’s “deplorables” that explains why conservatives are the way they are.   “Dear President Obama. Remember the boy who was picked up by the ambulance in Syria?” the boy, Alex, read in a video posted by the White House. “Can you please go get him and bring him to our home? Park in the driveway or on the streets and we’ll be waiting for you guys with flags, flowers and balloons.” “We will give him a family and he will be our brother,” Alex says. “Catherine, my little sister, will be collecting butterflies and fireflies for him. “We can invite him to birthday parties and he will teach us another language … And I will share my bike and I will teach him how to ride it. I will teach him additions and subtractions in math.” “These are the words of a six-year-old boy — a young child who has not learned to be cynical or suspicious or fearful of other people because of where they come from, how they look, or how they pray,” Obama wrote on his Facebook page, adding “we should all be more like Alex.” It’s a beautiful story – one of hope and pure love that all of us should feel fortunate just to be aware of.  Naturally, conservatives had to sh*t all over it:  You might be wondering how a group of people can be so racist and…deplorable. Fortunately, one of them hopped out of the basket to inform you. “What’s wrong with being a racist?” one commenter calling himself “VarnstarkBittlewater” asks when someone remarks that the comments got quite, quite racist. Another person, “pdubya,” replies “everyone is” to which Mr. Bittlewater responds, “my point exactly.”  In case you missed it, conservatives genuinely believe everyone — black, white, polka-dot — is a racist at his or her core, and that this excuses their racism. After all, “if everyone is doing it…” You can watch the video below. At least you’ll appreciate how awesome it is:  Featured image via screengrab</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>527</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>529</end>
        <start>528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>835</end>
        <start>530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1181</end>
        <start>836</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1458</end>
        <start>1182</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1618</end>
        <start>1459</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1619</end>
        <start>1619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1762</end>
        <start>1620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2023</end>
        <start>1763</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2024</end>
        <start>2024</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2222</end>
        <start>2025</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2299</end>
        <start>2223</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2300</end>
        <start>2300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2330</end>
        <start>2301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Winning Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>206</end>
        <start>151</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>472</end>
        <start>461</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>614</end>
        <start>531</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>834</end>
        <start>675</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>890</end>
        <start>837</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1180</end>
        <start>904</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>1183</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1457</end>
        <start>1425</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1797</end>
        <start>1764</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1850</end>
        <start>1830</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1945</end>
        <start>1938</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1967</end>
        <start>1956</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2022</end>
        <start>2005</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2221</end>
        <start>2197</start>
    </quotes>
    <title></title>
    <uri>http://winningdemocrats.com/this-one-comment-from-a-fox-news-fan-is-all-you-need-to-know-about-conservatives-screenshots/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
