<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton faced off for the first general election debate on Monday night, against the backdrop of tightening polls and sky-high expectations. Here’s how it went down, by the numbers: Number of interruptions (via Pew Research): 51 times — Trump interrupted Clinton Story Continued Below 17 times — Clinton interrupted Trump Number of times Obama’s name was used: 18 times — Even though his lame-duck status is approaching, President Obama still loomed large over the first presidential debate. Number of times Trump said he agreed with Clinton: 6 — Trump said he agrees with her on child care, the need to improve the relationships between communities and the police, the “no fly, no buy” gun control measure, her stance on cyber security, that nuclear weapons pose the greatest threat to the U.S., and that Clinton is an experienced candidate&gt; Number of times Trump said “wrong” during the debate: 12 The total amount of retweets a nearly four-year-old Trump tweet has received: 81, 633 (and growing) —Proving that Trump lied when he said during the debate that he had never said global warming was a hoax created by the Chinese, the tweet was the most retweeted tweet of the entire debate. The amount of Twitter conversation around Trump: 62 percent The amount of Twitter conversation around Clinton: 38 percent</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>206</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>287</end>
        <start>207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>309</end>
        <start>288</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>346</end>
        <start>310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>516</end>
        <start>347</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>867</end>
        <start>517</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>924</end>
        <start>868</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1214</end>
        <start>925</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1274</end>
        <start>1215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>1275</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>710</end>
        <start>696</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>901</end>
        <start>896</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump and Clinton debate, by the numbers</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-trump-debate-numbers-228762?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
