<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Adam Kelsey VERONICA STRACQUALURSI</author>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/whitehouse/hillary-clinton.htm">
        <end>153</end>
        <start>138</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TerenceCrutcher?src=hash">
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>1085</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Following the shooting death of an unarmed black man by a police officer in Tulsa, Oklahoma, last Friday, Democratic presidential nominee Hillary Clinton spoke out today against police violence. “This horrible shooting again. How many times do we have to see this in our country? In Tulsa, an unarmed man with his hands in the air,” Clinton said, calling into "The Steve Harvey Morning Show." Forty-year-old Terence Crutcher was fatally shot by a white police officer after his SUV stalled on the road. Video of the incident released after the shooting appears to show Crutcher with his hands raised in the air.     Calling the act “unbearable” and saying officer-involved shootings “need to be intolerable,” Clinton appealed to a white audience to address unconscious discrimination. "Maybe I can, by speaking directly to white people, say look, this is not who we are. We have got to do everything possible to improve policing, to go right at implicit bias," she said.  Another unarmed Black man was shot in a police incident. This should be intolerable. We have so much work to do. #TerenceCrutcher -H  Clinton’s policy proposal for criminal justice reform includes developing national standards on police officers’ use of force, supporting legislation to end racial profiling, and committing $1 billion in funding to training programs and research to “tackle” implicit bias. ABC News’ Julia Jacobo and Josh Haskell contributed to this report.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>194</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>392</end>
        <start>195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>611</end>
        <start>393</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>612</end>
        <start>612</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>613</end>
        <start>613</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>614</end>
        <start>614</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>615</end>
        <start>615</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>784</end>
        <start>616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>970</end>
        <start>785</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>971</end>
        <start>971</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1104</end>
        <start>972</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1105</end>
        <start>1105</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1378</end>
        <start>1106</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1379</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>ABC News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>391</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>959</end>
        <start>786</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary Clinton Calls Tulsa Police Shooting 'Horrible,' Reiterates Call for Improved Policing</title>
    <uri>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/hillary-clinton-calls-tulsa-police-shooting-horrible-reiterates/story?id=42229444&amp;cid=abcnp_fb</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
