<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/389B235600000578-3797779-image-a-1_1474370161244.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3797779/Palestinian-tries-stab-Israel-soldier-shot-dead-army.html#ixzz4KpKCMlUo">
        <end>1342</end>
        <start>1328</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I love a story with a happy ending! When a Palestinian teenager attempted to lure an Israeli soldier into an ambush, the last thing he probably expected was to be shot down before he could carry out his fatal plan. It makes me all warm and fuzzy inside.  If there’s one thing you need to know about Israeli soldiers, male and female, it’s that they are trained to know the moves you are going to make before you even think about making them. They are faced with life and death situations every single day, because they live in the most dangerous area in the world and have been targeted by Palestinians and Muslims around the world for as long as anyone can remember. Apparently this 16 year-old didn’t know what you and I know, and it was the very last mistake he ever made. A surveillance camera captured the 21-second event where Issa Tarayra – as identified by the Palestinian Health Ministry – approached an IDF soldier before attempting to stab him. Forces responded to the threat immediately and put the young man down. Luckily nobody but Tarayra was harmed, as the soldier that was targeted had managed to duck out of the way of the knife just in time. Watch the video below, but be aware that while it’s not extremely graphic footage, it may be considered shocking to some. Viewer discretion is advised:   According to The Daily Mail, this is the ninth attack of its kind since the end of the Muslim holiday Eid al-Adha and ahead of October’s Jewish holidays. I can’t say I feel too terribly bad for the kid, who decided to risk his life on one stupid act. One less scumbag in the world and good riddance. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>35</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>214</end>
        <start>36</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>253</end>
        <start>215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>254</end>
        <start>254</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>667</end>
        <start>255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>775</end>
        <start>668</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1160</end>
        <start>776</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1312</end>
        <start>1161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1313</end>
        <start>1313</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1314</end>
        <start>1314</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1468</end>
        <start>1315</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1614</end>
        <start>1469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>1615</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <title>VIDEO: Dramatic moment Palestinian lures Israeli soldier for knife attack – but is then shot dead</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/video-dramatic-moment-palestinian-lures-israeli-soldier-knife-attack-shot-dead/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
