<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Frank Lea</author>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/22/la-police-union-police-commission-wants-cops-to-run-from-armed-suspects/">
        <end>1061</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I can’t believe this nonsense. You’re going to be mad that I told you this. You’re going to wonder where the toughness of America went and what happened to make people think being a p*ssy is the way to be. When I look at cops, I envision people who are strong, tough, and hard working. Except for that one overweight cop that every station has. You know, the guy who actually eats the donuts. Forget him. He’ll be on desk duty eventually. I’m talking about real cops. The cops I know are all in good shape, work out, and run towards danger. They will save any person that’s in harms way. They don’t care if the person is white, black, or even Muslim. A good cop saves everyone, and that’s what most cops are – good cops. And that’s how it’s supposed to be. But then there’s this idiot from the LA Police Commission who wants cops to run AWAY from armed suspects. Are you kidding me? That’s ridiculous. Cops are trained to eliminate threats, not run away from the threat while the criminal either gets away or hacks someone with a meat cleaver.  The Daily Caller – The Los Angeles Police Commission wants LAPD police officers to run away when a suspect confronts them with a weapon, warns the Los Angeles Police Protective League, the labor union of the city’s police officers. Hypothetically speaking, if I wanted to rob a bank tonight, could I go there with a knife and the cops will run away from me? I don’t have to stab anyone, I just have to show cops that I have a deadly weapon and the cops will run to their cars and drive away. Is that how it works? That opens the Pandora Box for an unwarranted increase in crime based on the fact that LAPD might be ordered to run away from violent perpetrators in the future. I guess the LAPD won’t be allowed to save lives anymore. Very sad state of affairs if this really happens. I hope every LAPD cop does the right thing and does not listen to this nonsense. Cops are trained for battle and they’re not afraid to eliminate a violent threat. And we should let them eliminate a threat if it puts anyone in danger. Training people to run away, instead of eliminating, will generate a nation of p*ssy cops and that’s not who I want to protect me. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>30</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>75</end>
        <start>31</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>205</end>
        <start>76</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>720</end>
        <start>206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>756</end>
        <start>721</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1043</end>
        <start>757</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1044</end>
        <start>1044</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1276</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1402</end>
        <start>1277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1558</end>
        <start>1403</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1720</end>
        <start>1559</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1777</end>
        <start>1721</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1827</end>
        <start>1778</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1908</end>
        <start>1828</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1990</end>
        <start>1909</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2061</end>
        <start>1991</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2192</end>
        <start>2062</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2193</end>
        <start>2193</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1276</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>LA Police Commission Tells Officers How To Deal With Armed Suspects And It Is INSANE</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/la-police-commission-officers-armed-suspects/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
