<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Assistant Attorney General John Carlin, the longest-serving head of the Justice Department's National Security Division who has overseen a flurry of high-profile terrorism and cyber espionage cases, will step down next month, officials said. Mary McCord is set to replace him as acting assistant attorney general on Oct. 15. Story Continued Below Carlin, 43, joined the National Security Division in 2009, only three years after it was established to consolidate the Justice Department's national security and intelligence functions, and was confirmed as head in 2014. He has overseen a robust increase in prosecutions for domestic terrorism, including the Boston Marathon bomber, Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, and steered the first conviction for attempting to construct a radiological device with the prosecution last year of Glendon Scott Crawford, a member of the Ku Klux Klan found guilty of planning to target unsuspecting Muslim-Americans with lethal doses of radiation. Attorney General Loretta Lynch praised his pioneering role. "He oversaw the unprecedented indictment of five members of the Chinese military for cyber-enabled economic espionage and the investigation of the attack on Sony Pictures Entertainment’s computer systems," she said in a statement. "And he forged crucial collaborations with our partners in the intelligence community, law enforcement and the private sector, enhancing our collective ability to detect and deter threats as they arise.” Since 2013, 110 individuals nationwide have been charged as foreign fighters for global terrorist groups, for engaging in violent extremism in the U.S. or for providing material support to the Islamic State, according to the Justice Department. “John Carlin is a dedicated public servant committed to upholding the rule of law, pursuing justice and keeping Americans safe," Lisa Monaco, assistant to the president for homeland security and counterterrorism, said in a statement. "Throughout his distinguished career — most recently as assistant attorney general for national security — John has worked, largely behind the scenes, to do exactly that." Carlin's division played an instrumental role earlier this year in several international computer hacking cases. Su Bin, a Chinese national, was sentenced to 46 months after pleading guilty to working with Chinese military officers to steal military technical data from U.S. defense contractors. Seven Iranian hackers were also indicted for working on behalf of private companies connected with Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps to deny service to the U.S. financial sector. One of the defendants was also indicted for compromising the industrial control system of the Bowman Dam in Rye, N.Y. Carlin previously served as the chief of staff to then-FBI Director Robert Mueller and was a federal prosecutor, serving as the national coordinator of the Justice Department’s Computer Hacking and Intellectual Property Program and as an assistant U.S. attorney for the District of Columbia. A Justice Department official said Carlin was not prepared to discuss his future plans, but predicted he'd be a big draw for the private sector.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>241</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>324</end>
        <start>242</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>346</end>
        <start>325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>568</end>
        <start>347</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>966</end>
        <start>569</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1026</end>
        <start>967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1461</end>
        <start>1027</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1706</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2112</end>
        <start>1707</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2225</end>
        <start>2113</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2594</end>
        <start>2226</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2712</end>
        <start>2595</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3004</end>
        <start>2713</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3149</end>
        <start>3005</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Head of Justice National Security Division to step down</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/john-carlin-steps-down-national-security-justice-228803?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
