<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>McIntosh</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/577834_Zombie-Hillary.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ABCLiz">
        <end>1898</end>
        <start>1891</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/YG4vi1GrqT">
        <end>1995</end>
        <start>1969</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ToadonaWire/status/777351566466674688">
        <end>2044</end>
        <start>2026</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>With yet two bombings and stabbings being committed within a 12-hour span, America has been reminded that we are the target of both homegrown hatred and the fanatical cult-like fallowing of a medieval ‘religion’. As expected, the two candidates running for office gave their comments on the matter..  But it was only one that really caught the attention of the media and not for what was said, but rather how it was delivered. Hillary Clinton used her response to a New York City bombing Saturday night to yet again take a swing at Donald Trump, but opponents and the media wondered if she was swinging while she was under the influence of something else. A tranquilized-sounding Clinton looked as if she was dazed out of her mind, as well as looking as if she was about to drop over and fall asleep. She spoke with the media pool that have been following her around on the campaign: “I’ve been briefed about the bombings in New York and New Jersey and the attack in Minnesota. Obviously we need to do everything we can to support our first responders, I’ll have more to say about it when we actually know some facts.” As she was giving her take, a reporter asked about Donald Trump’s reply and if she had any further comment on it. “I think it’s important to know the facts about any incident like this. That’s why it’s critical to support the first responders, the investigators who are looking into it trying to determine what did happen. I think it’s also wiser to wait until you have information before making conclusions because we are just in the beginning stages of trying to determine what happened,” she said. Twitter has gone crazy over the interview, with many followers saying they believed Clinton was either drugged up, or she just didn’t have the energy to wake herself up in a time of need. Either, or – it’s not Presidential material.  Is she highly medicated or what?? RT @ABCLiz: Hillary Clinton, on her campaign plane, responds to explosion in NYC pic.twitter.com/YG4vi1GrqT — OrdinaryToad (@ToadonaWire) September 18, 2016   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>299</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>300</end>
        <start>300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>426</end>
        <start>301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>655</end>
        <start>427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>800</end>
        <start>656</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>883</end>
        <start>801</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1232</end>
        <start>1119</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1619</end>
        <start>1233</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1807</end>
        <start>1620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1852</end>
        <start>1808</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1853</end>
        <start>1853</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1995</end>
        <start>1854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2044</end>
        <start>1996</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2045</end>
        <start>2045</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2046</end>
        <start>2046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2047</end>
        <start>2047</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>885</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1608</end>
        <start>1234</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2044</end>
        <start>1854</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>VIDEO: Hillary’s ‘Presidential’ Response To Weekend Bombings, Labeled As ‘Zombie’-Like</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/video-hillarys-presidential-response-weekend-bombings-labeled-zombie-like/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
