<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/brad-kapernick-728x407.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Colin-Kaepernick-sitting-anthem.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Paisley_Brad_2007_2.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Brad Paisley doesn’t seem like one who would call out any other dude, but apparently he is! Brad Paisley is one of our favorite country artists, and he has more American pride than almost any other country artist. Although we were surprised at his latest statement, we kind of weren’t surprised at the same time. If you have any kind of social media, or you read the news anywhere you have probably heard about a man by the name of Colin Kaepernick. He is the San Fransisco 49ers quarterback and he refused to stand up during the National Anthem.  Of course, this caused a lot of controversy all over the U.S considering the fact that football is America’s sport. Kaepernick stated his reasoning behind sitting during the National Anthem and it only made American’s more mad…well most of them at least. “I am not going to stand up to show pride in a flag for a country that oppresses black people and people of color…To me, this is bigger than football and it would be selfish on my part to look the other way. There are bodies in the street and people getting paid leave and getting away with murder.”  In response to his comment his team made a statement saying that it is an individuals choice to choose wether they stand for the anthem or not. “The national anthem is and always will be a special part of the pre-game ceremony. It is an opportunity to honor our country and reflect on the great liberties we are afforded as its citizens. In respecting such American principles as freedom of religion and freedom of expression, we recognize the right of an individual to choose and participate, or not, in our celebration of the national anthem.” This didn’t set well with Brad Paisley though, and he made sure that his fans knew he didn’t support Kaepernick’s decisions. The country star was recently performing at then PNC Music Pavilion in Charlotte and a video came up behind him that had fans rolling laughing.  Paisley was performing a fan favorite song “Celebrity” that talks about stars who let fame get to their heads. It’s a humorous song, but the best part was the video that was playing behind Paisley while he sand the song. The video was of making fun of celebrities like Kim Kardashian, Justin Bieber, and Donald Trump. The crowd was laughing hysterically but then a video of a cartoon Kaepernick was kneeling on the football field and other players were standing around him! The crowds tone changed quick and they turned their laughs into yelling and BOOING. Paisley didn’t say anything about Kaeapernick before showing the video, but apparently he is going to be showing it at all of his concerts!  What do you think about the video idea?</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>91</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>312</end>
        <start>92</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>546</end>
        <start>313</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>547</end>
        <start>547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>802</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1102</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1103</end>
        <start>1103</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1247</end>
        <start>1104</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1649</end>
        <start>1248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1918</end>
        <start>1650</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1919</end>
        <start>1919</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2140</end>
        <start>1920</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2393</end>
        <start>2141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2617</end>
        <start>2394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2618</end>
        <start>2618</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2658</end>
        <start>2619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>804</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1648</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1973</end>
        <start>1964</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1102</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1649</end>
        <start>1248</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Brad Paisley Has A Brutal Message For Cop-Haters, This Is SPOT ON</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/brad-paisley-has-a-brutal-message-for-cop-haters-this-is-spot-on/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Brad+Paisley%2F9%2F21&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2FBrad+Paisley%2F9%2F21</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
