<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/697755-fbi-director-gets-a-big-wake-up-call-from-congress-after-letting-hillary-off-the-hook/">
        <end>38</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Breaking-4-e1474467438375.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/07/644946-fbi-director-comey-ripped-for-the-dangerous-example-he-created-on-hillary-emails/">
        <end>1049</end>
        <start>1032</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/685916-fbi-releases-the-notes-from-their-investigation-of-hillarys-private-email-server/">
        <end>320</end>
        <start>299</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/07/643273-the-private-meeting-between-bill-clinton-and-loretta-lynch-has-launched-a-fresh-investigation/">
        <end>1412</end>
        <start>1397</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/07/644776-loretta-lynch-just-put-the-nail-in-the-coffin-of-the-fbi-investigation-on-hillarys-emails/">
        <end>1464</end>
        <start>1449</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/07/645210-congressman-hurd-torches-fbi-director-comey-over-clinton-emails/">
        <end>1494</end>
        <start>1476</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/07/645135-comey-consequences-for-actions/">
        <end>1516</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.washingtonexaminer.com/gop-subpoenas-fbi-to-turn-over-clinton-email-docs/article/2602352#.V-Gncoh74_M.twitter">
        <end>1728</end>
        <start>1720</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Breaking1-e1474467492453.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It looks like FBI Director James Comey is sitting in a pot of hot water and the temperature is steadily being increased. He let Hillary Clinton skate completely on the email scandal. He even said she was lying and was guilty, but let her off anyway. No one can figure out why either. Comey released highly redacted notes of his interview with Hillary Clinton. They were practically useless. Attorney General Loretta Lynch is just as complicit for meeting with Bill Clinton just before Hillary testified to the FBI. Obviously, briefing him on what Hillary should and should not say. Congress has repeatedly requested that Comey provide certain documents on Clinton’s email scandal and he has repeatedly failed to provide them. In a further attempt to get Comey to comply, Lamar Smith of Texas has slapped Comey with a subpoena compelling him to cough up the documents.  From the Independent Journal Review: The FBI Director’s recommendation to the Attorney General not to indict Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton for legal infractions with her private email server while at the State Department still has many political observers shaking their heads over the obvious legal double standard. The decision-making of FBI Director Comey, who recently sent highly redacted notes of his interview process and investigation of Hillary Clinton, and Attorney General Loretta Lynch, who had a private meeting with Bill Clinton prior to her case being dismissed, have been highly scrutinized. After grilling Comey on the Hill, Congress requested that the director deliver certain documents so lawmakers could better understand the scope and breadth of Hillary Clinton’s extra-legal email activities. The director has reportedly failed to deliver, and now Congress is once again trying to get transparency. The Washington Examiner reported: House Committee on Science, Space and Technology Chairman Lamar Smith, R-Texas, subpoenaed FBI Director James Comey on Tuesday for documents and information related to the security of the private email account and server Hillary Clinton used when she led the State Department. Smith asked Comey for the documents in a Sept. 9 letter, but then issued the subpoena after Comey failed to comply with the request. “The committee continues to have questions about the structure and security of the email system used by former Secretary Clinton and whether she and her staff employed cybersecurity standards required by FISMA,” the statement from the committee read. But I doubt they will ever get the answers they are seeking… they will get stonewalled by the Obama Administration, the FBI and the Clintons, just as they always do. We seem to no longer have three functioning separate branches of government in this nation. The Executive Branch seems to rule over all now, making the Judicial Branch submissive to it and the Legislative Branch all but irrelevant. There is no better example of that than the corruption surrounding Hillary Clinton.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>283</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>581</end>
        <start>284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>867</end>
        <start>582</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>868</end>
        <start>868</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>905</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1204</end>
        <start>906</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1495</end>
        <start>1205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1808</end>
        <start>1496</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1842</end>
        <start>1809</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2119</end>
        <start>1843</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2252</end>
        <start>2120</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2669</end>
        <start>2253</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2985</end>
        <start>2670</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2986</end>
        <start>2986</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2987</end>
        <start>2987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2463</end>
        <start>2254</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2252</end>
        <start>906</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: FBI Director James Comey – SUBPOENAED By Congress For Letting Hillary Off The Hook!</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/corruption/breaking-fbi-director-james-comey-subpoenaed-congress-letting-hillary-off-hook/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
