<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <links href="http://thefederalistpapers.org/us/black-dallas-cop-suing-black-lives-matter-for-starting-anti-police-race-war">
        <end>66</end>
        <start>56</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.scribd.com/document/324251965/Pennie-v-Soros-et-al-Amended-Complaint#from_embed">
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1926</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.scribd.com/user/248061868/BreitbartTexas#from_embed">
        <end>1983</end>
        <start>1969</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A Sergeant employed by the Dallas Police Department has officially filed a lawsuit in federal court against the notorious Black Lives Matter group for allegedly inciting anti police violence. The Sergeant is Demetrick Pennie whose the President of the Dallas Fallen Officer Foundation. He’s worked in law enforcement for seventeen years. Quite an impressive resume. In his lawsuit he said, “police officers and other law enforcement persons of all races and ethnicities including but not limited to Jews, Christians and Caucasians.” Defendants in the case include other race baiters such as Al Sharpton, President Obama, Hillary Clinton, Louis Farrakhan, George Soros, and The New Black Panthers Party. Pennie reports that they have, “repeatedly incited their supporters and others to engage in threats of and attacks to cause serious bodily injury or death upon police officers and other law enforcement persons of all races and ethnicities.” Furthermore, the lawsuit contends that the defendants have encouraged their supporters and citizens, “to engage in threats and attacks” against law enforcement officers around the country, including the July 7 murders of five Dallas police officers by Micah Johnson after a Black Lives Matter demonstration.” Larry Klayman who is a renowned conservative lawyer of FreedomWatch is representing Pennie in his case. Klayman told reporters in a press release, “Sergeant Pennie and I feel duty-bound to put ourselves forward to seek an end to the incitement of violence against law enforcement which has already resulted in the death of five police officers in Dallas and the wounding of seven more, just in Texas alone.” The lawsuit spans 66-pages and seeks a whopping $500 million in compensatory damages. Now while that number is completely ludicrous and next to impossible to obtain Pennie and Klayman are likely to obtain some portion of that number. This is a copy of the lawsuit. Pennie v. Soros et al Amended Complaint by BreitbartTexas on Scribd  Sgt. Pennie told Breitbart news why he felt the need to bring about this lawsuit and spoke about his motives saying, “This action was brought to stop the violence and killings of law enforcement officers in Dallas and throughout the nation.” You guys certainly have our prayers that you get compensation for all the pain and suffering good cops have had to deal with over the last few years. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>191</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>365</end>
        <start>192</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>389</end>
        <start>366</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>532</end>
        <start>390</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>733</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>943</end>
        <start>734</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1044</end>
        <start>944</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1252</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1399</end>
        <start>1253</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1660</end>
        <start>1400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1894</end>
        <start>1661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1925</end>
        <start>1895</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1993</end>
        <start>1926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1994</end>
        <start>1994</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2111</end>
        <start>1995</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2236</end>
        <start>2112</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2386</end>
        <start>2237</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2387</end>
        <start>2387</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>531</end>
        <start>391</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>942</end>
        <start>735</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>1046</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1659</end>
        <start>1401</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2235</end>
        <start>2113</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BOOM! Black Dallas Cop Suing Black Lives Matter For Starting Anti-Police Race War</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/boom-black-dallas-cop-suing-black-lives-matter-for-starting-anti-police-race-war/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
