<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.suffolk.edu/news/67596.php#.V-QJJfkrKUm">
        <end>106</end>
        <start>102</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump leads Hillary Clinton by 1 point among Florida’s likely voters, a new Suffolk University poll released Thursday shows, placing the candidates in a statistical dead heat. On the Sunshine State’s crowded presidential ballot, the Republican nominee leads the former secretary of state by a narrow 45 percent to 44 percent margin. Of the four other candidates named on the ballot, only Libertarian Gary Johnson and Green Party candidate Jill Stein registered any support, with 3 percent and less than 1 percent, respectively. Because the poll’s margin of error is plus-or-minus 4.4 percentage points, Trump’s 1 point lead puts him in a statistical tie with Clinton in Florida. Still, it is more good news for the Manhattan billionaire who has also polled ahead in recent days in the key swing states of Nevada, Ohio and North Carolina. President Barack Obama won those three states as well as Florida in his 2008 presidential bid and lost only North Carolina from that group in 2012. In the Florida senate race, incumbent GOP Sen. Marco Rubio leads Democratic Rep. Patrick Murphy by 9 points, 43 percent to 34 percent. Rubio, a former Republican presidential candidate, had initially said he would not run for reelection to the Senate if he failed to earn the nomination but wound up entering and winning Florida’s GOP Senate primary. Murphy defeated firebrand liberal Rep. Alan Grayson in the Democratic primary to earn his spot on the general election ballot. The Suffolk University poll was conducted from Sept. 19-21 among 500 likely Florida voters. The poll’s margin of error was plus-or-minus 4.4 points.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>182</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>534</end>
        <start>183</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>992</end>
        <start>535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1470</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1619</end>
        <start>1471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Poll: Trump, Clinton in virtual tie in Florida</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/swing-states-2016-election/2016/09/poll-clinton-trump-florida-228525?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
