<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=702wJC6O-6A">
        <end>695</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/18/obama-jokes-about-isis-on-same-day-america-gets-bombed-twice/">
        <end>1213</end>
        <start>1137</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Even if you are President Obama, your jokes need to have good timing. Unfortunately for our President, his ISIS joke came at the same time as the terrorists bombings in New Jersey and New York. Even comedians have bad day. Chalk this one up as a bad day for our Comedian-in-Chief  As Written By Blake Neff for the Daily Caller: Obama Jokes About ISIS Same Day America Gets Bombed. President Barack Obama made a joke with unfortunately bad timing Saturday, quipping that the Islamic State was no big deal compared to his birth certificate, only to have America hit by two separate explosions. While addressing a dinner held by the Congressional Black Caucus Foundation Saturday night, Obama joked about Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump’s recent declaration that Obama was, in fact, born in America. “I don’t know about you guys, but I am so relieved that the whole birther thing is over,” Obama said. “I mean, ISIL, North Korea, poverty, climate change, none of those things weighed on my mind like the validity of my birth certificate.” Unfortunately, at almost the same time Obama made his remarks, the … Full Story Here: Obama Jokes About ISIS Same Day America Gets Bombed Twice | The Daily Caller</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>279</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>280</end>
        <start>280</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>327</end>
        <start>281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>380</end>
        <start>328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>591</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1050</end>
        <start>812</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1119</end>
        <start>1051</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1136</end>
        <start>1120</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1213</end>
        <start>1137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>900</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1049</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1213</end>
        <start>1120</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama jokes about ISIS</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/obama-jokes-about-isis/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
