<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tiffiny Ruegner</author>
    <links href="https://policy.m4bl.org/platform/">
        <end>42</end>
        <start>28</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackLivesMatter?src=hash">
        <end>732</end>
        <start>715</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Blklivesmatter">
        <end>798</end>
        <start>783</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/IIlnTbgE1S">
        <end>822</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/DMVBlackLives/status/755807855794675712">
        <end>875</end>
        <start>862</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2016/aug/16/black-lives-matter-cashes-100-million-liberal-foun/">
        <end>1394</end>
        <start>1383</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/07/22/black-lives-matter-denounces-friendly-cookout-with-local-cops/#ixzz4LUCXJP4l">
        <end>2141</end>
        <start>2128</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/BlakeDontCrack/status/756392445751889920">
        <end>3418</end>
        <start>3405</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Black Lives Matter released their platform last month that calls for defunding police departments, race-based reparations, voting rights for illegal immigrants, fossil-fuel divestment, an end to private education and charter schools, a “universal basic income” and free college for blacks. Based on this platform it is obvious that ‘black people’ don’t have parents or families to teach them how to take care of themselves and their own needs.   Based on that ‘platform’ it comes as no surprise that Black Lives Matter got upset when an unofficial BLM chapter held a protest that turned into a cookout with the local police. The BLM made sure to denounce the chapter and event immediately:  THIS IS NOT AN OFFICIAL #BlackLivesMatter CHAPTER! THIS IS NOT IN LINE WITH OUR PRINCIPLES. @Blklivesmatter https://t.co/IIlnTbgE1S — BlackLivesMatter DC (@DMVBlackLives) July 20, 2016   Trying to heal the wounds of a nation and come together by working together is NOT the goal of Black Lives Matter. In their tweet and many conversations about the event thereafter, they have revealed that their goal is destruction. They want to rip apart America by creating a divide between races which is essentially the goal of their major donor, George Soros. Soros is known for disrupting the economies of nations to profit from the unrest. This is why the major Black Lives Donor has given at least $33 Million in grants to Black Lives Matter through his Open Society Foundation and from the Center For American Progress. Soros funded political movement, Occupy Wallstreet, didn’t have the bones and anger to rip apart America because it was a bunch of people who don’t want to work. But the black community is a huge part of the thread of what is America. Soros’ attempt to create a massive racial divide between ‘white and black’ on the backs of familial deaths in the black community and blaming it on society instead of the individual looks like a winning movement. To disallow communities to try and heal that divide is contrary to Soros’ plan. What happened in the Wichita, Kansas community was an attempt to close that divide. KSNW, the NBC affiliate station covering the area, said that the event, which was hosted by the Sunflower Community Action group, wasn’t just a lighthearted celebration — it was a way for the community to reach out to its police department to discuss issues surrounding police-community relations. The Wichita Eagle reported that “At one table, three men – a black man, a Hispanic man and a white man – sat down with burgers next to Lt. Travis Rakestraw to share their ideas.” Black Lives Matter later responded to their initial tweet that the event was against BLM principles saying, “Our statement about BLM BBQ’s with police was a direct response to the tons of people and orgs who were upset by the event. We assured folks our principles were still focused on dismantling the system.” Dividing people by race, gender, age and religion is the key to dismantling the system. The ‘cops’ are the enforcers of ‘the system’ which is called RULE OF LAW. Without rule of law you will have dismantled the melting pot that is America. Who will survive the anarchy that Black Lives Matter are working for? Who is most likely to lose out? Inner-cities are most likely to lose out if anarchy replaces rule of law.  To end police brutality you have to end the police. — Brotha B (@BlakeDontCrack) July 22, 2016   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>443</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>444</end>
        <start>444</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>445</end>
        <start>445</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>689</end>
        <start>446</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>690</end>
        <start>690</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>822</end>
        <start>691</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>875</end>
        <start>823</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>876</end>
        <start>876</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>877</end>
        <start>877</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1953</end>
        <start>878</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2117</end>
        <start>1954</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2594</end>
        <start>2118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3322</end>
        <start>2595</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3323</end>
        <start>3323</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3375</end>
        <start>3324</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3418</end>
        <start>3376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3419</end>
        <start>3419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3420</end>
        <start>3420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3421</end>
        <start>3421</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>259</end>
        <start>237</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2593</end>
        <start>2449</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2905</end>
        <start>2704</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>875</end>
        <start>691</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2594</end>
        <start>2118</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3418</end>
        <start>3324</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BlackLivesMatter BOSS Comes Clean – Now We Know, Their Leaders Seek No Solutions…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/headline-blacklivesmatter-boss-comes-clean-now-we-know-their-leaders-seek-no-solutions/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
