<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="http://www.military.com/daily-news/2016/09/16/navy-to-hold-all-hands-training-webinars-new-transgender-policy.html">
        <end>439</end>
        <start>418</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.military.com/daily-news/2016/08/08/navy-marines-to-accept-transgender-recruits-by-july-2017.html">
        <end>1611</end>
        <start>1579</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.militarytimes.com/articles/defense-department-covers-gender-reassignment-surgery">
        <end>1819</end>
        <start>1792</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It was only a matter of time before the military would start reeducating servicemen (or is it “servicepeople?”) about how to behave around others who are born with one set of sex organs but “identify” as a member of the opposite sex. All troops will be required to be trained in how to behave around transgender people by July of 2017, coinciding with the date that the Navy will begin accepting transgender recruits. Military.com reported: In an all-Navy message published Tuesday, Chief of Naval Personnel Vice Adm. Robert Burke said a three-pronged training approach will equip senior leaders and rank-and-file personnel for the changes. “This training will emphasize policies and expectations of personal behavior,” the message states. Beginning Nov. 1, mobile training teams composed of Navy fleet representatives and subject matter expects will be dispatched to deliver face-to-face briefs to senior leaders, including commanding officers, executive officers, command master chiefs, and chiefs of boat. These sessions will also be open to equal opportunity advisers, ombudsmen and other command-designated representatives who will have a role in training the tenant commands on policies governing transgender troops. Along with permitting transgender troops to serve openly, the military is creating procedures for troops to change their “gender marker” in the administrative Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System, and laying out rules to govern how troops might undergo medical gender transitions while in uniform. Transgender troops will be required to use the bathroom and berthing facilities associated with their preferred gender, Navy officials have said. And service leaders will be on alert for those who seek to single out or mistreat their transgender counterparts. The Military Times reported that transgender troops are now eligible to receive sex-reassignment surgery paid for by the Pentagon (taxpayers) as long as they’re active-duty, and there is approval from their doctors and military health officials. The surgical procedure to rearrange the active duty military member’s genitals to vaguely resemble those of the opposite sex can be performed at a military hospital, or if it’s not available at the time – or if there’s a long wait time – Tricare will cover it at a private hospital.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>233</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>440</end>
        <start>234</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>640</end>
        <start>441</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>739</end>
        <start>641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1008</end>
        <start>740</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1222</end>
        <start>1009</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1531</end>
        <start>1223</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1677</end>
        <start>1532</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1791</end>
        <start>1678</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2037</end>
        <start>1792</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2320</end>
        <start>2038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2321</end>
        <start>2321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2467</end>
        <start>2322</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2541</end>
        <start>2468</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>109</end>
        <start>95</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>199</end>
        <start>191</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>718</end>
        <start>642</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1358</end>
        <start>1345</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1699</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2503</end>
        <start>2491</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Navy to Begin Mandatory TRANSGENDER Behavioral Education</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36877/navy-to-begin-mandatory-transgender-behavioral-education/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
