<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump quickly laid into each other over trade during the first presidential debate, with Clinton citing her husband’s work on NAFTA as evidence she’s thought a lot about trade deals and Trump calling NAFTA the worst deal “ever approved” in the U.S. “I think my husband did a pretty good job [on trade deals] in the 1990s. I think a lot about what worked and how we can make it work again,” Clinton said. Story Continued Below “He approved NAFTA, which is the single worst trade deal ever approved in this country,” Trump shot back.The GOP nominee has harnessed anger among working-class voters on trade this year — a strategy that garnered him massive support from blue-collar workers and even prompted other Republicans who have supported free trade to flip their positions. Clinton said that “we’re going to enforce the trade deals we have and we’re going to hold people accountable.” She continued by saying that the country “increased global exports 40 percent” during her time as Secretary of State. “You go to new England, Ohio, Pennsylvania, you go anywhere you want, Secretary Clinton, and you will see devastation where manufacturing is down 30, 40, sometimes 50 percent. NAFTA is the worst trade deal maybe ever,” Trump shot back. “Donald, you may live in your own reality but that is not the facts,” Clinton said to Trump.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>275</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>430</end>
        <start>276</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>452</end>
        <start>431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>802</end>
        <start>453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1031</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1267</end>
        <start>1032</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1360</end>
        <start>1268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>262</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>415</end>
        <start>277</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>540</end>
        <start>454</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>912</end>
        <start>822</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>956</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1249</end>
        <start>1033</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>1269</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump pins NAFTA, 'worst trade deal ever,' on Clinton</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-clinton-come-out-swinging-over-nafta-228712?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
