<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/glen-campbell-1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ashley-campbell-800.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.people.com/article/glen-campbell-daughter-ashley-acm-honors">
        <end>1178</end>
        <start>1172</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ashley-campbell-02-800.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/150619181526-12-glen-campbell-restricted-super-169.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Glen Campbell’s family released that he was in his final stages of Alzheimer’s and we were all extremely heartbroken to hear the news. When we found out that Glen Campbell was in his final stages of Alzheimer’s we weren’t sure what to expect the next couple of months. Unfortunately, this meant that Glen Campbell had lost all ability to speak or play guitar and it was just a matter of time before we had to say goodbye forever.  Campbell family has handled the situation very gracefully and they have been as strong as they possibly can be while they watch him wither away. His wife has become an advocate for Alzheimer’s and his children are also very involved. Glen Campbell made an exceptional impact on country music, and it has been absolutely heartbreaking to see him this way. Although he isn’t able to attend any shows, the country music world has surrounded him with love from afar.  Recently at the ACM Honors, four special country men took the stage to honor Glen Campbell and all that he has done for country music. Dierks Bentley, Blake Shelton, Toby Keith and Keith Urban gave one of the greatest tributes of all time and Glen Campbell’s daughter spoke to PEOPLE about the honor that it was. “The Academy of Country Music reached out to us a while ago and we were completely thrilled…I hope people see how his music and his voice really touched people and is still touching people now. It’s the definition of timeless.”  Her father is now 80-years-old and he is being cared for at a full-time care facility near their home in Nashville, Tennessee. Ashley says that her father’s disease is definitely progressing but that lately he has stayed pretty steady with little to no change. She went on to say that sometimes he will see her and light up with a smile, and he’ll hug her. Of course, with the disease progressing you never know what to expect when you walk in the doors where he is. “He’s definitely progressing but he’s been pretty steady lately…There’s no giant leaps and bounds, but for the most part he is just in his own world. When I go and visit him, he might notice I’m there and his face will light up and he’ll give me a hug.”  And although his attention span is really short right now, Ashley says that he finds joy in being around others which is a huge blessing for her and her family at this point in the disease. “(He’s) just very happy and content and a joy for everyone to be around…That’s all you can ask for at that stage.”  We are heartbroken to hear about Glen, but happy that he still loves to be around his family! Please say a prayer for him in the comments below!!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>134</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>429</end>
        <start>135</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>430</end>
        <start>430</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>893</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>894</end>
        <start>894</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1207</end>
        <start>895</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1435</end>
        <start>1208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1436</end>
        <start>1436</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1697</end>
        <start>1437</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1903</end>
        <start>1698</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2157</end>
        <start>1904</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2158</end>
        <start>2158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2348</end>
        <start>2159</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2463</end>
        <start>2349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2464</end>
        <start>2464</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2610</end>
        <start>2465</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1209</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2156</end>
        <start>1905</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2462</end>
        <start>2350</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1435</end>
        <start>1208</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2157</end>
        <start>1904</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2463</end>
        <start>2349</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Glen Campbell’s Family Just Posted An Emotional Health Update, This Left Me In Tears</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/glen-campbells-family-just-posted-an-emotional-update-this-left-me-in-tears/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Glen+Campbell%2F9%2F22&amp;utm_content=Right+Wing+News%2FGlen+Campbell%2F9%2F22</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
