<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://www.wilsoncenter.org/person/aaron-david-miller">
        <end>1471</end>
        <start>1453</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/06/netanyahu-prime-minister-obama-president-foreign-policy-us-israel-israeli-relations-middle-east-iran-defense-forces-idf-214004">
        <end>1667</end>
        <start>1653</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/21/us/politics/donald-trump-issues.html?_r=0">
        <end>5216</end>
        <start>5207</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://forward.com/news/345068/donald-trump-praises-era-when-my-jews-said-merry-christmas-michele-bachmann/">
        <end>7338</end>
        <start>7334</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>President Barack Obama and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu are holding what is expected to be their final meeting as heads of government on Wednesday—and there is every reason to expect that this one in New York, at the United Nations General Assembly, will be as fruitless as previous encounters. It is no secret that U.S.-Israel relations have become volatile and tense over the past eight years, with Obama and Netanyahu sparring over Israeli settlements and the all-but-moribund peace process, Iran’s nuclear program, and the uprisings of the Arab Spring. But the likelihood of a sputtering end to the Barack-and-Bibi relationship does lead one to ask: Which of the two candidates who are running to replace Obama next January—Hillary Clinton or Donald Trump—might do somewhat better in restoring the U.S.-Israel relationship and pushing for peace? Story Continued Below Trump surrogate and former New York Mayor Rudy Giuliani claimed at the Republican convention that Netanyahu and other government ministers favored Trump. Our sources say the Israeli security cabinet is divided but on the whole views Clinton as the safer course. There is, in any event, no doubt that the governing Likud Party has become closely aligned with Republicans in recent years, and that Netanyahu was betting on a Mitt Romney victory four years ago. “The notion that they don’t intervene in our politics and we don’t intervene in theirs is pure nonsense,” as Aaron David Miller, a Middle East negotiator for successive U.S. administrations, has put it. “Netanyahu has clearly made his preferences clear on the Republican side.” But Netanyahu is himself often second-guessed by Israel’s national security elites. And the answer to the question of who really would be better for a future U.S.-Israel alliance, a President Clinton or a President Trump, requires starting with a more basic issue: What does it mean to be a good ally to Israel? The current Israeli government seems to think that a good American ally would stop nagging Jerusalem about West Bank settlements, forget about the Israel-Palestine peace process, provide a blank check for security assistance, use military force in the region more readily, tear up the nuclear deal with Iran, and also supply weapons for Israel to strike Iran unilaterally if it thought it was necessary at some point. Hillary Clinton certainly would not follow this agenda to the letter; in that sense, her administration might well share some of Obama’s priorities. She clearly values the U.S.-Israel alliance highly, she is committed to Israel’s security, and she has credibly promised to fend off diplomatic efforts that Israelis see as “delegitimizing” the Jewish state whether at the U.N., through sanctions, boycotts or punitive disinvestment. At the same time, she has confirmed that the peace process and a two-state solution will be central to her Israel policies. And she promises to safeguard, not tear up, the nuclear deal with Iran. Safeguarding means holding Iran to its terms and being prepared, as Obama promised in spring 2012, to use military force if needed to prevent Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon. Many Israelis derided Obama’s commitment—wrongly, in our view. But Clinton’s credibility regarding the use of force should not be in doubt. On balance, we think, she would be a better president in the long run for Israel. Here’s why. If Jerusalem hopes for an American president to renege on the nuclear deal, Trump may well be their man. He has certainly bragged about his history of walking away from agreements. What happens then, however, is a question for which Trump has no convincing answer. Some of his advisers point to Richard Nixon’s “madman” theory of how to frighten rivals with the unpredictability of American leadership. But Nixon, whatever his other faults, was a shrewd geo-strategist (and he had Henry Kissinger by his side). Trump, judging by his erratic and impulsive behavior on just about any given day of this campaign, seems far too close to the madman template for anyone’s comfort—least of all a small Middle Eastern state that depends on a steadiness of commitment from its American protector. Steadiness is one of the last words that come to mind when thinking about Trump’s various statements about Israel and the Palestinians. He could embrace something resembling neutrality and demand a return on U.S. assistance—signature Trump foreign policy themes—or, alternatively, as he put it, he could be "the most pro-Israel president ever.” This uncertainty about his instincts does not bode well for alliance management. Indeed, his innate isolationism and nativist demagoguery portend two kinds of trouble for U.S. relations with Israel. First, Trump would enter office as the only genuinely isolationist president since the 19th century—an unsettling prospect for Israel, which depends heavily on U.S. internationalism (and an experience that Israel, which is only 68 years old, has never had). Although not, as a rule, philosophically inclined, Trump has expressed a coherent view of international relations as fiercely transactional and zero sum. This view extends to alliances, as he made clear in a New York Times interview in which he explicitly disavowed America’s Article 5 guarantee to defend NATO allies including Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania. “If we cannot be properly reimbursed for the tremendous cost of our military protecting other countries, and in many cases the countries I’m talking about are extremely rich … Then yes, I would be absolutely prepared to tell those countries, 'Congratulations, you will be defending yourself.”’ In the world according to Trump, alliances such as NATO are inherently bad arrangements for the United States because the country is defending European allies who have little capacity to reciprocate, and who are unwilling to adequately pay for their protection. Likewise, maintaining a nuclear umbrella over South Korea and Japan seems to be a foolish and dangerous entanglement when those countries could just as well develop and deploy nuclear weapons themselves. And, of course, ”isolationism” is a mild term for what Trump conceives as the proper relationship between the U.S. and its southern neighbor. Perhaps Trump will make an exception to his expectation of a “return on investment” for commitment to allies, and he will stand by Israel no matter what it can or cannot do for the U.S. in return. If so, however, it would be out of character. Second, Trump’s invective against Muslims and other immigrant communities might appear in sync with Israeli hard-liners—the GOP nominee has indeed pointed to Israel’s security barrier and security profiling of Muslims as models for his own Great Wall on the Mexican border and promised ban on Muslims entering the country. But if Israel’s government really prefers Trump on this basis, this will drive another wedge between Israel and American Jews. Most American Jews are politically liberal, and they are particularly allergic to fear-mongering rhetoric against minorities. The experience of millennia has taught them that security for diaspora communities depends on a general climate of liberal tolerance. When demagogues single out minorities, Jews have to ask themselves—are we next? So, to take a small but telling example, when Trump has said that “my Jews”—presumably his employees—used to say “Merry Christmas,” and implies that his presidency will usher in a new era in which “Happy Holidays” will be a euphemism of the past, American Jews are not amused. The fact is, the U.S.-Israel alliance needs to be nurtured for the long haul, which means facing up to its real problems and reinforcing its moral foundations. It is wrong to think that the problems between Obama and Netanyahu have been determined by the personalities of the two leaders. Generational transformation on both sides has deepened strategic differences over the best way to manage a fragile regional balance of power, Palestinian political aspirations, and the increasingly anarchic conditions in the region. Israel is becoming more religious and less democratic. The United States is becoming more diverse—this, after all, is what Trump’s followers are angry about—and, arguably, more liberal. Surveys of young Israeli Jews show a sharp decline in support of Israel’s identity as a democratic state, from 26.1 percent in 1998 to 14.3 percent today. The growing religious nationalist population is becoming increasingly powerful in Israeli politics and society, including the Israel Defense Force. In 1990, 2.5 percent of officer candidates self-identified as religious, compared with 26 percent in 2008. Young Americans, in contrast, are more liberal than their parents on matters related to Israel-Palestine. A recent Pew Survey indicated that 57 percent of self-styled “liberal Democrats” sympathized with Palestinians more than Israel—at a time when younger Democrats are more and more likely to call themselves liberal. Politics in both countries appear to be tracking these trends. Last May, Netanyahu fired Defense Minister Moshe Yaalon for defending a senior officer’s right to criticize the government. Rather than seek to shore up his coalition by replacing him with a center-left figure, Netanyahu opted for the far-right wing Avigdor Lieberman as defense minister, creating what Israeli columnist Nahum Barnea has called “the most radical government … in Israeli history.” Meanwhile, as Guiliani has contended, it may well be right that the Democratic Party’s leftward movement could bring additional tensions to relations with Israel. Bernie Sanders supporters on the Democratic Platform Committee failed in the effort to include language more harshly critical of the Israel occupation of the West Bank. There is little doubt, however, that this represented the views of many of his younger supporters. *** What can be done to revive the U.S.-Israel relationship, under either a President Clinton or President Trump? In our recent book on U.S.-Israel relations, we suggest that one approach would be to negotiate a formal alliance enshrined in a treaty that would specify mutual responsibilities. The U.S. would undertake a legally binding commitment to defend Israel from attack, particularly by Iran. Although the White House has already declared this commitment publicly, a solemn treaty obligation would inject it with greater credibility in Iranian as well as Israeli eyes. To underscore the depth of obligation, the U.S. could deploy a tripwire force—as it long did in the Asia and Europe—to ensure that Israel’s adversaries understood that an attack on Israel would be tantamount to one on Americans that would bring the United States into any military conflict. In return, Israel would agree to a final status accord with the Palestinians along the territorial lines that the U.S. has long endorsed: the 1967 borders with mutually agreed swaps. The U.S., working closely with Israel and Jordan, would not only help secure the parties’ safety, but work with European donors to put the new Palestinian state on a firm footing to reduce the possibility of revanchist violence. Under this arrangement, the U.S. would contemplate a military assistance package that came closer to Israel’s vision for the one that has just been signed, while Israel’s withdrawal from the West Bank would ensure robust trade ties with Europe well into the future. Many on both sides will say that this program entails too many risks for too uncertain a gain. Israelis for whom past is prologue will argue that the practical benefits of a treaty is available at no cost. It certainly doesn’t fit with Donald Trump’s purely transactional view of international relations. But in an increasingly violent Middle East, it behooves both countries to reconsecrate a relationship based on a shared moral and strategic vision. As a matter of moral temperament and strategic vision, Hillary Clinton would appear far more likely to make this happen.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>569</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>862</end>
        <start>570</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>884</end>
        <start>863</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1621</end>
        <start>885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2351</end>
        <start>1622</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3299</end>
        <start>2352</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3393</end>
        <start>3300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4181</end>
        <start>3394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4725</end>
        <start>4182</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5636</end>
        <start>4726</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6244</end>
        <start>5637</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6487</end>
        <start>6245</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7554</end>
        <start>6488</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7714</end>
        <start>7555</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8262</end>
        <start>7715</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8992</end>
        <start>8263</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9452</end>
        <start>8993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9883</end>
        <start>9453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9887</end>
        <start>9884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10750</end>
        <start>9888</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11428</end>
        <start>10751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>12002</end>
        <start>11429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1448</end>
        <start>1345</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1620</end>
        <start>1548</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2689</end>
        <start>2675</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3712</end>
        <start>3706</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5634</end>
        <start>5344</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6327</end>
        <start>6307</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7352</end>
        <start>7345</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7408</end>
        <start>7392</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7490</end>
        <start>7476</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8858</end>
        <start>8841</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9451</end>
        <start>9402</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Barack and Bibi—Goodbye to All That?</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/09/obama-bibi-netanyahu-israel-trump-clinton-2016-214267?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
