<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Hortense Goulard</author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/chris-spillane/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>25</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/sarah-wheaton/">
        <end>152</end>
        <start>139</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/chris-spillane/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>25</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/chris-spillane/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>25</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/benjamin-oreskes/">
        <end>505</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/michael-crowley/">
        <end>634</end>
        <start>619</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nahal-toosi/">
        <end>650</end>
        <start>639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/michael-kruse/">
        <end>790</end>
        <start>777</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/ryan-heath/">
        <end>954</end>
        <start>944</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/tara-palmeri/">
        <end>968</end>
        <start>956</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/harry-cooper/">
        <end>982</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/quentin-aries/">
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>987</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/harry-cooper/">
        <end>982</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/tom-mctague/">
        <end>1164</end>
        <start>1153</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/ivo-oliveira/">
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1407</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/elana-schor/">
        <end>1621</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/kyle-cheney/">
        <end>1634</end>
        <start>1623</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/louis-nelson/">
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nicholas-vinocur/">
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/florian-eder/">
        <end>2012</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/janosch-delcker/">
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>2017</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/anthony-skinner/">
        <end>2237</end>
        <start>2222</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/charlie-cooper/">
        <end>2344</end>
        <start>2330</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/barbara-surk/">
        <end>2690</end>
        <start>2678</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/madeline-conway/">
        <end>3324</end>
        <start>3309</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cristiano-lima/">
        <end>3499</end>
        <start>3485</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/bryan-bender/">
        <end>3623</end>
        <start>3611</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nicholas-vinocur/">
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/tim-king/">
        <end>3992</end>
        <start>3984</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nahal-toosi/">
        <end>650</end>
        <start>639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/shane-goldmacher/">
        <end>4240</end>
        <start>4224</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/andrew-restuccia/">
        <end>4261</end>
        <start>4245</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/jacopo-barigazzi/">
        <end>4418</end>
        <start>4402</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/edward-isaac-dovere/">
        <end>4537</end>
        <start>4518</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/janosch-delcker/">
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>2017</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/konstantin-richter/">
        <end>4966</end>
        <start>4948</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/paul-dallison/">
        <end>5076</end>
        <start>5063</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/brent-griffiths/">
        <end>5206</end>
        <start>5191</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/maia-de-la-baume/">
        <end>5249</end>
        <start>5233</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/louis-nelson/">
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/carter-stoddard/">
        <end>5551</end>
        <start>5536</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/laurens-cerulus/">
        <end>5679</end>
        <start>5664</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/paul-dallison/">
        <end>5076</end>
        <start>5063</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.handelsblatt.com/politik/deutschland/jahresbericht-deutsche-einheit-der-bedrohte-frieden/14576922.html">
        <end>7219</end>
        <start>7207</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/far-right-afd-overtakes-merkels-conservatives-in-regional-vote/">
        <end>7953</end>
        <start>7908</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/hate-crime-in-the-uk-still-high-after-brexit-vote/">
        <end>8147</end>
        <start>8131</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/hungary-anger-grows-viktor-orban-award-writer-racism/">
        <end>8147</end>
        <start>8131</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/theresa-may-tells-polish-pm-of-regret-at-attacks/">
        <end>8147</end>
        <start>8131</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/ivo-oliveira/">
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1407</start>
    </links>
    <links>
        <end>9305</end>
        <start>9292</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>11/19/16, 3:14 PM CET BY Chris Spillane So is anti-establishment message of Nigel Farage, the Labour leader said. 11/19/16, 1:55 PM CET BY Sarah Wheaton Alumni of the Obama White House spent days mourning Trump’s win. Now they’re ready to fight. 11/19/16, 11:37 AM CET BY Chris Spillane Dick Schoof: ‘Chance of attack in the Netherlands is real.’ 11/19/16, 10:38 AM CET BY Chris Spillane Government could focus on starting the process of leaving the bloc sooner. 11/19/16, 10:13 AM CET BY Benjamin Oreskes Diplomats say the president-elect already has a playbook to undermine the global body. 11/19/16, 10:01 AM CET BY Michael Crowley and Nahal Toosi Flynn, Bannon represent ‘Islamophobic’ thinking of the type rejected by Bush and Obama, critics say. 11/19/16, 5:25 AM CET BY Michael Kruse The blue-collar workers who put Donald Trump in the White House are ready for him to deliver. How much time will they give him? 11/19/16, 5:20 AM CET BY Ryan Heath, Tara Palmeri, Harry Cooper and Quentin Ariès  11/18/16, 9:09 PM CET BY Harry Cooper A Polish political party’s links to a pan-European group raise questions about funding. 11/18/16, 6:31 PM CET BY Tom McTague Signs that Britain’s political class is coming to terms with June’s EU referendum. 11/18/16, 6:26 PM CET BY Hortense Goulard Conservative MEP denounced Juncker’s efforts to drum up support for Schulz as ‘outrageous.’ 11/18/16, 5:31 PM CET BY Ivo Oliveira Drawing the top stories around the globe. 11/18/16, 4:55 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Italians are likely to reject prime minister’s reform package in next month’s vote. 11/18/16, 4:48 PM CET BY Elana Schor, Kyle Cheney and Louis Nelson The president-elect starts building out his administration with loyalists. 11/18/16, 4:01 PM CET BY Nicholas Vinocur Left-wingers hope that by backing Alain Juppé, they will see off two political enemies. 11/18/16, 3:15 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Jens Stoltenberg did not mention the total number or reasons for the requests. 11/18/16, 3:02 PM CET BY Florian Eder and Janosch Delcker Wird Martin Schulz die SPD in den Bundestagswahlkampf führen? Oder schafft er es, doch noch einmal EU-Parlamentspräsident zu werden? Er muss sich bald entscheiden. 11/18/16, 2:34 PM CET BY Anthony Skinner Syrian refugees are pawns in Turkish president’s pursuit of power. 11/18/16, 2:33 PM CET BY Charlie Cooper Shadow Brexit secretary ‘seriously pissed off’ at colleague’s comments. 11/18/16, 2:33 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet German chancellor is ‘championing the interests of Europe,’ Witold Waszczykowski said. 11/18/16, 12:58 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Nikola Gruevski stepped down in January over a wire tapping scandal. 11/18/16, 12:48 PM CET BY Barbara Surk Jens Stoltenberg said he had a ‘good talk’ with the president-elect. 11/18/16, 12:35 PM CET BY Esther King Majority of those who failed to gain international asylum come from the Balkan states. 11/18/16, 11:48 AM CET BY Esther King Immigration is what keeps the country running, says pro-EU Lord. 11/18/16, 10:57 AM CET BY Esther King Conditions at offshore detention center for refugees are ‘cruel, inhuman and degrading,’ said François Crépeau. 11/18/16, 9:36 AM CET BY Esther King Foreign Minister Linas Linkevičius warned that Vladimir Putin could use transition period in Baltics, Syria. 11/18/16, 8:55 AM CET BY MADELINE CONWAY Former ambassador to the UN says there are ways of supporting the opposition that does not involve the use of American military force. 11/18/16, 8:39 AM CET BY Cristiano Lima Her presence is likely to raise fresh concerns about potential conflicts of interest. 11/18/16, 8:35 AM CET BY Bryan Bender The retired lieutenant general’s hardline views on Islam — as well as laudatory statements about Russia — have made him a lightning rod, as did his strident attacks on Hillary Clinton during the campaign. 11/18/16, 5:33 AM CET BY Nicholas Vinocur The center-right’s first ever presidential primary looked all over. Now it’s wide open. 11/18/16, 5:25 AM CET BY Tim King The Günther Oettinger controversies are tainting this European Commission by intimate association. 11/18/16, 12:17 AM CET BY Nahal Toosi Much of Europe is alarmed over what Trump’s presidency could augur. 11/17/16, 11:52 PM CET BY Shane Goldmacher and Andrew Restuccia ‘We feel way ahead of schedule and never in a rush to do the wrong thing,’ said campaign manager Kellyanne Conway. 11/17/16, 9:42 PM CET BY Jacopo Barigazzi Maltese interior minister not impressed with Bratislava’s migration plan. 11/17/16, 9:33 PM CET BY Edward-Isaac Dovere In Berlin, the president warned his successor that his divisive campaign style won’t wear well in the Oval Office. 11/17/16, 8:24 PM CET BY Janosch Delcker US President hopes Trump won’t ‘simply take a Realpolitik approach.’ 11/17/16, 8:21 PM CET BY Hortense Goulard European Parliament president will only accept foreign minister role if he is also the SPD candidate for the top job. 11/17/16, 8:18 PM CET BY Konstantin Richter Germans, of all people, are now called on to be bulwarks of democracy. 11/17/16, 8:06 PM CET BY Paul Dallison and Esther King Euroskeptic party stands accused of breaking rules on spending EU funds. 11/17/16, 7:16 PM CET BY Brent Griffiths  11/17/16, 6:31 PM CET BY Maïa de La Baume Brussels faults Ankara for ‘neglecting and undermining’ democracy and the rule of law. 11/17/16, 6:27 PM CET BY Louis Nelson  11/17/16, 5:47 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Jean-Marie Le Pen should receive €15,000 because he was prevented from carrying out his duties. 11/17/16, 4:57 PM CET BY Carter Stoddard Net debt has ballooned to £338 million, and currency fluctuations are partly to blame. 11/17/16, 4:34 PM CET BY Laurens Cerulus In finally passing her surveillance bill, Britain’s PM just made Brexit even more complicated. 11/17/16, 4:13 PM CET BY Hortense Goulard French prime minister called for more European integration amid rising nationalism. 11/17/16, 3:23 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Former European Council president joins forces with Flemish singer. 11/17/16, 2:53 PM CET BY Paul Dallison Corey Lewandowski said president-elect will work closely with Theresa May, with no need for UKIP leader as a go-between. 11/17/16, 2:37 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Freedom Party leader’s comments on Moroccans living in the Netherlands were ‘unnecessarily offensive.’ 11/17/16, 2:11 PM CET BY Esther King Nigel Farage’s party stands accused of breaking rules on spending EU funds. Demonstrators against the arrival of refugees stand guarded by policemen near a refugees camp on August 22, 2015 in Heidenau, Germany | Matthias Rietschel/Getty Images By Hortense Goulard 9/21/16, 12:35 PM CET Updated 9/21/16, 12:45 PM CET Violent acts targeting foreigners and migrants have sharply risen in the eastern part of Germany in recent years, the German government warned in a report to be published on October 3, marking the country’s national unity day. The report cites “countless attacks on refugees and their shelters” in the past year as well as outbursts of violence in Heidenau and Freital, two cities located near Dresden in the state of Saxony. Such attacks are “symbols of a growing hate of foreigners.” Excerpts of the report were published on Wednesday in the Handelsblatt newspaper after the business daily obtained a copy of it. The “worrying trend” could “threaten the peace of the Eastern German society,” said Iris Gleicke according to Handelsblatt. Gleicke is a member of the government in charge of the country’s former Eastern bloc that was under communist rule. Areas in former East Germany remain poorer than former West Germany, with a GDP about a quarter lower than in the West, the report said, adding that differences have largely disappeared since the reunification in 1990. According to statistics, hate crime in the East is well above the rest of the country. In the state of Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, where the far-right Alternative for Germany registered an unprecedented electoral success earlier this month, attacks on foreigners and migrants reached 58.7 per million inhabitants. The average for the western part of the country is 10.5, according to Handelsblatt. Also On Politico Hortense Goulard Also On Politico Hortense Goulard Also On Politico Ivo Oliveira Authorities started tracking violence against foreigners in 2001. It reached its peak in 2015, according to the report. The report also warned that far-right groups have been gaining strength from rising hatred against foreigners, saying that one such terror organization known as the National Socialist Underground has killed 10 people in recent years. The report noted that there are fewer foreigners in eastern Germany than in other parts of the country, underlining the fact that violence and hatred are not the result of the influx of migrants, but rather due to emigration from the East to other, richer parts of the country and a lack of social structures. The report also noted an increase in violent incidents from left-wing radicals in the former East. Left-wing militants “misuse demonstrations [against the far-right] and committed a number of criminal acts, sometimes associated with extreme violence, especially against the police,” it said.  © 2016 POLITICO SPRL Log in to access content and manage your profile. If you do not have a login you can register here.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>39</end>
        <start>22</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>113</end>
        <start>40</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>135</end>
        <start>114</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>152</end>
        <start>136</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>245</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>268</end>
        <start>246</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>286</end>
        <start>269</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>346</end>
        <start>287</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>369</end>
        <start>347</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>387</end>
        <start>370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>462</end>
        <start>388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>485</end>
        <start>463</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>505</end>
        <start>486</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>592</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>615</end>
        <start>593</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>650</end>
        <start>616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>773</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>790</end>
        <start>774</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>918</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>940</end>
        <start>919</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1001</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1023</end>
        <start>1002</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1039</end>
        <start>1024</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1040</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1149</end>
        <start>1128</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1164</end>
        <start>1150</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1247</end>
        <start>1165</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1269</end>
        <start>1248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1270</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>1290</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1403</end>
        <start>1382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1404</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1461</end>
        <start>1420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1484</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1584</end>
        <start>1501</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1606</end>
        <start>1585</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1607</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1726</end>
        <start>1652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1748</end>
        <start>1727</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1749</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1769</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1878</end>
        <start>1857</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1895</end>
        <start>1879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1974</end>
        <start>1896</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1996</end>
        <start>1975</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>1997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2196</end>
        <start>2033</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2218</end>
        <start>2197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2237</end>
        <start>2219</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2304</end>
        <start>2238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2326</end>
        <start>2305</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2344</end>
        <start>2327</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2416</end>
        <start>2345</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2438</end>
        <start>2417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2455</end>
        <start>2439</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2542</end>
        <start>2456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2565</end>
        <start>2543</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2582</end>
        <start>2566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2651</end>
        <start>2583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2674</end>
        <start>2652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2690</end>
        <start>2675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2759</end>
        <start>2691</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2782</end>
        <start>2760</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2783</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2884</end>
        <start>2798</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2907</end>
        <start>2885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2922</end>
        <start>2908</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2987</end>
        <start>2923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3010</end>
        <start>2988</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3025</end>
        <start>3011</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3137</end>
        <start>3026</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3159</end>
        <start>3138</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3174</end>
        <start>3160</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3283</end>
        <start>3175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3305</end>
        <start>3284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3324</end>
        <start>3306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3459</end>
        <start>3325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3481</end>
        <start>3460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3499</end>
        <start>3482</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3585</end>
        <start>3500</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3607</end>
        <start>3586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3623</end>
        <start>3608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3828</end>
        <start>3624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3850</end>
        <start>3829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3870</end>
        <start>3851</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3958</end>
        <start>3871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3980</end>
        <start>3959</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3992</end>
        <start>3981</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4091</end>
        <start>3993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4114</end>
        <start>4092</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4129</end>
        <start>4115</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4197</end>
        <start>4130</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4220</end>
        <start>4198</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4261</end>
        <start>4221</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4376</end>
        <start>4262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4398</end>
        <start>4377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4418</end>
        <start>4399</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4492</end>
        <start>4419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4514</end>
        <start>4493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4537</end>
        <start>4515</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4652</end>
        <start>4538</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4674</end>
        <start>4653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4693</end>
        <start>4675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4762</end>
        <start>4694</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4784</end>
        <start>4763</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4804</end>
        <start>4785</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4922</end>
        <start>4805</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4944</end>
        <start>4923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4966</end>
        <start>4945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5037</end>
        <start>4967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5059</end>
        <start>5038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5092</end>
        <start>5060</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5165</end>
        <start>5093</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5187</end>
        <start>5166</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5206</end>
        <start>5188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5207</end>
        <start>5207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5229</end>
        <start>5208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5249</end>
        <start>5230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5336</end>
        <start>5250</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5358</end>
        <start>5337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5374</end>
        <start>5359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5375</end>
        <start>5375</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5397</end>
        <start>5376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5414</end>
        <start>5398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5510</end>
        <start>5415</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5532</end>
        <start>5511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5551</end>
        <start>5533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5638</end>
        <start>5552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5660</end>
        <start>5639</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5679</end>
        <start>5661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5774</end>
        <start>5680</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5796</end>
        <start>5775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5816</end>
        <start>5797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5900</end>
        <start>5817</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5922</end>
        <start>5901</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5939</end>
        <start>5923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6007</end>
        <start>5940</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6029</end>
        <start>6008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6046</end>
        <start>6030</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6167</end>
        <start>6047</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6189</end>
        <start>6168</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6206</end>
        <start>6190</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6309</end>
        <start>6207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6331</end>
        <start>6310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6346</end>
        <start>6332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6422</end>
        <start>6347</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6590</end>
        <start>6423</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6610</end>
        <start>6591</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6632</end>
        <start>6611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6662</end>
        <start>6633</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6889</end>
        <start>6663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7277</end>
        <start>6890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7517</end>
        <start>7278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7736</end>
        <start>7518</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8130</end>
        <start>7737</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8147</end>
        <start>8131</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8164</end>
        <start>8148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8181</end>
        <start>8165</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8198</end>
        <start>8182</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8215</end>
        <start>8199</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8228</end>
        <start>8216</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8348</end>
        <start>8229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8582</end>
        <start>8349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8892</end>
        <start>8583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9184</end>
        <start>8893</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9185</end>
        <start>9185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9206</end>
        <start>9186</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9306</end>
        <start>9207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico EU</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>6956</end>
        <start>6908</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7147</end>
        <start>7107</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7297</end>
        <start>7283</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7355</end>
        <start>7306</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9174</end>
        <start>9013</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hate crime ‘threatens peace’ in eastern Germany: report</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.eu/article/hate-crime-threatens-peace-in-eastern-germany-report/?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
