<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Cassy Fiano</author>
    <links href="http://www.allenbwest.com/allen/mr-president-youve-just-crossed-line">
        <end>554</end>
        <start>478</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Obama’s time as president is almost over and millions of Americans are counting down the days until he vacates the Oval Office. He promised before taking office that he would fundamentally change America and he did… for the worse. It’s hard to believe that his legacy will be remembered fondly once he’s left office, considering that virtually everything he has implemented has been a miserable failure. But that hasn’t stopped him from patting himself on the back anyway — and telling Americans that they need to protect his legacy once he’s left office. In a speech to the Congressional Black Caucus on Saturday night, Obama used Jim Crow laws and slavery in an effort to encourage people to vote for the “right” candidate. He told the people assembled that his legacy was at stake, so they needed to give him a good send off by registering people to vote. And those people, of course, need to vote for Hillary Clinton.   While Obama did not mention Hillary by name, he said it would be an insult to him if the black community does not support her. “My name may not be on the ballot, but our progress is on the ballot,” he said. “And there is one candidate who will advance those things. And there is another candidate who’s defining principal, the central theme of his candidacy is opposition to all that we have done.” He then cited the historic turnout among the African-American community in 2008 and 2012, saying, “I will consider it a personal insult, an insult to my legacy, if this community lets down it’s guard and fails to activate itself in this election. You want to give me a good send off? Go vote!”   Of course, history contradicts everything that Obama said. It was Democrats, not Republicans, that supported slavery, segregation and Jim Crow laws. The Republican Party was formed specifically to end slavery. The original Congressional Black Caucus were the first black members of Congress… and they were Republicans. Democrats came up with the Ku Klux Klan in order to prevent black Americans from voting. Meanwhile, Obama’s actual legacy with the black community isn’t exactly stellar. It was the Obama administration that cancelled D.C.’s school voucher program, so that low-income minority children could not go to expensive private schools, like the one Obama’s children got to attend. And under Obama’s leadership, unemployment and food stamp usage have skyrocketed, hitting the black community harder than any other. He’s done nothing about the destruction of the black family, the disproportionately high number of black babies aborted every year, or the fact that almost 76% of black children are born out of wedlock. And he wants to brag about his legacy? Is he out of his mind? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>557</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>923</end>
        <start>558</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>924</end>
        <start>924</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>925</end>
        <start>925</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1618</end>
        <start>926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1619</end>
        <start>1619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1620</end>
        <start>1620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2028</end>
        <start>1621</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2648</end>
        <start>2029</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2710</end>
        <start>2649</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2711</end>
        <start>2711</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>713</end>
        <start>708</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1120</end>
        <start>1052</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1321</end>
        <start>1132</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>1422</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama Tells America to Protect HIS Legacy – Thanks HIMSELF For All the “Great Things” He’s Done In 8 Years [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/barack-obama/obama-tells-america-protect-legacy-thanks-great-things-hes-done-8-years/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
