<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Morgan Winsor</author>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/elections/presidential-debates.htm">
        <end>32</end>
        <start>13</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/whitehouse/hillary-clinton.htm">
        <end>72</end>
        <start>57</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/donald-trump.htm">
        <end>116</end>
        <start>104</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/entertainment/miss-universe.htm">
        <end>482</end>
        <start>469</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/business/technology/instagram.htm">
        <end>1096</end>
        <start>1087</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/entertainment/actresses/rosie-odonnell.htm">
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1840</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Rosie/status/780612891057594368">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/elections/republican-primary.htm">
        <end>2037</end>
        <start>2026</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/reporters/megyn-kelly.htm">
        <end>2092</end>
        <start>2081</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As the first presidential debate was drawing to a close, Hillary Clinton took one last chance to hammer Donald Trump, hitting at his remarks on women. “This is a man who has called women pigs, slobs and dogs,” Clinton said fervently from the debate stage tonight. “And someone who has said pregnancy is an inconvenience to employers, who has said women don't deserve equal pay unless they do as good a job as men.” The Democratic presidential nominee brought up former Miss Universe Alicia Machado, who has said that Trump regularly bullied her when he took over the pageant in 1996, allegedly calling the Venezuelan beauty contestant “Miss Piggy” and “Miss Housekeeping.”   “And one of the worst things he said was about a woman in a beauty contest. He loves beauty contests, supporting them and hanging around them,” Clinton said. “And he called this woman ‘Miss Piggy.’ Then he called her ‘Miss Housekeeping,’ because she was Latina. Donald, she has a name. Her name is Alicia Machado.” Machado has since become an American citizen and has vowed to vote for Clinton, according to her Instagram.     The presidential hopefuls clashed over Trump’s remarks on women when "NBC Nightly News" anchor and debate moderator Lester Holt asked the Republican nominee to clarify controversial comments he made earlier that Clinton doesn’t have “a presidential look.” Trump said that by “look,” he meant “stamina.” “She doesn't have the look, she doesn’t have the stamina,” Trump said from the stage at Hofstra University in Hempstead, New York. "To be president of this country, you need tremendous stamina." Clinton soon chimed in, “One thing Lester, he tried to switch from looks to stamina.” While Trump denied some of Clinton’s allegations about his comments on women, he defended his harsh words for actor Rosie O’Donnell at tonight’s debate. “Rosie O'Donnell, I said very tough things to her, and I think everybody would agree she deserves it, and nobody feels sorry for her,” Trump said.    Back in August 2015 during the first GOP primary debate, Fox News host and debate moderator Megyn Kelly confronted Trump about using words like “fat pigs,” “dogs,” “slobs” and “disgusting animals” to describe some women. Trump interjected and said, “Only Rosie O’Donnell.” ABC News' Nicole Phillip, Maggie McNish and Sunny Choo contributed to this report.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>150</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>414</end>
        <start>151</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>672</end>
        <start>415</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>673</end>
        <start>673</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>674</end>
        <start>674</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>989</end>
        <start>675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1097</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1098</end>
        <start>1098</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1099</end>
        <start>1099</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1100</end>
        <start>1100</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>1101</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1404</end>
        <start>1102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1599</end>
        <start>1405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1685</end>
        <start>1600</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1838</end>
        <start>1686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1985</end>
        <start>1839</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1986</end>
        <start>1986</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1987</end>
        <start>1987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1988</end>
        <start>1988</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2261</end>
        <start>1989</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2344</end>
        <start>2262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>ABC News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1188</end>
        <start>1172</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1537</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary Clinton Slams Donald Trump for Calling Women 'Pigs, Slobs and Dogs'</title>
    <uri>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/hillary-clinton-slams-donald-trump-calling-women-pigs/story?id=42380925&amp;cid=abcnp_fb</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
