<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2016/09/18/fox-news-poll-many-voters-want-new-leadership-but-still-uneasy-about-trump.html">
        <end>1609</end>
        <start>1574</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I think what’s most likely is that the audience just thought the candidate was being funny. I mean, isn’t it a joke to say that anyone in the Clinton family is honest? Even if it weren’t a joke, the congressional candidate on the Democratic ticket had to have known that his comment would have elicited laughter from the audience. He made his comments during a debate with incumbent representative David Jolly. Former Florida Governor Charlie Crist is vying for Rep. Jolly’s spot in the state’s 13th congressional district. The moderator had asked Crist if he was planning on voting for his party’s nominee. Here’s how he answered: “I am proud of Hillary Clinton. I think she’s been a very good secretary of state, a very good senator from the state of New York. The thing I like most about her is I believe she is steady. I believe that she is strong. I believe that she is honest. And I look forward to voting for her.” “Honest” and “steady,” huh? That had to have been a joke. I don’t know exactly what he meant by “steady,” but that’s an interesting way to describe Hillary, especially in the midst of her health crisis. Why would he refer to her as being steady? She would have collapsed at that 9/11 memorial event if it weren’t for her security detail breaking her fall and carrying her into the van. The crowd reacted appropriately as one does when a comedian pokes fun at a politician.  Even Democrats understand Hillary’s aversion to honesty. A staggering 64% of voters – and that’s including Democrats – believe that their candidate is not honest or trustworthy, according to a recent Fox News poll. Of course, it probably won’t stop them from voting for her just the same.    The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>167</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>330</end>
        <start>168</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>523</end>
        <start>331</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>631</end>
        <start>524</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>921</end>
        <start>632</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>979</end>
        <start>922</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1307</end>
        <start>980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1394</end>
        <start>1308</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1395</end>
        <start>1395</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1684</end>
        <start>1396</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1686</end>
        <start>1685</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1687</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1833</end>
        <start>1688</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1907</end>
        <start>1834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>920</end>
        <start>633</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>929</end>
        <start>923</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>943</end>
        <start>936</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>943</end>
        <start>936</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>921</end>
        <start>632</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1869</end>
        <start>1857</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>FAIL: Dem. Congressional Candidate Calls Hillary ‘Honest’…Audience Boos and Laughs [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36906/fail-dem-congressional-candidate-calls-hillary-honestaudience-boos-and-laughs-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
