<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://freedomdaily.com/black-rapper-tells-truth-black-lives-matter/">
        <end>522</end>
        <start>501</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>When you WATCH this VIDEO you MUST have tissues out. The further into the video I went, the more I cried. It starts out with a guy saying, “This goes out to the people who support Black Lives Matter. Until I see y’all protesting black on black crime that goes on in our neighborhood every f***ing day, shut the f**ck up goin’ around saying that Black Lives Matter. Shut the f**ck up with that sh*t!” You might wonder what he’s talking about so here are some statistics from the Uniform Crime Report’s Supplemental Homicide Reports published annually by the federal government that support his concern on black on black crime. These numbers explain why this guy is saying that black people are killing black people… because they are and en masse: ⦁While only 6% of the U.S. population is identified as black and male, 57.9% of the persons legally killed by a private citizen in self-defense were black males. ⦁ However, 73.1% of the black males legally killed by a citizen in self-defense between 2009-2012 were killed by a black citizen. ⦁ 42.6% of victims of all solved criminal homicides from 2009-2012 were black males ⦁ 89.6% of black males killed in criminal homicides from 2009-2012 were killed by another black male ⦁ 40.6% of the police officers murdered in the line of duty from 2009-2012 were killed by black males* In 2012, white males were 38 percent of the population and committed 4,582 murders. That same year, black males were just 6.6 percent of the population but committed a staggering 5,531 murders. In other words: black people–at just a fifth of the size–committed almost 1,000 more murders than their white counterparts. The figures above highlight a horrific truth that black racialists and white liberals routinely ignore: Lawbreaking black Americans, young black males particularly, put themselves in close proximity to (mostly white male) police officers at rates sometimes five to 10 times higher than whites. This is a recipe for disaster. Thusly…. Blacka are only 13% of the population but have committed half of homicides in the United States for nearly 30 years. DOJ statistics show that between 1980 and 2008, black people committed 52% of homicides. In 2013, black criminals committed 38% of the murders. Whites accounted for just 31 percent. There are five times fewer black people than white people in America and, yet, they consistently carry out a larger share of the crimes? Given this rate, it’s no wonder that there aren’t more assistances where cops kill black criminals. The video then leads to the speech of a police captain who is reporting on the drive-by shooting of a little girl and how he now has to send his officers out there looking for suspects with a gun under their seat. The video then goes into an emotional string of video where you see police officers hesitating to a criminal with a gun pointed at them, the officer always gets shot when hesitating. It helps anyone understand WHY police officers MUST shoot when being threatened, if they don’t they will be killed. Here are statistics that really show you who is getting killed more often; white criminals are. Of the 1,491 persons that died from police use of force from 2009-2012: ⦁ 915 (61.4%) were white males ⦁ 481 (32.2%) were black males ⦁ 48 (3.2%) were males of other races ⦁ 28 (1.9%) were white females ⦁ 15 (1.1%) were black females ⦁ 4 (0.2%) were females of other races If there is anyone who should be afraid right now it should be: 1. White male criminals because you’re more likely to get shot by police. 2. Black person who lives around black people because you are more likely to become a victim of homicide around more black people. 3. People who are in the Black Lives Matter movement because you are increasing your risk of injury just by being in an environment where the cops are your enemy… who will protect you? Plus you are literally standing among the people who commit the HIGHEST disproportionate amount of violent crimes in the nation. 4. All of us because the BLM are going to destroy the greatest police force in the world that protects our Bill of Rights better than anyone right now. We are about to get a Federalized police force and the Constitution is DEAD without the local Sheriff. 5. Police Officers because they’re in more danger today than ever before because of the farce of Black Lives Matter movement giving people permission to shoot white Police Officers just because. NOW, watch this VIDEO to truly understand what Police Officers go through and how their hesitation may cost their life and the lives of others.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>399</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>745</end>
        <start>400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1325</end>
        <start>746</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1643</end>
        <start>1326</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2513</end>
        <start>1644</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3026</end>
        <start>2514</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3395</end>
        <start>3027</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4428</end>
        <start>3396</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4572</end>
        <start>4429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4573</end>
        <start>4573</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4574</end>
        <start>4574</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>398</end>
        <start>140</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>DONT STOP SHARING THIS- VIRAL VIDEO Exposes MAJOR Flaw Of Black Lives Matter!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/dont-stop-sharing-this-viral-video-exposes-major-flaw-of-black-lives-matter/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
