<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <links href="http://todaychristian.net/2016/09/18/outraged-parents-file-lawsuit-public-school-forced-child-convert-islam/">
        <end>69</end>
        <start>66</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A public high school has been accused of indoctrinated Islam into their students. Allegedly, the school has been mandating children profess the Islamic statement of faith, memorize the five pillars of Islam, as well as teaching students that the Muslims faith is stronger than a Christian or Jews. This is all according to lawsuit filed in federal court this past Wednesday. The lawsuit was filed on behalf of John and Melissa Wood with the Thomas More Law Center and the action is being taken against La Plata High School in Maryland. According to John Wood the school banished him from their property when he complained about the Islamic teachings. Richard Thompson, President of Thomas More, said, “Defendants forced Wood’s daughter to disparage her Christian faith by reciting the Shahada, and acknowledging Mohammed as her spiritual leader.” The Law Center commented that for non Muslims such as Christians and Jews that reciting the Shahada Islamic creed which is their statement of faith is the equivalent of converting. Spokespeople for the Charles County Public Schools have refused to comment other than to say they have not received any such lawsuit yet. However, the Principal Evelyn Arnold, Vice Principal Shannon Morris, and Charles County Board of Education were all named in the lawsuit. The lawsuit says, “During its brief instruction on Christianity, Defendants failed to cover any portion of the Bible or other non-Islamic religious texts, such as the Ten Commandments. Instead, the class included disparaging remarks about Christianity and the Pope. Such discriminatory treatment of Christianity is an unconstitutional promotion of one religion over another. United States Supreme Court precedent does not create a double standard that allows for the promotion of Islam in our public schools while disallowing and silencing teachings of Christianity and Judaism.” Classroom assignment copies indicate the teachers were instructing students that most Muslim people’s faith are stronger than that of the average Christian. As well, the copies show they taught students that Islam is a peaceful religion that treated their conquered nations with kindness and respect too. Part of the handout reads, “Nowhere in the Koran does it say you will go to paradise if you martyr yourself with a suicide bomb. Important: The majority of Muslims do not live this way.” It referenced the jihad as, “a holy war waged on behalf of Islam as a religious duty; a personal struggle in devotion to Islam especially involving spiritual discipline.” This reportedly occurred during the 2014-2015 school year. So lord only knows what these teachers have been education these students about for the past few years. Despite the fact the Thomas More Center has taken on this case neither the American Civil Liberties Union or the Freedom From Religion Foundation have weighed in on the issue.       </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>374</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>650</end>
        <start>375</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>700</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>701</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1027</end>
        <start>847</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1303</end>
        <start>1028</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1321</end>
        <start>1304</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1883</end>
        <start>1322</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2188</end>
        <start>1884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2215</end>
        <start>2189</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2375</end>
        <start>2216</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2403</end>
        <start>2376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2546</end>
        <start>2404</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2885</end>
        <start>2547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2887</end>
        <start>2886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2889</end>
        <start>2888</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2891</end>
        <start>2890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2892</end>
        <start>2892</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>845</end>
        <start>702</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1882</end>
        <start>1323</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2374</end>
        <start>2217</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2545</end>
        <start>2405</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Outraged Parents File Lawsuit: “Public School Forced My Child To Convert To Islam”</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/outraged-parents-file-lawsuit-public-school-forced-my-child-to-convert-to-islam/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
