<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://www.humanevents.com/2006/04/07/emexclusive-emthe-truth-about-la-raza/">
        <end>907</end>
        <start>900</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.humanevents.com/2011/07/28/isnt-the-southern-poverty-law-center-the-real-hate-group-2/">
        <end>971</end>
        <start>944</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.weaselzippers.us/296430-soros-announces-hes-spending-500-million-to-help-settle-muslim-refugees/">
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1420</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The only convincing reason I can see for raising taxes is that it’ll mean less money in the pockets of George Soros. While liberals bemoan money in politics, it’s often those liberals funded by the likes of Soros doing the complaining. As of 2016, his net worth is nearly $25 billion. The right-wing Koch Brothers (worth 42.5 billion apiece) are wealthier, but Soros “invests” much more in politics than Soros does. Soros started the Open Society Institute in 1993 as a way to redistribute his wealth to progressive causes.  Using Open Society as a conduit, Soros has given more than $10 billion to a who’s who of left-wing groups. Imagine how many hungry people worldwide that much money could’ve saved, but instead he put that money towards organizations bent on destroying our civil society. This partial list of recipients of Soros’ money says it all: ACORN, Apollo Alliance, National Council of La Raza, Tides Foundation, Huffington Post, Southern Poverty Law Center, Soujourners, People for the American Way, Planned Parenthood, and the National Organization for Women. On the bright side, at least it’s his money he’s wasting going towards these causes, not federal money. At eighty-six years of age, the man is nearing the end of his life, and throwing money to whoever will take it at this point. He’s heavily backed Black Lives Matter, and now, is putting his money where his mouth is on the refugee issue. As Weasel Zippers reports: Billionaire George Soros said in an opinion piece in the Wall Street Journal that he would invest $500 million to meet the needs of migrants. The White House announced the commitment from Soros and around 50 other companies ahead of Obama convening a refugee summit Tuesday afternoon. Soros also said that he plans to work more closely with the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees and the International Rescue Committee to assist in his investments. ‘In response, I have decided to earmark $500 million for investments that specifically address the needs of migrants, refugees and host communities. I will invest in startups, established companies, social-impact initiatives and businesses founded by migrants and refugees themselves. Although my main concern is to help migrants and refugees arriving in Europe, I will be looking for good investment ideas that will benefit migrants all over the world.’ ‘Governments must play the leading role in addressing this crisis by creating and sustaining adequate physical and social infrastructure for migrants and refugees.’ The lifetime cost of admitting only the 10,000 refugees we admitted in America comes out to a large $6.5 billion. George Soros isn’t going to be getting much bang for his buck (especially when its ten times cheaper to resettle refugees in the Middle East than in America and Europe) but if he wants to waste his money, I’m all for that. I’d rather him not have it anyway. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>116</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>415</end>
        <start>117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>794</end>
        <start>416</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1179</end>
        <start>795</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1443</end>
        <start>1180</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1585</end>
        <start>1444</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1728</end>
        <start>1586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1917</end>
        <start>1729</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2372</end>
        <start>1918</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2537</end>
        <start>2373</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2909</end>
        <start>2538</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2910</end>
        <start>2910</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>375</end>
        <start>368</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1478</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Soros Is Spending $500 Million To Bring THIS To America” – POS</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/soros-spending-500-million-america/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
