<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>eaglerising</author>
    <links href="http://dailycallernewsfoundation.org/2016/09/19/nyc-bombing-suspect-sued-police-for-anti-muslim-discrimination/">
        <end>38</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://live.reuters.com/Event/New_York_bombings?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=Social">
        <end>290</end>
        <start>277</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3796768/Ahmad-Rahami-sued-local-police-New-Jersey-claiming-persecuted-Muslim.html#ixzz4KiOknzUX">
        <end>573</end>
        <start>566</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>From the Daily Caller News Foundation: The man arrested Monday in connection with the New York City bombing sued his local police force over anti-Muslim discrimination claims. Ahmad Khan Rahami filed the lawsuit against cops in Elizabeth, N.J., where he was residing before he planted bombs in the Chelsea neighborhood of Manhattan, at a train station in Elizabeth, and on the route of a 5k Marine charity run on the Jersey shore. He claimed police were persecuting him for being a Muslim and subjecting him and his family to “selective enforcement” based on Islam, reports The Daily Mail. Rahami worked at a chicken restaurant called First American, owned by his family, who claimed the police tried to shut it down early each night with “baseless” tickets, and that locals said: “Muslims don’t belong here.” Rahami brought the suit along with his father Mohammad Sr. and his brother Mohammad. He was arrested following a shootout with police Monday, after he was found passed out in the doorway of a New Jersey bar.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>38</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>175</end>
        <start>39</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>589</end>
        <start>176</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>894</end>
        <start>590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1017</end>
        <start>895</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1018</end>
        <start>1018</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1164</end>
        <start>1019</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1238</end>
        <start>1165</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>548</end>
        <start>527</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>748</end>
        <start>740</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>808</end>
        <start>782</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1200</end>
        <start>1188</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Bombing Suspect Filed Anti-Muslim Discrimination Lawsuit Against Police</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36871/bombing-suspect-filed-anti-muslim-discrimination-lawsuit-against-police/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
