<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Randy Kreider Lee Ferran Mike Levine</author>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/world/isis.htm">
        <end>212</end>
        <start>208</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/International/pentagon-confirms-death-chief-isis-spokesman-abu-muhammad/story?id=42043019">
        <end>1038</end>
        <start>1012</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In a bloody page in the journal purportedly found on Ahmad Rahami when he was captured, the New York and New Jersey bombing suspect appears to praise major terrorist figures, including the main spokesman for ISIS. A reference to "Brother Adnani," presumably referring to the late Abu Muhammad al-Adnani, is the first public evidence that ISIS, as well as al-Qaeda, may have inspired Rahami's alleged violent acts. "I looked for guidance and [praise be to God] guidance came. Sheikh Anwar[,] Brother Adnani ... said it clearly attack the kuffar [unbelievers] in their backyard," the page says. "Sheikh Anwar" is likely a reference to influential American-born al-Qaeda cleric Anwar al-Awlaki, who was killed in a U.S. drone strike five years ago.       Elsewhere in the journal, Rahami purportedly praised al-Qaeda founder Osama bin Laden and 2009 Fort Hood shooter Nadal Hasan, according to a criminal complaint filed against Rahami late Tuesday, which doesn't mention al-Adnani. The Pentagon said al-Adnani was killed in a U.S. airstrike in Syria in late August. Before his death, he served as the primary spokesman for ISIS and often encouraged Western Muslims to conduct attacks in their home countries. "If you can kill a disbelieving American or European ... then rely on Allah and kill them in any manner or way, however it may be," Adnani said in an audio message two years ago. ISIS has not released any claim of responsibility for the bombings in New York, where 31 people were injured, and New Jersey, where no one was hurt.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>213</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>413</end>
        <start>214</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>745</end>
        <start>414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>746</end>
        <start>746</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>747</end>
        <start>747</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>748</end>
        <start>748</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>749</end>
        <start>749</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>750</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>979</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1206</end>
        <start>980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1385</end>
        <start>1207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1534</end>
        <start>1386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>ABC News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>245</end>
        <start>230</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>576</end>
        <start>415</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>487</end>
        <start>475</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1337</end>
        <start>1208</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>ISIS Figure Referenced in NYC Bomber's Purported Journal</title>
    <uri>http://abcnews.go.com/International/isis-figure-referenced-nyc-bombers-purported-journal/story?id=42258417&amp;cid=abcnp_fb</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
