<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://dennismichaellynch.com/somalian-muslims-minnesota-admit-law-actually-prefer/">
        <end>996</end>
        <start>968</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://video.foxnews.com">
        <end>1995</end>
        <start>1978</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.centerforsecuritypolicy.org/2015/06/23/nationwide-poll-of-us-muslims-shows-thousands-support-shariah-jihad/">
        <end>2274</end>
        <start>2248</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As if Donald Trump’s plan to ban Muslim immigration didn’t infuriate liberals enough, his plan to stop the Islamization of America has another component. Trump also expressed interest in deporting any Muslims who express support for Sharia law. In a bad turn of events for liberals, some actually attempted to hilariously defend Sharia in response to the latter. CNN commenter Sally Kohn took to Twitter, writing “Hey Donald Trump, many progressive Muslims — the ones we should support in ideaological fight against extremism — believe in Sharia!!” By the way, Kohn is a lesbian, and would be put to death under Sharia law. There’s no disagreement among scholars of Islamic law that death is the punishment for homosexuality – the debate is over how they should be killed. If that’s “progressive,” we have even more reasons to despite progressivism. I’m also sure most people aren’t on board with beheadings for apostasy, and cutting off the limbs of thieves. Now, as Dennis Michael Lynch reports, it’s clear what type of law (Sharia vs. American Law) many Muslims in America actually prefer. Fox News went to interview the Somalian Muslims on the streets of Cedar Riverside to learn the truth about how they really feel about living in America and American law. Every single one of them interviewed in the following video said they prefer Sharia law over American law.   “If you’re a Muslim, of course you want Sharia law,” they say. They believe it’s ok to kill someone if they insult Mohammad. They believe it’s perfectly normal to force their daughter to marry someone when she reaches the age of 15. When asked if they would prefer to live in America or Somalia, they say they would prefer Somalia. And the most stunning revelation of all is a young man at the end of the interview who admits, “I’m not Americanized, I just speak fluent and I an articulate what I’m trying to say, but as far as my culture and my preferences, I’m still Somalian.” Watch the latest video at video.foxnews.com Fox News also featured another interview on the Cedar Riverside streets in May, where it was stated that they have at least two Islamic schools that teach Sharia law: Scary. These results are consistent with a poll of American Muslims conducted by the Center for Security Policy last year. It found that More than half (51%) of U.S. Muslims polled also believe either that they should have the choice of American or shariah courts, or that they should have their own tribunals to apply shariah. Only 39% of those polled said that Muslims in the U.S. should be subject to American courts. America is a tolerant nation – but that doesn’t mean we should tolerate the intolerance of Sharia. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>244</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>548</end>
        <start>245</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>959</end>
        <start>549</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1092</end>
        <start>960</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1262</end>
        <start>1093</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1263</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1496</end>
        <start>1435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1604</end>
        <start>1497</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1703</end>
        <start>1605</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1951</end>
        <start>1704</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1995</end>
        <start>1952</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2162</end>
        <start>1996</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2169</end>
        <start>2163</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2583</end>
        <start>2170</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2682</end>
        <start>2584</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2683</end>
        <start>2683</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>547</end>
        <start>414</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>796</end>
        <start>784</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1423</end>
        <start>1373</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1950</end>
        <start>1800</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1196</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2162</end>
        <start>1996</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Somalian Muslims In Minnesota Admit Which Law They Actually Prefer (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/somalian-muslims-minnesota-admit-law-actually-prefer-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
