<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/jenner.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It’s true that conservatives have a tendency to take the opinions of reality stars with many grains of salt, especially because they have a tendency to be mindlessly liberal and ill-informed. Brody Jenner, however, has said something worth sharing. Brody is the son of Caitlyn (then Bruce) Jenner and actress Linda Thompson, and stars in “The Hills,” a show that I’ve never seen and for which I can give you no description.   Twitter exploded after Brody Jenner posted a comment on Instagram claiming that not everything is about race. Of course, adding “All Lives Matter” was pretty much the end of it. The perpetually-offended crowd took to their keyboards to let him know that he’s a terrible person because he’s white and a man, and straight and “cis-gender.” Below is the offending post: “I normally don’t speak about this type of stuff, but this is just ridiculous. I can’t even watch the news anymore without getting pissed off. This has nothing to do with race. White, black, brown, any color…if you have an officer of the law telling you to exit your vehicle (or do anything for that matter)…you comply. And not only do you comply, but you do so willingly and follow directions completely. And why in the world would you exit that vehicle with a weapon in hand (allegedly?!) That makes no sense! And if, let’s just say, you DON’T have a gun, why would you not put your hands up in the air and state “I do not have a gun” so that the officers can clearly see that you don’t??” After receiving backlash, he posted another photo on Instagram, salting the wounds of the whining babies on the left.  Predictably, liberals lost their ever-loving minds over this, but it’s honestly just par for the course with these people. They are always looking for something by which they can be offended. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>191</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>248</end>
        <start>192</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>423</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>424</end>
        <start>424</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>425</end>
        <start>425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>763</end>
        <start>426</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>792</end>
        <start>764</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1484</end>
        <start>793</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1602</end>
        <start>1485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1603</end>
        <start>1603</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1604</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1796</end>
        <start>1796</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>349</end>
        <start>339</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>571</end>
        <start>555</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>762</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1428</end>
        <start>794</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1484</end>
        <start>793</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Liberals Are Furious When Reality Star Brody Jenner Tells the Truth About Police Shootings on Twitter</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/liberals-furious-reality-star-brody-jenner-tells-truth-police-shootings-twitter/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
