<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://www.theblaze.com/stories/2016/09/25/baltimore-police-8-wounded-in-saturday-shooting-including-a-3-year-old-girl/">
        <end>54</end>
        <start>45</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomdaily.com/black-rapper-tells-truth-black-lives-matter/">
        <end>1853</end>
        <start>1838</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A devastating crime happened this weekend in Baltimore but it’s being totally ignored by the press and Black Lives Matter because the shooter was a criminal not a Police Officer. Outside some rowhouses about 8:30 p.m on Saturday a handful of people were shot. Investigators say the shooting was a premeditated act of revenge in response to a Labor Day weekend shooting in which a man was fatally shot and two women were wounded, one of them pregnant. Although the victims may have recognized the gunmen, authorities haven’t immediately been able to identify the suspects. Attackers had a shotgun and two handguns. One of the armed men emerged from an alley and the others ran down the street and opened fire just in front of the victims. The surprised victims were a 3-year-old girl, a woman and a half dozen men. While the the 3-year-old girl and her father were standing a slight distance away from the others and that the child was not an intended target but got hit anyway. By then, most signs of the attack had been cleared away. There was a bullet hole through the rear window of a car parked on the block. Neighbors sat quietly on their steps. Few wanted to talk about the attack. “They’re scared,” said a woman, who declined to be identified. “They ain’t talking too much.” So far there have been 240 killings in Baltimore and it appears to be from gang activity. On Sunday there were 4 other shootings and an 8-year-old boy was injured adding to the city’s mayhem. I guess the question is; where are the riots? Where are Black Lives Matter? Do they not really care about violence against minorities unless it’s from a Police Officer? Sadly, black on black crime is the biggest tragedy happening to minorities and yet Black lives Matter remains silent. Below are some statistic showing the hypocrisy of BLM: ⦁While only 6% of the U.S. population is identified as black and male, 57.9% of the persons legally killed by a private citizen in self-defense were black males. ⦁ However, 73.1% of the black males legally killed by a citizen in self-defense between 2009-2012 were killed by a black citizen. ⦁ 42.6% of victims of all solved criminal homicides from 2009-2012 were black males ⦁ 89.6% of black males killed in criminal homicides from 2009-2012 were killed by another black male ⦁ 40.6% of the police officers murdered in the line of duty from 2009-2012 were killed by black males* And while black people continue to kill black people en masse, it’s harder to get killed by a police officer if you’re black than getting hit by lightening. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>450</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>451</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1187</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1281</end>
        <start>1188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1282</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2395</end>
        <start>1643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2552</end>
        <start>2396</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2553</end>
        <start>2553</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1204</end>
        <start>1189</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>1252</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Black Gunmen Wound 8 People Including 3 Year old Girl on Saturday, No Protests, Riots, Or Looting….</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/black-gunmen-wound-8-people-including-3-year-old-girl-on-saturday-no-protests-riots-or-looting/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
