<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton warned about cyber-threats from Vladimir Putin. But Donald Trump is just as worried about obese, couch-bound hackers. Story Continued Below Clinton called recent cyber-attacks on various Democratic campaign arms, which are widely thought to be at the hands of Russian intelligence, “the most recent and most troubling” infiltrations from state actors. “I know Donald’s very praiseworthy of Vladimir Putin, but Putin is playing a very tough, long game here,” Clinton said. “That’s why I was so shocked when Donald publicly invited Putin to hack into Americans'” systems, Clinton said, adding that such comments make Trump “unfit to be the commander in chief.” But Trump said he’s not convinced that Putin is behind the attacks. “She said Russia, Russia, Russia, maybe it was. Could also be China,” Trump said. “Could also be somebody sitting on their bed that weighs 400 pounds.” Regardless, Trump didn’t miss an opportunity to highlight one of the most notable findings from the hack of the Democratic National Committee’s emails: that members of the party leadership were working against Sen. Bernie Sanders’s primary challenge against Clinton. “We learned that Bernie Sanders was taken advantage of by your people, by Debbie Wasserman Schultz,” Trump said, before referring to her subsequent ouster as the party chair. “Whether that was Russia, whether that was China, we don’t know.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>63</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>133</end>
        <start>64</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>155</end>
        <start>134</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>367</end>
        <start>156</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>487</end>
        <start>368</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>674</end>
        <start>488</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>742</end>
        <start>675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>894</end>
        <start>743</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>895</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1402</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>333</end>
        <start>299</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>472</end>
        <start>369</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>575</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>673</end>
        <start>638</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>744</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>893</end>
        <start>826</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1261</end>
        <start>1163</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1401</end>
        <start>1338</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump not convinced of Russian hacking</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-debate-russia-hacking-228737?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
