<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Marcos Da Silva</author>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/online/rnc-chair-trump-is-prepared-to-debate-because-hes-been-through-14-season-finales/">
        <end>314</end>
        <start>242</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/online/rnc-chair-trump-is-prepared-to-debate-because-hes-been-through-14-season-finales/">
        <end>329</end>
        <start>315</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Republican National Committee Chairman Reince Priebus appeared on CNN’s pre-Presidential Debate coverage Monday afternoon, absurdly joking with Wolf Blitzer that the Republican Party’s presidential candidate was ready for the debates because “he’d already been through 14 season finales” of Trump’s reality TV show The Apprentice. Of course, it makes absolutely no sense to equate a gaudy half-hour of programming that loosely classifies as entertainment with what is arguably the hardest and most significant hurdle in the journey to becoming the most powerful elected official on the planet, but false-equivalency is after all, the biggest theme of this election. In his latest act “The Donald,” who is apparently “not a fan of mock debates” because “he can get bored,” has decided to eschew traditional methods of debate preparation, instead opting to watch footage of Mrs. Clinton’s best and worst debate moments to look for vulnerabilities. When asked about Trump’s preparation for the debates, Priebus didn’t appear to be concerned about how Trump would perform at the debates, “He’s very comfortable,” Priebus said. “He did a great job in our primary debates. He will be prepared. He’s always shown up for the big dance.” Although Blitzer attempted to press Priebus for more specific details on how Trump is preparing for the debate, the RNC chair would not budge, saying he “didn’t want to get into all those details,” and changing the conversation to discuss the Clinton campaign instead. The Trump-Clinton debate will be at Hofstra University in Hempstead, NY Monday night at 9:00 PM EST and will be broadcast across all the major networks. It is expected to be the most viewed television debate of all time, and could reach up to 100 million viewers, almost certainly affecting the outcome of the November election. Donald Trump made a name for himself in the fact-free zones that were the Republican primary debates, where a group of neocons, corporate shills, and religious extremists argued over who was willing to murder more Middle Eastern people and who hated government the most. Trump thrived by being a bully, making fun of his opponents and literally talking about the size of his penis. He’s not going to be able to get away with that tonight. Watch the exchange here, courtesy of ThinkPolitics: </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>330</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>665</end>
        <start>331</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>945</end>
        <start>666</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1228</end>
        <start>946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1497</end>
        <start>1229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1498</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2265</end>
        <start>1827</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2317</end>
        <start>2266</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2318</end>
        <start>2318</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Occupy Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>286</end>
        <start>243</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>696</end>
        <start>685</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>742</end>
        <start>717</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>770</end>
        <start>753</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1107</end>
        <start>1085</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1227</end>
        <start>1124</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1425</end>
        <start>1383</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Republican Chairman: Trump Will Win Debate Because He’s “Been Through 14 Season Finales” (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/26/republican-chairman-trump-will-win-debate-hes-14-season-finales/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
