<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Antiphon Freeman</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/KellyannePolls">
        <end>1456</end>
        <start>1441</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/dZWTCwpoim">
        <end>1592</end>
        <start>1569</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Morning_Joe/status/780360090687647744">
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1624</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump’s campaign manager Kellyanne Conway was backed into a proverbial corner on MSNBC’s Morning Joe trying to defend Trump’s latest comments. Bloomberg Politics host Mark Halperin first called her out on the fact that Trump called the debate’s moderator a Democrat when that wasn’t even true. And, Conway’s response? Trump didn’t lie, he just didn’t know. Here’s Halperin: “He said Lester Holt (the debate moderator) was a Democrat. Lester Holt is a Republican. How could he say such a thing that just black-and-white factually incorrect?” “I don’t know that he knew what Lester Holt’s voter registration is,” Conway said. Conway tried to pivot, saying “first of all, if you tell me the media are not overly populated with Democrats, that’s false,” but Holt just wasn’t buying it. “I’m asking about a very specific thing,” Halperin said. “He made a factual claim about the moderator who deserves the right to be treated fairly and it was just wrong. And it’s a metaphor for his frequently in public stating things with no basis, that are wrong.” After much back and forth, Halperin just became exasperated trying to get an answer out of her. “You’re not answering what I asked you,” Halperin said. “I’m asking you how someone running for president can assert on the eve of the debate that the moderator is a Democrat, which is factually incorrect? How can he do that?” .@KellyannePolls: Trump ‘didn’t lie’ about Lester Holt, ‘a lie would mean that he knew the man’s party registration’ https://t.co/dZWTCwpoim — Morning Joe (@Morning_Joe) September 26, 2016 </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>155</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>380</end>
        <start>156</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>570</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>661</end>
        <start>571</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>827</end>
        <start>662</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1104</end>
        <start>828</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1200</end>
        <start>1105</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1439</end>
        <start>1201</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1592</end>
        <start>1440</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1593</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1643</end>
        <start>1643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1440</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Campaign Manager: Trump Doesn’t Lie, He Just Doesn’t Know The Truth</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/trump-campaign-manager-trump-doesnt-lie-he-just-doesnt-know-the-truth/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
