<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nathan Wellman</author>
    <links href="http://reason.com/archives/2016/08/02/penn-jillette-on-libertarianism-election/2">
        <end>102</end>
        <start>88</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Penn Jillette, most famous for being one half of magician duo Penn &amp; Teller, has shared with Reason TV about how Trump is more dangerous than anybody suspects, citing his time working with him on  Jillette talked to Nick Gillespie about how, similar to many aspects of Trump’s campaign, even the fundamental set up of the reality show was based on a lie. “I mean, we’re co-workers on a television show,” Jillette said. “He’s not seeing if he’s going to hire me. He has no job. The places he could hire me—the casinos that he has that have showrooms—he put into bankruptcy. He no longer owns them. So, he can’t hire me, plus I have a job, so that’s all completely fake, right?” Jillette reported that while he was on the show, the Trump organization tried to coerce him into endorsing a potential Trump presidency. “There was a time when they asked me while I was still on the show if Donald Trump ran for president, if I’d support him, and I said absolutely not. And I believe, and this may be the most damning thing you’ll hear me say about Trump, I believe I liked him more than anyone else who was on that show. During that time I said I would not support him for president. Now, I get a call instantly. Instantly! From the powers that be—not Trump himself—saying, ‘No, no, no. You must support him as president.’ They say ‘It’s going to come down to you and Trace [Adkins], and he’s going to want to know that you both support him for president. And I said, ‘Well, I don’t.’ And they said, ‘Well, you have to because he’s trying to—he’s looking at the big picture here.’ And I go, ‘We’re on a television show.'” Penn is an avowed libertarian, loyal to neither the Republican or the Democratic parties, and currently endorses Gary Johnson. Despite not being a big fan of Clinton, Penn says that Trump is an unusually incompetent candidate: “However bad you think he is, he’s worse.” “I think he doesn’t really have strong convictions and sense of right and wrong. He’s not really, really smart. He’s not stupid, you know. He’s not a dumb guy, but he’s not smart like presidents are smart. We make jokes—everybody’s makes jokes except me about George W. Bush not being smart. He’s smart. He just is. Obama’s smarter? Probably, sure. Obama’s smarter than Clinton? Probably. Almost certainly. But they’re up here, you know, and if we’re talking about it. You’re wherever you are, but you’re not smarter than Obama, you know. None of us are. Even the smart guys you know aren’t there. And Trump isn’t one of those people. He’s not someone who when you’re having a conversation with him—I probably listened to him talk for, I don’t want to exaggerate, but probably eight or nine hours. A monologue of Trump. And I can’t think of one thing he said that I went, ‘Oh yeah!'”      </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>196</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>676</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1885</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2769</end>
        <start>1886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2770</end>
        <start>2770</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2771</end>
        <start>2771</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2772</end>
        <start>2772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2773</end>
        <start>2773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2774</end>
        <start>2774</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2775</end>
        <start>2775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>402</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>675</end>
        <start>420</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1614</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1884</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2768</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2769</end>
        <start>1886</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Magician Penn Jillette had to work with Trump: “However bad you think he is, he’s worse.”</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/news/magician-penn-jillette-work-trump-however-bad-think-hes-worse/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
