<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tiffiny Ruegner</author>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/25/politics/netanyahu-trump-clinton-meetings/">
        <end>27</end>
        <start>11</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TrumpPence16?src=hash">
        <end>3299</end>
        <start>3286</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/StandWithIsrael?src=hash">
        <end>3316</end>
        <start>3300</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/Rfnfs4HBOt">
        <end>3339</end>
        <start>3316</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/U9dg05SUfI">
        <end>3366</end>
        <start>3340</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/LindaSuhler/status/780095672708046848">
        <end>3422</end>
        <start>3404</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/vIbKiS8N0N">
        <end>3558</end>
        <start>3532</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/YiddishNews/status/780087580499083266">
        <end>3422</end>
        <start>3404</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>CNN had an ominous headline today (it’s showing on google but they changed it on the story): Trump, Netanyahu meet for nearly 90 minutes. It’s like a BIG DEAL to CNN that Netanyaho met with Trump longer than Clinton saying that ‘Her meeting with the prime minister was somewhat shorter than his talk Sunday morning with Trump. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu met Hillary Clinton Sunday night at a New York hotel, after conferring earlier in the day with Donald Trump for nearly 90 minutes at Trump Tower’.   So why do you think Netanyahu met longer with Trump than Hillary? Well Hillary has been the Secretary of State during an unprecedented time where the United State’s devotion to Israel has waned dramatically. Under Hillary as Secretary of State, the U.S. has given over $100 billion to the terrorist regime in Iran whom Obama supports over Israel. This is what leaders look like.  The meetings between Netanyahu and Trump and Hillary materialized over 24 hours on Friday. Trump’s aid made a phone call to one of the prime minister’s advisers. Once it was clear that a meeting was going to happen, Netanyahu’s office contacted Clinton’s campaign to hold a meeting with her as well, to keep the balance. The Prime Minister’s senior official explained that, “The prime minister’s instruction was clear – if we meet with one side, we must also meet with the other side. We are following the number of meetings to make sure that one side doesn’t get more meetings than the other.” The Trump campaign statement said during the meeting, “Trump agreed that the military assistance provided to Israel and missile defense cooperation with Israel are an excellent investment for America,” amid the backdrop of speculation that Trump would support cutting U.S. military aid to Israel. Trump told Netanyahu that if elected, “there will be extraordinary strategic, technological, military and intelligence cooperation between the two countries.” Trump added that Israel is a “vital partner of the United States in the global war against radical Islamic terrorism.” The two also discussed the nuclear deal with Iran and the fight against ISIS. “Mr. Trump acknowledged that Jerusalem has been the eternal capital of the Jewish People for over 3000 years, and that the United States, under a Trump administration, will finally accept the long-standing Congressional mandate to recognize Jerusalem as the undivided capital of the State of Israel,” the statement read. “Mr. Trump recognized that Israel and its citizens have suffered far too long on the front lines of Islamic terrorism,” according to the statement. “He agreed with Prime Minister Netanyahu that the Israeli people want a just and lasting peace with their neighbors, but that peace will only come when the Palestinians renounce hatred and violence and accept Israel as a Jewish State.” Does Hillary have anything to worry about since she has hardly been able to retain a stable relationship between the US and Israel and now Trump is asking for private audiences reaffirming traditional promises the US has had with Israel since before the Obama Presidency? When it comes to looking Presidential, Trump is really kicking Hillary’s butt.    Readout Of Donald J. Trump's Meeting W/ Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu#TrumpPence16 #StandWithIsraelhttps://t.co/Rfnfs4HBOt pic.twitter.com/U9dg05SUfI — Linda Suhler, Ph.D. (@LindaSuhler) September 25, 2016    NY: Photos, PM Netanyahu meeting Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump in Manhattan this morning pic.twitter.com/vIbKiS8N0N — Yiddish News (@YiddishNews) September 25, 2016   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>517</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>518</end>
        <start>518</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>519</end>
        <start>519</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>866</end>
        <start>520</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>898</end>
        <start>867</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>899</end>
        <start>899</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1220</end>
        <start>900</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1494</end>
        <start>1221</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1791</end>
        <start>1495</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2147</end>
        <start>1792</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2468</end>
        <start>2148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2852</end>
        <start>2469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3203</end>
        <start>2853</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3204</end>
        <start>3204</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3205</end>
        <start>3205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3206</end>
        <start>3206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3368</end>
        <start>3207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3424</end>
        <start>3369</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3425</end>
        <start>3425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3426</end>
        <start>3426</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3427</end>
        <start>3427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3560</end>
        <start>3428</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3609</end>
        <start>3561</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3610</end>
        <start>3610</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3611</end>
        <start>3611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3612</end>
        <start>3612</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1491</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1693</end>
        <start>1548</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1947</end>
        <start>1829</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2066</end>
        <start>1979</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2445</end>
        <start>2147</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2585</end>
        <start>2468</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2849</end>
        <start>2616</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2850</end>
        <start>1493</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3422</end>
        <start>3205</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3607</end>
        <start>3426</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Meets Netanyahu – Vows Jerusalem Will Be Recognized as Israel’s Capital</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/trump-meets-netanyahu-vows-jerusalem-will-be-recognized-as-israels-capital/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
