<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/22/cnn-panel-devolves-into-verbal-pissing-contest-forces-host-to-pull-plug-video/">
        <end>1508</end>
        <start>1431</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Things got very rowdy on CNN, with the guests unable to control their passions for the subject at hand. It got so out of control that it forced host Alisyn Camerota to pull the plug on her guests. Somehow, to no one’s surprise, Donald Trump’s name got dragged into the argument. See the video and read the article.  As Written By Christian Daytok for Daily Caller: Cleveland’s Pastor James Davis and Atlanta Mayor Kasim Reed yelled at each other for more than a minute straight on CNN’s Thursday broadcast of “New Day,” forcing host Alisyn Camerota to pull the plug on the segment. The two guests had been brought on the panel to discuss ways to fix problems in the black community and how those goals would be achieved through the respective presidential candidates. “The bottom line is, we need school choice,” stated Davis. “We have to pull the education system and put it back in the neighborhood and get it out of these unions’ hands, and the rest of it, because at the end of the day, irrespective of the numbers, it’s too slow. It’s not enough. It’s too little, too late.” “You finally get the down trend and then the president goes out and has his victory, takes this victory lap over $250 increase in monthly income for the last eight years when inflation pretty much ate that in full, and so now we sit here with saying that mediocrity is wonderful,” he added. “We can’t bring this administration into…… Full Story Here: CNN New Day Panel Turns Into Verbal Pissing-Contest, Video | The Daily Caller</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>314</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>315</end>
        <start>315</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>364</end>
        <start>316</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>581</end>
        <start>365</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>767</end>
        <start>582</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1079</end>
        <start>768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1080</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1430</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1508</end>
        <start>1431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>518</end>
        <start>510</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>769</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>828</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1359</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1508</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>CNN Panel Gets So Heated Host Pulls the Plug [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/cnn-panel-gets-so-heated-host-pulls-the-plug-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
