<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <links href="http://dennismichaellynch.com/obama-u-s-must-give-freedoms-submit-international-rule/">
        <end>42</end>
        <start>35</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>President Obama just made his last address as a sitting President to the United Nations General Assembly. In his speech he stressed about the necessity of international law and order. He told the assembly of 140 different countries that the United States would have to give up some of our freedoms. Yup, you read that right. He passive aggressively made attacks against those who oppose a lenient form of refugee resettlement. As well, he noted that one of the worlds greatest problems being dealt with is when, “powerful nations contest the constraints placed on them by international law. We can press forward with a better model of cooperation and integration, or we can retreat… along age-old lines of nation and tribe and race and religion.” Several times he references global integration as well as noting that liberal societies show discrimination and intolerance when women choose to cover themselves. An obvious reference to the Burkini ban in France. Obama said, “And in Europe and the United States, you see people wrestle with concerns about immigration and changing demographics, and suggesting that somehow people who look different are corrupting the character of our countries.” The absolute worse part was then he said that America would likely have to accept more constraints, and deprive themselves of freedoms by binding ourselves to international rules. Specifically, he said, “We have to put our money where our mouths are. And we can only realize the promise of this institution’s founding to replace the ravages of war with cooperation if powerful nations like my own accept constraints. Sometimes I’m criticized in my own country for professing a belief in international norms and multilateral institutions, but I’m convinced in the long run giving up some freedom of action, not giving up our ability to protect ourselves or pursue our core interests but binding ourselves to international rules, over the long-term, enhances our security.” Watch his speech here,  This progressive politicians tune has not changed one bit. When in fact all the things he is criticizing about anti refugee sentiment are things that Americans and other Europeans actually believe and feel. Yet, he dismisses it. He and his administration are the only ones who feel this way. This way being a liberal narrative. The narrative being that Islam is a peaceful religion, jihadism does not represent Islam, more refugees should be allowed into the United States with less vetting, and that incoming refugees don’t deteriorate a countries culture. These are all true yet he dismisses it like it is completely false. Just because he and his administration don’t admit the truth to themselves does not mean the rest of us have to remain in the dark. He is an embarrassment of this country and is destroying the hegemonic presence the United States has in the global arena. He’s too passive. Everyone knows they can take advantage and walk all over us. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>324</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>511</end>
        <start>325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>746</end>
        <start>512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>972</end>
        <start>747</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1194</end>
        <start>973</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1397</end>
        <start>1195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1966</end>
        <start>1398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1989</end>
        <start>1967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1990</end>
        <start>1990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2282</end>
        <start>1991</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2616</end>
        <start>2283</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2950</end>
        <start>2617</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2951</end>
        <start>2951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>745</end>
        <start>513</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1193</end>
        <start>974</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1399</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama: U.S. Must Give Up Freedoms, Submit To International Rule – WATCH</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/obama-u-s-must-give-up-freedoms-submit-to-international-rule-watch/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
