<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>iPatriot</author>
    <links href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/keith-lamont-scott-video_us_57e3f48ce4b0e28b2b529219">
        <end>1151</end>
        <start>1136</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ipatriot.com/charlotte-police-department-hiding/">
        <end>1733</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>UPDATE: It just keeps getting better. Keith Lamont Scott’s mother, Vernita Scott Walker, said the man was reading…the Koran before he was shot. Ya can’t make this stuff up folks! Why isn’t the Charlotte-Mecklenburg Chief of Police, Kerr Putney, going to release the video of the altercation between police and Keith Lamont Scott? According to the chief, it is clear that Scott had a gun. But then he back tracked saying: “The video does not give me absolute, definitive, visual evidence that would confirm that a person is holding a gun.” So what does that mean? From his declaration, there is but one conclusion we can make in confidence – that Scott did in fact have a handgun. Evidently other evidence and witness accounts support the police narrative that officers opened fire only after Scott refused to drop his weapon, so he did in fact have a weapon. It was neither holstered nor in his waistband. He was in fact holding the weapon. It was not a book he was holding as “witnesses and family” have claimed. Therefore, since the weapon was drawn, Scott must have intended to use it. Yet leftist websites and news outlets like the Huffington Post, drew a different conclusion from chief Putney’s statement. They claim that, “He [Putney] did however, note that the video fails to establish that Scott was holding a gun when he was shot.” This is absolutely NOT what the Chief said. Putney obviously chose his words very carefully. We don’t know why – just that he did. Watching the video of that segment of the press conference, adds further context to his statement. As he is explaining that there is “no definitive evidence” that “a person” is pointing a gun, he uses his hand to… Read the rest of the story at www.iPatriot.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>178</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>329</end>
        <start>179</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>538</end>
        <start>330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>539</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1341</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1686</end>
        <start>1342</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1733</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1734</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1880</end>
        <start>1735</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1954</end>
        <start>1881</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>537</end>
        <start>422</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>998</end>
        <start>978</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1340</end>
        <start>1230</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1629</end>
        <start>1607</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>519</end>
        <start>511</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1916</end>
        <start>1904</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Keith Lamont Scott was Reading the KORAN Before he Got Shot?</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37021/keith-lamont-scott-was-reading-the-koran-before-he-got-shot/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
