<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/GettyImages-521929382.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/conservative-rumblings-hillary-clinton-may-cancel-debate-monday/">
        <end>225</end>
        <start>209</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Next week’s debate may be the nation’s most widely watched Presidential debate in YEARS. That is, if both participants actually bother to show up.  Trump-enthusiast and Gateway Pundit owner Jim Hoft published an article today in which he says that an unnamed “conservative leader” contacted him stating that Hillary may be pulling out of Monday’s debate. Now this… A conservative leader wrote The Gateway Pundit Wednesday morning to share this news: Hearing smart guys say that Hillary may cancel the debate on Monday … Hillary may be trying to run out the clock because she thinks she is ahead. Could it be that Hillary Clinton pulls out of the debate, or is this just propaganda for Trump? Or even, a way to garner more interest for the much-awaited debate between the Republican and Democratic Presidential candidates Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton? With the widely-publicized health problems facing the Democratic nominee, it may very well be that she faces a “medical emergency” just before she is slated to take the stage. What do you think is the legitimacy of these whisperings? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>88</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>146</end>
        <start>89</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>147</end>
        <start>147</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>364</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>449</end>
        <start>365</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>595</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>854</end>
        <start>596</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1030</end>
        <start>855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1088</end>
        <start>1031</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1089</end>
        <start>1089</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>279</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>984</end>
        <start>967</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>595</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>595</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>THIS JUST IN: Hillary May Be Cancelling Monday’s Debate…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/just-hillary-may-cancelling-mondays-debate/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
