<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/billionaires-sheldon-adelson-joe-ricketts-plan-donations-to-donald-trumps-campaign-1474340684">
        <end>557</end>
        <start>529</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The anti-Donald Trump movement is on its death bed, the Republican presidential nominee boasted on Wednesday. “You’ll hear about these Never Trumpers, who are dying. Right now they’re on respirators, OK,” Trump said in response to a question about whether he will stand firm on his commitment to naming “true constitutionalists” to the Supreme Court. Story Continued Below Trump cited an “amazing” Wall Street Journal report “about all of the support that we’re getting.” The real estate mogul appears to be referring to a story published online late Monday in which the Journal reported that billionaires Sheldon Adelson and Joe Ricketts plan to pump millions of dollars into Trump and a pro-Trump super PAC. “From lots of rich people even,” Trump said of the fresh support he’s getting. “They’re coming in. These were Never Trump, Never Trump, Never Trump and now they’re — believe me, they see lower taxes, they see cutting the regulations, they see job creation, which is so important, and it’s really been amazing.” “And one of the things that they see and that you people see,” he told the group of pastors inside a Cleveland church, “is that — and so important — the judges. So I picked 11 judges. Very, very much into the world of the Constitution because we have people that, in some cases, not — I think in all cases — will have absolutely no — the Constitution will have no bearing on their decisions, OK, if somebody else gets it. And we picked 11 and we’re adding nine more. We’re gonna have a total of 20 people and I will pick from that group of 20 people. These are 20 outstanding people.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>109</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>350</end>
        <start>110</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>372</end>
        <start>351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>709</end>
        <start>373</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1020</end>
        <start>710</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1605</end>
        <start>1021</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>203</end>
        <start>111</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>327</end>
        <start>304</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>396</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>470</end>
        <start>426</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>741</end>
        <start>711</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1019</end>
        <start>790</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1082</end>
        <start>1022</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1604</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump says Never Trumpers ‘are dying, on respirators’</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-never-trumpers-dying-228465?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
