<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sonja Bochow</author>
    <links href="http://pamelageller.com/2016/09/pro-isis-and-devout-muslims-rush-to-celebrate-nyc-bombing-we-cause-you-pain-inside-your-house.html/">
        <end>129</end>
        <start>101</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It’s happy times for ISIS and Caliphate supporters everywhere as they deliriously report and applaud the allegedly terrorist bomb that exploded in New York and the ISIS inspired knife attacker in a Minnesota mall. After the bomb went off, social media blew up with proud jihadist sympathizers scoring one for their team. Some of the comments on social media were as follows; “The lions of the Caliphate roar in New York, we cause you pain inside your house, the carrier of the Cross,” wrote one Twitter user who went by the name “I am ISIS, come and block me.” The account was soon suspended. Another, called “The Lone Wolves,” tweeted with the Arabic hashtag #ExplosionManhattanNewYork “Oh God burn America, take revenge in the name of your oppressed slaves and believers’ blood.” Others tweeted about “good tidings that keep coming” from New York, and one user affiliated with al-Qaeda in Syria tweeted: “Oh God go against America, the head of infidels. Oh God, count them and kill them one by one, and do not spare anyone of them.”   Evil walks this earth. It’s name is radical Islamic terrorism. It celebrates when the blood of infidels (meaning regular people who do not agree with radical Islam) is spilled. It laughs with glee when New York is terrorized. It mocks westerners, Americans, Christians and Jews. It cares nothing for pain, suffering and outrage. It wishes and works for the day that Islam dominates the earth. That evil prowls social media taking credit for and celebrating bloodshed. And this newest event is no exception. There is joy among jihadists as New Yorkers and Minnesotans lie in their own blood. They need to be stopped. But who will do it? See video of explosion below.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>322</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>376</end>
        <start>323</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>783</end>
        <start>377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1036</end>
        <start>784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1037</end>
        <start>1037</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1038</end>
        <start>1038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1431</end>
        <start>1039</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1506</end>
        <start>1432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1674</end>
        <start>1507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1704</end>
        <start>1675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1705</end>
        <start>1705</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1706</end>
        <start>1706</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1707</end>
        <start>1707</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>483</end>
        <start>376</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>559</end>
        <start>530</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>626</end>
        <start>610</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>780</end>
        <start>688</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>833</end>
        <start>804</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1033</end>
        <start>907</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>ISIS Supporters Celebrate Manhattan Bombing… “We cause you pain in your house.”</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/isis-supporters-celebrate-manhattan-bombing-we-cause-you-pain-in-your-house/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
