<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>The campaign for Senate control increasingly looks like a flip-of-the-coin affair — a 50-50 split after the election is not far-fetched. That could be a nightmare in the making for whoever wins the White House. Story Continued Below Any individual senator — from Elizabeth Warren on the left to Ted Cruz on the right — could almost single-handedly block the new president’s Cabinet picks, depending on which party is in power. If you think the past several years of Senate gridlock have been bad, that might look like a joy ride by comparison. “It’ll be a whole new shooting match,” said Sen. John Thune (R-S.D.). “One of the concerns that I have is that [with] the rancor of this campaign, everybody will feel like it’s still open season on whoever the elected president is,” said Sen. Heidi Heitkamp (D-N.D.). “I hope we can get beyond that.” The Senate’s unique power over confirmations means the chamber will be called upon early and often to ratify the Cabinet selections of the new president, whether it’s Hillary Clinton or Donald Trump. The election outcome could have a big bearing on that: What once looked like a potential wave year for Democrats has tightened to the point that an evenly divided Senate has become a real possibility. That would leave virtually no margin for error when it comes to approving the president’s team next year. “We’re looking at a Senate somewhere between 52 and 48. Probably the outside numbers are 48 for one side and 52 for the other,” said Sen. Roy Blunt (R-Mo.), who himself is up for reelection. “It could be a tied Senate.” That outcome would also present a new test for the relationship between Capitol Hill and the White House. The confirmation process has grown ever more partisan over the past 15 years, despite the move by Democrats to weaken the filibuster so that all nominees except those to the Supreme Court can be confirmed by a simple majority. The most likely Senate makeup is 51-49, or 50-50, in which case ties would be broken by the vice president. Democrats fear that even if Clinton wins but Republicans keep the Senate, the GOP would drag its feet on her Cabinet picks and hobble her administration out of the gate. “If you have President Clinton and a Republican-controlled Senate, as we’ve seen with judicial appointments, the majority leader has the ability to obstruct virtually at will,” said Sen. Sheldon Whitehouse (D-R.I.). “By refraining from bringing nominations to the floor, that could single-handedly prevent the president from confirming her team.” Warning shots are already being fired. On Wednesday, Warren, a Massachusetts Democrat, gave a speech at the Center for American Progress that included a sharp signal to Clinton not to pick insiders with ties to the financial industry for her administration. “When we talk about personnel, we don’t mean advisers who just pay lip service to Hillary’s bold agenda, coupled with a sigh, a knowing glance and a twiddling of thumbs until it’s time for the next swing through the revolving door,” Warren said. Moderates are already entertaining what it will be like next year to hold the keys to Clinton’s Cabinet. Five senators from red states are running for reelection, and several from purple states will be up for reelection, and any one of them could accrue effective veto power over nominees who rub them or their state the wrong way. “Senators who are up in 2018 are already talking about it,” said Senate Minority Whip Dick Durbin (D-Ill.). The Senate dynamics surrounding Supreme Court confirmations and legislation probably won’t shift much, since they need 60 votes to move forward. Outgoing Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid (D-Nev.) recently urged Democrats to scrap the supermajority requirement even for bills if they win back the chamber. But it’s unlikely the party would go there, at least for now. Sen. Brian Schatz (D-Hawaii), a stalwart liberal in the caucus, said he is “cautious” about dumping the 60-vote threshold on the legislative filibuster anytime soon. But “if the Republicans are now into almost a decade of a lack of good faith and cooperation, then I think we have to reconsider everything,” Schatz said. He added: “Most of us are not anxious to move in that direction, but if we can’t function, then what is it exactly that we’re protecting?” Republicans say that won’t be necessary. “I do hold out some hope that knowing [ascending Democratic Leader] Sen. [Chuck] Schumer the way I do — he and I work well together — that we can find ways to build consensus,” said Sen. John Cornyn (R-Texas). “It’s clear that voters don’t like the direction of the country now.” Republicans say they hope to play nice on nominees, too — even if Clinton is president. But there’s a lot of bad blood from the Obama era: Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) kept Attorney General Loretta Lynch waiting for weeks last year and has refused this year to fill a Supreme Court vacancy. Democrats, for their part, changed the Senate’s rules and spent more than a year in the majority confirming lifetime judges over the objections of GOP leaders. GOP senators said in interviews that the best way for the White House to get in sync with the Senate is to begin voting on the least controversial judges and Cabinet positions and get in a rhythm — rather than first take up nominees viewed as partisan or controversial. “The first ones that they send up will set the tone for a lot of that,” said Sen. Bob Corker (R-Tenn.), the Senate Foreign Relations chairman. Selecting “some radical,” he added, “would not be a great way to start the process.” And there are a couple of remaining moderates in the GOP conference, most notably Sen. Susan Collins of Maine. She said that unless there are “integrity” issues with a nominee, she’s inclined to help confirm the person. That could be a lifeline for Senate Democrats if every confirmation vote turns into a squeaker. “I hope we’re not going to get into blocking Cabinet nominees for the sake of blocking them,” Collins said.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>136</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>210</end>
        <start>137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>232</end>
        <start>211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>543</end>
        <start>233</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>613</end>
        <start>544</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>844</end>
        <start>614</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1351</end>
        <start>845</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1571</end>
        <start>1352</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1904</end>
        <start>1572</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2182</end>
        <start>1905</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2529</end>
        <start>2183</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2787</end>
        <start>2530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3033</end>
        <start>2788</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3365</end>
        <start>3034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3473</end>
        <start>3366</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3618</end>
        <start>3474</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3841</end>
        <start>3619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4007</end>
        <start>3842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4301</end>
        <start>4008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4342</end>
        <start>4302</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4622</end>
        <start>4343</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5091</end>
        <start>4623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5361</end>
        <start>5092</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5589</end>
        <start>5362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5905</end>
        <start>5590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6013</end>
        <start>5906</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>581</end>
        <start>545</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>775</end>
        <start>615</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>843</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1478</end>
        <start>1353</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1570</end>
        <start>1544</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2358</end>
        <start>2184</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2528</end>
        <start>2400</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3019</end>
        <start>2789</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3424</end>
        <start>3367</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3926</end>
        <start>3918</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4148</end>
        <start>4013</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4300</end>
        <start>4174</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4518</end>
        <start>4344</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4621</end>
        <start>4554</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5432</end>
        <start>5363</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5529</end>
        <start>5516</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5588</end>
        <start>5542</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5742</end>
        <start>5733</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5998</end>
        <start>5907</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Next president could face a 50-50 Senate</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/senate-divided-white-house-nightmare-228492?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
