<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton on Tuesday dismissed Donald Trump’s conspiracy theory that his microphone was tampered with ahead of Monday’s presidential debate, framing his excuse as a signal that he had a bad night in what was effectively a rhetorical mic drop. The Republican presidential nominee told “Fox and Friends” in a phone interview Tuesday morning that he was having problems with his microphone Monday night. “I don’t know if you saw that in the room, but my microphone was terrible. I wonder, was it set up that way on purpose?” Trump said. Story Continued Below After a brief gaggle aboard her campaign plane later in White Plains, New York, Clinton turned back toward the crowd of reporters to take one final question after initially saying “thank you” and walking away. While the question itself is unclear, a woman can be heard asking about a microphone, prompting Clinton to take a scathing parting shot at her opponent, as evidenced by the audible reaction (which included a group “oooh”) on the plane. “Anybody who complains about the microphone is not having a good night,” Clinton quipped as she walked away from reporters, this time for good.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>248</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>539</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>561</end>
        <start>540</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>771</end>
        <start>562</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1007</end>
        <start>772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1151</end>
        <start>1008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>306</end>
        <start>291</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>526</end>
        <start>408</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>752</end>
        <start>743</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>987</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1079</end>
        <start>1009</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton zings Trump on microphone conspiracy theory</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-microphone-trump-228783?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
