<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Charles Roberts</author>
    <links href="http://t.co/DyYw1T5ck2">
        <end>1727</end>
        <start>1701</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://metro.co.uk/2015/04/14/female-hunter-receives-death-threats-after-posing-with-dead-giraffe-5150499/">
        <end>241</end>
        <start>236</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/people/female-huntress-rebecca-francis-receives-barrage-of-death-threats-over-hunting-images-10175733.html">
        <end>850</end>
        <start>839</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Rebecca Francis, winner of the reality television show "Extreme Huntress," has been receiving death threats for pictures that she has posted to social media. The photos show her posing next to animals that she has killed while hunting. Metro reported that the Utah native has killed bears, moose, zebras and antelopes during her hunting career. She recently posed with a big smile next to a dead giraffe and posted it to Facebook. Many social media users reacted negatively; some even said that they wished the hunter was dead. Twitter user @AsapGinger1 wrote, “I know this is very hypocritical of me but I want to f****** shoot her just for this picture.”  Actor Ricky Gervais is also an animal rights supporter and tweeted the photo of Francis next to the dead giraffe. His message was retweeted more than 17,000 times. According to the Independent, Francis has eight children. However, multiple pregnancies and babies have not prevented her from hunting in the United States and Africa. “We hunt elk and deer every year without fail, even through pregnancy, and nursing babies. Our hunting trips are self-guided,” she said.  Francis has also hosted the television show "Eye of the Hunter." She claims to have killed a wide range of animals, including, “A 10 1/2 ft. brown bear, black bear, shiras moose, alaskan moose,  dall sheep, stone sheep, desert bighorn ram, rocky mountain bighorn ram, mule deer, whitetail deer, elk, mountain goat, antelope, arapawa ram, kudu, zebra, black wildebeest, giraffe, springbuck, blesbuck, lynx, badger, and squirrel.” Read Gervais' Tweet below: What must've happened to you in your life to make you want to kill a beautiful animal &amp; then lie next to it smiling? pic.twitter.com/DyYw1T5ck2 Sources: Metro, Independent / Photo Source: Metro</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>235</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>430</end>
        <start>236</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>527</end>
        <start>431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>656</end>
        <start>528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>657</end>
        <start>657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>821</end>
        <start>658</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>989</end>
        <start>822</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1126</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1127</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1556</end>
        <start>1128</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1583</end>
        <start>1557</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1727</end>
        <start>1584</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1777</end>
        <start>1728</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>America Now</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>655</end>
        <start>562</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1115</end>
        <start>991</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1555</end>
        <start>1256</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1727</end>
        <start>1584</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Young Woman Gets Death Threats After Publishing This Photo Online (Photo)</title>
    <uri>http://www.americanow.com/story/animal-rights/2016/07/26/young-woman-gets-death-threats-after-publishing-photo-online-photo?fb=rwn</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
