<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://graphics.latimes.com/usc-presidential-poll-dashboard/#about">
        <end>68</end>
        <start>64</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump has just received what has to be his most positive poll of the general election season, showing the Republican nominee opening up a large lead over Hillary Clinton, while support among black voters is soaring to levels Democrats had not thought possible. The new USC Dornsife/Los Angeles Times “Daybreak” poll released on Sunday shows Trump with a commanding 6.7 percent lead over Clinton, 47.7 percent to 41.0 percent, an indication that Hillary’s collapsing after being forced to leave a 9/11 memorial early is taking its toll, along with the every changing explanations for the health scare from her campaign, which ranged from “overheated” to the flu, to pneumonia. More impressive and yet worrisome for Democrats, and the reason the party, all Democrat Media Complex, and Hillary Clinton herself has been going full-force with the “birther equals racist” narrative, is Trump’s massive gains among black voters in the past week. Trump now has over 20 percent support among black voters, up from only 3 percent just a week ago. Hillary Clinton has 70 percent, significantly lower than the number typically enjoyed by Democrat nominees. Notable is that voters under the age of 35 previously were favored by sizable margins by Clinton, but now the bloviating billionaire and reality TV actor has an 8-point advantage. And among those with a high school education or less, Trump’s support has surged to a 21-point advantage, up from single digits only weeks ago. The LA Times poll has before been favorable to Trump previously, showing the race tighter than most when Clinton was leading significantly. However, this poll, with Trump’s sizable lead and improving performance among black voters, has got to cause panic among Democrats and the Clinton campaign. I thought several times last week that Democrats must be really worried about Trump going after black voters with the focus suddenly being on birtherism — an issue that hadn’t been talked about for several months that the media just recently brought back into the conversation. It’s likely that Clinton’s internal polling was also showing Trump’s surge among black voters even before the LA Times poll. Look for the race card to be ramped up even further in the coming days.  Email Subscribe</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>267</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>945</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1151</end>
        <start>946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1475</end>
        <start>1152</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1772</end>
        <start>1476</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2175</end>
        <start>1773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2247</end>
        <start>2176</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2248</end>
        <start>2248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2254</end>
        <start>2249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2264</end>
        <start>2255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politistick</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>316</end>
        <start>308</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>655</end>
        <start>645</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>871</end>
        <start>850</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The hardest-hitting political news.</title>
    <uri>http://politistick.com/trump-ahead-la-times-poll-gaining-ground-black-voters/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
