<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cA06xi">
        <end>1921</end>
        <start>1900</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1M75UbX">
        <end>1988</end>
        <start>1964</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cynqH0">
        <end>4113</end>
        <start>4089</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2cyicen">
        <end>4963</end>
        <start>4941</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2cZMY2O">
        <end>4995</end>
        <start>4973</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://wapo.st/2dokMt5">
        <end>6151</end>
        <start>6129</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2doh9Dw">
        <end>6213</end>
        <start>6189</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyp.st/2czNBSK">
        <end>6344</end>
        <start>6323</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nydn.us/2czNfvr">
        <end>6531</end>
        <start>6509</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/clk/313631530;141405222;h">
        <end>6741</end>
        <start>6660</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2czumZu">
        <end>8387</end>
        <start>8363</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.DonaldJTrump.com">
        <end>8816</end>
        <start>8789</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.bit.ly/2dns1C9">
        <end>8997</end>
        <start>8979</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cH2QaJ">
        <end>9066</end>
        <start>9042</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cYTcjB">
        <end>9116</end>
        <start>9092</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2dfJOJH">
        <end>9175</end>
        <start>9151</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cxPEBI">
        <end>9284</end>
        <start>9263</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dfoQak">
        <end>9352</end>
        <start>9331</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cygNVh">
        <end>9475</end>
        <start>9454</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dg4Ioj">
        <end>9566</end>
        <start>9545</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d2QBs8">
        <end>9654</end>
        <start>9633</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cRZYFM">
        <end>10736</end>
        <start>10712</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cyiLEW">
        <end>11408</end>
        <start>11384</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cnn.it/2cHKPZQ">
        <end>12671</end>
        <start>12650</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dg6vtN">
        <end>14029</end>
        <start>14008</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cyrrv1">
        <end>14197</end>
        <start>14176</start>
    </links>
    <links href="mailto:politicoevents@politico.com">
        <end>15305</end>
        <start>15278</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2docO3M">
        <end>15532</end>
        <start>15508</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2dovXlG">
        <end>15683</end>
        <start>15659</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2czTfnR">
        <end>15778</end>
        <start>15754</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2docVMK">
        <end>15881</end>
        <start>15857</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2dov64w">
        <end>16037</end>
        <start>16013</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2d00fIR">
        <end>16228</end>
        <start>16204</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2dyVlEm">
        <end>17583</end>
        <start>17559</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.wsj.com/2doqqvs">
        <end>18352</end>
        <start>18327</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bzfd.it/2cZOsdn">
        <end>19227</end>
        <start>19205</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/clk/313631529;141405222;p">
        <end>19384</end>
        <start>19332</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dcErt3">
        <end>20045</end>
        <start>20024</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d5ISHg">
        <end>20163</end>
        <start>20142</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.recode.net/2cRVjDT">
        <end>21495</end>
        <start>21467</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.wsj.com/2cypu1E">
        <end>21947</end>
        <start>21922</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BKzzKdRBXkb/">
        <end>22052</end>
        <start>21949</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d5OTDY">
        <end>23483</end>
        <start>23462</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dgsnZD">
        <end>24253</end>
        <start>24232</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dosXWe">
        <end>24279</end>
        <start>24258</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2d687YC">
        <end>24620</end>
        <start>24596</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27e678973237540b2c24276ad69c745b973abd98144e0c210a">
        <end>1988</end>
        <start>1964</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a2767f4940442aff97e7c066c727f9c20288dbf3b9a9c94af0b">
        <end>26629</end>
        <start>26605</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1OypFe9">
        <end>26673</end>
        <start>26649</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a274cd0c60878dc0107a2877730f30a3cf31907ea80300291ab">
        <end>26722</end>
        <start>26698</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1Nhtq5v">
        <end>26774</end>
        <start>26750</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27c2d30196dfdcef3b79d2e10c2707bcce21999529adf1def8">
        <end>26821</end>
        <start>26797</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2bLvcPl">
        <end>26869</end>
        <start>26845</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1FZeLcw">
        <end>26916</end>
        <start>26892</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27f2079f7785f61ccb759e0f2b4aaa39da6b3d00c5a28d5b28">
        <end>1988</end>
        <start>1964</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Politico POLITICO's must-read briefing on what's driving the day in Washington Good morning from Hempstead, New York. The general consensus is this: Donald Trump didn’t throw up on his shoes. But Hillary Clinton had the far better night in their first 90-minute (it actually lasted 95 minutes) matchup here at Hofstra University on Long Island. Clinton mostly kept her cool -- as did Trump for the first portion of the evening. Trump ended up citing Sid Blumenthal, Rosie O’Donnell and referring viewers to Sean Hannity to vouch for his opposition to the Iraq War. The pre-debate buzz among reporters here was that Trump left himself the option to come to the spin room, but would only show up if he needed to change the narrative. He came to the spin room, and then spoke to Hannity live from the press filing center. Maggie Haberman (@maggieNYT) pointed out that “she can’t remember last time, if ever, a general election candidate went to the spin room.” Not a good sign for Trump. LAST NIGHT Hillary Clinton ended the debate by saying, “And one of the worst things he said was about a woman in a beauty contest. He loves beauty contests, supporting them and hanging around them. And he called this woman Ms. Piggy. Then he called her Ms. Housekeeping, because she was Latina. Donald, she has a name...Her name is Alicia Machado and she has become a U.S. citizen, and you can bet she's going to vote this November." Story Continued Below THIS MORNING Donald Trump went on “Fox and Friends” and said Machado was “the worst” contestant they had and chided her for gaining weight. “She was impossible...She was the winner and you know she gained a massive amount of weight and it was a real problem...This was many years ago, and [Clinton] found the girl and talked about her like she was Mother Teresa and it wasn’t quite that way, but that’s okay. Hillary has to do what she has to do.” Video clip http://bit.ly/2cA06xi (h/t Alex Burns) **SUBSCRIBE to Playbook: http://politi.co/1M75UbX --WHAT’S NEXT: The next presidential debate -- in St. Louis on Oct. 9 -- gives Trump an opportunity to bounce back. Remember: Mitt Romney trounced Barack Obama in the first debate. But the second event, which will be held at Wash. U., is a town hall, which brings its own challenges for both candidates. Clinton mostly skated on some of Trump’s signature attacks: Benghazi, her private email server, the FBI investigation, immigration and the Clinton Foundation. Trump is certain to hammer away on those issues in the coming weeks, and try to inject them into the conversation in Missouri. The vice presidential debate is in Farmville, Virginia, on Oct. 4 -- one week from today. WHAT TO WATCH FOR: How the down-ballot candidates react. Top Republican operatives running Senate and House races say they weren’t thrilled, but they don’t know that Trump’s bad night moves the needle. The early take is that Trump was stable for the first 30 minutes, which gives Republicans hope that any negative impact will be limited. 42 DAYS until Election Day. The government shuts down Friday. THE NARRATIVE -- “Clinton set the trap and Trump walked in: The Democrat dominated the debate. Will it matter?” by Eli Stokols: “‘Donald was very fortunate in his life, and that’s all to his benefit,’ Clinton started. ‘He started his business with $14 million, borrowed from his father, and he really believes that the more you help wealthy people, the better off we'll be and that everything will work out from there.’ Trump quickly dismissed Clinton’s characterization, saying he received ‘a very small loan’ that he turned into a company valued, he claimed, in the billions. ‘I say that only because that’s the kind of thinking that our country needs.’ In the moment, he seemed calm—but from that point forward he was anything but. ‘She mind-screwed him from the beginning by mentioning the loan from his father,’ said Rob Stutzman, a GOP operative in California. ‘That was brilliant psychological warfare on her part. He slowly unwound from there, culminating in borderline incoherency over the final 30 minutes.’” http://politi.co/2cynqH0 JMART and PAT HEALY on A1 of the NYT, “CANDIDATES PRESS POINTED ATTACKS IN ACERBIC DEBATE -- Trump Raps Clinton on Trade and Email -- She Counters on His Fitness”: “In a relentlessly antagonistic debate, Donald J. Trump and Hillary Clinton clashed over trade, the Iraq war, his refusal to release his tax returns and her use of a private email server, with Mr. Trump frequently showing impatience and political inexperience as Mrs. Clinton pushed him to defend his past denigration of women and President Obama. Mr. Trump repeatedly interrupted Mrs. Clinton and at times talked over her throughout the 90-minute debate, making slashing attacks that surely pleased his Republican base but may have been off-putting to women and undecided voters. He also left unchallenged her assertion that he paid no federal taxes for years.” http://nyti.ms/2cyicen … A1 PDF http://nyti.ms/2cZMY2O --WaPo leadall by Phil Rucker and Anne Gearan: “Donald Trump unrelentingly blamed the nation’s chronic problems on ‘typical politician’ Hillary Clinton, yet he found himself mostly on the defensive in their first debate here Monday night as she denounced him for racial insensitivity, hiding potential conflicts of interest and ‘stiffing’ those who helped build his business empire … Trump … spent much of the evening explaining himself — over his temperament, treatment of women and minorities, business practices and readiness to be commander in chief, as well as over his long perpetuation of a falsehood about Barack Obama’s birthplace to delegitimize his presidency. ‘He has a long record of engaging in racist behavior, and the birther lie was a very hurtful one,’ said Clinton ... ‘Barack Obama is a man of great dignity, and I could tell how much it bothered him and annoyed him that this was being touted and used against him.’ Trump, who earlier this month at last acknowledged Obama’s birth in Hawaii, replied by invoking Clinton’s 2008 rivalry with Obama: ‘When you try to act holier than thou, it really doesn’t work.’” http://wapo.st/2dokMt5 FOR REFERENCE -- The full transcript http://politi.co/2doh9Dw GOTHAM WATCH -- N.Y. Post (with photo of a grimacing Trump): “DON, NOT OUT -- Brawler Trump survives debate” http://nyp.st/2czNBSK … N.Y. Daily News (with large Clinton photo, and a grimacing Trump): “FACE OF THE NATION -- Hillary’s look says it all as Trump buries himself in bumbling blather” http://nydn.us/2czNfvr **** A message from BP: Over the past 10 years, no energy company has invested more in the U.S. than BP – $90 billion in total. Take 90 seconds to see what else we’re doing to help keep America moving forward. ****** GLENN THRUSH’s “OFF MESSAGE” -- “5 takeaways from the first presidential debate: Clinton hits him where it hurts, and Trump’s boorish reaction hands her a win”: “Trump was wimpy on defense. Trump is supposed to be the big meanie but it was Clinton who hit him where it hurt most … What about the Clinton Foundation? The former secretary's debate team … expected him to savage her on the various questions raised about her family's foundation. They were worried about it. While he hammered her ever-so-briefly on emails, he was so engaged in self-justification, he flat-out forgot to pursue an attack that could have made the night a lot less lousy. His ‘30 years’ attack worked - and he’ll use it again … [T]here were a few gold nuggets strewn in the wreckage of Hofstra - the most valuable an assault (demonstrable and fact-checker-friendly) on Clinton’s effectiveness in 25-plus years of public life … “Clinton effectively attacked his business career … Clinton plucked the strains of what could be a genuine crossover hit this fall among ever-elusive white working-class voters and independents: Trump’s failure to turn over his tax returns. Clinton went there with a vengeance – engaging in a little Trump-esque fact-free speculation about the motives of the billionaire developer-turned-reality TV star … Her most effective attack - and his worst answer. If the GOP nominee needed any more proof that preparation trumps bombast in a general election debate, he got it when Clinton launched a merciless attack on his habit of stiffing contractors who have labored on his construction projects over the years.” http://politi.co/2czumZu --@realDonaldTrump: “Nothing on emails. Nothing on the corrupt Clinton Foundation. And nothing on #Benghazi. #Debates2016 #debatenight … Wow, did great in the debate polls (except for @CNN - which I don’t watch). Thank you! … @newtgingrich just said ‘a historic victory for Trump.’ NICE! … @DRUDGE_REPORT’s First Presidential Debate Poll: Trump: 80% Clinton: 20% Join the MOVEMENT today &amp; lets #MAGA! http://www.DonaldJTrump.com” TEXT FROM TRUMP -- “Tonight’s WIN is for hard-working Americans like YOU. Let’s keep pushing. Our movement must finish strong. Fund our POST DEBATE RESPONSE -&gt;” www.bit.ly/2dns1C9 BEHIND THE SCENES: The CLINTON campaign set http://politi.co/2cH2QaJ … The TRUMP campaign set http://politi.co/2cYTcjB … Pins in the Anheuser-Busch tent http://politi.co/2dfJOJH … The bar in the Anheuser-Busch tent, which served beer and food throughout the debate http://bit.ly/2cxPEBI … Don King gaggling on behalf of Donald Trump http://bit.ly/2dfoQak … House Homeland Security Chairman Mike McCaul (R-Texas) huddling with retired Lt. Gen Michael Flynn http://bit.ly/2cygNVh … Megyn Kelly doing a post-debate standup from the media filing tent http://bit.ly/2dg4Ioj … Clinton spokesman Brian Fallon’s much buzzed-about festive coat http://bit.ly/2d2QBs8 SPOTTED: Bob Barnett talking to Corey Lewandowski in the Anheuser-Busch tent … Reps. Marsha Blackburn (R-Tenn.), Paul Tonko (D-N.Y.), Chris Collins (R-N.Y.), Xavier Becerra (D-Calif.), Cedric Richmond (D-La.), Joe Crowley (D-N.Y.), Charlie Rangel (D-N.Y.), Eliot Engel (D-N.Y.), Mike Kelly (R-Pa.) and Steve Israel (D-N.Y.) all at Hofstra for the main event … Don King waving an Israeli flag … Rick Lazio at the Long Island Marriott … Sheldon Adelson pulling up close to the debate hall in a stretch limo… Trump supporters Woody Johnson, Ray Washburne, David Tamasi and Rick Hohlt … Rev. Jesse Jackson, Vernon Jordan, Jay Dunn, David Jones, Al Mottur, Peter O’Keefe, J.B. Pritzker, Gene Karpinski of the League of Conservation Voters, Google’s Eric Schmidt … Scott Brown! BLAME GAME -- “Trump: My mic was ‘defective’,” by Yousef Saba: “[Donald] Trump complained in the spin room that his debate mic wasn’t working right, according to a video posted by a CBS journalist. ‘They gave me a defective mic!’ he told reporters. ‘[I] wonder, was that on purpose?’” http://politi.co/2cRZYFM -- “Giuliani: I’d skip next debates if I were Trump,” by Matthew Nussbaum: “Donald Trump should skip the next two debates unless he gets special guarantees from the moderators, former New York mayor and top Trump adviser Rudy Giuliani told reporters after the debate. ‘If I were Donald Trump I wouldn’t participate in another debate unless I was promised that the journalist would act like a journalist and not an incorrect, ignorant fact checker,’ Giuliani said. ‘The moderator would have to promise that there would be a moderator and not a fact checker and in two particular cases an enormously ignorant, completely misinformed fact checker.’” http://politi.co/2cyiLEW --@RosieGray: “.@JasonMillerinDC, asked several times by reporters, won't say if Trump pays federal income taxes” BY THE NUMBERS -- 18.6 million people engaged on Facebook creating 73.8 million likes, posts, comments and shares related to the debate. CNN/ORC POLL -- “Post-debate poll: Hillary Clinton takes round one,” by CNN polling director Jennifer Agiesta: “Hillary Clinton was deemed the winner of Monday night's debate by 62% of voters who tuned in to watch, while just 27% said they thought Donald Trump had the better night, according to a CNN/ORC Poll of voters who watched the debate … “Voters who watched said Clinton expressed her views more clearly than Trump and had a better understanding of the issues by a margin of more than 2-to-1. Clinton also was seen as having done a better job addressing concerns voters might have about her potential presidency by a 57% to 35% margin, and as the stronger leader by a 56% to 39% margin. The gap was smaller on which candidate appeared more sincere and authentic, though still broke in Clinton's favor, with 53% saying she was more sincere vs. 40% who felt Trump did better on that score. Trump topped Clinton 56% to 33% as the debater who spent more time attacking their opponent.” http://cnn.it/2cHKPZQ --@NateSilver538: “Clinton’s 35-point win in the CNN post-debate poll is the 3rd largest margin ever, after Romney-Obama I and Clinton-Bush 92 townhall.” LUNTZ’S FOCUS GROUP -- CLINTON WINS -- “Hillary Clinton came better prepared for tonight’s debate than any candidate in recent memory. She knew when to attack and when to explain – and how to pace it all over 90 minutes. Donald Trump started off great for the first few questions. He had an effective refrain of slamming Clinton’s ‘30 years’ of nothing, which resonated particularly well with independent voters. For the first 15-20 minutes, Trump’s numbers consistently went up whenever he railed against the current system and all its problems. Trump talked a lot about problems. But Clinton talked about solutions. ... “At the end of the night, Clinton moved the dials more with my group – 16 voters declared her the debate winner, while five said Trump won. Focus group consisted of 27 participants, all undecided voters from Pennsylvania. Pre-Debate: 10 leaned toward Clinton, six leaned toward Trump, and 11 were neutral. Post-Debate: 13 leaned toward Clinton, five leaned toward Trump, and nine were neutral.” NEW ADS -- Priorities USA is up with a new TV swing-state ad called “My Temperament” in Ohio, Florida, Nevada, Pennsylvania, Iowa, New Hampshire and North Carolina. http://bit.ly/2dg6vtN … Future45 -- a super PAC backed by the Ricketts and Adelson families -- is rotating this new ad called “Bad Experience” into its national TV buy http://bit.ly/2cyrrv1 HAPPENING TODAY -- Today is National Voter Registration Day. Hillary Clinton is in Raleigh. Tim Kaine is in Miami, Lakeland and Orlando. Anne Holton is in Detroit, Ann Arbor, Lansing and Grand Rapids. Bill Clinton is in Toledo and Cleveland. Donald Trump is going to Little Havana, Fla. for a town hall at 2 p.m. and Melbourne, Fla. for an for a 7 p.m. rally at the Orlando Melbourne International Airport’s AeroMod Hangar. He will also have two fundraisers: at Doral at noon and in Longwood, Fla. at 5 p.m. Mike Pence’s event in Waukesha, Wisconsin, has been canceled. EVENT TOMORROW -- Jake and Anna will sit down for a chat Wednesday morning with theSkimm co-founders and co-CEOs Carly Zakin and Danielle Weisberg at Twitter’s D.C. office. October is National Women’s Small Business Month, and Zakin and Weisberg recently were named to Fortune’s 40 under 40 list. Just this week, it became public that the New York Times invested in theSkimm. Join us for breakfast, conversation and networking. Join in on the conversation on Twitter at #POLITICOSkimm and send us a message at politicoevents@politico.com to learn more. HOW IT PLAYED -- Des Moines Register (banner headline under large banner photo) “ROUND 1 TO CLINTON -- Several Iowa political experts say she showed competence, but are unsure of impact” http://politi.co/2docO3M … L.A. Times (banner headline), “A TESTY OPENING ROUND -- Clinton and Trump engage fiercely over their pasts and their plans” http://politi.co/2dovXlG … Las Vegas Review-Journal (banner headline), “FIRST-ROUND FIREWORKS” http://politi.co/2czTfnR … Arizona Republic (banner headline, with two pull quotes) “ON THE OFFENSIVE” http://politi.co/2docVMK … Milwaukee Journal Sentinel (banner headline), “Clashing contenders … Clinton, Trump trade harsh attacks on records, temperament” http://politi.co/2dov64w … Cincinnati Enquirer (banner headline, with Trump quote about Clinton’s emails, and Clinton quote about Trump’s comments on race), “GLOVES COME OFF IN FIRST DEBATE” http://politi.co/2d00fIR HUFFPOST banner, “ORANGE CRUSH: DON DEMOLISHED AT DEBATE” ... Drudge, “Fire!” (an early banner featured a reader poll saying Trump won the debate) MEDIAWATCH -- “Lester Holt stays out of the way,” by Hadas Gold: “Lester Holt was on an island on Monday night. And for most of the first presidential debate, he stayed there, letting the battleships of Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump shoot their missiles at one another. It made for some memorable exchanges between Trump and Clinton, matched in close-up on most networks. For some debate watchers, that’s what they want their moderators to do: say ‘go’ and let them run. But it also left some gaps where viewers probably expected sharp questions. “There was no probing of Trump’s wall with Mexico, and vow to get the Mexicans to pay for it, or the Republican nominee’s ban on Muslims entering the country. And he barely prodded Clinton to explain her private email server in a question so gently worded that she was able to dispatch the issue with a few taut sentences.The Clinton Foundation? Wasn’t discussed; neither was the Benghazi attack. Few moderators have faced such intense scrutiny in the days leading up to the debate as Holt did, with Clinton’s allies demanding he serve as a fact-checker and Trump’s backers insisting that he allow the candidates to have their say.” http://politi.co/2dyVlEm -- “Donald Trump Says Lester Holt Did ‘Great Job,’ but Some Surrogates Disagree,” by WSJ’s Reid Epstein in Hempstead: “‘There were a few issues I felt like he should have raised, like the Clinton Foundation, that were not raised,’ Alabama Sen. Jeff Sessions said. ‘I would liked to have had a good discussion of [immigration]. … A good discussion of it would have been healthy.’ … ‘I thought he could have asked her more questions,’ [New York GOP Rep. Peter] King said. ‘If he was going to ask Donald Trump about his taxes he certainly could have asked Hillary Clinton about all the money she got from Wall Street and refuses to disclose the speeches that she made. You know, you have the moderator you have and you don’t complain about it.’” http://on.wsj.com/2doqqvs INSIDE THE CAMPAIGNS -- “The Myth Of ‘Trump-Whisperer’ Kellyanne Conway,” by BuzzFeed’s McKay Coppins: “[A]s the race has narrowed, Conway has emerged in the popular imagination of politicos and pundits as the deft handler who’s finally succeeded in domesticating Trump. … Interviews this week with more than half a dozen GOP sources close to the campaign suggest her ‘Trump-whisperer’ status is more made-for-TV myth than reality. ... [T]he biggest factor driving Conway’s outsize public reputation is her omnipresence on television. She spends far more time in front of the cameras than typical campaign managers do, appearing constantly on cable news, network morning shows, and even Bill Maher’s HBO talk show Real Time … Some have questioned whether it’s possible for her to effectively manage a national presidential campaign from a green room.” http://bzfd.it/2cZOsdn **** A message from BP: We’ve donated $147 million to U.S. community programs over the past five years. Check out the programs we support in your community. ****** BEYOND THE BELTWAY -- “Uprising activists: Charlotte mayor, police chief should resign,” by Charlotte Observer’s Ann Doss Helms: “Local and state activists called Monday for Police Chief Kerr Putney and Charlotte Mayor Jennifer Roberts to resign, as the city’s latest round of tension between police and the black community moves into its second week. At a Monday news conference held by Charlotte Uprising, a coalition that emerged during last week’s protests, speakers said both officials have failed to protect the city’s African American and working class citizens and withheld information about two fatal shootings last week.” http://bit.ly/2dcErt3 FIRST IN PLAYBOOK – New Hillary video: “Which version of Donald Trump showed up at the debate?” http://bit.ly/2d5ISHg -- Former Rep. Gabby Giffords and her husband Captain Mark Kelly on gun violence in the first debate: “Donald Trump paid lip service to gun safety, which is no surprise because it's this year's political high ground. However, we know he supports the gun lobby's efforts to protect loopholes that let criminals get guns. That's dangerous, and it puts our communities at risk. Hillary, on the other hand, was passionate and forceful in her support of stronger gun laws that save lives.” The statement comes as they are launching a 14-state “Vocal Majority Tour” to try and make the 2016 election a referendum on gun safety. FUTURECAST – “Uber is researching a new vertical-takeoff ride offering that flies you around,” by Re/code’s Kara Swisher: “[T]he fast-growing ride-sharing company [is] seriously looking at a new form of transportation to offer its customers: Short-haul flying in cities. The technology is called VTOL — which stands for vertical takeoff and landing. Simply put, VTOL is an aircraft that can hover, take off and land vertically, which would also describe a helicopter. But, unlike the typical helicopter, these planes have multiple rotors, could have fixed wings and perhaps eventually would use batteries and be more silent. In time, like cars, such aircraft would be autonomous.” http://on.recode.net/2cRVjDT VALLEY WATCH -- “Disney Considers Offer for Twitter: Sale process in early stages and follows announcement of Twitter talks with Salesforce,” by WSJ’s Dana Cimilluca, Joann Lublin and Erich Schwartzel: “Twitter, with a stock-market value of about $20 billion, has also held preliminary talks with Salesforce.com Inc. … The sale process is in early stages and it is far from guaranteed that anyone will end up buying Twitter.” http://on.wsj.com/2cypu1E  Cuccinelli bumoer sticker in the rear window of a pickup (presumably second hand from VA) in Phnom Penh A photo posted by Jon Fasman (@jonfasman) on Sep 25, 2016 at 11:38pm PDT SPOTTED at the debate, per pooler Zeke Miller: “Mark Cuban (who appears to be seated in the front row), Dan Malloy, Jesse Jackson, Andrew Cuomo and Sandra Lee, Reince and Sally Priebus, Donna Brazile, Don King, Rudy Giuliani in conversation with Sheldon Adelson ... Mike Flynn, One of the Baldwin brothers with a Trump button, Bill de Blasio, Ray Washbourne, Several members of the NY delegation taking a selfie, Charles Rangel calling out to Don King ‘welcome home, welcome home, we missed you.’ ... Mike Pence sitting up front” 2016 PLAYERS -- “How a Young Campaign Staffer Battling Stage 4 Cancer Helped Hillary Clinton Decide Her VP,” by People’s Sandra Sobieraj Westfall: “When Hillary Clinton and Tim Kaine talked with PEOPLE about their budding partnership, one mysterious bit in the interview stood out: ‘Some of my staffers,’ the senator from Virginia said to Clinton softly, ‘we have been through some challenging times, and you have taken good care of them.’ Enter Tyrone Gayle. Because the ‘some of my staffers’ turns out to be Gayle – and the ‘some challenging times’ is Gayle's life-and-death battle with Stage 4 colon cancer. Gayle, 28, was just about marking his one-year anniversary as a domestic-policy spokesman at Clinton's Brooklyn, New York, campaign headquarters last March when the diagnosis upended his world.” http://bit.ly/2d5OTDY HOT DOC -- WELCOME TO THE NEIGHBORHOOD! -- Rep. Mark DeSaulnier (D-Calif.) bought a new condo on North Carolina Avenue, SE. He picked up the studio apartment in September for $252,000, according to D.C. property records. DeSaulnier was elected for the first time in 2014. He replaced longtime California Democrat George Miller, and he represents a heavily Democratic district in the East Bay. TV TONIGHT – PBS’ “The Contenders: 16 for ’16” tonight looks at reasons why Michael Dukakis and Mitt Romney lost their chance at the presidency, in an episode called “The Technocrats”. “Was it Dukakis’ goofy grin in the seat of a war machine or, perhaps, Romney’s failure to follow in his father’s footsteps as a proponent of Civil Rights?” Preview clips http://bit.ly/2dgsnZD ... http://bit.ly/2dosXWe TRANSITIONS -- “Bill Corr and Kristi Martin Join Waxman Strategies”: “Corr comes to Waxman with decades of experience in health policy work, most recently as Deputy Secretary of HHS. ... Kristi Martin has left her post as a Senior Advisor in the Office of Health Reform at HHS to serve as Vice President at Waxman.” http://politi.co/2d687YC BIRTHDAYS: Juleanna Glover (hat tips: Becca, Pepper) … DNC Chair Debbie Wasserman Schultz is 5-0 ... Politico’s Tony Romm … Lucy McCalmont, coordinating producer at the Sports Tribune ... New America Foundation head Anne-Marie Slaughter ... Carl Woog, director of strategic comms at NSC and a DoD and Ash Carter alum and the pride of Phoenix … Megan Grant, VP for strategic comms at Glover Park Group and a CNN alum ... Jeff Birnbaum, president of BGR Public Relations and longtime D.C. journalist, is 6-0 ... Brian Killheffer, the king of Delaware, is 35 ... ex-CAPer Christina DiPasquale (h/t DJW) ... LaVerne Alexander, COS to Rep. Donald Payne (h/t Jamie Oh) ... David Ratcliff (h/t Jon Haber) ... Meridith McGraw of ABC News (h/t Natalie Boyse) … Will Bredderman … Marcus Sebastian Mason, senior partner of the Madison Group (h/t Robb Watters) ... Caitlyn “Oh Word?” Schneeweiss ... Christina DiPasquale, founder and CEO of Balestra Media … … Ed Niles, lead media strategist at BlueLabs and a DCCC alum ... Deloitte’s Alexa Wertman is 26 ... AP’s Pablo Gorondi … Sara Chieffo of the League of Conservation Voters … Concetta Cantelmo of Budd Lake, N.J. ... Martin D. Franks, who served in the Carter administration before becoming the longtime head of lobbying (and many other things) for CBS Corporation ... WJLA alum Tim Traylor … Charles Percy … Rene Carbone Bardorf, chief comms officer at National Defense Industrial Association ... Earl Plante is 44 ... Georgi Tsakonis is 61 ... Sean Miller ... NBC News’ Matthew Vann ... PwC’s Scott Moshier is 31 ... former Rep. Ed Case (D-HI) is 64 ... Geoff Burgan, DWS’ press secretary … Michelle Carrier ... Kathy Heinan ... Lee Wasserman ... John Loredo ... Abby Curran (h/ts Teresa Vilmain) ... Shaun Cassidy is 58 ... comedian Marc Maron is 53 ... Gwyneth Paltrow is 44 ... Lil’ Wayne is 34 ... singer Avril Lavigne is 32 (h/ts AP) SUBSCRIBE to the Playbook family: POLITICO Playbook http://politi.co/1M75UbX ... New York Playbook http://politi.co/1ON8bqW … Florida Playbook http://politi.co/1OypFe9 ... New Jersey Playbook http://politi.co/1HLKltF ... Massachusetts Playbook http://politi.co/1Nhtq5v ... Illinois Playbook http://politi.co/1N7u5sb ... California Playbookhttp://politi.co/2bLvcPl ... Brussels Playbook http://politi.co/1FZeLcw ... All our political and policy tipsheets http://politi.co/1M75UbX</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>78</end>
        <start>9</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>984</end>
        <start>79</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1418</end>
        <start>985</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1440</end>
        <start>1419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1938</end>
        <start>1441</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1988</end>
        <start>1939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2668</end>
        <start>1989</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3007</end>
        <start>2669</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3069</end>
        <start>3008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4113</end>
        <start>3070</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4995</end>
        <start>4114</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6151</end>
        <start>4996</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6213</end>
        <start>6152</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6531</end>
        <start>6214</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6748</end>
        <start>6532</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7652</end>
        <start>6749</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8387</end>
        <start>7653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8817</end>
        <start>8388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8997</end>
        <start>8818</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9654</end>
        <start>8998</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10426</end>
        <start>9655</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10736</end>
        <start>10427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11408</end>
        <start>10737</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11522</end>
        <start>11409</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11659</end>
        <start>11523</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>12005</end>
        <start>11660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>12671</end>
        <start>12006</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>12825</end>
        <start>12672</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>13447</end>
        <start>12826</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>13842</end>
        <start>13448</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>14197</end>
        <start>13843</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>14767</end>
        <start>14198</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15320</end>
        <start>14768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>16228</end>
        <start>15321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>16375</end>
        <start>16229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>16925</end>
        <start>16376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>17583</end>
        <start>16926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>18352</end>
        <start>17584</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>19227</end>
        <start>18353</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>19391</end>
        <start>19228</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20045</end>
        <start>19392</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20163</end>
        <start>20046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20785</end>
        <start>20164</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21495</end>
        <start>20786</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21947</end>
        <start>21496</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21948</end>
        <start>21948</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22052</end>
        <start>21949</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22125</end>
        <start>22053</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22655</end>
        <start>22126</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>23483</end>
        <start>22656</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>23876</end>
        <start>23484</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24279</end>
        <start>23877</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24620</end>
        <start>24280</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>25566</end>
        <start>24621</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>26505</end>
        <start>25567</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>26984</end>
        <start>26506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>956</end>
        <start>866</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1491</end>
        <start>1041</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1061</end>
        <start>1052</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1887</end>
        <start>1582</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3180</end>
        <start>3088</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4087</end>
        <start>3199</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4275</end>
        <start>4153</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4939</end>
        <start>4279</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6127</end>
        <start>5044</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6321</end>
        <start>6276</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6507</end>
        <start>6415</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6776</end>
        <start>6765</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6907</end>
        <start>6782</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8361</end>
        <start>6911</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8816</end>
        <start>8409</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8977</end>
        <start>8838</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10472</end>
        <start>10442</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10710</end>
        <start>10491</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10789</end>
        <start>10741</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11382</end>
        <start>10813</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11521</end>
        <start>11424</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11727</end>
        <start>11677</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12648</end>
        <start>11772</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12824</end>
        <start>12691</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>13841</end>
        <start>12866</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>13926</end>
        <start>13912</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>14149</end>
        <start>14135</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15506</end>
        <start>15402</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15657</end>
        <start>15566</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15752</end>
        <start>15731</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15855</end>
        <start>15839</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16011</end>
        <start>15931</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16202</end>
        <start>16171</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16285</end>
        <start>16247</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16305</end>
        <start>16300</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16424</end>
        <start>16391</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>17557</end>
        <start>16442</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>17664</end>
        <start>17588</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18325</end>
        <start>17703</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18425</end>
        <start>18378</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>19203</end>
        <start>18457</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>19479</end>
        <start>19415</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>20022</end>
        <start>19522</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>20140</end>
        <start>20086</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>20647</end>
        <start>20267</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>20722</end>
        <start>20703</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>20879</end>
        <start>20800</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21465</end>
        <start>20909</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21636</end>
        <start>21513</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21920</end>
        <start>21699</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22654</end>
        <start>22174</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22763</end>
        <start>22673</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>23460</end>
        <start>22804</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>23922</end>
        <start>23896</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24059</end>
        <start>24044</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24216</end>
        <start>24063</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24346</end>
        <start>24296</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24594</end>
        <start>24350</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>25491</end>
        <start>25483</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22125</end>
        <start>21949</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BEHIND THE SCENES of the first debate: WHO WAS TALKING TO WHO, PHOTOS -- NARRATIVE: CLINTON wins -- GIULIANI: ‘I’d skip next debates if I were Trump’ -- B’DAY: Juleanna Glover</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/tipsheets/playbook/2016/09/behind-the-scenes-of-the-first-debate-who-was-talking-to-who-photos-narrative-clinton-wins-giuliani-id-skip-next-debates-if-i-were-trump-bday-juleanna-glover-216525?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
