<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/carrie-underwood-vows-to-make-christmas-about-family-for-her-first-holiday-as-a-mom-737075.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/CMIL38.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Carrie Underwood got candid with her fans, and we love her for it. If anyone is the queen of modern-day country music, it’s Carrie Underwood. She’s got it all and more! One thing we absolutely love about Carrie Underwood is how candid she is with all of us. She’s never afraid to be real and tell people how life really is. She shares with us things that she’s learned from being a wife, a mom, a friend and a daughter. All the things that she wished she was told, she shares. And then some.  She sticks up for people who are being bullied, and fights for the things she believes in. All in all, Carrie shows us what it looks like to be a good and graceful leader. Recently Underwood was in Nashville performing one of her shows. During the middle of it, she paused to talk about a great woman and role model in the country music industry, Dolly Parton. Underwood then went on to sing one Parton’s hit songs, ‘I Will Always Love You.’ After she was done with the beautiful rendition, she paused to thank a special group of people in her life. Underwood explained that she couldn’t make it through certain times without strong women helping and guiding her along the way. “I have learned a lot about a whole incredible group of amazing women over the past year and a half of my life. I’ve gained just an incredible appreciation for moms — for my own mother and for the mothers of my friends and just people that I know that have had kids. I never knew what it was like to just juggle everything and try to be everything to everyone.” All of those words were said through tears streaming down the star’s face. She was genuine and heartfelt about everything she was saying. You can tell that she’s been impacted tremendously by this group of ladies.  After she said all of that, she encouraged all of her fans. She let everyone know that she appreciates them and their support so much. Then she laughed as she let the crowd know that she may not make it through her next song, which was “What I Never Knew I Always Wanted.” Carrie never fails to make every moment real and heartfelt. It’s something that we as fans absolutely adore about her. She has never let her fame and success get in the way of showing love, kindness and gratefulness to everyone. Watch the amazing moment below!  We love you, Carrie!! </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>168</end>
        <start>67</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>323</end>
        <start>169</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>491</end>
        <start>324</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>492</end>
        <start>492</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>934</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1170</end>
        <start>935</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1532</end>
        <start>1171</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1746</end>
        <start>1533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1747</end>
        <start>1747</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2020</end>
        <start>1748</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2249</end>
        <start>2021</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2281</end>
        <start>2250</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2282</end>
        <start>2282</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2305</end>
        <start>2283</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1531</end>
        <start>1172</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2019</end>
        <start>1985</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1532</end>
        <start>1171</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1532</end>
        <start>1171</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Carrie Underwood Uncontrollably Cries On Stage, This Left Me In Tears</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/carrie-underwood-uncontrollably-cries-on-stage-this-left-me-in-tears/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=carrie+underwood%2F9%2F27&amp;utm_term=Right+Wing+News%2Fcarrie+underwood%2F9%2F27</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
