<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>McIntosh</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/gettyimages-609609104.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/carr2.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Charlotte has seen some of the worst rioting over a cop shooting in a while and regardless of what the liberal media labels these people, they are not protesters. Protesters have a right to protest. They are protected under the Constitution. No. These folks we have here are rioters. They have burned, smashed, looted and now murdered each other over the latest police shooting (by the way, the officer was black).  Justin Carr, 26, passed away on Thursday after being critically wounded during the riots over the shooting of Keith Lamont Scott by a black police officer. Carr was shot as rioters fought with police in riot gear lined arm-in-arm standing guard at the Omni Hotel at about 8:30 pm. City officials say Carr was not shot by an officer, but some protesters have claimed that he was wounded by a cop. No arrests have been made in Carr’s death, but a homicide investigation has been launched.  Police Chief Kerr Putney has put detectives on the case to try and find out who it was that made the shot, while the Charlotte Clergy Coalition for Justice have other plans… ‘I saw the man go down on the pavement,’ Minister Steve Knight of Mission gathering Christian Church in Charlotte said. ‘It was an ambush. The victim was shot while he stood between two ministers, and we believe he was shot by police.’ Of course. Rioters are burning, looting and beating people, and it’s the cops. These people are pathetic. Knight also claimed: ‘We would like to see surveillance video from the surrounding area that may have captured the shooting to determine who was responsible for the shooting.’ Justin Carr is dead. Shot in the head. Does this sound like a peaceful protest? Well, it’s not one I’m familiar with. Is there any reasoning or waiting for the facts anymore?   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>414</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>415</end>
        <start>415</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>571</end>
        <start>416</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>696</end>
        <start>572</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>902</end>
        <start>697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>903</end>
        <start>903</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1077</end>
        <start>904</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1313</end>
        <start>1078</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1314</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1595</end>
        <start>1420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1770</end>
        <start>1596</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1771</end>
        <start>1771</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1772</end>
        <start>1772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1773</end>
        <start>1773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <title>VIDEO: Protester Who Was Shot In The Head Dies…And Now Cops Are Being Blamed. AGAIN.</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/video-protester-shot-head-dies-now-cops-blamed/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
