<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://nypost.com/2016/09/18/inside-the-scramble-to-cover-up-clintons-private-email-server/amp/">
        <end>119</end>
        <start>96</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nypost.com/2016/07/05/fbi-director-james-comeys-full-remarks-on-clinton-email-probe/">
        <end>455</end>
        <start>367</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>One question on the mind of many is why would the Clinton IT staff plead the 5th? Based on this report from the NY Post, we may have part of our answer: The FBI report noted there were many hacking attempts into the system, both while Clinton was secretary of state and afterward when Platte River Networks took over the administration of the home server. The agency said none had been successful, and it never named the hackers or their points of origin. But multiple internal Platte River e-mails reviewed by The Post show that computers in China tried on three occasions in 2014 to log into Clinton’s server and a computer in Russia tried once in 2013. The internal communications also revealed how the execs belatedly tightened security on Clinton’s now-controversial home server and frantically sought to “cover our asses” when news broke that the former secretary of state’s communications were deleted. “Any chance you found an old e-mail with their directives to cut the backups back in Oct‐-Feb? . . . If we had that e-mail, we are golden,” Platte River IT consultant Bill Thornton wrote to colleagues on Aug. 19, 2015. “Wondering how we can sneak an e-mail in now after the fact asking them when they told us to cut the backups and have them confirm it for our records. Starting to think this whole thing really is covering up some shaddy s- -t.” Thornton and fellow Platte River specialist Paul Combetta refused to answer questions last week before a congressional committee probing the server scandal. Each cited his Fifth Amendment rights. Recently Judicial Watch submitted questions to Hillary Clinton that a federal judge required her to answer. That may be why crooked Hillary almost passed out on 9-11, since the date looms. Perhaps we will finally get real answers to the racketeering of The Clinton Mafia. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>81</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>152</end>
        <start>82</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>455</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>655</end>
        <start>456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>909</end>
        <start>656</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1128</end>
        <start>910</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1356</end>
        <start>1129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1552</end>
        <start>1357</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1824</end>
        <start>1553</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1825</end>
        <start>1825</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Black Sphere</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>826</end>
        <start>811</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1355</end>
        <start>1130</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1552</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Why Clinton IT Staff Took the 5th</title>
    <uri>http://theblacksphere.net/2016/09/clinton-staff-took-5th/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
