<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://www.youngcons.com/state-department-admits-terrorists-are-posing-as-refugees-obama-continues-push-to-increase-refugees-anyway/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Refugees.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/21/state-department-jihadis-have-posed-as-refugees-to-enter-us/?utm_campaign=atdailycaller&amp;utm_source=Twitter&amp;utm_medium=Social">
        <end>1035</end>
        <start>1023</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Refugees1-e1474551241634.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Obama has known from the very beginning that there are terrorists among the unvetted refugees he is bringing in. That was a certainty. He just doesn’t care. When he first said he wanted to bring in 10,000 refugees, I laughed. I told people he was planning on 250,000 and people laughed at me. Now he says 110,000 and I’m telling you, it will be way more than that and many of them will be ISIS connected. Obama is not only terraforming the US into a Muslim nation, he is deliberately bringing terror and chaos to our streets to destroy us. Just as he has done with race wars. It’s been the plan all along. Now they have the chutzpah to actually admit they know it, but they are still defending their actions. They have no intention of slowing down, much less stopping the influx. This is one of those areas that I agree with Donald Trump on… this must be stopped until we can adequately vet these people. Obama now knows that Hillary could lose, so he is doubling down on this and violence and death will follow.  From the Daily Caller: Islamic State terrorists have tried to pose as refugees in order to gain admittance to the U.S., Department of State spokesman John Kirby admitted Wednesday. “I wouldn’t debate the fact that there’s the potential for ISIS terrorists to try to insert themselves,” Kirby said on Fox News. “And we’ve seen that in some of the refugee camps in Jordan and in Turkey, where they try to insert themselves into the population.” He was defending President Barack Obama’s plan to bring in 110,000 new refugees in the next year, a huge increase from the 70,000 the U.S. typically admits, saying the vetting process is “good.” Any sane leader after having their country hit with numerous terrorist attacks, many of which are directly traceable to refugees, would back off and consider their actions and the consequences. But not Obama. We got hit by at least three terrorist attacks last week and he went to the UN and went all out for bringing in far more refugees. Obama hates America and he is a traitor to this country. Every action he has taken while in office screams that he is an enemy within. Yet, we are doing virtually nothing to stop him. Terrorism and dead Americans are the result of our apathy and complacency. Obama and his administration admit that this will end in terrorism. We know it will too. Why are we just letting this happen? Has America lost her will to fight and survive?  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>605</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1012</end>
        <start>606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>1013</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1036</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1194</end>
        <start>1037</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1456</end>
        <start>1195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1991</end>
        <start>1652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2424</end>
        <start>1992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2425</end>
        <start>2425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2426</end>
        <start>2426</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1298</end>
        <start>1196</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1325</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1650</end>
        <start>1645</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1037</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>State Department ADMITS Terrorists Are Posing As Refugees – Obama Moves To INCREASE Intake…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/barack-obama/state-department-admits-terrorists-posing-refugees-obama-moves-increase-intake/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
