<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Onan Coca</author>
    <links href="http://www.tmz.com/2016/09/19/gene-simmons-bombings-profiling-terrorists/">
        <end>685</end>
        <start>669</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>“[Ahmad Khan Rahami] should go to jail and be somebody’s girlfriend.” — Rock Legend Gene Simmons commenting on recent NY/NJ bomber Ahmad Khan Rahami Hall of Fame rock legend Gene Simmons made a name for himself playing the bass guitar and singing for the pop-rock band KISS. In more recent years he’s been a reality TV star, a cultural icon, and an outspoken defender of the free market system and personal liberty. The combination of these things has made Simmons marketing gold among more conservative NASCAR loving, flag waving Americans. The folks at TMZ recently ran into Simmons in the airport security line and asked him for his thoughts on the recent bombings. Simmons told TMZ that he thought the Muslim terrorist bomber, Rahami, “should go to jail and be somebody’s girlfriend.” Ouch. TMZ then asked Simmons how he would solve the problem of Islamic terrorism in America, to which Simmons replied, rather politically incorrectly, that we needed to do more profiling. “Nobody says the word ‘profile.’ Everyone needs to get smart. I’m ok with profiling. I want you to stop me first. I want you to stop me because I look a certain way. And if I’m clear, then profile someone else. It’s emergency powers during war. There’s a war going on.” But what about the people who were being “unfairly” profiled, TMZ wondered. Simmons held nothing back in his perfect response. “It is unfair. That’s why the words ‘too bad’ exists.” BOOM.  Thank you for being awesome, Mr. Simmons. Maybe when Donald Trump gets elected President he’ll consider making Gene Simmons the director of Homeland Security? Ooh, and then KISS could play at all of the White House State functions! Hey, I can dream, can’t I?  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>148</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>668</end>
        <start>149</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>976</end>
        <start>669</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1246</end>
        <start>977</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1428</end>
        <start>1247</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1435</end>
        <start>1435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1694</end>
        <start>1436</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1695</end>
        <start>1695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1841</end>
        <start>1696</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1915</end>
        <start>1842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>68</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>68</end>
        <start>21</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1245</end>
        <start>978</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1297</end>
        <start>1289</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1427</end>
        <start>1375</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1877</end>
        <start>1865</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>KISS Bassist Gene Simmons on How to Stop Islamic Terrorism: “PROFILE” [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37013/kiss-bassist-gene-simmons-on-how-to-stop-islamic-terrorism-profile-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
