<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/38AE9F0800000578-3801796-image-a-77_1474541057817-620x354.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>What do you do if you’re sitting in your vehicle and suddenly you’re surrounded by a seemingly hostile group? Step one should obviously be to lock your doors to make it just a little bit harder for them to break in. Step two is up to you. Do you put the pedal to the floor and power through? Do you call the police and wait. This guy had another idea entirely and it worked like a charm.  A random white guy was driving through the riots taking place in North Carolina when he was surrounded by the protesters/rioters. The photographer who witnessed the incident thought that he was going to get mugged, but for some reason they just let him through. That seems very bizarre considering that we’ve seen videos of rioters stopping cargo trucks, stealing the items within and lightening them on fire. That being the case, why would they just let one guy go? Well, they saw what he was waving out the window and they must have thought that it was in their best interest to leave him alone. While being white in the middle of an angry BLM mob would usually be a death sentence, this guy had thought ahead. When his car was surrounded, he calmly rolled down his window and let the protesters know that he had a handgun. The group quickly dispersed and let the man continue driving to his destination. This is exactly how people should handle these kinds of situations. Do you think that he did the right thing? Or should he just have driven through? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>109</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>215</end>
        <start>110</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>324</end>
        <start>216</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>387</end>
        <start>325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>388</end>
        <start>388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>650</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>855</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>986</end>
        <start>856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1214</end>
        <start>987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1295</end>
        <start>1215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1444</end>
        <start>1296</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1445</end>
        <start>1445</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <title>White Guy Walled In Car By BlackLivesMatter Protesters – They See What He’s Brandishing And Scatter…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/white-guy-walled-car-blacklivesmatter-protesters-see-hes-brandishing-scatter/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
