<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://fox13now.com/2016/09/12/prominent-latino-activist-tony-yapias-charged-with-rape/">
        <end>160</end>
        <start>152</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Tony Yapias took umbrage at Donald Trump for calling some Latinos coming from Mexico illegally “rapist.” Yapias’ crime? Rape. Oh the irony. As FOX News reported, Well-known Hispanic activist Tony Yapias was charged with rape after he allegedly assaulted a woman who ended their four-year relationship a few months ago. Yapias, 50, known as Adolfo Tony Yapias-Delgado, was formally charged in the 3rd District Monday with rape, a first-degree felony and evidence tampering, a class A misdemeanor. Yapias is the director of Proyecto Latino de Utah. “No” means “no”, even in Spanish, Antonio! According to court documents Yapias went to the woman’s home in South Salt Lake on March 21. “The victim had terminated the relationship 10 days prior and had expressed strongly and repeatedly in text messages that the relationship was over and she did not want anything to do with the defendant,” court documents state. Documents indicate that Yapias persisted and went to her home. “…The victim’s last text to the defendant, before he arrived at her home said: ‘I said no. don’t you get it.’ The defendant responded with a series of three text messages as follows: ‘No, I don’t get it,’ then ‘I’ll be there’ followed a short time later by ‘I’m here,’” It appears Yapias wasn’t concerned about any borders or rights of people not to be harassed. Let’s see if the Liberals can figure out a way to make a poster child out of this monster.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>104</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>139</end>
        <start>105</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>161</end>
        <start>140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>318</end>
        <start>162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>495</end>
        <start>319</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>546</end>
        <start>496</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>589</end>
        <start>547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>910</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>973</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1243</end>
        <start>974</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>1244</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1427</end>
        <start>1337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1429</end>
        <start>1428</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1430</end>
        <start>1430</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Black Sphere</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>103</end>
        <start>96</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>550</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>64</end>
        <start>62</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>886</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1242</end>
        <start>975</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>546</end>
        <start>162</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1243</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Anti-Trump Latino Activist Arrested</title>
    <uri>http://theblacksphere.net/2016/09/anti-trump-latino-activist-arrested/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
