<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Rat.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/weird-news/how-easy-rat-wiggle-up-8875329">
        <end>315</end>
        <start>304</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fdengarden.com%2Fpest-control%2FHow-to-Deal-with-a-Rat-Swimming-Up-the-Toilet-Bowl&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGrBo2hKPavomDqikXrAC31YqRNzg">
        <end>826</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Not reading enough off-the-wall news? Well, boy howdy, do I have a story for you. If you know anything about mice and rats, you know that they don’t exactly live out in the open. They rely on small spaces and dark paths for the bulk of their travel. some of these small, dark spaces include the pipes of your toilets. We’ve all seen videos of rats in toilets and you have to admit, it would be pretty frightening to stumble tiredly into your bathroom in the middle of the night and find a large rodent staring back at your from your porcelain throne.  See what I mean? Who wants to find that? Here is a video that shows how simple it is for these guys to climb up into your toilet.   If you live in a place that is rife with these furry menaces, there is something you can do to prevent them from disturbing your bathroom time. To keep rats away, install sewer pipes made of PVC or clay, at least 24 inches wide. Place a one-way rat baffle (a cap, basically), in the pipeline. And make sure any rubbish and drains are tightly sealed to stop rats congregating near your house in the first place. If you can’t do that, because you live in an apartment or some such accommodation, call your plumber and let them know you’re having rat problems and see if they can help you. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>81</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>317</end>
        <start>82</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>550</end>
        <start>318</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>551</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>592</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>681</end>
        <start>593</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>682</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>683</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>827</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>912</end>
        <start>828</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1094</end>
        <start>913</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1270</end>
        <start>1095</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1271</end>
        <start>1271</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1094</end>
        <start>828</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>VIDEO: This is how easy it is for a rat to wiggle up into your toilet</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/video-easy-rat-wiggle-toilet/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
