<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1M75UbX">
        <end>1639</end>
        <start>1615</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>John Boehner has his first private-sector job in roughly a quarter century. The former speaker of the House is joining Squire Patton Boggs, the multinational law firm, as a strategic adviser based in Washington and Cincinnati. Story Continued Below The firm has a healthy lobbying practice, but Boehner will not become a lobbyist, according to the firm. He will "serve as a strategic advisor to clients in the U.S. and abroad, and will focus on global business development." Boehner's post-Congress livelihood is starting to take fuller shape. Last week, the tobacco giant Reynolds America announced he's joining its board of directors, a job that is likely to bring him north of $400,000 a year. Boehner will have plenty of friends and allies at Squire Patton Boggs, including former Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott (R-Miss.), former Rep. Jack Kingston (R-Ga.), and former Sen. John Breaux (D-La.). Boehner's former top aide, David Schnittger, is a senior policy adviser at Squire Patton Boggs, as is Natasha Hammond, who worked for Boehner for nine years. John Criscuolo and Amy Lozupone, both Boehner aides, will join him at the firm. Squire Patton Boggs has deep ties to Boehner's home state of Ohio. CEO Mark Reuhlmann's father, Gene, was the mayor of Cincinnati, and Squire Sanders, one of the firms that predated Squire Patton Boggs, was founded in Cleveland. “With Speaker Boehner joining our team, we're better positioned than ever to grow our brand throughout the world and to fully capitalize on our integrated global platform," Mark Ruehlmann said in a news release. **SUBSCRIBE to POLITICO Playbook: http://politi.co/1M75UbX</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>75</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>226</end>
        <start>76</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>248</end>
        <start>227</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>474</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>696</end>
        <start>475</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1139</end>
        <start>697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1368</end>
        <start>1140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1580</end>
        <start>1369</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1639</end>
        <start>1581</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Boehner joining Squire Patton Boggs</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/boehner-joining-squire-patton-boggs-228409?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
