<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Colin Taylor</author>
    <links href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/emaoconnor/witnesses-say-police-shot-critically-injured-charlotte-prote?utm_term=.bq7EaNBP6V#.jd0R7MgyoD">
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>1065</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JoyAnnReid/status/779373392122306560">
        <end>1306</end>
        <start>1257</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/7492/">
        <end>1502</end>
        <start>1399</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>To cap off a week in which police officers shot and killed two unarmed black men, a Georgia police officer has been arrested after it was discovered that she had fabricated a story about being shot by black man. Jackson Officer Sherry Hall has been charged with “false statements, tampering, interference with government property and a violation of oath of office.” “After following leads and evidence, the investigation has now revealed that there is no, and never was, a suspect shooter at large in Jackson, Georgia” announced special agent Joe Wooten, who was investigating the “case.” Hall reported that on September 13th, a black man had shot her in her bulletproof vest, but it was discovered that the entire thing – radio call, tear in shirt, spent shell – was all a set-up. The story is a stark reminder that the word of the police cannot always be taken at face value. When a protester was shot in the head during the Charlotte riots, the police immediately announced it was a civilian-on-civilian shooting, but multiple eyewitness reports say that it was a rubber bullet fired by riot police. A picture emerged of recently slain disabled black man Keith Lamont Scott showing a gun on the ground – but the video released by his grieving wife shows no gun but instead shows a cop dropping his glove. A police officer in St. Louis, Missouri, was recently charged with a homicide after it was discovered he had shot and killed a black man and then planted a gun on his body to justify his murder. In an increasingly post-truth political atmosphere, we must demand and receive evidence. We cannot rely on the word of anybody – our politicians or police officers.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>365</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>781</end>
        <start>366</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1502</end>
        <start>782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1667</end>
        <start>1503</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Occupy Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>364</end>
        <start>263</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>517</end>
        <start>367</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>587</end>
        <start>582</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>JUST IN: Georgia Cop Arrested After Shooting Herself And Blaming “Black Man”</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/24/just-georgia-cop-arrested-shooting-blaming-black-man/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
