<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Ryan Denson</author>
    <links href="http://www.mcclatchydc.com/news/politics-government/election/article103597232.ece/BINARY/The%20full%20McClatchy-Marist%20poll">
        <end>96</end>
        <start>64</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/election/2012/results/race/president/">
        <end>281</end>
        <start>261</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/ELECTION/2008/results/polls.main/">
        <end>324</end>
        <start>312</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3794607/Trump-Ivana-s-divorce-papers-claim-cruel-inhuman-portions-court-documents-missing-pulled-without-judge-s-order.html">
        <end>1679</end>
        <start>1632</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It’s no wonder Trump is losing — and losing badly — with women. A new poll from McClatchy-Marist shows Clinton leading Trump by 24 points among registered female voters (58 percent to 34 percent), and 23 points among likely female voters. Remember, Mitt Romney lost the female vote by 11 points, and John McCain by 13 points. While the Trump campaign and his supporters scratch their heads as to why he’s performing so poorly with the demographic that makes up the majority of the country, the Clinton campaign is reminding them why. A new (and brutal) ad has just been released from the Clinton camp. Asking voters if Trump is “the president we want for our daughters?” the ad, titled Mirrors, uses the Donald’s deplorable, sexist, offensive and objectifying words against women From, “I’d look her right in that ugly face of hers,” to “A person who’s flat-chested is very hard for them to be a 10,” showcases women all across the country looking at themselves — their bodies, appearance — at their phones, wondering if they are worthy, as Trump’s disgusting words echo off the screen. When talking about Kim Kardashian, Trump thought it would be a good idea to talk about her famous asset: “Does she have a good body? No. Does she have a fat ass? Absolutely.” So presidential. The most damning part comes at the end, when Howard Stern asks Trump, “So you treat women with respect?” Trump’s answer? “No, I can’t say that either.” This ad is so powerful. Trump, who is well known to be a serial misogynist, sexist, and all around pig, should be ashamed of the way he regards women, their appearances, and livelihoods. No wonder his first wife cited ‘cruel and inhumane’ treatment as the grounds for their divorce, and called him a “chauvinist” on TV. Little girls, and indeed little boys, are watching. Their parents have a choice: do we elect a man who has a proven track record of demeaning women he doesn’t even know, or do we elect a woman who wants to tap everyone’s potential, no matter who they are or what they look like. Watch the powerful ad that showcases just how much of a pig Donald Trump is:  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>325</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>533</end>
        <start>326</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>779</end>
        <start>534</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1086</end>
        <start>780</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1261</end>
        <start>1087</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1383</end>
        <start>1279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1399</end>
        <start>1384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1430</end>
        <start>1400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1750</end>
        <start>1431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2029</end>
        <start>1751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2106</end>
        <start>2030</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2107</end>
        <start>2107</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2108</end>
        <start>2108</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>669</end>
        <start>629</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>832</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>899</end>
        <start>838</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1260</end>
        <start>1193</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1382</end>
        <start>1350</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1429</end>
        <start>1401</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1742</end>
        <start>1732</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton Ad SLAMS Trump For His Disgusting Insults Towards Women And Their Bodies</title>
    <uri>http://author.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/23/clinton-ad-slams-trump-for-his-disgusting-insults-towards-women-and-their-bodies/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
