<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>By Christina Manduley, CNN</author>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/profiles/chris-moody">
        <end>613</end>
        <start>602</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/profiles/vanessa-yurkevich">
        <end>635</end>
        <start>618</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>(CNN)CNN announced Monday a nationwide tour of key swing states, presidential debate sites and destinations around the country on the #MyVote camper and projection tour, in partnership with Instagram, Facebook and CA Technologies. #MyVote launched steps from the White House at the Newseum in Washington, where the camper displayed the first in a series of campaign trail photos taken by the Instagram community via an immersive, one-of-a-kind virtual projection experience. The public can see these images at each debate stop and more locations to be announced as the tour unfolds. CNN correspondents Chris Moody and Vanessa Yurkevich will travel with the #MyVote camper, report from the ground and talk to citizens to capture the faces and voices of the people. They aim to go beyond the polls and the noise to grasp the real pulse of America. At the tour stops, members of the community are invited to enter the #MyVote camper and take a photo with either a red, blue or purple background filter. They can then share that photo on Instagram, using the #MyVote hashtag. CNN will be gathering the data collected on the tour and folding it into the election coverage. The #MyVote camper will serve as CNN's Facebook Live HQ and the social media hub on the road trip and at each presidential debate location stop in New York, Missouri, Virginia and Nevada. </mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>230</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>582</end>
        <start>231</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>845</end>
        <start>583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1167</end>
        <start>846</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1355</end>
        <start>1168</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1356</end>
        <start>1356</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>CNN</portal>
    <title>Introducing #MyVote: A nationwide social tour to Election Day</title>
    <uri>http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/20/politics/my-vote-road-trip-to-election-day/index.html?sr=fbpol092016ivanka-trump-female-republican-roundtable0928PMStoryLink&amp;linkId=29008986</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
