<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/donald-trumps-business-plan-left-a-trail-of-unpaid-bills-1465504454">
        <end>610</end>
        <start>603</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton on Monday called on Donald Trump to apologize to people who have worked on the real estate mogul's properties who have not been paid in full. Do "the thousands of people that you have stiffed over the course of your business not deserve some kind of apology from someone who has taken their labor, taken the goods that they've produced and then refused to pay them?" Clinton said at the first debate of the general election. "I can only say that I'm certainly relieved that my late father never did business with you." Story Continued Below Over the course of the campaign, reports have emerged about Trump refusing to pay what some vendors said he owed them. "I have met a lot of the people who were stiffed by you and your businesses, Donald," Clinton said, adding that there was an architect in the audience who wasn't fully paid by Trump for designing a clubhouse at a Trump golf course. "It's a beautiful facility. It immediately was put to use. And you wouldn't pay what the man needed to be paid what he was charging you." "Maybe he didn't do a good job and I was unsatisfied with his work," Trump responded. Trump went on to suggest that he had only taken that route four times, and that he was within his legal rights to do so. "My obligation right now is to do well for myself, my family, my employees, for my companies," he said. "And that's what I do. But what she doesn't say is the tens of thousands of people that are unbelievably happy and they love me."</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>157</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>534</end>
        <start>158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>556</end>
        <start>535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>675</end>
        <start>557</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1045</end>
        <start>676</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1131</end>
        <start>1046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1252</end>
        <start>1132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1486</end>
        <start>1253</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Clinton to Trump: Apologize to workers you stiffed</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-trump-apologize-workers-228724?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
