<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>The Senate will vote on Wednesday to override President Barack Obama’s veto of legislation that would allow the families of the victims of the Sept. 11, 2001 attacks to sue the government of Saudi Arabia, Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) said Monday. The House is likely to vote on the override Thursday or Friday, a Republican leadership aide said. Story Continued Below Congress is expected to easily clinch the two-thirds support needed to override Obama’s veto, which would be the first veto override of his presidency. The legislation, known formally as the Justice Against Sponsors of Terrorism Act, sailed through Congress with no recorded objections earlier this year. But with a veto override apparently imminent, some lawmakers, particularly ones who specialize in national security policy, have become increasingly vocal about their concerns with the bill. Both the chairman and the top Democrat on the House Armed Services Committee — Republican Mac Thornberry of Texas and Democrat Adam Smith of Washington — are circulating letters urging lawmakers to oppose JASTA. They warn that the legislation could open up U.S. officials abroad to retaliation.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>264</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>363</end>
        <start>265</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>385</end>
        <start>364</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>537</end>
        <start>386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>881</end>
        <start>538</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1176</end>
        <start>882</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Senate to vote Wednesday on override of Saudi 9/11 bill</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/senate-to-vote-wednesday-on-override-of-saudi-9-11-bill-228684?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
