<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Baron</author>
    <links href="https://damdems.wordpress.com/2014/05/17/true-story-gen-stanley-mcchrystal-told-obama-i-wouldnt-piss-on-your-grave/">
        <end>289</end>
        <start>269</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>This is a true story.  General Stanley McChrystal was the Commander of US Forces in Afghanistan and he had frequent disagreements on the conduct of the war with his Commander-in-Chief. At one point McChrystal was called into the Oval Office and he knew his Army career was about to be over. When former U.S. Military Commander in Afghanistan, Stanley McChrystal, was called into the Oval Office by Barack Obama, he knew things weren’t going to go well when the President accused him of not supporting him in his political role as President. “It’s not my job to support you as a politician, Mr. President, it’s my job to support you as Commander-in-Chief,” McChrystal replied, and he handed Obama his resignation.  Barack Obama has a long history of hating the US military and men and women who serve.  He is never one to let someone have the last word but he failed in this instance. Not satisfied with accepting McChrystal’s resignation the President made a cheap parting shot. “I bet when I die you’ll be happy to pee on my grave.” The General saluted. “Mr. President, I always told myself after leaving the Army I’d never stand in line again. Good job General McChrystal.  I’m pretty sure that after five or six years of being in the ground the line will have diminished enough so that you won’t have to stand in line.  You’re an honorable man, we know you wouldn’t cut in front of others.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>184</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>290</end>
        <start>185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>540</end>
        <start>291</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>712</end>
        <start>541</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>713</end>
        <start>713</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>883</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1033</end>
        <start>884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1145</end>
        <start>1034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1392</end>
        <start>1146</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>654</end>
        <start>542</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1032</end>
        <start>980</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>712</end>
        <start>291</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1145</end>
        <start>884</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama: “I bet when I die you’ll be happy to pee on my grave.”</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/01/30/obama-i-bet-when-i-die-youll-be-happy-to-pee-on-my-grave/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
