<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>The Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee now plans to spend at least $5 million in Indiana, a media-tracking source confirmed Tuesday, as Democrat Evan Bayh’s once-dominant lead over Republican Todd Young has narrowed rapidly in the race considered a key part of Democrats’ strategy to take the Senate majority. The Senate Democrats’ campaign arm initially planned to spend $2.5 million supporting Bayh in Indiana as part of their broader strategy to bolster spending in traditionally conservative-leaning states such as North Carolina. But the DSCC has since doubled their ad reservations in Indiana. Story Continued Below “We expanded the map this year into states like Indiana where we can pick up an open Republican-held seat and further put the GOP on defense as they struggle to keep their hold on their majority,” a Democratic official said. Meanwhile, Senate Majority PAC — the super PAC dedicated to electing Democrats to the Senate — is adding an additional $1 million to their initial spending, bring its total ad reservation to $1.7 million in Indiana, a spokesman said. Bayh, who announced in July that he would make a last-minute comeback bid, has led in the limited public polling so far. But Bayh began his run with internal polling that showed him leading Young by more than 20 points. The most recent poll in the race, conducted by WTHR/Howey Politics earlier this month, shows Bayh with a four-point lead over Young.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>315</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>605</end>
        <start>316</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>627</end>
        <start>606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>852</end>
        <start>628</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1086</end>
        <start>853</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1439</end>
        <start>1087</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>823</end>
        <start>629</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Senate Dems add another $2.5 million in Bayh's Indiana race</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/evan-bayh-indiana-young-senate-228816?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
