<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/092216-NASCAR-Herbert-Ames.vresize.1200.675.high_.27.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RIP?src=hash">
        <end>1622</end>
        <start>1618</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JimmieJohnson/status/778966792391778304">
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/BobMargolis">
        <end>1741</end>
        <start>1729</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JimmieJohnson/status/778967979732111364">
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/BobMargolis">
        <end>1741</end>
        <start>1729</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/DanielHemric/status/778942312810438656">
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/jfcassidy/status/778931516487372801">
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As if this week was not tragic enough, we get hit with this news. It seems as if every member of NASCAR is beloved in some form or fashion. There are just some really fine people involved within this sport, and there has been for years and years. A cool thing about NASCAR is that it’s not just the drivers that are well known and loved. It’s their crew chiefs or family members. It’s executives, hardcore fans and amazing reporters. Everyone has an amazing role to play in the sport of NASCAR. Sadly, two of those beloved members have passed away. Bob Margolis and Herbert Ames. Two of some of the finest men in all of NASCAR.  Herbert was more of a beloved friend of NASCAR. He was involved in many things that gave on the behalf of the sport, and he was long time friends with almost everybody in NASCAR. Tom Jensen, reporter for Fox Sports, expressed Herbert’s personality in a great way: “If you walked up to him and asked what he did in the sport, he’d bellow loudly and say, ‘Whatever the hell I want to do!'” Margolis was known for being a first-rate writer and reporter for NASCAR. He was different than everybody else because he gave younger writers a chance to really show what they got in the complicated world of NASCAR. He always told it exactly how it was and was loved for that. It’s clear that Bob captured the hearts of many more than he probably ever knew. Both of these are already extremely missed by many in the NASCAR community, as they are mourning their losses. I played a little golf with Jim Hunter and Herbert Ames… I can only imagine the heckling taking place between those two right now. #RIP — Jimmie Johnson (@JimmieJohnson) September 22, 2016  My thoughts are also with the family and friends of @BobMargolis. — Jimmie Johnson (@JimmieJohnson) September 22, 2016  To hear we lost @BobMargolis this morning is hard to fathom…I'll cherish the time &amp; conversations we shared over the past couple of years. — Daniel Hemric (@DanielHemric) September 22, 2016  I listened intently to what Bob Margolis had to say. He understood the complexities of the sport &amp; hit them head-on. Prayers to his family. — Jim Cassidy (@jfcassidy) September 22, 2016  It’s always horrible to lose great people, but we know they’re in a much better place than here! Our thoughts and prayers are with both of these men’s friends and families as they navigate what to do in the coming days. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>65</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>246</end>
        <start>66</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>494</end>
        <start>247</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>627</end>
        <start>495</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>628</end>
        <start>628</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>892</end>
        <start>629</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1016</end>
        <start>893</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1375</end>
        <start>1017</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1486</end>
        <start>1376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1622</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1676</end>
        <start>1676</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1742</end>
        <start>1677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1743</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1796</end>
        <start>1796</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1935</end>
        <start>1797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1986</end>
        <start>1936</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1987</end>
        <start>1987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2127</end>
        <start>1988</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2173</end>
        <start>2128</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2174</end>
        <start>2174</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2395</end>
        <start>2175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1015</end>
        <start>894</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1016</end>
        <start>893</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1677</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1986</end>
        <start>1797</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2173</end>
        <start>1988</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Two NASCAR Legends Just Died, You Will Truly Be Missed Bob And Herbert</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/sports/nascar/breaking-nascar-just-lost-two-legends/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=NASCAR+Legends%2F9%2F23&amp;utm_content=Right+Wing+News%2FNASCAR+Legends%2F9%2F23</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
