<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>James shale</author>
    <links href="http://thehill.com/blogs/ballot-box/191187-now-for-sale-art-by-george-w-bush">
        <end>84</end>
        <start>47</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Dear President Bush. I am interested in buying the artwork that you recently offered. You are multi-talented and an amazing man! I have been a faithful defender and supporter of you and your policies. However, your lack of support for the Republican Party and presidential nominee has left me confused and disappointed. Your silence in the face of republicans, including your father, supporting the opposition has made me question your judgment and integrity. Silence and passivity have historically allowed great tragedies to unfold. It would be a tragedy to elect a president who would continue to accelerate the destruction of principals that we hold dear. As stated, I would like to buy your artwork – but not if it symbolizes a world view that no longer supports conservative ideals. I would like to be able to continue to support and defend the Bush family. I cannot do so until it is clear where your support and loyalty stand. Please make clear to the American people that your will honor your legacy by opposing the radical left and supporting conservative values. The decline of America has been precipitous and needs to be stopped. I look forward to your reply. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>128</end>
        <start>21</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>200</end>
        <start>129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>659</end>
        <start>201</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1073</end>
        <start>660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1142</end>
        <start>1074</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1172</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1173</end>
        <start>1173</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>IPatriot</portal>
    <title>A Letter to President Bush</title>
    <uri>http://ipatriot.com/letter-president-bush/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
