<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/09/2016-donald-trump-fact-check-week-214287">
        <end>4069</end>
        <start>4039</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>HEMPSTEAD, N.Y. — Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump are counting down the hours to their first debate, a heavily hyped and critical encounter that comes as a fresh batch of polls show the race narrowing to a virtual dead heat. The showdown is expected to be a study in contrasts: Clinton, the longtime politician and consummate preparer who has pored over briefing materials in recent weeks, versus Trump, a first-time political candidate who, if aides are to be believed, has eschewed many elements of traditional debate preparation ahead of what could be the most watched political event in U.S history. Story Continued Below The two candidates arrive at Hofstra University in an increasingly taut race, as Clinton’s once-comfortable lead in August has evaporated into a knife’s edge contest well within the margin of error in the most crucial swing states. “A wheel-to-wheel race,” Trump’s running mate, Indiana Gov. Mike Pence, called it in a radio interview with Hugh Hewitt earlier on Monday. Trump and Clinton face two fundamentally different questions headed into Monday night. For Trump: Can the celebrity candidate best known only a few short years ago as the star of “The Apprentice” demonstrate the gravitas necessary for voters to envision him in the Oval Office? For Clinton: Can a woman who has been in the public spotlight for more than two decades — as first lady, senator and secretary of state — ease the electorate’s lingering questions about her trustworthiness? “This debate will have a huge impact,” predicted Judd Gregg, a Republican who played Al Gore and John Kerry in President George W. Bush’s mock debate preparations. Because Trump and Clinton enter the debate with historically high unfavorability ratings, Gregg said, “I think the person who wins this debate is the candidate who is able to increase their likeability and, at the same time, is able to have Americans see them as a leader who will take the country in a positive direction.” TV networks are expecting record audiences with countdown clocks ticking down the hours and minutes in recent days. Clinton’s campaign has prepared for two different Trumps to show up at Hofstra, her aides have said. The first is the insult-throwing bombastic showman who rampaged through Republican primaries. The second is the more controlled and sober candidate who has appeared on the campaign trail of late, someone who might even make a magnanimous gesture toward Clinton on the debate stage. Trump has stayed more disciplined with the help of teleprompters at his rallies and by not subjecting himself to tough questioning in recent weeks, bypassing formal press conferences for 60 days and, for the most part, avoiding extensive interviews with outlets other than Fox News. Neither of those are options on Monday night. But Mari Maseng Will, a longtime GOP debate coach, said Trump has been so outlandish on the campaign trail for the past 15 months that the typical bar for what counts as misbehaving on the debate stage is unusually high for him. “A sigh wouldn’t do it,” she said, referring to Gore’s now-infamous exasperation with Bush in the 2000 debates. “The only thing he could do to turn away people… would be mean,” she said. “That’s a killer in American politics, even for him.” Trump successfully navigated 11 Republican primary debates, but he never had to face one of his opponents one-on-one. Indeed, the smallest crowd he competed against was three other candidates, meaning he will have to fill nearly double the amount of time he ever has before on Monday. That could prove a challenge for a candidate who has mastered the quick sound bite and quip but lacks the depth of knowledge on policy that Clinton has. The debate will last for 90 minutes with no bathroom or commercial breaks. In the hours leading up to the debate, the Clinton and Trump camps sparred less about each other and more about the role of moderator Lester Holt, an NBC anchor. Clinton backers urged Holt to fact-check Trump, whose misrepresentations on the campaign trail have far outnumbered Clinton’s. “We are concerned that Donald Trump may lie, he may throw misinformation out there, and that Hillary will have to spend all of her time trying to correct the record rather than talking about the things she wants to accomplish,” Clinton campaign manager Robby Mook said on CBS on Monday Kellyanne Conway, Trump’s campaign manager, complained about Clinton’s “very public and very coordinated attempt to game the refs.” But such pre-game spin and expectations-management end at 9 p.m. eastern. Then the bright lights will shine on Clinton and Trump alone.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>225</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>604</end>
        <start>226</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>626</end>
        <start>605</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>627</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>997</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1482</end>
        <start>998</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1646</end>
        <start>1483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1970</end>
        <start>1647</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2086</end>
        <start>1971</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2469</end>
        <start>2087</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2798</end>
        <start>2470</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3139</end>
        <start>2799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3268</end>
        <start>3140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3553</end>
        <start>3269</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3781</end>
        <start>3554</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4070</end>
        <start>3782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4356</end>
        <start>4071</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4488</end>
        <start>4357</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4624</end>
        <start>4489</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>882</end>
        <start>860</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1192</end>
        <start>1178</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1520</end>
        <start>1484</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1969</end>
        <start>1750</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3051</end>
        <start>3029</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3203</end>
        <start>3141</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3267</end>
        <start>3216</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4297</end>
        <start>4072</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4487</end>
        <start>4429</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton and Trump ready for debate showdown</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-trump-debate-228688?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
