<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan chalked up Donald Trump’s proposal to ban Muslims from entering the U.S. to simple political posturing and said that such a plan would not be “remotely possible.” Speaking through a translator in an interview with MSNBC, Erdoğan was asked if Trump’s campaign rhetoric would prompt him to advise Turkish citizens, most of whom are Muslim, not to visit the U.S. if the Manhattan billionaire wins the White House. He responded by saying he thinks such a ban would never actually come to fruition. Story Continued Below “Well, I don't think that this is remotely possible because politics is a marathon and it's a long process,” he said. “Many things can be said throughout the rallies before elections and things will turn out to be very different post-elections. No political figure, no politician in this world is confined to their own local grounds.” Trump has backed away from that Muslim ban, first introduced during the Republican primary, in favor of a ban on all immigration from nations compromised by terrorism. In some speeches and interviews, he has said he would ban immigration from all nations where sufficient vetting cannot occur. Erdoğan was also asked which candidate, Trump or Democrat Hillary Clinton, would be have the better relationship with Turkey if elected, a question he refused to answer. “Well, you are entrapping me. I'm not going to fall into that trap,” Erdoğan said. “The best thing for me is to see the will of the people being served in the United States, the choice of the American people will be the right choice. I believe democracy more than anything else.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>201</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>532</end>
        <start>202</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>554</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>889</end>
        <start>555</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1183</end>
        <start>890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1353</end>
        <start>1184</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1633</end>
        <start>1354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>200</end>
        <start>182</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>662</end>
        <start>556</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>888</end>
        <start>674</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1421</end>
        <start>1355</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1438</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Turkish President Erdoğan: Trump’s Muslim ban isn’t possible</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-muslim-ban-turkey-president-erdogan-228565?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
