<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>shelby andrews</author>
    <links href="http://downtrend.com/71superb/black-lives-matter-co-founder-calls-for-cop-free-black-communities">
        <end>111</end>
        <start>77</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.complex.com/life/2016/09/black-lives-matter-alicia-garza-charlotte">
        <end>938</end>
        <start>931</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Alicia Garza, co-founder of BlackLivesMatter, has demanded that there should black communities without any cops. This ignorant statement of hers is turning heads throughout the whole country, but not for the reasons she wants.  In the wake of the latest spate of black men forcing cops to shoot them, one of the founders of the Black Lives Matter movement says it’s time for the police to leave the black community. The idea apparently is that black neighborhoods, full of the worst criminals this country has to offer, would be safer without the protection of the police department. Alicia Garza co-founded Black Lives Matter on the lie of Trayvon Martin’s death and it came to national prominence on the lie of Michael Brown’s death. With a foundation built entirely out of bullshit, it’s no surprise that everything that comes out of the mouth of one of their founding mothers is completely asinine. Garza did an interview with Complexand it was one for the ages. In regards to the recent police shootings of black men in Tulsa, OK and Charlotte, NC, Garza hasn’t seen the videos, which support the police officers, but somehow she knows the cops were wrong. “I’ve chosen not to[watch the videos]. I think we know what it looks like when somebody is murdered, said Garza. Yeah, screw the facts. She doesn’t want them getting in the way of her preconceived notions and general hatred of law enforcement. Then there is this about the Charlotte riots, which erupted after a black cop shot and killed an armed black man: “The thing that people get so concerned about is how do we stop the violence in Charlotte, but yet we’re not thinking about the fact that there’s been violence in Charlotte since way before whatever is happening there has happened. The brother who was killed is a form of state violence. He was killed and the police will not release the video. The police are not taking accountability for the violence that they enact in our communities and yet there isn’t as much outrage about that as there is about some broken windows and lost property,” she said. A black protester shot and killed another random protester. Mobs of blacks have beaten the shit out of innocent white people because of the color of their skin. This is more than broken windows and lost property and it’s based on yet another lie. “How do we stop violence, looting, and riots? The way that we stop that is by making sure that people have the things that they need to thrive. When people are systematically denied their right to adequate housing, adequate schools, to adequate food, to dignity—this is a response and a reaction that we should absolutely expect,” Garza said. What a lot of people do to get adequate housing, schools, food, and dignity is work, you know, like at a job where they earn money to buy necessities. It works a lot better than looting for those things or hoping the government will give them to you. And finally Garza says the black community would be better off without any police at all: “Ultimately, policing in and of itself is problematic. I know that in this country we give a lot of veneration to police. In the ethos of this country, police can do no wrong. And if and when police do wrong, it’s a case of individual bad apples, as opposed to a corroded and corrupt system… Quite frankly, many of our [Black Lives Matter] members are continuing to investigate what it would mean to have police-free communities. I think what we’ve continued to see over time is that no moral appeal is actually stopping the deaths of black people, whether they be armed or unarmed,” said Garza. Interesting theory. She’s saying that cops kill blacks so getting them out of black neighborhoods will mean no blacks will ever be killed. This ignores the fact that almost all black people are killed by other blacks and that by removing cops from the equation there will be even more black killers running loose in the black community. But hey, good luck with that. Do these people realize what a cop free community would look like? It’s not all happy and bliss as they think it would be. It would make matters SO much worse. I can’t stress this enough; WE NEED POLICE. enchanted Sep 26, 2016 at 4:34 pm I will bet ten dollars she wouldn’t live in a cop free zone.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>226</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>227</end>
        <start>227</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>583</end>
        <start>228</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>966</end>
        <start>584</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1274</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1405</end>
        <start>1275</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1519</end>
        <start>1406</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2072</end>
        <start>1520</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2319</end>
        <start>2073</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2662</end>
        <start>2320</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2913</end>
        <start>2663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3003</end>
        <start>2914</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3599</end>
        <start>3004</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3966</end>
        <start>3600</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4170</end>
        <start>3967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4180</end>
        <start>4171</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4204</end>
        <start>4181</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4265</end>
        <start>4205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2061</end>
        <start>1163</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2649</end>
        <start>2321</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3586</end>
        <start>3005</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3966</end>
        <start>228</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BlackLivesMatter Co-Founder DEMANDS Cop Free Black Communities…</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/09/24/blacklivesmatter-co-founder-demands-cop-free-black-communities/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
