<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/muslims-deal-with-lgbt">
        <end>701</end>
        <start>648</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Liberals are constantly talking about how Islam is the religion of peace and tolerance. The reality is far more disturbing. Liberals also like to whine about how intolerant people are in regards to LGBT rights, yet they completely ignore where the real intolerance and oppression towards gay people lies. The Islamization of Europe is proving just how wrong liberals are on both counts. European liberals welcomed thousands upon thousands of Muslim refugees into their countries, and the results have been near catastrophic. Sharia law has been creeping across Europe, and for people who are hated by Islam, that’s truly worrying. A sad example is a despicable attack on a gay man in Brighton, England. On Sunday, Aaron Woods was walking down the street with his friend, Brian Markintosh. According to Markintosh, they were approached by a man who started screaming homophobic slurs at Woods. But it only got worse — the man then started physically attacking Woods, punching him in the face. Markintosh said the attacker “was shouting all this Muslim stuff … Aaron was in so much pain. He was really screaming.” He continued, “He’s such a gentle giant. He’s the kindest person you could imagine — this geezer broke his jaw with a knuckleduster. He was filming the young gay guys.”  This wasn’t the first attack on gay people, either. Earlier this month, a similar attack took place, when a gay couple was attacked by two men. Is it merely a coincidence that the increase of Muslims in Europe has since an increase in homophobic attacks? The truth is that since the Muslim migrants have entered Europe, there has been a huge increase in crime. From attacks on gay people to sexual assault, Europe is in a bad spot right now. The homophobic attacks are easily explained: sharia law teaches that homosexuality is a sin punishable by death. ISIS, for example, is known to kill gay people in brutal ways, such as throwing them from the tops of buildings. It’s no surprise that an increase in Muslims would make Europe more dangerous for gay Europeans. The question is, will any liberals be honest enough to admit it? Or will they continue to deny the obvious and put people’s lives at risk? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>386</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>702</end>
        <start>387</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>703</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1281</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1536</end>
        <start>1282</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2046</end>
        <start>1537</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2185</end>
        <start>2047</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2186</end>
        <start>2186</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1110</end>
        <start>1022</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1279</end>
        <start>1127</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Homosexual Thinks Muslims Will Accept Him, Instantly Learns How They Deal With LGBT</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/homosexual-thinks-muslims-will-accept-instantly-learns-deal-lgbt/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
