<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Jeff Dunetz</author>
    <links href="http://www.washingtonexaminer.com/woodward-20-wapo-reporters-dig-dirt-on-trump-every-phase-of-his-life/article/2591021">
        <end>269</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/trumps-hitlerian-disregard-for-the-truth/2016/09/19/1603877e-7e8e-11e6-8d13-d7c704ef9fd9_story.html?utm_term=.00cc09fe2765">
        <end>617</end>
        <start>604</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2016/09/13/dont-compare-donald-trump-to-adolf-hitler-it-belittles-hitler/?utm_term=.5e99aa40a6b9">
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>1119</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://lidblog.com/september-is-trump-is-hitler-month-at-the-washington-post/">
        <end>1258</end>
        <start>1202</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Like much of the mainstream media, the Washington Post is going out of its way to disparage Donald Trump. But the Post isn’t satisfied with the normal biased reporting—they have gone above and beyond assigning 20 reporters just to dig up dirt on the Republican nominee. That must have failed because now they are taking the lazy, but disgusting way out with inappropriate Hitler references. Twice in this month Post columnists have compared Donald Trump to Adolf Hitler. Perhaps the editors have designated September as “Trump Is Hitler Month” at the Washington Post. On Monday they featured a column by Richard Cohen which said in part, (…) while Trump is neither an anti-Semite nor does he have designs on neighboring countries, he is Hitlerian in his thinking. He thinks the truth is what he says it is. Mr. Cohen didn’t mention what despot Hillary’s lies reminded him of, but then again the post would never have a “Hillary is Hitler month.” While a Hillary comparison would be just as wrong, the fact that they are only creating a “Trump” month is incredibly sexist. Six Day’s before Mr. Cohen, another columnist  Shalom Auslander wrote, “Don’t compare Donald Trump to Adolf Hitler. It belittles… Read the rest of the story at Jeff Dunetz’s blog The Lid  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>567</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>637</end>
        <start>568</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>806</end>
        <start>638</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>807</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1201</end>
        <start>1072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1258</end>
        <start>1202</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1259</end>
        <start>1259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1405</end>
        <start>1260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1479</end>
        <start>1406</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>542</end>
        <start>521</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>944</end>
        <start>920</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>104</end>
        <start>99</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>806</end>
        <start>638</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1441</end>
        <start>1429</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>It’s “Trump is HITLER” Month at the Washington Post</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36955/its-trump-is-hitler-month-at-the-washington-post/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
