<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Greg Campbell</author>
    <links href="http://www.theblaze.com/stories/2016/09/22/students-forced-to-change-american-bbq-themed-campus-event-after-school-says-name-is-offensive/">
        <end>761</end>
        <start>693</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>One does not have to bleed red, white and blue in order to live in this country. However, whenever I encounter anti-American vitriol that masquerades as “enlightened” political correctness, I always wonder, “If you hate what this country stands for, then why do you live here?” That’s the question that should be posed to those who have forced students to change a school event’s “American theme” because it is supposedly offensive.   Students at Ramapo College in Mahwah, New Jersey, were planning on putting on a themed barbecue event for fellow students and faculty. The theme was “America.” As students made preparations for the event, however, they were informed by staff that they would have to change the event as the patriotic theme was too “offensive.” The staffer who issued the edict, Bischoff Hall Assistant Residence Director Ariana Rivera, claimed that, among other things, the use of Uncle Sam on flyers was too “military and recruitment-oriented.” Because college students looking for a good pulled pork sandwich might instead join the Army? Doubtful… Rivera claimed that the order came from the administration. When asked who was issuing the order, she replied, “To be honest, I’m not sure. I think it was administrative. I was told that our advertising was too ‘military and recruitment-oriented,’ because we had the Uncle Sam saying ‘I want you.’ I think? However, we saw other posters with that same idea, so I really don’t know.” The event went forward with a watered-down theme and around 300 students were in attendance. College officials remained elusive and cagey about the reasoning behind the demands and claimed that the issue was a “miscommunication.” Still, students tasked with putting on the event have vowed to move forward with finding answers for why there was an issue in the first place. In either case, what seems the most troubling is not just that there seems to be a pervasive element in academia that despises patriotism, but that people have become so comfortable with redundant bureaucracy that orders are passed-on mindlessly without ever discovering who is issuing such ridiculous orders and why. “Because we said so” is the mantra of all bureaucratic tyrants. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>277</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>432</end>
        <start>278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>433</end>
        <start>433</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>434</end>
        <start>434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>594</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>761</end>
        <start>595</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>963</end>
        <start>762</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>964</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1450</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1680</end>
        <start>1451</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1824</end>
        <start>1681</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2142</end>
        <start>1825</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2206</end>
        <start>2143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2207</end>
        <start>2207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>165</end>
        <start>154</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>276</end>
        <start>208</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>395</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>593</end>
        <start>585</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>432</end>
        <start>422</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>962</end>
        <start>928</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1449</end>
        <start>1180</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1679</end>
        <start>1662</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2162</end>
        <start>2144</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Students Fight Back After Being FORCED To Change BBQ ‘American Theme’ – Because It’s Offensive…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/students-fight-back-forced-change-bbq-american-theme-offensive/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
