<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://thehill.com/policy/national-security/297596-state-it-official-warned-clinton-inner-circle-about-internal">
        <end>1759</end>
        <start>1670</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The Hillary Clinton staff dismissed State Department IT technician concerns over private server. Cheryl Mills, Hillary’s Chief of Staff said that other Secretaries of State had done it. As you remember, that was their excuse; everybody did it. Then they went on to say that Colin Powell endorsed it. The liberal mantra: Blame anyone, but don’t take responsibility. Read more below.  As Written By Katie Bo Williams for The Hill: The State Department technician who set up Hillary Clinton’s private server told FBI officials that he conveyed internal concerns that the setup violated federal record-keeping rules to Clinton’s “inner circle,” according to investigation notes released Friday afternoon. Bryan Pagliano told investigators that in 2009, two State IT specialists asked him whether he was aware of the clintonemail.com domain, then asked him to relay to Clinton’s team that the server could be a federal records retention issue. Pagliano conveyed the message to Cheryl Mills, Clinton’s chief of staff during her tenure as secretary of State. He told investigators that Mills replied that other secretaries of State had also used private email accounts, citing Colin Powell. The details come from 189 pages of notes from the FBI’s interviews with State officials, Clinton aides, IT technicians who worked on the server and others, released late Friday afternoon. The pages contain a few previously-unknown tidbits — including the revelation that Clinton at one point had a Gmail account, used so an unnamed aide could send her articles of interest to read. But the aide said he was “fairly sure” that the account was never used after it was …. Full Story Here: State IT official warned Clinton ‘inner circle’ about concerns with email setup | TheHill</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>381</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>382</end>
        <start>382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>428</end>
        <start>383</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>700</end>
        <start>429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>701</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1183</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1371</end>
        <start>1184</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1565</end>
        <start>1372</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1652</end>
        <start>1566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1669</end>
        <start>1653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1759</end>
        <start>1670</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>639</end>
        <start>626</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1603</end>
        <start>1592</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1759</end>
        <start>1653</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>State IT Official Warned Clinton ‘Inner Circle’ </title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/state-it-official-warned-clinton-inner-circle/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
