<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/08/donald-trump-isis-oil-226925">
        <end>3963</end>
        <start>3941</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2016/jun/22/donald-trump/trump-still-wrong-his-claim-opposed-iraq-war-ahead/">
        <end>4248</end>
        <start>4233</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump said Hillary Clinton has spent her “entire adult life” fighting the Islamic State and will never be able to defeat the terrorist group. Clinton retorted that Trump "has no plan" to fight the radical group, and put him on the defensive over his past support for the Iraq War. Story Continued Below The foreign policy section of Monday's debate touched on Russia, Iran, and nuclear weapons—but no subject animated the candidates like their exchanges about the terrorist militia's rise and which candidate is better-equipped to crush it. Repeating a pattern throughout the debate, Trump made his case with bold, and questionable, claims, while Clinton defended her position with less memorable but more factual assertions. With polls showing high voter anxiety over terrorism, Trump took the first shot on the subject early in the debate, with a charge that Clinton's web site had posted details of her war plan. "You're telling the enemy everything you want to do," Trump said. "No wonder you've been fighting ISIS your entire adult life." That was a head-scratching claim, given that Clinton is 68 and the Syria-based group, also known as ISIS, has only existed in its current form since 2014. (A predecessor group was founded in 2004.) But Clinton ignored Trump's puzzling assertion. "At least I have a plan to fight ISIS," she quipped. Clinton later added that while Trump has claimed he has a "secret plan" to fight ISIS, "the only secret is that he has no plan." Clinton took more seriously his charge—supported by many national security experts—that the 2011 U.S. troop withdrawal from Iraq had enabled ISIS's creation. "They wouldn't even have been formed if you left some troops behind, like 10,000, or maybe something more than that," Trump said. President Barack Obama oversaw the exit of U.S. troops, which he celebrated at the time. Clinton was then serving as Obama's Secretary of State. But she countered that it was the George W. Bush administration which failed to reach an agreement with Iraq's government that would have allowed U.S. forces to remain in the country on terms acceptable to Washington. "George W. Bush made the agreement about when American troops would leave Iraq, not Barack Obama," Clinton said. "And the only way that American troops could have stayed in Iraq was to get an agreement from the Iraqi government that would have protected our troops—and the Iraqi government would not give that." Experts have debated that point for years, with some claiming that Obama never really wanted such an agreement and didn't try as hard as he could have to secure one. Yet some some former Obama officials—including the U.S. ambassador to Iraq at the time of the withdrawal, James Jeffrey— say that Clinton argued internally for maintaining a troop presence in the country beyond 2011. ISIS evolved from the group al Qaeda in Iraq (AQI), founded in the wake of the 2003 U.S. invasion of that country. The group was nearly wiped out by the U.S. military but regained strength after the American withdrawal, and as it joined the fight in Syria's civil war. In 2014, AQI cut ties to al Qaeda and renamed itself the Islamic State in Iraq and the Levant, and is often called the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria, or ISIS. There is almost no expert support for Trump's longtime insistence, which he repeated Monday, that the U.S. should have seized Iraq's oil fields as a form of war booty, and that doing so would have allowed the U.S. to prevent ISIS's rise. "Had we taken the oil—and we should have taken the oil—ISIS would not have been able to form either, because the oil was their primary source of income," Trump said. Trump has argued for years that the U.S. should commandeer Iraq's oil, though he has not addressed basic questions like how many troops it would take and how the oil would be transported from a country sure to be hostile to the seizure of its most valuable commodity. Nor did Trump ever describe the plan in the past as a way to prevent militants from flourishing, even as many national security experts were doing so. Clinton, who cast a Senate vote to authorize the U.S. invasion of Iraq in 2002, sought to turn Trump's talk of Iraq history back against him by citing his well documented comments in favor of the U.S. invasion before it happened. "Donald supported the invasion of Iraq," she said. "I did not support the war in Iraq. That is a mainstream media nonsense put out by her," Trump said. Trump proceeded to claim he had "numerous conversations" with Fox News host Sean Hannity, in which he opposed the war, but of which there is no public record. The debate's moderator, Lester Holt, endorsed Clinton's version of events. "The record shows otherwise," he told an irritated Trump. As he often has before, Trump again cited an August 2004 interview with Esquire as evidence of his opposition to the war. "They did an article in a major magazine, shortly after the war started, I think in ‘04, but they did an article which had me totally against the war in Iraq," Trump said. But by that time, more than a thousand American troops had died in Iraq, photos documenting the Abu Ghraib prison abuse scandal had emerged, and public support for the occupation was falling fast. Clinton reiterated her pledge to "intensify" airstrikes against ISIS, enlist technology companies to track down on the group's Internet activities, and support Arab and Kurdish fighters on the ground in Iraq and Syria—largely steps the Obama administration is already taking. Clinton did not repeat her past talk of establishing a "no-fly zone" in northern Syria. Clinton also raised the subject of Russia, pressing her campaign's recent charge that Trump is suspiciously respectful of Russian president Vladimir Putin and that he holds Kremlin-friendly views of NATO and Ukraine. "There's no doubt now that Russia has used cyber attacks against all kinds of organizations in our country, and I am deeply concerned about this. I know Donald is very praiseworthy of Vladimir Putin. But Putin is playing a very tough, long game here," Clinton said. Defying the strong consensus view of U.S. intelligence officials, Trump cast doubt on Russia's alleged role in the recent hack and exposure of Democratic National Committee emails. "I don't think anybody knows it was Russia who broke into the DNC. She's saying Russia, Russia, Russia. Maybe it was. I mean, it could be Russia, but It could also be China, but it could also be lots of other people," Trump said. "It also could be someone sitting on their bed that weighs 400 pounds, OK?"</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>148</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>287</end>
        <start>149</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>309</end>
        <start>288</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>547</end>
        <start>310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>732</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>922</end>
        <start>733</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1050</end>
        <start>923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1478</end>
        <start>1051</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1766</end>
        <start>1479</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2129</end>
        <start>1767</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2441</end>
        <start>2130</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2824</end>
        <start>2442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3254</end>
        <start>2825</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3492</end>
        <start>3255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3658</end>
        <start>3493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4077</end>
        <start>3659</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4358</end>
        <start>4078</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4618</end>
        <start>4359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4751</end>
        <start>4619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5242</end>
        <start>4752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5606</end>
        <start>5243</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5823</end>
        <start>5607</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6089</end>
        <start>5824</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6270</end>
        <start>6090</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6576</end>
        <start>6271</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>49</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump presses Clinton on growth of ISIS</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/donald-trump-hillary-clinton-isis-228749?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
