<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://freebeacon.com/author/chandler-gill/">
        <end>250</end>
        <start>237</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freebeacon.com/politics/benenson-trouble-explaining-mills-immunity/">
        <end>1167</end>
        <start>1107</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>When asked to explain the unexplainable, the Clinton strategist, Joel Benson, could not do it. Chris Wallace at FOX tried to get the reason for Cheryl Mills asking for immunity in FBI investigation. Se the non-response in the video. BY: Chandler Gill for Washington Free Beacon: The chief strategist for Hillary Clinton’s campaign, Joel Benenson, could not clearly explain Sunday why Clinton’s former chief of staff, Cheryl Mills, asked the FBI for limited immunity if she did nothing wrong. “Let’s turn to another issue,” Fox News’ Chris Wallace said. “We learned on Friday that as part of the FBI investigation into Hillary Clinton’s private email system that Cheryl Mills, her chief of staff when Clinton was secretary of state, that she was one of the people, five people, who received limited immunity. How do you explain that, Joel?”  Benenson first said that limited immunity is “fairly routine.” “It’s fairly appropriate and routine when people are sitting down with them, turning over a wealth of materials that have nothing to do with the investigation at hand,” Benenson said……. Full Story Here: Benenson Has Trouble Explaining Why Mills Asked for Immunity</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>232</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>278</end>
        <start>233</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>491</end>
        <start>279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>839</end>
        <start>492</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>840</end>
        <start>840</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>903</end>
        <start>841</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1089</end>
        <start>904</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1106</end>
        <start>1090</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1167</end>
        <start>1107</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>521</end>
        <start>493</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>838</end>
        <start>554</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>902</end>
        <start>887</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>905</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1167</end>
        <start>1090</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary Clinton Strategist Could Not Explain THIS? [Video]</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/hillary-clinton-strategist-could-not-explain-this-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
