<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/exclusive-george-hw-bush-to-vote-for-hillary-228395?cmpid=sf">
        <end>363</end>
        <start>357</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.ifyouonlynews.com/politics/laura-bush-drops-atom-bomb-on-election-hints-she-might-vote-hillary-clinton/">
        <end>1373</end>
        <start>1358</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/04/08/laura-bush-hints-shed-rather-see-hillary-as-president-than-repub/">
        <end>1735</end>
        <start>1731</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The 2016 election is shaping up to be the weirdest (and nightmarish) election in decades. Up is down, night is day, and stupid is smart. Once Donald Trump became the nominee of a major party for the presidency, all existing and established norms went up in smoke. And the crazy is just getting started, so make sure you’ve got your passport handy. Politico writes that Former President George H.W. Bush is completely snubbing Donald Trump and plans to vote for Hillary Clinton in November. This revelation came from Kathleen Hartington Kennedy Townsend, the former Maryland lieutenant governor and daughter of the late Robert F. Kennedy. Kennedy announced the news on Facebook yesterday when she posted a picture  shaking hands next to Bush Sr with this caption: “The President told me he’s voting for Hillary!!” This is actually not very shocking when you consider how much the Bushes have shown their contempt for Trump, after ruining their chances of continuing their political dynasty with low-energy Jeb. Neither George Bush Sr. or George W. Bush showed up at the Republican National Convention in Cleveland, and Jeb Bush has constantly let it be known that he has absolutely no intentions of voting for Trump. So perhaps this can be viewed as more of a repudiation of Trump than a glowing endorsement of Hillary. Former First Lady Laura Bush dropped a major bombshell in April of this year when she essentially indicated that she was supporting Hillary. Here’s what Laura Bush about the presidential race: “I want our next president – whoever he or she might be – to be somebody who is interested in women in Afghanistan and who will continue US policies… that we continue to do what we’re committed to do as a country,” she said, as she appeared on stage alongside her twin daughters Jenna and Barbara. “That’s who I want – or the kind of people that will do that and will pay attention to our history, and know what’s what’s happened before and know specifically how we can continue to do the good things that we do around the world.” Say what you will about George W. Bush–and there’s plenty–but his father was mostly a man of principle who put the country above petty politics. This is yet another reminder of how fractured the Republican Party has become. Featured image via Getty   Republicans thought this would be a cake walk. Boy were they wrong.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>348</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1319</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1512</end>
        <start>1320</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2043</end>
        <start>1513</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2267</end>
        <start>2044</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2293</end>
        <start>2268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2294</end>
        <start>2294</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2362</end>
        <start>2295</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>If You Only News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>764</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1725</end>
        <start>1513</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2041</end>
        <start>1811</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2042</end>
        <start>1512</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>George Bush Sr. Delivers Ultimate Taunt To Trump By Saying He Will Vote For Hillary</title>
    <uri>http://www.ifyouonlynews.com/politics/george-bush-sr-delivers-ultimate-taunt-to-trump-by-saying-he-will-vote-for-hillary/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
