<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <mainText>So here is a moral question, are you responsible for telling your partner you have an STD or is it only if they ask? Or is your partner responsible for keeping themselves clean? Apparently Jim Carrey’s ex-girlfriend committed suicide after contracting a sexually transmitted disease and/or infection from him. Carrey found out that he is being sued for her wrongful death by her estranged husband.   According to the reports, he’s being sued for illegally acquiring pain killers that were found in her body and were eventually ruled to be her cause of death. He denied the claims that he gave her three STDs, Herpes 1&amp;2 and Gonnorhea. Now, a handwritten letter has been made public that details the torture that Cathriona White faced after she contracted the diseases. Say: ‘I gave you this, intentional or not, I gave it to you. I understand that this is something that will affect you for the rest of your life and future relationships. What can make this right?’ Instead of that, I was disrespected, degraded, called a whore, an opportunist, threatened, our relationship belittled. …and I don’t really think you can see. Like it’s not an issue to you. I’m just an ungrateful bitch who you’ve done so much for and I took advantage. That simply is not true. Picking myself back up emotionally and mentally is one thing, people have bad experience and break-ups, it’s hard but with time they move on, meet someone new, start over. Add in disease. How does someone move on and meet someone new? …I am damaged. I am disgusting. When I shower I feel sick. Getting turned on…what’s that? Certainly not something that happens (to) me any more. I will always be damaged goods and have a stigma attached. So I have to accept something I was always afraid of. Being alone. Being abandoned and alone.” The closing of her letter is perhaps the most heartbreaking part of the whole thing, and honestly, it made me cry. “Be good to yourself. I will always have love in my heart for you. I pray that you are content and have peace in your life and in your soul.” It takes a big person to wish well the very person who is the reason she is so miserable that she took her own life. Whose side are you on, team Carrey or team White? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>177</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>397</end>
        <start>178</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>398</end>
        <start>398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>399</end>
        <start>399</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>558</end>
        <start>400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>768</end>
        <start>559</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>965</end>
        <start>769</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1084</end>
        <start>966</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1258</end>
        <start>1085</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1493</end>
        <start>1259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1792</end>
        <start>1494</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1907</end>
        <start>1793</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2049</end>
        <start>1908</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2166</end>
        <start>2050</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2216</end>
        <start>2167</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2217</end>
        <start>2217</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2048</end>
        <start>1909</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1792</end>
        <start>769</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2049</end>
        <start>1908</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Letter from Jim Carrey’s Girlfriend Who Killed Herself Reveals Torment Over Contracting STDs from Him</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/letter-jim-carrey-girlfriend-killed-reveals-torment-contracting-stds/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
