<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tim Brown</author>
    <links href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/more-800-immigrants-mistakenly-granted-citizenship-130452164--politics.html">
        <end>387</end>
        <start>380</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>According to Homeland Security’s Inspector General, at least 858 immigrants from foreign countries that pose national security risks, as well as those from countries with high immigration fraud who had orders to have them deported were “mistakenly” granted citizenship. An internal Homeland Security audit was released Monday, which documented the “mistake.” The Associated Press reports: The report does not identify any of the immigrants by name, but Inspector General John Roth’s auditors said they were all from “special interest countries” — those that present a national security concern for the United States — or neighboring countries with high rates of immigration fraud. The report did not identify those countries. DHS said the findings reflect what has long been a problem for immigration officials — old paper-based records containing fingerprint information that can’t be searched electronically. DHS says immigration officials are in the process of uploading these files and that officials will review “every file” identified as a case of possible fraud. The gap was created because older, paper records were never added to fingerprint databases created by both the now-defunct Immigration and Naturalization Service and the FBI in the 1990s. ICE, the DHS agency responsible for finding and deporting immigrants living in the country illegally, didn’t consistently add digital fingerprint records of immigrants whom agents encountered until 2010. And this is what happens when government puts its nose in things like healthcare and other unconstitutional things it usurps its authority to meddle in. If the central government had been focused only on the things it is authorized to deal with, this matter would more than likely never have occurred. Not only that, but you can rest assured that no one will be held accountable in the matter. While DHS is blaming paper issues and fingerprints, there were some of those who were awarded citizenship that were set to be deported. While Chairman of the House Homeland Security Committee Michael McCaul called on ICE to have all immigration fingerprints digitized, but the threat to national security is great since citizens can apply and obtain security clearances or take jobs which are security sensitive. According to Roth, at least three of these new citizens acquired aviation or transportation worker credentials, granting them access to secure areas in airports or maritime facilities and vessels. He went on to state that their credentials were revoked once it was discovered that they had been given citizenship mistakenly. He also said that another individual had been given the role of a law enforcement officer. While changes were recommended and DHS agreed with them and said they would work to implement them, this problem has been going on for years. According to the AP report, “The government has known about the information gap and its impact on naturalization decisions since at least 2008 when a Customs and Border Protection official identified 206 immigrants who used a different name or other biographical information to gain citizenship or other immigration benefits, though few cases have been investigated.” What has really been done about it? Nothing. Are we really to expect something new?  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>269</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>358</end>
        <start>270</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>388</end>
        <start>359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>725</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1069</end>
        <start>726</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1461</end>
        <start>1070</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1991</end>
        <start>1856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2268</end>
        <start>1992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2593</end>
        <start>2269</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2684</end>
        <start>2594</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2826</end>
        <start>2685</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3194</end>
        <start>2827</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3278</end>
        <start>3195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3279</end>
        <start>3279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3425</end>
        <start>3280</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3499</end>
        <start>3426</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>247</end>
        <start>237</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>357</end>
        <start>349</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>543</end>
        <start>517</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1028</end>
        <start>1018</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3193</end>
        <start>2856</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1716</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3461</end>
        <start>3449</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>858 Immigrants Granted Citizenship…by “Mistake”</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36890/858-immigrants-granted-citizenship-by-mistake/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
