<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/big-government/2016/09/23/obama-responds-charlotte-overwhelming-majority-protesters-right/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Barack.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Barack1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>What a racist asshat this president is. He just came out and spoke on the Charlotte riots and it was exactly what I expected… lame and in support of violent radicals. He says the majority of people protesting are doing it the right way, if you can believe it. Is the right way killing fellow protesters? Is the right way looting and burning? Is the right way killing police officers across the nation? What a reprehensible statement and by the way, the exact opposite of what he said over the Baltimore riots. You don’t see these people doing the ‘wrong thing’ every once in a while. It’s rampant and getting increasingly worse, which is exactly what Obama wants. He’s now pandering to the Black Lives Matter, New Black Panthers, Nation of Islam devotees for Hillary Clinton. If he seems to condone their barbaric actions, he might win their votes… or so his twisted logic goes.  From Breitbart: President Barack Obama dismissed the recent violence and destruction in Charlotte, North Carolina by rioters reacting to the shooting of an armed African-American man by an African-American police officer. “The overwhelming majority of people who have been concerned about police-community relations [are] doing it the right way,” Obama said. “Every once in a while you see folks doing it the wrong way. Looting, breaking glass, those things are not going to advance the cause.” Obama made his comments during an interview with Good Morning America’s Robin Roberts at the brand new Smithsonian National Museum of African American History and Culture. He argued that Americans should recognize that there was a real problem in the justice system that the protestors in Charlotte were reacting to. “I think it’s important to separate out the pervasive sense of frustration among a lot of African Americans about shootings of people and the sense that justice is not always color blind,” he said. Obama didn’t condemn the violence or the murder at all. He didn’t support the police either. Big shocker there. He’s an absolute disgrace to the black community. He always has been. We were well on our way to being a colorblind society until Obama started dividing us. He’s a stone cold racist. It was a black cop who shot a black man there in North Carolina, but Obama managed to make it all about race in the end. Typical. He paid weak homage to being peaceful… but that is not what he means and he knows that is not what has and will happen in the streets of America. I guess the difference in North Carolina was that the area wasn’t ‘black’ enough and by wording things the way Obama did, he greenlighted further violence by Black Lives Matter and other radicals. But hey… vote for Hillary!  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>509</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>878</end>
        <start>510</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>879</end>
        <start>879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>895</end>
        <start>880</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>896</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1374</end>
        <start>1102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1546</end>
        <start>1375</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1691</end>
        <start>1547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1889</end>
        <start>1692</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2071</end>
        <start>1890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2460</end>
        <start>2072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2684</end>
        <start>2461</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2685</end>
        <start>2685</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2686</end>
        <start>2686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1225</end>
        <start>1103</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1373</end>
        <start>1240</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1879</end>
        <start>1693</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1889</end>
        <start>896</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>President Obama FINALLY Speaks On Charlotte RIOTS – “…Protesters Doing It The Right Way.”</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/barack-obama/president-obama-finally-speaks-charlotte-riots-protesters-right-way/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
