<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://bearingarms.com/bob-o/2016/09/19/hillary-clinton-wants-put-man-stopped-mall-terror-attack-business/">
        <end>14</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bearingarms.com/bob-o/2016/09/19/man-shot-crossroads-mall-terrorist-uspsa-competitor-3-gun-shooter/">
        <end>1059</end>
        <start>1048</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://tacticaladvantagemn.com/">
        <end>1272</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Jason Falconer, the NRA-certified firearms instructor and off-duty police officer, who shot the ISIS terrorist who stabbed eight people in St. Cloud, Minnesota, is someone that Hillary Clinton wants to put out of business. In fact, it’s one of the primary things she intends to do first if she is elected president. This is a brave man who saved countless lives by taking out a Jihadist. The same kind of Islamic refugee that Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton just love to death. Falconer owns Tactical Advantage Firearms Training, Inc. which is one of those businesses that Clinton just despises… because it has to do with guns, training people how to safely use weapons and is a protector and promoter of our Second Amendment rights. This is one of the biggest reasons not to ever vote for Hillary Clinton… EVER. From Bearing Arms: We told you this morning how USPSA Shooter, 3-Gunner, and NRA-certified firearms instructor Jason Falconer shot and killed a 22-year-old Somali immigrant who went on a stabbing rampage inside a St. Cloud, (MN) Mall on Saturday, saving countless lives. What we didn’t tell you is that Hillary Clinton wants to bankrupt Falconer, driving him out of the business of saving lives. Falconer is the president and owner of Tactical Advantage, LLC and Tactical Advantage Firearms Training, Inc. His business interests all revolve around training law-abiding citizens to carry concealed firearms for self-defense to protect themselves and loved ones from criminal predators (and apparently terrorists). If elected President, Hillary Clinton will do everything in her power to see Jason Falconer driven out of business and into bankruptcy. Falconer’s Tactical Advantage, LCC, is a full-service training facility with a firing range, gun rentals, firearms training and gun sales to law-abiding citizens. It is American as apple pie and one that I love. The 2005 Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act (PLCAA) provides limited legal protection to businesses such as Falconer’s to protect them from frivolous lawsuits that would take them under. Clinton wants to do away with PLCAA, removing that protection and exposing the business to radical lawfare. Clinton repeatedly and falsely claims that PLCAA offers gunmakers and dealers “immunity.” It’s an outrageous falsehood and is vintage Clinton. She hates the Second Amendment and will do all she can to quash and eliminate it. She is the single biggest threat to our right to bear arms we have ever faced as a nation. Jason Falconer has spent his entire life protecting his fellow citizens, first as a law enforcement officer and then when concealed carry became legal in Minnesota, he took the initiative to create a firearms training company and then a range and retail shop in order to provide the best possible self-defense training to others that he could. Hillary Clinton wants to take that away and destroy all of it. The fact that he took down an Islamic extremist probably makes her hate him all the more. Just say no to Hillary Clinton, so heroes like Falconer are celebrated, not punished.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>315</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>316</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>832</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1084</end>
        <start>833</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1209</end>
        <start>1085</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1319</end>
        <start>1210</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1526</end>
        <start>1320</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1527</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1874</end>
        <start>1663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2176</end>
        <start>1875</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2492</end>
        <start>2177</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3075</end>
        <start>2493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3076</end>
        <start>3076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3077</end>
        <start>3077</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2265</end>
        <start>2256</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1214</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>DESPICABLE! Hillary Wants To Put Hero Cop Who Stopped Mall Terror Attack Out Of BUSINESS</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/despicable-hillary-wants-put-hero-cop-stopped-mall-terror-attack-business/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
