<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>By Eric Bradner, CNN</author>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/poll-clinton-trump-in-virtual-dead-heat-on-eve-of-first-debate/2016/09/24/b99c95de-81cb-11e6-8327-f141a7beb626_story.html?wpisrc=al_alert-COMBO-politics%252Bnation">
        <end>150</end>
        <start>115</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.mcall.com/news/local/elections/mc-pa-trump-clinton-debate-poll-20160924-story.html">
        <end>1009</end>
        <start>955</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>(CNN)Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump are virtually tied headed into their first presidential debate Monday night, a new ABC News/Washington Post poll shows. The survey shows likely voters split 46% for Clinton and 44% for Trump -- with 5% supporting Libertarian Gary Johnson and 1% backing the Green Party's Jill Stein. That's well within the poll's 4.5 percentage point margin of error. Among a broader group -- registered voters -- Clinton and Trump are tied at 41%, with Johnson at 7% and Stein at 2%. The results show the race has tightened in recent weeks. In the same poll, Clinton led by 5 points in early September and by 8 points in early August. A new CNN Poll of Polls incorporating the results of the new Post-ABC Poll finds the margin in an average of the five most recent polls holding at a three-point edge for Clinton, 43% back her, 40% Trump in that calculation. There's been a similar tightening in the key swing state of Pennsylvania, a new Allentown Morning Call/Muhlenberg College survey shows. That poll, released Sunday, has Clinton at 40% to Trump's 38%, with Johnson at 8% and Stein at 3%. That's a drop for Clinton, who led by 8 points in the same poll a week earlier. The ABC News/Washington Post poll also underscored that the 9 p.m. ET Monday debate at Hofstra University in New York will be a crucial moment in the campaign for both candidates. Eight in 10 voters said they plan to watch the debate -- with expectations slightly higher for Clinton, with 44% saying they expect her to win the debate while 34% expect Trump to win. Jennifer Agiesta contributed to this report.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>157</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>388</end>
        <start>158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>505</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>656</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>880</end>
        <start>657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1195</end>
        <start>881</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1560</end>
        <start>1196</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1605</end>
        <start>1561</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>CNN</portal>
    <title>Poll: Clinton, Trump virtually tied headed into debate</title>
    <uri>http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/25/politics/clinton-trump-virtually-tied-poll-debate/index.html?sr=fbpol092616clinton-trump-virtually-tied-poll-debate0834AMStoryLink&amp;linkId=29187801</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
