<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Mockarena COTR</author>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3802941/Disney-pulls-controversial-costume-new-Polynesian-princess-film-Moana-stores-apologizes-brownface-outfit.html">
        <end>27</end>
        <start>20</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-22-20-51-24.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/people-are-upset-that-the-polynesian-demigod-in-disneys-moana-looks-obese/">
        <end>606</end>
        <start>595</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-22-20-54-57.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I’m so disappointed by this. We mentioned this on our show earlier this week, but the Perpetually Offended Brigade set their sights on Disney’s Maui Halloween Costume, calling it “brownface” and disrespectful to Polynesian cultures, and cultural appropriation, and probably a bunch of other stupid things that only perpetually offended losers get bent out of shape about. Here’s the Maui character from the upcoming Disney film Moana.  Perhaps you remember the outrage from a couple months ago, when people decided they were also angry that the Maui character is fat.  If you missed that story, here you go.  In that post, we are reminded that Maui is a demi-god character in an ANIMATED FICTIONAL DISNEY MOVIE.  And yet, people are still mad. But the outrage went even further, because now people are mad about the Maui Halloween costume.  Here’s what it looks like:  Infuriating, huh.  I mean, how DARE they create a costume that so closely resembles the character? Someone correct me if I’m wrong, but isn’t the point of dressing up as a character for Halloween to look AS MUCH LIKE THAT CHARACTER as possible?  And if in fact, that IS the point, then WTF is all the fuss about?  The costume is made to look like the character.  WHICH IS FICTIONAL. That’s it.  End of story. But squeaky wheels apparently get the grease in our culture now, so Disney has pulled the costume, which I think is patently ridiculous.  They will no longer sell it.  Their statement said: “The team behind ‘Moana’ has taken great care to respect the cultures of the Pacific Islands that inspired the film, and we regret that the Maui costume has offended some. We sincerely apologize and are pulling the costume from our website and stores.” Translation:  We have no backbone.  Or testicles.  Or common sense. Please add this to the ever-growing list of things that progressives insist on being total killjoys about. Way to let the SJW morons win, Disney. Gawd.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>28</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>371</end>
        <start>29</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>434</end>
        <start>372</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>435</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>743</end>
        <start>436</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>867</end>
        <start>744</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>868</end>
        <start>868</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>967</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1277</end>
        <start>968</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1467</end>
        <start>1278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1720</end>
        <start>1468</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1788</end>
        <start>1721</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1895</end>
        <start>1789</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1934</end>
        <start>1896</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1940</end>
        <start>1935</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Chicks On The Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>189</end>
        <start>180</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1719</end>
        <start>1469</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1720</end>
        <start>1468</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>OMG DISNEY CAVED, You Guys. They Caved.</title>
    <uri>http://www.chicksontheright.com/omg-disney-caved-you-guys-they-caved/?utm_source=RWN&amp;utm_medium=RWN&amp;utm_campaign=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
