<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-20-at-8.28.17-AM.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-20-at-8.30.02-AM.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>We’ve never seen anything like this before in the sport of NASCAR… There are many people that don’t believe in things that NASCAR does. But those are mostly things like penalties and rules on the track. It’s not often that we say anyone complain about how the sport treats and includes people, simply because everyone for the most part thinks NASCAR does a pretty swell job. But it looks like there’s ONE person who disagrees. That one person is Terrance Cox III, a Georgia man who has operated Diversity Motorsports Racing as well created a group to protest against NASCAR, alleging that officials, teams and owners are unjust towards the minority community.  This past Friday, Cox filed a $500 million race discrimination lawsuit against NASCAR and its race teams due to claims that the sanctioning body of NASCAR would never help him as he tried to make NASCAR more racially diverse. In Cox’s complaint, he stated that “potential sponsors were encouraged by NASCAR to not work with him but instead go for drivers like Tony Stewart and Dale Jr.” They also allegedly refused to promote different programs that Cox created in order to make NASCAR more diverse.  Lastly, Cox is claiming that NASCAR has “engaged in unlawful intentional racial discrimination by refusing to sanction African-American owned racing teams … and by refusing to hire African-American drivers for its racing teams.” Has NASCAR responded to this? HELL YEAH! They’ve released a statement defending their Drive for Diversity program and have let Cox and everyone know that they are going to fight this lawsuit. “NASCAR embraces all individuals interested and involved in our sport, whether as partners, fans, competitors or employees, and there is no merit to this lawsuit. NASCAR has a long-standing history of investing in diversity efforts including the NASCAR Drive for Diversity, NASCAR Diversity Internship and NASCAR Diversity Pit Crew Development programs. … We stand behind our actions, and will not let a publicity-seeking legal action deter us from our mission. NASCAR not only will defend our organization against these meritless allegations, but we will be asserting our own claims against Mr. Cox for his defamatory actions. We established these [diversity] programs to create opportunities for women and minorities, and embrace people of all backgrounds, within the industry. Diversity both on and off the track continues to be a top priority for NASCAR and its stakeholders.“ There is one full-time African-American driver in NASCAR and his name is Darrell Wallace Jr. Wallace races for Roush Fenway Racing and competes in the Xfinity Series. We will give further detail as the case unfolds. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>202</end>
        <start>67</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>426</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>659</end>
        <start>427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>660</end>
        <start>660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>886</end>
        <start>661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1160</end>
        <start>887</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>1161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1390</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1582</end>
        <start>1391</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2463</end>
        <start>1583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2630</end>
        <start>2464</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2680</end>
        <start>2631</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1046</end>
        <start>923</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1389</end>
        <start>1203</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2463</end>
        <start>1583</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: NASCAR Sued For $500 Million, This Could Be The End</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/sports/nascar/breaking-nascar-sued-for-500-million-this-could-be-the-end/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=NASCAR+Sued%2F9%2F21&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2FNASCAR+Sued%2F9%2F21</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
