<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Protests erupted overnight Tuesday into Wednesday in Charlotte, North Carolina, after a police officer shot and killed an African-American man while looking for another person who had an outstanding warrant. According to local reports, police officers saw Keith Lamont Scott getting out of his car while holding a gun. The Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Department said Scott posed an imminent danger to officers, and Officer Brentley Vinson, who is also African-American, shot the man. Story Continued Below "As is standard procedure with any officer involved shooting, Officer Vinson has been placed on paid Administrative Leave," the police department said in a statement Tuesday night. Protesters gathered near the scene of the shooting, an area near the campus of the University of North Carolina at Charlotte. Footage from the protests showed people shouting “Black lives matter,” “Hands up, don’t shoot” and “No justice, no peace.” A reporter with a local NBC affiliate posted a video of a journalist injured by a rock hurled in her direction, as the police department deployed its civil emergency unit. At 10:46 p.m., the department’s official Twitter account said that an officer “sustained injuries in an attempt to deescalate agitators during demonstration.” Approximately 12 officers were injured during the protests, according to a later tweet from the department early Wednesday morning. The latest incident comes on the heels of another police-involved shooting in Tulsa, Oklahoma, last Friday that claimed the life of Terence Crutcher, an unarmed 40-year-old man.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>207</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>484</end>
        <start>208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>506</end>
        <start>485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>687</end>
        <start>507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1267</end>
        <start>688</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1399</end>
        <start>1268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1577</end>
        <start>1400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>883</end>
        <start>864</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>907</end>
        <start>886</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>935</end>
        <start>914</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1266</end>
        <start>1188</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>12 police officers injured during North Carolina protests</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/north-carolina-protests-keith-lamont-scott-228450?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
