<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>S. White</author>
    <links href="http://thefederalistpapers.org/us/womans-crusade-against-neighbors-pro-trump-signs-lands-her-in-hot-water">
        <end>30</end>
        <start>20</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>What the hell did I just watch? Words are really failing me right now… None of what I want to say is going to make any sense to you until you watch this video yourself…so here you go. WARNING: Video might make you want to punch your screen. Don’t.  Two words popped up in my head while I was watching this video… Retarded chihuahua. I don’t even mean that as an insult. Purely descriptive wording… Boy those Liberals LOVE their First Amendment right don’t they? This woman went on and on about hers… The problem is…they love it until they disagree with what you’re saying/supporting. Then you’re a racist, misogynist, bigot, homophobe, or plug in whatever “phobe” you want here. I’m embarrassed that she’s a woman, that does not reflect any good on us at all. In fact, she is everything WRONG with America. She calls the guy a big redneck, doesn’t like what she sees on his lawn then proceeds to FLIP him off. Then makes herself the victim? The woman needs to go slap herself. The REAL victim is Ben…poor poor Ben. The kid is doomed! Then of course our poor Police Officers…this is the garbage they are having to deal with EVERYDAY now. If I were the guy she flipped off, knowing now that she has to pass the house EVERYDAY… I would put out a sign that said… Sarah: 0 Redneck: 1 I’d pay to watch the video she’d put out after seeing that sign… I really hate social justice warriors, they give me a headache. Rude. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>31</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>70</end>
        <start>32</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>183</end>
        <start>71</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>240</end>
        <start>184</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>247</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>248</end>
        <start>248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>312</end>
        <start>249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>332</end>
        <start>313</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>397</end>
        <start>333</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>499</end>
        <start>398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>678</end>
        <start>500</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>806</end>
        <start>679</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>940</end>
        <start>807</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>976</end>
        <start>941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1014</end>
        <start>977</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1033</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1136</end>
        <start>1034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1258</end>
        <start>1137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1343</end>
        <start>1279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1407</end>
        <start>1344</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1408</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1414</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>634</end>
        <start>629</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>VIDEO: Woman’s Tantrum Over Neighbor’s Trump Yard Signs BACKFIRES In Her Face!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/womans-tantrum-trump-yard-signs/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
