<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>The “horrible” shooting death of an unarmed black man in Tulsa, Oklahoma, on Friday is “just unbearable and needs to be intolerable,” Hillary Clinton said Tuesday. Speaking to radio host Steve Harvey, Clinton anxiously contrasted herself and her opponent, Donald Trump. “Oh my gosh, can I have the whole hour?” Clinton said when asked what separates her from the Republican presidential nominee. “I think it really comes down to our visions and our values. You know, I have a vision where we continue to pursue equality and justice and opportunity for everybody.” Story Continued Below Clinton highlighted how she’s been a champion for minorities and women and touted her plans to raise incomes, create more good jobs, make colleges — including historically black colleges and universities — more affordable and address systemic racism before talking about the Tulsa shooting unprompted. “This horrible shooting — again. How many times do we have to see this in our country?” Clinton asked, referring to the incident in which Terence Crutcher, an unarmed black man, was shot dead by police despite having his hands up as he walked to his SUV with armed officers behind him. “In Tulsa? An unarmed man? With his hands in the air? I mean, this is just unbearable and it needs to be intolerable.” For her part, Clinton suggested that she could be part of the solution to reform policing practices and remove bias by appealing to white Americans. “You know, maybe I can, by speaking directly to white people, say, ‘Look, this is not who we are.’ We’ve got to do everything possible to improve policing, to go right at implicit bias,” Clinton said. “There are good, honorable, cool-headed police officers. We’ve seen them in action in New York over the last, you know, 48 hours because of the terrorist attack. We can do better. We have got to rein in what is absolutely inexplicable, and we’ve got to have law enforcement respect communities and communities respect law enforcement because they have to work together.” The former secretary of state also recalled meeting Marian Wright Edelman, who founded the Children’s Defense Fund, as a law school student. “That gave me the opportunity to really see what we need to do because I believe you’ve gotta change both laws and hearts,” Clinton said. “We’ve gotta change laws to protect people, to protect everything about them, and we’ve got to be a clear and loud voice for our society being what it should be: the city on the hill striving for the more perfect union,” she continued. “And that’s my view. And I don’t think that’s how my opponent sees it.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>163</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>563</end>
        <start>164</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>585</end>
        <start>564</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>887</end>
        <start>586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1292</end>
        <start>888</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1441</end>
        <start>1293</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2013</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2292</end>
        <start>2014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2600</end>
        <start>2293</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>13</end>
        <start>5</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>132</end>
        <start>88</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>309</end>
        <start>271</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>562</end>
        <start>397</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>974</end>
        <start>889</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1291</end>
        <start>1175</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1627</end>
        <start>1443</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2012</end>
        <start>1644</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2277</end>
        <start>2156</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2512</end>
        <start>2294</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2599</end>
        <start>2530</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton: Tulsa shooting by police should be 'intolerable’</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/terence-crutcher-tulsa-shooting-clinton-228411?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
