<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Cassy Fiano</author>
    <links href="http://thefederalist.com/2016/09/20/obama-un-giving-freedom-enhances-security/">
        <end>616</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Freedom is the bedrock that this nation was built upon. The problem is, liberals hate freedom. Oh, sure — they pay lip service to its importance, but ultimately, they want people to be subservient to a liberal-controlled government. They may not want a tyrannical king, but a tyrannical government of socialist-loving politicians pushing government-controlled everything is A-OK with them. They can’t ever say this out loud, though. Which makes the speech Obama just gave to the United Nations rather surprising. Obama actually admitted that he thinks it’s necessary for the United States to give up a little liberty… you know, for “safety”. Tuesday, Obama spoke to the United Nations General Assembly. “We can only realize the promise of this institution’s founding to replace the ravages of war with cooperation if powerful nations, like my own, accept constraints,” he said. “Sometimes I am criticized in my own country for professing a belief in international norms and multilateral institutions. But I am convinced in the long run, giving up some freedom of action, not giving up our ability to protect ourselves or pursue our core interests, but binding ourselves to the international rules over the long-term enhances our security.”   So evidently, Obama believes that we should relinquish more of our freedom and sovereignty so that the international community can rule over us. How this will make the country safer, he didn’t explain. But safety relies on us bringing more Muslim refugees into the United States. “Ultimately our world will be more secure if we are prepared to help those in need and the nations who are carrying the largest burden with respect to accommodating these refugees,” Obama said. Obama may want to take a look at how Germany is doing. Accepting tons of refugees without screening them first has certainly not made their country safer — it’s made it more dangerous. And right here in the United States, we have had multiple terrorist attacks over the last year.   How allowing over 110,000 Muslim refugees with no vetting whatsoever into our country will keep us safe is not something that Obama can actually explain, because it’s a completely ludicrous idea. And turning the United States into a country that has to answer to the United Nations before we act on anything doesn’t make us safer, either. It’s a typical liberal idea: something that is nonsensical and useless, yet will weaken the country and strip Americans of their constitutionally-protected rights. But hey, who needs freedom, right? Obama has an agenda to push. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>643</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1241</end>
        <start>644</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1242</end>
        <start>1242</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1243</end>
        <start>1243</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1717</end>
        <start>1244</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1998</end>
        <start>1718</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1999</end>
        <start>1999</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2000</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2567</end>
        <start>2001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2568</end>
        <start>2568</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>639</end>
        <start>633</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>867</end>
        <start>704</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1238</end>
        <start>879</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1702</end>
        <start>1523</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama To UN: ‘Giving Up Liberty, Enhances Security In America…’ [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/barack-obama/obama-un-giving-liberty-enhances-security-america/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
