<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Miss CJ</author>
    <links href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2016/sep/22/pauline-hanson-says-49-support-for-ban-on-muslim-immigration-is-too-low">
        <end>246</end>
        <start>228</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.news.com.au/national/western-australia/man-who-filmed-exchange-between-woman-and-hanson-supporter-banned-from-facebook/news-story/317430d4356e62fbce5607c9b4f822f3">
        <end>548</end>
        <start>530</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Dang… and I thought our Social Justice Zealots were insane (I mean, they are. But this is NUTS). In this video, a Muslim woman from Perth, Australia, is having an unholy fit when she sees someone wearing a Pauline Hanson shirt. If you don’t know, Pauline Hanson is a right-wing senator in Australia who has proposed a ban on Muslim immigration in her country. Oh, and this confrontation took place on a university campus, which doesn’t surprise me – Well, she’s got the special snowflake screeching down. I’ll give her that much. According to this, the man with the shirt said he was a former student coming to meet with someone on campus and he has every right to be there, even though the Muslim woman demanded he leave. Just because he was wearing a shirt. Listen lady – maybe that’s how they do things in Islamic countries where you aren’t even allowed to THINK anything that goes against Muslim beliefs, but in first-world civilizations, we welcome ALL KINDS of opinions. Well, that’s the theory, at least. Maybe not much longer if the Cult of Social Justice gets their way.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>96</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>359</end>
        <start>97</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>449</end>
        <start>360</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>529</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>759</end>
        <start>530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>976</end>
        <start>760</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1079</end>
        <start>977</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Chicks On The Right</portal>
    <title>Australian Muslim FREAKS OUT At Someone Wearing A Pauline Hanson T-Shirt</title>
    <uri>http://www.chicksontheright.com/australian-muslim-freaks-out-at-someone-wearing-a-pauline-hanson-t-shirt/?utm_source=RWN&amp;utm_medium=RWN&amp;utm_campaign=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
