<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/federal-agents-discovery/">
        <end>612</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/big-government/2015/11/18/report-8-syrians-caught-at-texas-border-in-laredo/">
        <end>827</end>
        <start>818</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A border wall isn’t just to keep out illegal immigrants – it acts as a national security measure. China didn’t build their great wall to keep out immigrants, they built it to keep out foreign invaders. We need a border for that reason too, in addition to solving the problem of illegal immigration. The entire nation of Mexico is essentially run by drug cartels, and they’ve racked up a death toll that would make ISIS envious. Additionally, if ISIS is going to enter America, our unsecured Southern Border is their best bet.  And for that reason, you can bet they already are trying… As the Conservative Tribune reported: Eight Syrian nationals attempted to illegally enter the United States from Mexico on Monday, raising new concerns about security inside the United States in the wake of the Paris terror attacks. Breitbart cited two unnamed federal agents who said the Syrians were intercepted at the Juarez Lincoln Bridge in Laredo, Texas. While Border Patrol has yet to confirm this report, National Border Patrol Council Local 2455 President Hector Garza did confirm that he was also receiving similar reports from multiple agents. “Border Patrol agents who we represent have been contacting our organization to voice concerns about reports from other agents that Syrians crossed the U.S. border from Mexico in the Laredo Sector,” he said. “Our agents have heard about Syrians being apprehended in the area from other federal agents. At this time, I cannot confirm or deny that Syrians have crossed, for security reasons.” It would be a lot easier to catch these terrorists if the Obama administration let border patrol do their jobs. Border Patrol Agent Hector Garza, acting in his role as president of the National Border Patrol Council, Local 2455 said on Fox News earlier this month that  “Eight out of ten people that are caught entering our country illegally are not deported and are allowed to stay in the United States,” Garza explained. “Unfortunately for Border Patrol agents, we are trying to do our jobs as best we can with the very limited resources that we have.” We need a border and stronger border security – and there’s only one Presidential candidate willing to help with both. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>201</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>525</end>
        <start>202</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>526</end>
        <start>526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>584</end>
        <start>527</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>622</end>
        <start>585</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>817</end>
        <start>623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1139</end>
        <start>818</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1530</end>
        <start>1140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1531</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2085</end>
        <start>1643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2204</end>
        <start>2086</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2205</end>
        <start>2205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1337</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1529</end>
        <start>1349</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1935</end>
        <start>1802</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2084</end>
        <start>1955</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1292</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Federal Agents Make Massive Discovery at Southern Border… ISIS Is Here</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/breaking-federal-agents-make-massive-discovery-southern-border-isis-2/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
