<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Mr. Wendal</author>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/2016-presidential-race/2016/09/20/hillary-clinton-vows-speak-directly-white-people-stop-racial-police-shootings/">
        <end>393</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Really? Hillary Clinton is now vowing to take on racism, and she’s starting with our Police Officers? This woman is an idiot. Words nearly fail me on this one…because it is just so ridiculous! The woman, is making all the wrong choices, and desperately trying to win votes. The so-called ‘racism’ issue does not begin with Police Officers or white people… The woman has gone certifiably … MAD. “We gotta tackle the systemic racism, this horrible shooting again, how many times do we have to see this in our country?” she said in an appearance on the Steve Harvey show. Clinton was specifically referring to the police shooting of Terence Crutcher in Tulsa, Oklahoma, saying he had his “hands in the air” when he was killed. “This is unbearable and it needs to be intolerable,” she said. Clinton told Harvey that if the African-American community came out and voted for her, she would work to stop racial shootings by police officers. “Maybe I can by speaking directly to white people say, ‘Look this is not who we are,’” she said. “We’ve got to do everything possible to improve policing, to go right at implicit bias. Actually Hillary…what we need to is to STOP putting divisive, selfish, wicked people into the White House as President…who creates problems so they can look like a hero when they say stupid crap like this. She wants this chaos, Obama wants this chaos. It’s breeding grounds for ‘stupid’ and they want the American people… stupid, so they can continue running the place however they please.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>192</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>355</end>
        <start>193</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>393</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>723</end>
        <start>394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>786</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>933</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>934</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1324</end>
        <start>1119</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1370</end>
        <start>1325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1508</end>
        <start>1371</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>515</end>
        <start>395</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>702</end>
        <start>686</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>775</end>
        <start>725</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1019</end>
        <start>935</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>394</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary VOWS To Put White People And Cops In Their Place To STOP Racial Police Shootings…</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/09/20/hillary-vows-to-put-white-people-and-cops-in-their-place-to-stop-racial-police-shootings/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
