<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Greg Campbell</author>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3796719/Cash-strapped-ISIS-trades-23-stolen-human-organs-northern-Iraq-oil-reserves-dry-up.html">
        <end>636</end>
        <start>608</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>President Obama routinely paints a rosy picture regarding the war on terror. He assures us that ISIS is decimated and that we have little to fear from the looming presence of radical Islam throughout the world.   He’s wrong. Not only are we engaged culturally in a very serious war with radical Islam, at best, our military efforts can only be described as hindrances to the advancement of the murderous elements of Islam. However, as weak as our response to ISIS has been, it is satisfying to see that our airstrikes are making life more difficult for the terrorist factions that require money to wage war. According to an Iraqi source, ISIS has begun harvesting the organs of their dead and dying in order to traffic the organs for cash as our airstrikes decimate their oil fields and rob them of the riches therein. “Special medical unit of the organization proceeded to steal human organs for about 23 ISIS militants of those who slept in the hospitals of Nineveh,” the Iraqi source said. “What has been stolen from those members included the kidneys, intestines and more; they were transferred under tight control to affiliated hospital on the outskirts of the city.” The source who wished to remain anonymous for obvious reasons, said that the move comes as a reaction to the decimation of oil fields. “This came after the loss of the majority of sources of financial funding, particularly with regard to crude oil, which it provides about 80% of the imports of the terrorist organization.” It is gratifying to see that ISIS must tighten their belts. However, what the world needs is a complete and thorough domination and destruction of radical Islam and so long as the Western world confuses idiocy with tolerance, it’s unlikely that we will see the leadership necessary to fix this problem. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>210</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>211</end>
        <start>211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>212</end>
        <start>212</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>422</end>
        <start>213</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>607</end>
        <start>423</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>818</end>
        <start>608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>992</end>
        <start>819</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1172</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1307</end>
        <start>1173</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1496</end>
        <start>1308</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1799</end>
        <start>1497</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1800</end>
        <start>1800</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>820</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1171</end>
        <start>994</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1495</end>
        <start>1309</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1172</end>
        <start>819</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1496</end>
        <start>1308</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>ISIS Is So Hard Up For Cash That It’s Harvesting Organs From Its OWN Dead And Injured Members</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/isis-hard-cash-harvesting-organs-dead-injured-members/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
