<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Elvin Bartley</author>
    <links href="http://bearingarms.com/bob-o/2016/09/20/terence-crutcher-shot-hands-heres-definitive-proof/?utm_content=buffer87acc&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=facebook.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">
        <end>1003</end>
        <start>991</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bearingarms.com/bob-o/2016/09/20/terence-crutcher-shot-hands-heres-definitive-proof/?utm_content=buffer87acc&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=facebook.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">
        <end>3420</end>
        <start>3405</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As cities are burned in wake of yet another “peaceful protest” involving uninformed public that don’t wait for the facts, it should come as no surprise to anyone that when the facts are released, a different story resents itself altogether. Terence Crutcher was a black man shot by police earlier this week. Immediately the media portrayed it as “unarmed black man shot by racist white cop.” However, when more details came out, it’s clear that the media did its best to bury the story and glom onto the newest “victim” of the media’s outrage machine. Here’s the truth of what happened, and it’s every Black Lives Matter supporter’s worst nightmare. Not only did Crutcher not have his hands raised, but it appears that the officer’s account of him reaching in the car was justified, as well as the bombshell that PCP was found in his car, with the jury out on if it was in his system. If it was, that lends credence to the officer’s story, making him incredibly hard to subdue. According to Bearing Arms, Numerous media organizations that should know better, from Sky News, to Reuters, to NPR, are claiming that white Tulsa (OK) Police Department officer Betty Shelby shot and killed Terence Crutcher standing in the road with his hands up. That is a demonstrable lie, as proven with simple screen captures from video footage from the police helicopter circling overhead.  In the photo above, Crutcher, wearing a white shirt and tan pants, can be seen walking away from Officer Betty Shelby. His hands are clearly raised… at this precise moment.  Unfortunately for all concerned, Crutcher does not obey lawful commands to freeze, and walks back to his vehicle.  As shown above, Crutcher walks to the driver’s side door, and his right hand is still clearly raised. His left hand is still up as well, but blends into the dark color of the windows.  As Mr. Crutcher squares up with the driver’s side door of his vehicle straddling the centerline of the road, his hands are still raised. But they don’t stay there.  As the helicopter continues in a counterclockwise turn, Mr. Crutcher clearly drops his hands to his side.  As we can see above, Mr. Crutcher’s right hand has dropped and is just in front of his waist. His left hand still appears to be up and positioned near the upper door frame or “A” pillar.  At the moment just before Mr. Crutcher simultaneously shot once by Officer Shelby (right) and tased by Officer Tyler Turnbough (left), Mr. Crutcher’s hand is clearly down near his waist near the right front pants pocket area. This is when both officers decided to discharge respective weapons.  The image above is just after Mr. Crutcher was simultaneously shot once in the chest and tased.  In the image directly above, Mr. Crutcher has just been shot, and the wound to his chest is just starting to bleed. throught the hole. Mr. Crutcher will begin bleeding much more profusely within fractions of a second, then roughly 2 seconds later, he will collapse to the ground. Here’s the video. Watch it for yourself. * * * Without passing any judgments one way or the other on whether Mr. Crutcher’s actions warranted the shot fired by Officer Shelby, one thing is 100% clear, and that is that Terence Crutcher’s hands were not raise when he was shot, but down by his side. The mainstream media is, universally and without question, lying to you about the circumstances of Terence Crutcher’s shooting. Read more here… </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>240</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>884</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>977</end>
        <start>885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1004</end>
        <start>978</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1240</end>
        <start>1005</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1371</end>
        <start>1241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1372</end>
        <start>1372</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1545</end>
        <start>1373</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1546</end>
        <start>1546</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1660</end>
        <start>1547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1661</end>
        <start>1661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1845</end>
        <start>1662</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1846</end>
        <start>1846</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1983</end>
        <start>1847</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2010</end>
        <start>1984</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2011</end>
        <start>2011</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2117</end>
        <start>2012</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2305</end>
        <start>2118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2306</end>
        <start>2306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2600</end>
        <start>2307</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2601</end>
        <start>2601</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2697</end>
        <start>2602</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2698</end>
        <start>2698</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2833</end>
        <start>2699</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2978</end>
        <start>2834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3019</end>
        <start>2979</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3025</end>
        <start>3020</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3276</end>
        <start>3026</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3404</end>
        <start>3277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3420</end>
        <start>3405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3421</end>
        <start>3421</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Yes Im Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>61</end>
        <start>45</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>390</end>
        <start>347</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>518</end>
        <start>512</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>No, Terence Crutcher Did Not Have His Hands Up When He Was Shot By Police</title>
    <uri>http://www.yesimright.com/no-terence-crutcher-did-not-have-his-hands-up-when-he-was-shot-by-police/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
