<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://detroit.cbslocal.com/2016/09/20/are-athlete-national-anthem-protests-costing-nfl-viewership/">
        <end>969</end>
        <start>958</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/brandonkatz/2016/09/12/tv-ratings-should-nfl-sweat-lower-ratings-for-season-debut-and-sunday-night-football/#344c302d6ae8">
        <end>1926</end>
        <start>1920</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/OfficialRightWingNews/posts/1535323903194400">
        <end>2369</end>
        <start>2355</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>This is just beautiful. This is the way it should be. No government involvement, no forcing people to do things they don’t want to do, just the people using their views to give their opinions on the NFL National Anthem controversy. I’m not a big sports fan, but I know several people who are. They bleed their team colors and are a little too serious about winning. They would travel across the country to see their team play and they have cut their ties with the NFL. Their hardcore devotion to their team is not enough to get them past the fact that they don’t want to see the country they love disrespected by people who have done nothing but gain from our freedom. SANTA CLARA, CA – SEPTEMBER 12: Colin Kaepernick #7 of the San Francisco 49ers kneels in protest during the National Anthem prior to playing the Los Angeles Rams in their NFL game at Levi’s Stadium on September 12th, 2016 in Santa Clara, California. (Photo by Robert Reiners/Getty Images) James Olson is not alone, but he is a perfect example of what millions of Americans are feeling right now. James Olson, a Sports Illustrated subscriber since fourth grade, watches action-packed NFL games on TV to escape from the endless round of political bickering playing out on other channels. But with more national anthem protests cropping up, he feels like politics has taken over his favorite sport, too. So he’s tuning out. “I want to say to these guys ‘If you weren’t playing in the NFL, you would be working at McDonalds. I think people have had it,” said, Olson, a Birmingham, Mich., resident. People don’t watch sports for half-baked political statements, they watch because they like to see their favorite player score, giving them bragging rights until the next game. If they wanted politics, they’d turn on the news. What happens when a beloved sport like football becomes entwined with something as deeply divisive as politics? Well according to Forbes, the first official game of the season brought in 13% fewer viewers than last year. This, they said, is the lowest number of live viewers in the last seven years. So, now I pose a question to you; should Americans turn off the TV when football comes on? Should we choose to support our nation over our favorite team and more importantly, do you actually think it will yield the desired results? Let us know your thoughts on our Facebook page! </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>231</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>468</end>
        <start>232</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>668</end>
        <start>469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>957</end>
        <start>669</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1064</end>
        <start>958</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1254</end>
        <start>1065</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1389</end>
        <start>1255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1562</end>
        <start>1390</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1789</end>
        <start>1563</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1901</end>
        <start>1790</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2089</end>
        <start>1902</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2369</end>
        <start>2090</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2370</end>
        <start>2370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1517</end>
        <start>1391</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1562</end>
        <start>1065</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>PAYBACK: National Anthem Protests Are Costing the NFL Viewership</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/payback-national-anthem-protests-costing-nfl-viewership/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
