<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rodney Lee</author>
    <links href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/caitlyn-jenner-contemplated-suicide-during-her-transition-w432741">
        <end>403</end>
        <start>396</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.theguardian.com/society/2004/jul/30/health.mentalhealth">
        <end>1272</end>
        <start>1261</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.sexchangeregret.com/research/suicide-study">
        <end>1668</end>
        <start>1636</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thenewamerican.com/culture/item/19507-the-transgender-con-many-transgender-people-regret-switch">
        <end>1772</end>
        <start>1724</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Caitlyn Jenner has been all over the spectrum the last few months. He even admitted to contemplating suicide. Caitlyn said he was not gay, but straight woman aren’t interested (anymore), he’s confused, he’s got buyer’s remorse on the surgery. His show is canceled. Where does he go from here? Life just hasn’t been greener on the other side for Bruce..Caitlyn…whoever he is today!    US Magazine Reports: “The 66-year-old I Am Cait star — formerly known as Bruce — told Simmons, 46, that she thought about taking her own life shortly after having her Adam’s apple surgically shaved, a part of her body she “always hated.” When a paparazzo captured shots of Jenner leaving the doctor’s office after the procedure in February 2014, the former Olympian said she nearly lost it. “I could not sleep that night. I’m up at 3 a.m. walking up and down my hallway, thinking, Damn, all this s–t is going to come out tomorrow and it’s going to be horrible,” she recounted. “And I said, ‘You know what? Easy way. Go in the other room. You got a gun. Let’s just end it right here.’” The TV personality — who has been open about her brush with suicide with friends and family — added that the whole experience was one of the worst moments in her life.”    It is not a rarity. David Batty in the UK Guardian wrote: A review of more than 100 international medical studies of “post-operative” transsexuals finds up to 20% regret transitioning and no conclusive evidence was found that shows gender reassignment surgery improves the lives of transsexuals, with many people remaining severely distressed and even suicidal after the operation. A staggering 41 percent of transgender people in the United States have attempted to commit suicide. 65 percent of people who’ve had cosmetic surgery, which is relatively minor body alteration, later regret the decision. So it is no wonder that Caitlyn is in this huge state of confusion.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>109</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>292</end>
        <start>110</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>380</end>
        <start>293</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>381</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>383</end>
        <start>382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>404</end>
        <start>384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>774</end>
        <start>405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1068</end>
        <start>775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1237</end>
        <start>1069</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1238</end>
        <start>1238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1240</end>
        <start>1239</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1298</end>
        <start>1241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1622</end>
        <start>1299</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1723</end>
        <start>1623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1843</end>
        <start>1724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1911</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1912</end>
        <start>1912</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1914</end>
        <start>1913</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>620</end>
        <start>406</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>944</end>
        <start>776</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>962</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1373</end>
        <start>1359</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The End for Bruce “Caitlyn” Jenner: Very Sad</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/08/24/bruce-caitlyn-jenner/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
