<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Stephen D Foster Jr</author>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/01/23/politics/donald-trump-shoot-somebody-support/">
        <end>978</end>
        <start>960</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It’s official. Trump’s supporters will vote for Donald Trump no matter what he does or what lies he tells, even if his tax returns reveal the truth. During his show on Tuesday night, Jimmy Kimmel ran yet another “Lie Witness News” segment featuring Trump supporters being asked questions based on the false story of him finally releasing his tax returns. The Kimmel reporter on the street asked Trump fans what they think now that the tax returns reveal that Trump is close with Putin, leases his wife Melania, writes off gold-plated toilets as a business expense, and supports child molester Jared Fogle. As it turns out, every single Trump supporter said they are still voting for the Republican nominee no matter what, even if it is true that Trump contributed to the legal defense fund of a convicted child molester. In fact, his supporters made excuses for Trump in order to justify his actions. So when Donald Trump said that he could go out and shoot someone dead in broad daylight in the middle of Fifth Avenue and not lose any votes, he was right. Because Trump’s supporters were not fazed by any of the claims presented to them. They were even okay with him lying on his returns by listing his occupation as a farmer. Seriously. Here’s the video via YouTube.  Trump’s supporters are truly deplorable people who just want to watch the world burn. It doesn’t matter what he says or what he does or how much he embarrasses America, Donald Trump’s supporter will vote for him no matter what. So the question is will the rest of us sit home on Election Day and let the lunatics win? Or will we get our asses off the couch and make sure Donald Trump never sets a single toe inside the White House? Because if his supporters don’t mind him doing all of these despicable things, that means Trump could basically do whatever he wants in office without political consequences and that would be disastrous for the nation. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>152</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>362</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>613</end>
        <start>363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>908</end>
        <start>614</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1064</end>
        <start>909</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1237</end>
        <start>1065</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>1238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1281</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1369</end>
        <start>1282</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1515</end>
        <start>1370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1719</end>
        <start>1516</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1940</end>
        <start>1720</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1941</end>
        <start>1941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <title>WATCH: Jimmy Kimmel Demonstrates That Trump Could Support Child Rape And Not Lose Any Votes</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/21/watch-jimmy-kimmel-demonstrates-that-trump-could-support-child-rape-and-not-lose-any-votes/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
