<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links>
        <end>613</end>
        <start>601</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>What a sign of the times it is when the terrorist who planted and detonated a number of explosives in New Jersey and New York City Saturday will be receiving better care than our own veterans who’ve fought to protect ourselves from men like him. It sounds unreal, but that’s the truth in Obama’s America. We’re all aware of the scandal at the Veteran’s Administration that broke back in 2014, which showed that the VA had inhumanely long waiting lists, and even went as far as to cover up the true extent of their inefficiency. Trump pointed out this sick truth at a campaign speech he gave today. As BizPacReview reported: “We have caught this evil thug who planted the bomb,” he said of (the terrorist) Rahami. “Thank you, law enforcement. Thank you, police.” Then he launched in to the part the haters predictably found fault with. “But the bad part, now we will give him amazing hospitalization. He will be taken care of by some of the best doctors in the world,” said Trump. “He will be given a fully modern and updated hospital room. And he’ll probably even have room service, knowing the way our country is. And on top of all of that, he will be represented by an outstanding lawyer.” Watch below:  Wouldn’t it be nice if our Veterans received the same treatment? Instead, over 300,000 have died while waiting from care from the VA. There are also a number of veterans who have committed suicide either waiting for direct care or psychological care – a number of such suicides happening in VA parking lots.  We can provide state of the art medical care to a man who tried to slaughter innocent Americans – don’t you think it’s time the government gets its act together and starts providing it to those returning from the battlefield? I can’t imagine what it would feel like being one of the doctors using your time to rescue a man who died in a shootout with police, who had tried to massacre countless Americans due to his religious ideology. Admittedly, I think I’d be tempted to make a medical “error” or two. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>304</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>527</end>
        <start>305</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>623</end>
        <start>528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>761</end>
        <start>624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>834</end>
        <start>762</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1191</end>
        <start>835</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1204</end>
        <start>1192</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1205</end>
        <start>1205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1514</end>
        <start>1206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1740</end>
        <start>1515</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2019</end>
        <start>1741</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2020</end>
        <start>2020</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>676</end>
        <start>625</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>760</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>966</end>
        <start>836</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1190</end>
        <start>981</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>46</end>
        <start>41</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>952</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>DISGUSTING! Because Of Hillary &amp; Obama, NY Terrorist Will Get Better Treatment Than US Vets!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/disgusting-because-of-hillary-obama-ny-terrorist-will-get-better-treatment-than-us-vets/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
