<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Ben Marquis</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/terence-crutchers-shooting-is-not/">
        <end>341</end>
        <start>325</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.tulsaworld.com/news/local/police-say-pcp-found-in-vehicle-occupied-by-terence-crutcher/article_d965a1f2-072b-57bf-a682-6b1cfb22b246.html">
        <end>602</end>
        <start>591</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/druggie-cop-homeless-man-epic/">
        <end>991</end>
        <start>967</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/truth-crutcher-bad-for-media/">
        <end>1474</end>
        <start>1448</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>An officer-involved shooting that took place over the weekend in Tulsa, Oklahoma, has drawn heavy criticism from the usual suspects in the Black Lives Matter movement and their allies in the liberal media. Video of the incident filmed from a helicopter overhead appeared to some to show a 40-year-old unarmed black man named Terence Crutcher with his hands over his head being shot and killed by white police officer Betty Shelby, seemingly confirming the narrative that police routinely use excessive force and deadly violence against black men who pose no threat to them. But according to Tulsa World, evidence was discovered in Crutcher’s vehicle that, while unknown to the officers on the scene at the time, could nevertheless explain some of the man’s behavior that led to the officer feeling compelled to fire her weapon. Inside the vehicle beside which Crutcher was shot and killed was discovered a vial of PCP, a highly dangerous drug that can often create a psychopathic and violent state of mind in its users. In fact, there were numerous anecdotal accounts of individuals on PCP who become nearly impervious to pain, including gunshots, continuing to attack police officers and innocent bystanders alike even as they are being shot repeatedly in locations that would instantly drop an ordinary non-drug using suspect. Another matter that could very well help explain Crutcher’s attitude and actions during the incident was that he had a lengthy criminal rap sheet, including several counts of resisting arrest and prior drug convictions for which he had served time. It is also noteworthy that Crutcher had a warrant out for his arrest related to previous charges of resisting arrest and drug use, so he could have made clear through his words and attitude that he had no intention of peacefully being arrested or returning to prison. All of this is evidence that could conceivably corroborate the view of the officer on the scene who reportedly stated Crutcher looked “like a bad dude” who “could be on something.” It was expected that the medical examiner’s office will release a toxicology report detailing whether Crutcher had the powerful drug in his system at the time of the incident, along with the rest of the broader autopsy report. Please share this on Facebook and Twitter to help spread the word that PCP was found in Terence Crutcher’s vehicle, which may explain why his actions prompted a Tulsa police officer to shoot him. Do you think the presence of PCP in this man's car changes anything? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>205</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>573</end>
        <start>206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>827</end>
        <start>574</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1019</end>
        <start>828</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>1020</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1577</end>
        <start>1329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1845</end>
        <start>1578</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2026</end>
        <start>1846</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2253</end>
        <start>2027</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2449</end>
        <start>2254</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2548</end>
        <start>2450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1996</end>
        <start>1981</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2025</end>
        <start>2003</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Police Find Something a Lot Scarier Than a Gun in Terence Crutcher’s Car</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/police-find-something-crutchers/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-21&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
