<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/paul-ryan-trump-tax-returns-228219">
        <end>637</end>
        <start>600</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>House Speaker Paul Ryan met privately on Monday with Donald Trump’s daughter, Ivanka Trump, according to two people familiar with the meeting. Ryan was in New York to deliver a policy address at the Economic Club of New York and had a private meeting with Ivanka Trump afterward. The meeting was at her request, according to one of the people. Story Continued Below Ryan and Donald Trump have had a strained relationship since Trump emerged as the Republican presidential nominee back in May. Ryan waited weeks before endorsing Trump and has continued to criticize him, including last week when Ryan called for Trump to release his taxes. Ivanka Trump has emerged as one of her father’s most trusted advisers and confidantes, including pushing him just last week to roll out a new package for child care. She stood behind him on stage as he unveiled the plan. Neither Trump’s campaign nor Ryan’s office immediately responded to a request for comment on the meeting Monday in New York, or what was on the agenda for the discussion.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>142</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>343</end>
        <start>143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>365</end>
        <start>344</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>638</end>
        <start>366</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>859</end>
        <start>639</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1030</end>
        <start>860</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Ivanka Trump meets with Paul Ryan in New York</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/ivanka-trump-meets-with-paul-ryan-in-new-york-228374?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
