<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2015_0306_5574_2169.jpeg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/montgomery-gentry-c6abd8c3e9e56d5a.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/mgunderground/status/780058218366107648">
        <end>1866</end>
        <start>1848</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/xCJlTZCIHX">
        <end>2394</end>
        <start>2368</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/mgunderground/status/780110161415319552">
        <end>1866</end>
        <start>1848</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>There have been so many deaths in country music over the past couple of months, and we thought that we were going to have to say goodbye to another legend Saturday night. It was a normal Saturday night at the Cornstock Concert on the Hill in Garnett, Kansas until Eddie Montgomery collapsed on stage in the middle of his performance. Many of you probably know the country star from the country duo Montgomery Gentry.  Montgomery Gentry was founded in 1999 when Eddie Montgomery and Troy Gentry came together and graced us all with their talents. The country duo has released 6 studio albums since their big debut and has had several No. 1 hits such as “If You Ever Stop Loving Me”, “Something to Be Proud Of”, “Lucky Man”, “Back When I Knew It All” and “Roll with Me”. The duo rose to fame shortly after the start of their career and they have continued to be a country favorite over the years. The duo was performing at their concert Saturday (September 24th) when Eddie Montgomery collapsed on the stage.  The medics immediately rushed to the stage and it was just moments later that he was walking off. The concert continued as Troy Gentry lead the band out. It was just four songs later that Eddie walked back out on the stage and apparently told the audience that he was not feeling well all day and that he was very dehydrated. And just like anything else, rumors started. Fans all over were saying that Eddie had a heart attack right there on stage. Apparently, they weren’t listening or they didn’t believe that he was actually dehydrated. The next morning on the duo’s Twitter they announced that Eddie was doing well and that it was definitely not a heart attack. There are false reports floating around that Eddie had a heart attack last night. NOT TRUE. He was dehydrated and returned to the stage. — Montgomery Gentry (@mgunderground) September 25, 2016  Eddie wanted to reassure everyone that he was indeed alive and that he didn’t have a heart attack, so a couple of hours after the initial post he took it upon himself to post a photo of him and his wife. Not only that, but he made sure that all of his fans knew that he was drinking PLENTY of water – doing his best to prevent the same thing from happening again. Eddie and Jennifer send their regards from Key West and thanks for all of the prayers and well wishes. And he's drinking plenty of H20! pic.twitter.com/xCJlTZCIHX — Montgomery Gentry (@mgunderground) September 25, 2016  We are so glad that Eddie is feeling better! I can’t imagine how scary this was for him and his fans!  We are praying for you Eddie!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>170</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>416</end>
        <start>171</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>417</end>
        <start>417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>768</end>
        <start>418</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1006</end>
        <start>769</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1007</end>
        <start>1007</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1333</end>
        <start>1008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1673</end>
        <start>1334</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1810</end>
        <start>1674</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1866</end>
        <start>1811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1867</end>
        <start>1867</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2231</end>
        <start>1868</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2394</end>
        <start>2232</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2450</end>
        <start>2395</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2451</end>
        <start>2451</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2553</end>
        <start>2452</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2554</end>
        <start>2554</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2584</end>
        <start>2555</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>679</end>
        <start>653</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>707</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>720</end>
        <start>711</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>747</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>766</end>
        <start>754</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1866</end>
        <start>1674</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2450</end>
        <start>2232</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Legendary Country Star Collapses On Stage During Performance, Please Pray For Eddie</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/breaking-legendary-country-star-collapses-on-stage-during-performance-please-pray-for-eddie/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Legendary+Country%2F9%2F26&amp;utm_content=Right+Wing+News%2FLegendary+Country%2F9%2F26</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
