<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>C.E. Dyer</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/new-autopsy-report-brown-shooting/">
        <end>122</end>
        <start>113</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/terence-crutchers-shooting-is-not/">
        <end>190</end>
        <start>182</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.weaselzippers.us/296470-terance-crutcher-just-finished-9-year-sentence-for-drug-trafficking-had-prior-convictions-for-resisting-arrest/">
        <end>522</end>
        <start>520</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bearingarms.com/bob-o/2016/09/20/terence-crutcher-shot-hands-heres-definitive-proof/">
        <end>2233</end>
        <start>2221</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.tulsaworld.com/news/local/pcp-found-in-vehicle-occupied-by-terence-crutcher-on-friday/article_d965a1f2-072b-57bf-a682-6b1cfb22b246.html">
        <end>2620</end>
        <start>2602</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Terence Crutcher was shot and killed on Sept. 16 in an officer-involved shooting in Tulsa, Oklahoma. Since then, the media have tried to push a false narrative that Crutcher had his hands up when he was shot — but video evidence, as it often does in these cases, disproved the media’s theory. There’s also more information that the mainstream media conveniently left out. Crutcher had a hefty criminal record before he was shot. In fact, he had just been released in May after nine years in prison for drug trafficking, WZ reported. He also had a history of resisting arrest. Behold the rap sheet: 1996 Shooting with intent to kill — Dismissed 2001 Petit larceny — Conviction 2004 Driving while suspended — Conviction 2005 Driving while suspended, resisting officer — Conviction 2006 Driving while suspended — Conviction Driving with open container — Dismissed 2006 Trafficking in illegal drugs — Conviction. (He was also charged in that incident with assault on a police officer and resisting, but that was dismissed.) 2011 Public intoxication (while in prison for drug trafficking) — Conviction 2012 Public intoxication — Conviction Obstructing an officer — Conviction 2013 DUI — Conviction Resisting officer — Conviction Open Container — Conviction Failure to wear seatbelt — Conviction Speeding — Conviction But even all of that was not all. Take a look at the numerous open warrants for Crutcher. These Aug. 30 warrants were active at the time of his death, and as you can see in the graphic below, they included things like DUI, resisting, drug trafficking and public intoxication.  The media are actively pushing the narrative that Crutcher had his hands up and that the police shot him anyway. We’ve heard this lie peddled by the media before, in the Michael Brown case, and clearly the obtuse media didn’t learn a thing. Helicopter video footage of Crutcher’s altercation with police has surfaced. Take a look:  Now, you watch that video and listen to the commentary. Did it look to you like Crutcher was following commands? You can hear an officer say that Crutcher was “still walking” and that he wasn’t “following commands.” Another officer said that he “could be on something.” Take a look at these pictures Bearing Arms grabbed from the video that disprove the media’s false narrative:       As you can see, Crutcher was not shot with his hands up. He was clearly flouting officer orders, and at the time of his shooting he lowered his right hand toward his waistband. Oh, and by the way, the media have run with the story that Crutcher was unarmed, but didn’t seem too interested in the PCP that was found in his car and that the Tulsa Police Department officer who shot Crutcher, Betty Shelby, was trained to spot PCP abuse, according to Bearing Arms. In any of these cases, the legal system should be given time to do its job, but the media have decided to run false narratives that fit their agenda without all the facts and, in some cases, despite the facts. As you can see above, there’s clearly more to the story. Please share this on Facebook and Twitter if you agree that the mainstream media use cases like this to bolster their divisive and dangerous agenda against law enforcement. What's your take on the Crutcher case and the mainstream media's attempt to push a false narrative? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>292</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>371</end>
        <start>293</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>532</end>
        <start>372</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>597</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1311</end>
        <start>598</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1345</end>
        <start>1312</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1587</end>
        <start>1346</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1588</end>
        <start>1588</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1701</end>
        <start>1589</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1829</end>
        <start>1702</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1919</end>
        <start>1830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1920</end>
        <start>1920</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2190</end>
        <start>1921</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2299</end>
        <start>2191</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2300</end>
        <start>2300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2301</end>
        <start>2301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2302</end>
        <start>2302</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2303</end>
        <start>2303</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2304</end>
        <start>2304</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2305</end>
        <start>2305</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2482</end>
        <start>2306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2767</end>
        <start>2483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2977</end>
        <start>2768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3034</end>
        <start>2978</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3207</end>
        <start>3035</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3337</end>
        <start>3208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2094</end>
        <start>2081</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2135</end>
        <start>2116</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2189</end>
        <start>2167</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Truth About Terence Crutcher Comes Out… It’s BAD for the Media</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/truth-crutcher-bad-for-media/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-21&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
