<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/3am/celebrity-news/jennifer-anistons-husband-justin-theroux-8927305">
        <end>941</end>
        <start>931</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Conservatives are so fed up with hearing about these two Hollywood stars’ marital problems and I’m right there in that group. There is nothing more boring than people who thrive on gossip and what is going wrong in another person’s life. That being said, I’m sure a lot of you are thinking, “Okay, but if she feels that way then why is she writing this story?” The answer to that is quite simple, I agree with Jennifer Aniston’s boyfriend, who was asked about the split up.  No doubt the media was looking for an answer to the effect of, “She’s grinning ear-to-ear and licking her chops.” The problem with that is, Justin Theroux refused to indulge them with a juicy, scandalous answer. It’s no secret that most people expect Aniston to be pleased that the man who cheated on her is splitting from the woman with whom he had the fling. There has to be at least a deep, dark pleasure, right? If there is, Theroux isn’t saying. What he did say is something that I think everyone can agree with, especially men and women who have endured divorce and children of divorce. “As a child of divorce, all I can say is that’s terrible news for those children, and that’s all you can really say,” the 45-year-old star said. “It’s boring to sort of comment on anything else. People are having a bad time. That’s horrible.” You’ll find anyone who is hard-pressed to disagree that divorce isn’t easy on the family unit, even if it is what’s best in the long-run. The first thing I thought when I heard that they were splitting up was, “Oh no, those poor babies.” Anyone who has felt the effects of divorce was probably thinking the same thing. Yes, their relationship was a relatively long one, but that doesn’t mean it was perfect. I just hope they do whatever it takes to make sure those children receive the best of them both and that the babies don’t ever feel like it is their fault that their parents decided to get a divorce. No child should EVER have to feel like they are the reason that their parents didn’t stay married. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>237</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>360</end>
        <start>238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>473</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>474</end>
        <start>474</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>686</end>
        <start>475</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>925</end>
        <start>687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1212</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1310</end>
        <start>1213</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1448</end>
        <start>1311</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1629</end>
        <start>1449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2017</end>
        <start>1630</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2018</end>
        <start>2018</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>359</end>
        <start>292</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>587</end>
        <start>539</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1184</end>
        <start>1069</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1309</end>
        <start>1214</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1547</end>
        <start>1522</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1310</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Jennifer Aniston’s husband gives honest answer when asked about Angelina Jolie &amp; Brad Pitt’s divorce</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/jennifer-anistons-husband-gives-honest-answer-asked-angelina-jolie-brad-pitts-divorce/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
