<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Posted by Conover Kennard on 20 Sep 2016</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/oreillyfactor">
        <end>640</end>
        <start>626</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/yDs6v1Jjhz">
        <end>668</end>
        <start>642</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/SopanDeb/status/778036404702019584">
        <end>711</end>
        <start>693</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/trump-bashes-military-for-botched-syria-bombing-frets-that-russia-is-absolutely-furious-at-us/">
        <end>2061</end>
        <start>2053</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freakoutnation.com/2016/09/vladimir-putins-opinion-seems-very-very-important-to-donald-trump/">
        <end>2319</end>
        <start>2286</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Scammer-turned reality show star-turned-Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump chatted with Fox News’s Bill O’Reilly last night and commenced to bash our military, as one does when running for the White House while trying to garner the patriotic™ conservative vote. While insulting President Barack Obama, Donald also took shots at the military, calling troops the “gang that couldn’t shoot straight.” In just 15 seconds, Donald said “win” or “winning” nine times in less than 15 seconds while offering no details  on how he would obtain these ‘wins.’ Trump says "win" or "winning" nine times in less than 15 seconds to @oreillyfactor: pic.twitter.com/yDs6v1Jjhz — Sopan Deb (@SopanDeb) September 20, 2016  “Well, I know how to win. I know how to win. I have been winning. I do win. Even in sports. I win,” Donald told O’Reilly. “And we don’t win. Our country doesn’t win. We don’t win at trade. We don’t win. We can’t beat ISIS. Can you imagine General Douglas MacArthur or General Patton? Can imagine they are spinning in their grave right now when they see the way we fight,” he continued. “We announce that we are sending certain people over here at a certain time. Everything is political. It’s very, very sad. Then we bomb the Syrian troops. You saw that over the weekend. We bombed, I guess we killed more than 80 troops.” Watch:  At that point, Donald seemed concerned that Russia would be upset with the U.S. even though they were consulted beforehand. And now Russia is absolutely furious at us. But we bomb the wrong people. I mean, we are like the gang that couldn’t shoot straight. Our country, with this leader, is the gang that couldn’t shoot straight. That’s what it is. The United Stats made a tactical error and accidentally bombed a detachment of Syrian government forces Saturday after mistakenly believing them to be ISIS forces. “The United States has relayed our regret through the Russian Federation for the unintentional loss of life of Syrian forces,” an Obama administration official announced at the time, according to Mediaite. However, the Russians, who appear to really want a Trump administration, criticized the bombings, even though again, they raised no objections when they were consulted before the incident took place. Russian diplomats then floated a Trump conspiracy theory, because of course: After the botched strike, Russian diplomats floated a Trump conspiracy theory that the Obama administration is actively helping ISIS. In fact, wherever the Islamic State abuts his enemies, Assad has actively assisted them with his own air power, while Putin has pursued a policy of allowing extremists to leave Russia and join ISIS. Donald offered no alternatives as to how he would prevent a botched bombing. He just says the word ‘win’ repeatedly and his supporters eat it up. So does Vladimir Putin, apparently. This man wants to get his little hands on the nuclear codes. Let that sink in for a moment. Shockingly, Sean Hannity, the Patriot, has been strangely quiet since Donald bashed our military. The rest of the media is probably waiting for Hillary to cough. Photo by Sara D. Davis via Getty.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>271</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>407</end>
        <start>272</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>557</end>
        <start>408</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>668</end>
        <start>558</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>711</end>
        <start>669</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>712</end>
        <start>712</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1335</end>
        <start>713</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1342</end>
        <start>1336</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1343</end>
        <start>1343</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1467</end>
        <start>1344</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1468</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2262</end>
        <start>1857</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2339</end>
        <start>2263</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2672</end>
        <start>2340</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2946</end>
        <start>2673</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3108</end>
        <start>2947</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3142</end>
        <start>3109</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Winning Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>406</end>
        <start>372</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>444</end>
        <start>441</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>457</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1083</end>
        <start>836</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1334</end>
        <start>1100</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1982</end>
        <start>1858</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>711</end>
        <start>558</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1468</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2672</end>
        <start>2340</start>
    </quotes>
    <title></title>
    <uri>http://winningdemocrats.com/donald-trump-just-unleashed-a-disgusting-attack-on-our-troops-but-the-media-is-silent-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
