<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/original-11.jpeg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>NASCAR officials have been working hard for a couple weeks now on how they really ant post race inspections to look. We’ve seen NASCAR’s Executive Vice President, Steve O’Donnell, speak out several times over the matter of post race inspections and how he’d like them to go. Basically, he wants the attention off of that aspect of things so estate everyone can focus on good racing. So in order for that to happen, O’Donnell and the rest of the executives have changed the format a bit, as we all know by now! They cut out the lower two tears of the penalty system and are only focusing on issuing penalties for failing post race laser inspection if the car fails it to a large degree.  However, executives realize that this may give drivers some leeway for cheating tactics. And Steve O’Donnell is trying to nip that in the bud. In a meeting this past weekend at New Hampshire, he made himself very clear as to what their expectations from the drivers were. “I want to make clear to everybody here that in NASCAR’s judgment, any measures that are taken to circumvent what happens for postrace inspection, we are going to react. We know that’s subjective. But ask all of you not to put it in our hands because we will react if we have to. I think everybody knows what that means. We want to concentrate on the race. … We couldn’t be more clear. I hope everybody agrees with that.” It’s awesome to see the officials making themselves clear and being open about their expectations!  We’ll see how open they are in the future however, seeing that O’Donnell didn’t clarify what cheating was in their books. There are allegations that “no cheating” might even include stopping the drivers from weaving back and forth on the cool down lap. Only time will tell! </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>116</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>382</end>
        <start>117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>685</end>
        <start>383</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>686</end>
        <start>686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>958</end>
        <start>687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1380</end>
        <start>959</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1602</end>
        <start>1381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1755</end>
        <start>1603</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1379</end>
        <start>960</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1631</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1380</end>
        <start>959</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>NASCAR Just Called Teams Out For Cheating, You Won’t Believe This</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/sports/nascar/nascar-just-called-teams-out-for-cheating-you-wont-believe-this/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=nascar+cheating%2F9%2F27&amp;utm_term=Right+Wing+News%2Fnascar+cheating%2F9%2F27</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
