<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>100% FED Up</author>
    <links href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2016/sep/19/dhs-granted-citizenship-illegals-terrorist-nations/">
        <end>2525</end>
        <start>2523</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The nation’s top immigration officer said that the “11 million” undocumented aliens in the United States are “not going away,” are “in effect” citizens, and added that deporting the few the administration wants out is unpleasant: THIS SHOULD BE CONSIDERED TREASON! SKIP TO THE 25:00 MARK FOR HIS COMMENTS ON ILLEGALS: Well, he just made 858 illegals from “hotbed” terror countries American citizens!  Hundreds of illegal immigrants from terrorist hotbeds who were supposed to have been deported were instead granted citizenship because Homeland Security didn’t have fingerprints on file to check their identity, the department’s inspector general said in a stunning new report Monday. At least two of those approved are now being investigated by the FBI for links to terrorism, investigators said. But in most cases, Homeland Security and federal prosecutors have let the illegal immigrants-turned-citizens get away with their potential fraud. Charges were brought in just two of the more than 800 cases identified. One of the persons granted citizenship through the error-riddled process is now a law enforcement officer, and three others worked in security-sensitive fields — including two who worked in sensitive areas at airports. “USCIS granted U.S. citizenship to at least 858 individuals ordered deported or removed under another identity when, during the naturalization process, their digital fingerprint records were not in the DHS digital fingerprint repository,” the inspector general said. The 858 cases involved people from so-called “special interest” countries, or from neighboring countries with major immigration fraud problems. Special interest countries are those places the government has identified as posing national security problems to the U.S. WHAT’S EVEN MORE UNBELIEVABLE: Investigators late last year identified another 953 cases that also seemed suspicious. The problem, according to the audit, is tens of thousands of illegal immigrants and criminal aliens whose files are so old that their fingerprints are still on paper cards. U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, the agency that approves applications, wasn’t checking those paper-based files, so it didn’t know the aliens were ineligible or had been ordered kicked out of the country already. The inspector general said some fingerprints have been digitized, but it identified 148,000 aliens who have been ordered deported but whose fingerprints are not in the IDENT system the department uses for its fingerprint checks. Read more: WT </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>229</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>400</end>
        <start>230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>684</end>
        <start>401</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1501</end>
        <start>685</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1799</end>
        <start>1769</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2511</end>
        <start>1800</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2525</end>
        <start>2512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2526</end>
        <start>2526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>100 Percent Fed Up</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>62</end>
        <start>52</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>125</end>
        <start>110</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>141</end>
        <start>132</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>362</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1472</end>
        <start>1236</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1564</end>
        <start>1548</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>HOW DID 858 ILLEGALS From TERROR “HOTBEDS” Get Full Citizenship When They Were Supposed To Be Deported? [Video]</title>
    <uri>http://100percentfedup.com/858-illegals-terror-hotbeds-get-full-citizenship-supposed-deported-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
