<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3790824/Anthony-Weiner-carried-months-long-online-sexual-relationship-troubled-15-year-old-girl-telling-hard-asking-dress-school-girl-outfits-pressing-engage-rape-fantasies.html">
        <end>93</end>
        <start>87</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/22/politics/first-on-cnn-us-attorney-investigating-weiner-sexting-allegations/">
        <end>271</end>
        <start>263</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A spokesperson for the New York Police Department said “detectives are looking into” a report that former congressman Anthony Weiner traded sexually explicit messages with a girl who identified herself as a 15-year-old high school student. The exchange was first reported by the Daily Mail yesterday, which withheld the name of the girl because she is a minor. Story Continued Below Later Thursday, CNN reported that U.S. Attorney Preet Bharara's office has subpoenaed Weiner for his cell phone and other records. Weiner yesterday referred reporters to a statement he had given the Daily Mail, saying he regretted his online conversations but pointing to a letter the girl wrote calling the incident “a hoax.” The girl later recanted that characterization, and shared with the Daily Mail a series of images and messages she said she traded with Weiner up until July. Weiner’s 2013 mayoral campaign was rocked by revelations that he had traded sexually explicit messages with a woman after he had resigned from office in 2011. Weiner's resignation was prompted by an exchange with another woman that he accidentally posted to his public Twitter feed. Mayor Bill de Blasio today said today the situation is "horrible." "I've known Anthony over the years, but I know Huma much better, having served side by side with her during the 2000 Senate campaign," said de Blasio, who managed Hillary Clinton's campaign for the U.S. Senate that year. "I think the world of Huma. I just feel horrible for her and her son that they're going through this. It's not a secret, Anthony obviously has a real problem that needs treatment, and all I can say is I hope he will pursue the treatment he needs and stick with it until his issues are addressed." Yesterday, Governor Andrew Cuomo said if the report is true, it is "sick" and potentially "criminal."</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>239</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>360</end>
        <start>240</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>382</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>513</end>
        <start>383</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>866</end>
        <start>514</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1149</end>
        <start>867</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1216</end>
        <start>1150</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1217</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1836</end>
        <start>1735</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>83</end>
        <start>56</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>708</end>
        <start>701</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>New York NYPD 'looking into' Weiner communication with teen</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/states/new-york/city-hall/story/2016/09/nypd-probe-weiner-communication-with-teen-105728?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
