<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/london/2016/09/20/merkel-admits-wrong-migrant-policy/">
        <end>48</end>
        <start>40</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>German Chancellor Angela Merkel finally admitted to the press that if she could go back in time to change her stance on her open migrant policy she would. She is also admitting she is willing to consider a new policy direction. Merkel told the media at a press conference, “If I knew what change in refugee policy the people in Germany want, I would be prepared to consider it.” These comments came shortly after the defeat of the Christian Democratic Union in Berlin’s Sunday elections. She also said, “If I could, I would go back in time to be better prepared for the refugee crisis in 2015, for which we were rather unprepared.” She took responsibility for the poor election results after finding out the results of the Mecklenburg-Vorpommern election. Callying the defeat bitter and saying that she took full responsibility as the parties leader and as the countries leader. The results of the edition are considered to be as a result of the anti migrant sentiment many Germans now have. As well as the rise of the anti mass migration Alternative for Germany known as AfD. These factors have forced Merkel to at least consider a change in her stance. Regardless of her new admission she all but flat out dismissed the possibility that she would actually implement the change she says she deeply regrets. In other words it is all talk and no walk. She is willing to regret because it makes her look good but not enough to actually implement the change people so desperately want. However, she did say she would not embrace the critiques and criticisms of the Christian Social Union. They have notoriously called for a cap on the migrants coming into Germany each year. They specifically want to cap it at 200,000. As well, they want to prioritize Christian migrants over Muslims. But Merkle will not budge on that. Merkel stated, “If people don’t want Muslim asylum-seekers purely because of their religion, that is contrary to our party principles and to Germany’s. The CDU and I cannot go along with that.” Christian Social Union party leader Horst Seehofer threatened to withdraw support for Merkle during her 2017 campaign. Specifically for not implementing the migrant cap. The campaign will be in the federal election. He said, “It is high time we find common ground to survive at the next election.” The growing anti migrant atmosphere has been a direct result of an increase in terrorism, increasing migrant crime as well as violent crime. Which people automatically associate with more incoming refugees. Understandably so. If it ain’t broke don’t fix it. This could perhaps be an indicator as well that she could lose in the next federal election. Or at least win by an only marginal amount. Serves her right considering her policies are as progressive as President Obama’s and Hillary Clinton’s. She is no different which is why many Americans too cannot stand her. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>272</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>378</end>
        <start>273</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>502</end>
        <start>379</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>631</end>
        <start>503</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>878</end>
        <start>632</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1154</end>
        <start>879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1482</end>
        <start>1155</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1832</end>
        <start>1818</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2011</end>
        <start>1833</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2236</end>
        <start>2012</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2309</end>
        <start>2237</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2567</end>
        <start>2310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2879</end>
        <start>2568</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2880</end>
        <start>2880</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>377</end>
        <start>274</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>630</end>
        <start>504</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2010</end>
        <start>1834</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2308</end>
        <start>2238</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BOOM! Merkel Admits Flooding Germany With Muslim Refugees Was WRONG</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/boom-merkel-admits-flooding-germany-with-muslim-refugees-was-wrong/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
