<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Jamison Black</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/RapSheet/status/778621393705570304">
        <end>750</end>
        <start>732</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Vikings?src=hash">
        <end>760</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/FitzBeatSr">
        <end>800</end>
        <start>789</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JosinaAnderson">
        <end>818</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/RapSheet/status/778616109335506944">
        <end>750</end>
        <start>732</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Vikings?src=hash">
        <end>760</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/SAaCqQlNbF">
        <end>1076</end>
        <start>1053</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/USATODAYsports/status/778623730591363073">
        <end>750</end>
        <start>732</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The Vikings continue to receive bad news on the offensive side of the ball. When Minnesota Vikings running back Adrian Peterson went down in pain holding his knee, the news didn’t look good in regards to their star back.  Early reports were that he would just miss a few games at most due to a torn meniscus, but that news has taken a turn for the worst. The star running back is set for surgery on Thursday and will miss three-to-four months with the knee injury.  This puts his time table for December at the earliest and a likely playoff push for the NFC North. With Adrian Peterson having surgery tomorrow, he’s likely out until December at least. Would loom large for a potential playoff appearance. — Ian Rapoport (@RapSheet) September 21, 2016  #Vikings RB Adrian Peterson has told @FitzBeatSr &amp; @JosinaAnderson he’s having his meniscus repaired — not trimmed. Would mean out months. — Ian Rapoport (@RapSheet) September 21, 2016  #Vikings RB Adrian Peterson is set to have meniscus surgery Thursday. He is holding out hope for a playoff return. https://t.co/SAaCqQlNbF — USA TODAY Sports (@USATODAYsports) September 21, 2016  Peterson has shown over and over that he is a special type of player on the football field and off, so if anyone can come back from this injury sooner than expected, it would be the Vikings soon to be Hall-of-Fame running back.  However, age isn’t on his side and no matter how much you train and get ready for the season, the older you get the more difficult it is to get out there after major injuries. This puts a major clamp on the Vikings hope for the playoffs as they are now down both of their leaders on offense.  Teddy Bridgewater was lost for the year in the preseason as he torn his ACL on a non-contact play in practice. Matt Asiata and Jerrick McKinnon are the likely candidates to take over the running back position for the remainder of the season while Peterson is out as he recovers from his knee surgery.  Both backs are average, but they don’t bring what Peterson brings to the table. You never ask for an injury, but this is football and injuries happen.  With the recent injury to Peterson, this only helps both those other teams in the NFC North and the rest of the conference on making the playoffs. Here’s to a speedy recovery for Peterson!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>75</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>76</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>564</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>704</end>
        <start>565</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>705</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>890</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>936</end>
        <start>891</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>937</end>
        <start>937</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1076</end>
        <start>938</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1132</end>
        <start>1077</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1133</end>
        <start>1133</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1538</end>
        <start>1134</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1766</end>
        <start>1539</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2037</end>
        <start>1767</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2256</end>
        <start>2038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2298</end>
        <start>2257</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>565</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>936</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1132</end>
        <start>938</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING : Minnesota Dealt Another Blow On Offense</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/sports/nfl/breaking-minnesota-dealt-another-blow-offense/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Adrian+Peterson%2F9%2F21&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2FAdrian+Peterson%2F9%2F21</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
