<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Cassy Fiano</author>
    <mainText>There has been a lot of speculation surrounding the shooting death of Keith Scott at the hands of Charlotte police. The police department says the shooting was justified, as Scott had a gun and threatened officers. Scott’s defenders say that he was merely waiting to pick up his children from their bus stop and was holding a book, not a gun. What is the truth? It’s still unclear, but a new revelation from Scott’s wife may shed some more light on what really happened.   The media has begun to dig into Scott’s background and found that Rakeyia Scott took out a restraining order against him, claiming that he was abusive. She also said that he had a gun and threatened to kill her. In it, she wrote, “He hit my 8 year-old in the head a total of three times with is [sic] fist… .He kicked me and threaten [sic] to kill us last night with his gun. He said he is a ‘killer’ and we should know that.”   The form also asked if there was any reason law enforcement officers should view him as a potential threat and if he carries a weapon. She answered “yes” and wrote, “He carries a 9mm black.” The order was filed October 9th, 2015 and less than two weeks later, Scott voluntarily cancelled it herself. But it certainly lends credence to the department’s claim that Scott was armed and dangerous. Police also released the dashcam and bodycam footage from the shooting, as well as photos of the handgun Scott had on him at the time. The gun was allegedly the same weapon that another homeowner reported as stolen after someone broke into their house.   And police dispute the notion that Scott was merely waiting for his children’s bus to arrive, peacefully reading a book and doing nothing wrong. They first observed him rolling a blunt, which was not a priority for them at first. But when they saw him hold up a gun, they took more notice and decided to arrest him, because the combination of drugs and guns is a threat to public safety. The officers, who were originally in plain clothes, outfitted themselves with marked duty vests and equipment so it would be clear they were police officers, and gave Scott multiple commands to drop the gun. He refused. Scott’s DNA and fingerprints were found on the gun, which was loaded. So again, we have another case of the Black Lives Matter movement exploiting a justified police shooting and using it to spawn riots and violence in the name of “justice.” </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>470</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>471</end>
        <start>471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>472</end>
        <start>472</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>899</end>
        <start>473</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>900</end>
        <start>900</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>901</end>
        <start>901</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1092</end>
        <start>902</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1548</end>
        <start>1093</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1549</end>
        <start>1549</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1550</end>
        <start>1550</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2228</end>
        <start>1551</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2400</end>
        <start>2229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2401</end>
        <start>2401</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>898</end>
        <start>704</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1054</end>
        <start>1051</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1091</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2399</end>
        <start>2391</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Wife of Keith Scott: “He Kicked Me and Threatened to Kill Us Last Night With His Gun” [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/black-lives-matter/wife-keith-scott-kicked-threaten-kill-us-last-night-gun-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
