<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rika Christensen</author>
    <links href="http://www.stltoday.com/news/local/crime-and-courts/new-videos-provide-fresh-look-at-st-louis-police-killing/article_e0530fba-5db7-500e-9b31-3dd4512fe5bc.html">
        <end>482</end>
        <start>464</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.stltoday.com/online/jason-stockley-internal-memo/pdf_28d8a070-6c25-5a5e-83a0-fae7f6d87592.html">
        <end>1089</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In 2011, St. Louis police officer Jason Stockley shot and killed Anthony Lamar Smith, a drug suspect that he was trying to arrest. At the time, Stockley claimed that he saw Smith reaching for a gun, which is why he fired his. Self-defense, that’s all it ever is, isn’t it? The problem is…Smith was unarmed and now there’s not just evidence of that, but there’s also evidence that Stockley may have done worse than lie. There is a strong possibility that he planted the gun in Smith’s car after murdering him to cover his own ass. Smith did flee the scene of a possible drug deal and a high-speed chase ensued. Stockley was carrying a personally-owned AK-47 that Smith, in escaping, almost knocked out of his hands. Stockley was not authorized to carry that weapon while on duty, which goes a long way towards demonstrating Stockley as an unethical officer at the very least. He was also recorded as saying that he was going to kill Smith. Stockley’s partner, Brian Bianchi, said that he warned Stockley about a revolver on the seat of Smith’s car, and Stockley himself said he feared Smith was about to pull the revolver when he approached: “Before striking me [with his car], I observed, in plain view in the subject’s hand while resting on the passenger seat, a silver handgun. The handgun was pointing up and towards me… Because of the presence of a weapon and because I felt my personal safety was in jeopardy, as was the safety of P.O. Bianchi, and bystanders, I fired several shots at the subject.” It’s apparently hard to see in the videos whether Stockley handled the revolver; however, it’s damned telling that only his DNA was on the gun. Something of Smith would definitely have been there if he’d been handling the gun, as Stockley alleged. The St. Louis Board of Police Commissioners did pay a $900,000 settlement to Smith’s family in 2013, but Stockley himself was not charged with murder. That is, until this year, when this new evidence came to light. Stockley is now charged with first-degree murder, but is free on a $1 million bond. He left the St. Louis Police Department in 2013. Watch below for more background on this story:  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>428</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>541</end>
        <start>429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>950</end>
        <start>542</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1156</end>
        <start>951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1345</end>
        <start>1157</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1528</end>
        <start>1346</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1782</end>
        <start>1529</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1999</end>
        <start>1783</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2179</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2180</end>
        <start>2180</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2181</end>
        <start>2181</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1527</end>
        <start>1157</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Damning New Evidence Shows Cop Who Murdered Unarmed St. Louis Man Likely Planted Gun</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/20/damning-new-evidence-shows-cop-who-murdered-unarmed-st-louis-man-likely-planted-gun/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
