<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tim Brown</author>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/if-you-want-security-pursue-liberty/">
        <end>216</end>
        <start>202</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/1180-documented-examples-of-barack-obamas-lying-lawbreaking-corruption-cronyism-hypocrisy-waste-etc/">
        <end>1467</end>
        <start>1368</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/2011/10/michelle-obama-barack-obama-kenyan-ambassador-claim-kenya-is-obamas-birthplace/">
        <end>1552</end>
        <start>1503</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn5.freedomoutpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Hansard-05.11.08A_2.pdf">
        <end>1592</end>
        <start>1561</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://1tjy1il8myg2badl72uj53gv.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Washingtons-Farewell-Adress.pdf">
        <end>2850</end>
        <start>2820</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/obama-order-progress-can-come-individuals-surrender-rights-powerful-sovereign/">
        <end>3841</end>
        <start>3730</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In his final speech to the worthless United Nations Security Council, Barack Hussein Obama Soetoro Sobarkah urged that Americans give up their liberty and sovereignty and submit to world government. In stark contrast to founding father Benjamin Franklin, who uttered the famous words, “Those who would give up essential Liberty, to purchase a little temporary Safety, deserve neither Liberty nor Safety,” Obama called on Americans to give up more liberty for security.  “We can only realize the promise of this institution’s founding to replace the ravages of war with cooperation if powerful nations like my own accept constraints,” Obama said. He then added that “powerful nations” like the United States must give up their autonomy to realize security. “I’m convinced in the long run giving up some freedom of action, not giving up our ability to protect ourselves or pursue our core interests but binding ourselves to international rules, over the long-term, enhances our security.” Obama said. Of course, Obama was doing this to praise the United Nations, an organization that is anti-American, anti-Christian and totalitarian at its core. So, what’s the problem? Obama is convinced and that should make us just fall in line? Wasn’t he the guy that was convinced Obamacare would lower costs and provide everyone with health insurance? Did that materialize? Nope. This man has lied through his teeth the entire time he has been in office and we’ve documented that. While Obama, a clear foreigner by his words, his wife’s word’s, a Kenyan Ambassador and the record of the Kenyan Parliament (despite what Trump and others say), claims that his view is the right one, he also acknowledges that real Americans, born and bred here, oppose him. These people do so rightly. “Sometimes I’m criticized in my own country for professing a belief in international norms and multilateral institutions, but I’m convinced in the long run…” Obama said. “We have to put our money where our mouths are.” Yes, but the problem is America is not normal to the international community. She has been unique throughout her history. She was unique because her foundation was established upon the Bible, not upon “international norms,” which were pagan in origin. That’s what made America great. “I believe that at this moment we all face a choice,” Obama added after denouncing the building of a southern wall on the US border. “We can choose to press forward with a better model of cooperation and integration or we can retreat into a world sharply divided and ultimately in conflict along age-old lines of nation and tribe and race and religion. I want to suggest to you today that we must go forward and not back.” While I do agree with some bit of cooperation as in working with other countries on trade and things of that nature, which George Washington acknowledged we should do, I disagree with how Obama believes that we do that. His idea is to reward bad behavior, even to encourage it and to redistribute the wealth of the united States. That is not only unconstitutional, it’s immoral and wrong and he has no authority to do such things. Yet, Congress and the people have allowed him to do it. Finally, Obama stated that the United Nations was established to replace the ravages of war with peaceful cooperation. No, it was not. The majority of countries in the United Nations are either Communists, Socialists or Islamists. There is nothing peaceful about those ideologies in the least. As a friend of mine aptly stated, “They (the founders of the UN) wanted the organization they formed to be perceived as a dove when in reality it was to be a venomous snake.” This is not the first time Obama has pushed this globalist mentality either. Remember when he addressed dignitaries and members of NATO in 2014? If not, click here to listen to that speech. Even conservatives were livid that we pointed out what he was actually saying. View the entire speech to the United Nations below.       The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>198</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>468</end>
        <start>199</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>469</end>
        <start>469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>645</end>
        <start>470</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>755</end>
        <start>646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>998</end>
        <start>756</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1144</end>
        <start>999</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1468</end>
        <start>1145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1770</end>
        <start>1469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1989</end>
        <start>1771</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2273</end>
        <start>1990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2696</end>
        <start>2274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3183</end>
        <start>2697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3652</end>
        <start>3184</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3921</end>
        <start>3653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3973</end>
        <start>3922</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3974</end>
        <start>3974</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3976</end>
        <start>3975</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3978</end>
        <start>3977</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3979</end>
        <start>3979</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4125</end>
        <start>3980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4199</end>
        <start>4126</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>403</end>
        <start>286</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>632</end>
        <start>471</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>600</end>
        <start>584</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>985</end>
        <start>757</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1927</end>
        <start>1772</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1988</end>
        <start>1942</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2212</end>
        <start>2192</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2326</end>
        <start>2275</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2695</end>
        <start>2408</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3651</end>
        <start>3513</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4161</end>
        <start>4149</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama Says it’s Time to Give up Liberty and SUBMIT to World Government</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36918/obama-says-its-time-to-give-up-liberty-and-submit-to-world-government/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
