<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>There’s a reason far-left, progressive whack job Senator Elizabeth Warren was given the nickname Fauxcohantas. She’s as phony as a $3 bill. Warren earned that nickname after it was discovered that she lied for years about being part Native American, then when confronted, she touted her “Pow Pow’s” high cheekbones as evidence that he was Native American. She rails against Wall Street when she has made millions because of Wall Street. Warren went after Donald Trump when it was reported that he made money flipping houses without disclosing that she has done the same. We should be used to Warren’s feigning outrage because she does so when it is politically expedient. That leads to the Senate hearing today in which Warren grilled the CEO of Wells Fargo, John Stumpf, over thousands of workers being caught setting up fake accounts in order to earn bonuses. Wells Fargo has since fired those workers and said that there could be more people let go if they discover further shenanigans. But that wasn’t enough for Fauxcohantas. She had to get up on her hypocritical high horse when the cameras were running to score her political talking points. Although the individuals who actually bilked the customers out of money were fired, Warren has the audacity to chastise the Wells Fargo CEO because senior executives were not fired accusing him of “gutless leadership.” “You haven’t fired a single senior executive. Instead, evidently, your definition of accountable is to push the blame to low-level employees who don’t have the money for a fancy PR firm to defend themselves. It’s gutless leadership.” Where were these words from Elizabeth Warren when Barack Obama blamed low-level IRS employees in Cincinnati for the IRS targeting, harassing, and intimidation of conservative and Tea Party groups? Where were these tough words when it turned out people at the top not only knew what was going on but orchestrated it? Where was Fauxcohontas when Lois Lerner was able to retire with a cushy pension and faced absolutely no repercussions for her hand in the scandal. Where was Warren when Obama lied to the American people in an interview with Bill O’Reilly before the Super Bowl when he said there wasn’t a smidgen of corruption? And did Elizabeth Warren demand that VA executives who were keeping fake log books in order to get bonuses be fired? Did she go on record of accusing Barack Obama of “gutless leadership” for his failure to fire anyone when it came to the VA scandal or the IRS scandal? Did she say Obama created the environment for such despicable practices to occur, practices which led to the death of hundreds of veterans and impact on the livelihood of Americans who were simply practicing their First Amendment rights in criticizing their government? No. Elizabeth Warren didn’t say a damn word about those things. Why? Because it would not have been politically expedient. Yes, there’s a reason Elizabeth Warren was given the nickname “Fauxcahontas.” She’s a big, filthy, hypocritical fake and political opportunist. That was exposed and made perfectly clear with her rant against the Wells Fargo CEO. Watch Elizabeth “Fauxcahontas” Warren in all her hypocritical glory.   Email Subscribe</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>139</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>570</end>
        <start>140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>861</end>
        <start>571</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1148</end>
        <start>862</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1367</end>
        <start>1149</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1601</end>
        <start>1368</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2228</end>
        <start>1602</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2767</end>
        <start>2229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2890</end>
        <start>2768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2968</end>
        <start>2891</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3119</end>
        <start>2969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3188</end>
        <start>3120</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3189</end>
        <start>3189</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3190</end>
        <start>3190</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3196</end>
        <start>3191</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3206</end>
        <start>3197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politistick</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>297</end>
        <start>288</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1366</end>
        <start>1347</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1600</end>
        <start>1369</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1365</end>
        <start>1347</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2967</end>
        <start>2954</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2966</end>
        <start>2954</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1601</end>
        <start>1368</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The hardest-hitting political news.</title>
    <uri>http://politistick.com/in-30-seconds-elizabeth-warren-shows-what-a-huge-hypocrite-she-is/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
