<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tom Cahill</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/elcajonpolice/status/780898728563441664">
        <end>682</end>
        <start>664</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AlfredOlango?src=hash">
        <end>759</end>
        <start>746</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Nettaaaaaaaa/status/780971270556876800">
        <end>858</end>
        <start>840</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://linkis.com/www.nydailynews.com/o26Ru">
        <end>1206</end>
        <start>1178</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Periscope?src=hash">
        <end>1909</end>
        <start>1899</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/rrMukk0J79">
        <end>1943</end>
        <start>1920</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ashleyNBC7/status/780898134410956800">
        <end>682</end>
        <start>664</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nbcsandiego.com/news/local/Officer-Involved-Shooting-in-El-Cajon-395014341.html">
        <end>2063</end>
        <start>2016</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.aclusandiego.org/san-diego-aclu-statement-shooting-el-cajon/">
        <end>2233</end>
        <start>2208</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/elcajonpolice/status/780957438585352192">
        <end>858</end>
        <start>840</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/elcajonpolice/status/780961171230760961">
        <end>858</end>
        <start>840</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>An allegedly unarmed, mentally disabled black man having a seizure was shot by police Tuesday afternoon. The shooting happened minutes after his sister called 911 for medical assistance. Police in El Cajon, California — outside of San Diego — tweeted on Tuesday afternoon that officers had an encounter with an “erratic subject” that ended with officers shooting the man, later identified as Alfred Olango. Black Lives Matter organizer Johnetta Elzie tweeted that Olango died from his wounds. Officers responded to an erratic subject that ended with an officer involved shooting. We will post updates here as they are available. — El Cajon Police (@elcajonpolice) September 27, 2016  Being told there's been a fatal police shooting in San Diego. #AlfredOlango is the name. Have a friend there at the scene. — Johnetta Elzie (@Nettaaaaaaaa) September 28, 2016  In a Facebook Live video, streamer Rumbie Mubaiwa talked to Olango’s sister, who said her brother was 30 years old. Olango was allegedly having a seizure, and his sister called 911 for medical assistance. Minutes after police arrived, Olango had been shot. “I called for help, I didn’t call for you guys to kill him,” the woman screamed at police while sobbing uncontrollably. “Oh my god, you killed my brother!” “I should have called the crisis communications team,” the woman said.  In a Periscope filmed at the scene of the shooting by NBC 7 reporter Ashley Matthews, at least two witnesses to the shooting said Olango was shot with his hands oustretched, and was unarmed. “I see a man, I see a black man surrounded by officers with their guns out, which caught my attention,” a witness said, stretching out his hands to demonstrate. “The black male is up with his hands like this, scared to death, not knowing which way he’s gonna go … as soon as he runs this way, they discharge. Boom, boom, boom five shots right into him.” Watch on #Periscope: Untitled https://t.co/rrMukk0J79 — Ashley Matthews (@ashleyNBC7) September 27, 2016  According to NBC 7, police confiscated the cell phones of employees at a local restaurant near the scene of the shooting, and told employees to not talk to anyone. The American Civil Liberties Union of San Diego issued a public statement condemning the confiscation of witnesses’ phones. “Confiscating cell phones is a violation of the Fourth Amendment (unreasonable seizure without warrant or exigent circumstance) and the First Amendment (interference with the right to record in public) under the U.S. Constitution and analogous rights under the California Constitution,” stated ACLU of San Diego executive director Norma Chavez-Peterson. “It is hard to see any kind of Fourth Amendment exigent circumstances at issue here.” However, the police department tweeted that no phones were confiscated. We ask that the community please be careful about reacting to inaccurate information. No phones were confiscated from anyone at the scene. — El Cajon Police (@elcajonpolice) September 28, 2016  One employee who recorded video of the shooting on her phone turned the video over to police. El Cajon Police told local media they are currently reviewing the video as part of the investigation. In a tweet, the police department said that the video does not show Olango raising his hands in the air before he was shot. El Cajon police are not currently equipped with body cameras. The investigation just started, but based on the video voluntarily provided by a witness, the subject did NOT have his hands up in the air — El Cajon Police (@elcajonpolice) September 28, 2016  The name of the officer who shot Olango is currently being withheld.   (EDITOR’S NOTE: This story was updated at 11:30 PM Eastern Time to note that Olango had died in the hospital, and to include tweets from the El Cajon Police Department alleging that Olango’s hands were not in the air, and that no phones were confiscated at the scene. This article was also amended to include a statement from the ACLU of San Diego.)        </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>186</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>492</end>
        <start>187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>628</end>
        <start>493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>629</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>683</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>806</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>807</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>859</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>860</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1272</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1343</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1344</end>
        <start>1344</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1535</end>
        <start>1345</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1889</end>
        <start>1536</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1943</end>
        <start>1890</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1994</end>
        <start>1944</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1995</end>
        <start>1995</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2283</end>
        <start>1996</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2723</end>
        <start>2284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2795</end>
        <start>2724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2934</end>
        <start>2796</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2988</end>
        <start>2935</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2989</end>
        <start>2989</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3371</end>
        <start>2990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3510</end>
        <start>3372</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3564</end>
        <start>3511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3565</end>
        <start>3565</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3634</end>
        <start>3566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3636</end>
        <start>3635</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3986</end>
        <start>3637</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3988</end>
        <start>3987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3989</end>
        <start>3989</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3990</end>
        <start>3990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3991</end>
        <start>3991</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3992</end>
        <start>3992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3993</end>
        <start>3993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3994</end>
        <start>3994</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>327</end>
        <start>312</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1176</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1271</end>
        <start>1238</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1326</end>
        <start>1274</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1638</end>
        <start>1537</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1888</end>
        <start>1698</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2569</end>
        <start>2285</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2722</end>
        <start>2639</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>493</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1994</end>
        <start>1890</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2988</end>
        <start>2796</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3564</end>
        <start>3372</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Cops Kill Unarmed, Mentally Disabled Black Man Having Seizure After His Sister Called 911</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/cops-shoot-disabled-man/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
