<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/f/?id=00000157-59e9-d502-ad5f-dbedd6be0001">
        <end>213</end>
        <start>207</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A lawyer for Hillary Clinton told a House committee Friday the panel won't be receiving some information it subpoenaed about security arrangements for Clinton's server. Clinton attorney David Kendall sent a letter to House Science Committee Chairman Lamar Smith (R-Texas) saying that the panel's subpoena to Florida-based computer security company SECNAP went too far by demanding details on safeguards in place after Clinton emails from her time as secretary state were removed from the server in 2014. "Documents regarding this equipment are likely to contain sensitive information related to security of the current network and/or server," Kendall added. "Because these documents are unrelated to the Committee's investigation and contain sensitive security information, I respectfully object to the portion of the subpoena seeking their production." A spokeswoman for Smith did not immediately respond to a request Friday night seeking comment on Kendall's letter. Smith has been pressing for records from the FBI and private firms as part of his panel's investigation into the security vulnerabilities of the private system Clinton used to store the tens of thousands of emails she exchanged while secretary. Other House and Senate committee are conducting similar inquiries. When the House Oversight Committee called in computer technicians from the Clintons' main computer contractor Platte River Networks last week, Smith was granted special permission to sit on the dais. He said his panel was being denied information because of resistance from Clinton and her attorneys. "SECNAP counsel confirmed to my staff that the Clinton's private LLC is actively engaged in directing their obstructionist responses to congressional subpoenas. This is a clear obstruction of justice. Americans deserve to know the truth, which is now being blocked by the Clinton organization," Smith said. A former Clinton aide, Justin Cooper, did testify at that hearing, but the questioning of the computer technicians was to no avail since both exercised their Fifth Amendment rights. Asked about Kendall's response to the Science Committee subpoena, a spokeswoman for the panel's ranking Democrat Rep. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas had no specific comment, However, the spokeswoman pointed to an earlier statement sharply criticizing the chairman's email-related probe and questioning the panel's jurisdiction over the issue. “I am outraged that the Chairman is recklessly abusing the Committee’s investigatory powers to brazenly do the bidding of the Trump campaign. I am certain that the Science Committee will not uncover any ‘smoking gun’ after this issue has already been thoroughly investigated by the Benghazi Committee at a cost of $7 million in taxpayer dollars as well as by the FBI," Johnson said. "This Committee desperately needs to get back to the work of ensuring continued American leadership in science and innovation and the legitimate oversight of our research and development enterprise.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>168</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>503</end>
        <start>169</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>853</end>
        <start>504</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1581</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1888</end>
        <start>1582</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2070</end>
        <start>1889</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2413</end>
        <start>2071</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2996</end>
        <start>2414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2995</end>
        <start>2415</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton lawyer rejects subpoena for current server security details</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/under-the-radar/2016/09/hillary-clinton-emails-subpoena-server-security-228614?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
