<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Elvin Bartley</author>
    <links href="http://www.yesimright.com/bill-clinton-ruined-hillarys-campaign-by-doing-one-stupid-thing-we-can-send-him-to-jail/">
        <end>803</end>
        <start>730</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/l3gLIPf1vV">
        <end>1376</end>
        <start>1350</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/morningjoe?src=hash">
        <end>1388</end>
        <start>1377</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FBI?src=hash">
        <end>1393</end>
        <start>1389</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/jaazee1/status/767681953667641344">
        <end>1429</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=033pctltIwk">
        <end>1868</end>
        <start>1861</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/jaazee1/status/767681953667641344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">
        <end>1877</end>
        <start>1870</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Let’s just put it this way: If Donald Trump’s campaign was found guilty of this crime, the media would pre-emptively announce his resignation and carry him out of town, pitchforks and torches in hand. However, Hillary Clinton is apparently immune to any criticism in the media. Don’t know what I’m talking about? Let me fill you in. The campaign Hillary4America, a group that advocates for the policies of Hillary Clinton, was searching for recruits to go to the polls and preach the word of Clinton. Two things are wrong with this: First, it’s illegal to go to a polling/voter registration place and tell people who to vote for. It’s the reason why candidates can’t go to a polling/voter registration place and talk with voters, despite Bill Clinton doing it anyway and the media staying quiet about it. This seems like a clear cut case of voter manipulation and fraud. Second, the idiots behind Hillary4America didn’t know that one of their prospective recruits, the very people they were instructing to violate voter laws, had a hidden camera on the whole time and exposed them for the crooks they really are. Here is the entire thing, caught on tape. If this doesn’t clue you in into the mindset of people voting for Hillary, I don’t know what will. Hidden cam shows Hillary4America training recruits to DELIBERATELY break voter registration law!pic.twitter.com/l3gLIPf1vV #morningjoe #FBI — jaazee (@jaazee1) August 22, 2016  Want more? Here’s yet another Hillary campaign volunteer registering people to vote with signs that are against Donald Trump. When she’s pressed on her partisan hackery, she just runs away when she realizes that she’s being filmed. Yeah, sure sounds familiar, doesn’t it?  We need to get out and vote to make sure that this particularly virulent strain of political manipulation gets left behind for good. Who’s with me? (Source: YouTube, Twitter) </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>332</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>532</end>
        <start>333</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>870</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1112</end>
        <start>871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1253</end>
        <start>1113</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1393</end>
        <start>1254</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1429</end>
        <start>1394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1430</end>
        <start>1430</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1702</end>
        <start>1431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1703</end>
        <start>1703</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1851</end>
        <start>1704</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1878</end>
        <start>1852</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1879</end>
        <start>1879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Yes Im Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1429</end>
        <start>1254</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary’s Campaign Knew It Was Voter Fraud, But They Didn’t Know The Cameras Were On</title>
    <uri>http://www.yesimright.com/hillarys-campaign-knew-it-was-voter-fraud-but-they-didnt-know/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
