<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/agenda/story/2015/05/inside-war-on-coal-000002">
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>1352</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Soon after Donald Trump’s campaign manager, Kellyanne Conway, said the GOP nominee believes “global warming is naturally occurring,” Mike Pence declared “there’s no question” human activities impact the climate. “There’s no question that the activities that take place in this country and in countries around the world have some impact on the environment and some impact on climate,” Pence, Trump’s running mate, said Tuesday on CNN. Story Continued Below The confusion came on the heels of Monday’s presidential debate, in which Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton pointed out that Trump previously said climate change is a hoax perpetrated by the Chinese. “The concept of global warming was created by and for the Chinese in order to make U.S. manufacturing non-competitive,” Trump wrote on Twitter in 2012. Trump later said it was a joke. On Tuesday, Pence told CNN it was “a humorous tweet” and sought to turn the argument on the Democrats. “What Donald Trump said was a hoax is that bureaucrats in Washington, D.C., can control the climate of the earth,” Pence said. “And the reality is that this climate change agenda that Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton want to continue to expand is killing jobs in this country.” Pence has repeatedly pledged that he and Trump will end the so-called “war on coal,” a reference to Obama administration policies that have led to the closures of a number of coal-fired power plants.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>211</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>433</end>
        <start>212</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>455</end>
        <start>434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>656</end>
        <start>456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>840</end>
        <start>657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>943</end>
        <start>841</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1221</end>
        <start>944</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1421</end>
        <start>1222</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>131</end>
        <start>93</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>173</end>
        <start>154</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>382</end>
        <start>213</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>775</end>
        <start>658</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>892</end>
        <start>876</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1057</end>
        <start>945</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1220</end>
        <start>1072</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1305</end>
        <start>1293</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Pence: ‘No question’ humans impact climate</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/mike-pence-climate-change-228799?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
