<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kate Yoder Grist staff Emma Foehringer Merchant Katie Herzog Katie Herzog Abigail Bechtel Amelia Urry</author>
    <links href="http://www.businessinsider.com/should-i-repair-or-replace-my-shoes-2015-4">
        <end>194</end>
        <start>158</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/19/waste-not-want-not-sweden-tax-breaks-repairs">
        <end>428</end>
        <start>408</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thelocal.se/20160917/sweden-wants-to-make-repairing-things-cheaper">
        <end>628</end>
        <start>614</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/politics/climate-movement-trump-strategy/">
        <end>1482</end>
        <start>1436</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/energy-environment/wp/2016/11/18/on-its-way-out-obama-administration-tries-to-slam-the-door-shut-on-arctic-drilling/?utm_term=.b288bb88a663">
        <end>1946</end>
        <start>1915</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/climate-energy/shell-just-abandoned-its-arctic-drilling-plans/">
        <end>2520</end>
        <start>2482</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/climate-energy/activists-blockade-seattle-port-to-protest-shells-arctic-drilling-plans/">
        <end>2609</end>
        <start>2596</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2016/nov/17/untapped-oil-texas-permian-basin-900-billion">
        <end>2905</end>
        <start>2886</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/grist/status/798653002743615489">
        <end>3214</end>
        <start>3174</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://grist.org/politics/trump-will-be-the-fossil-fuel-industrys-greatest-gift/">
        <end>3304</end>
        <start>3220</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.bloomberg.com/energy">
        <end>3422</end>
        <start>3403</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newswest9.com/story/33729804/billions-of-gallons-of-oil-estimated-in-permian-basin-expert-speaks">
        <end>3746</end>
        <start>3736</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.colorlines.com/articles/watch-standing-rock-documentary-sheds-light-nodapl-fight">
        <end>3955</end>
        <start>3942</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/briefly/tim-kaine-says-a-potential-dakota-access-reroute-would-be-the-right-thing-to-do/">
        <end>4059</end>
        <start>4021</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/justice/trumps-victory-could-be-a-big-win-for-the-dakota-access-pipeline-but-opponents-stand-strong/">
        <end>4254</end>
        <start>4222</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nsidc.org/arcticseaicenews/charctic-interactive-sea-ice-graph/">
        <end>4596</end>
        <start>4590</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/briefly/this-is-what-near-record-low-arctic-sea-ice-looks-like/">
        <end>4786</end>
        <start>4770</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Antarctic?src=hash">
        <end>5128</end>
        <start>5118</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Arctic?src=hash">
        <end>5140</end>
        <start>5133</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/seaice?src=hash">
        <end>5148</end>
        <start>5141</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/nObJ4WqsUl">
        <end>5223</end>
        <start>5197</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/granlund_aarne/status/799272863282921472">
        <end>5276</end>
        <start>5259</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/briefly/the-last-five-years-were-say-it-with-me-the-hottest-five-years-on-record/">
        <end>5322</end>
        <start>5308</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/energy-environment/wp/2016/11/17/the-north-pole-is-an-insane-36-degrees-warmer-than-normal-as-winter-descends/?utm_term=.765c7ac60ffa">
        <end>5554</end>
        <start>5528</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://strangerthings.wikia.com/wiki/Upside_Down">
        <end>5584</end>
        <start>5569</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/pittsburgh-has-a-naughty-rooster-and-nobody-can-catch-him-1479400296">
        <end>5636</end>
        <start>5628</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://grist.org/briefly/page/2">
        <end>5754</end>
        <start>5733</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://vip.wordpress.com/?utm_source=vip_powered_wpcom&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_campaign=VIP%20Footer%20Credit">
        <end>5868</end>
        <start>5851</start>
    </links>
    <links>
        <end>5937</end>
        <start>5927</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Get Grist in your inbox Sweden again It’s a response to the strange situation we’re in, where buying and shipping a new pair of shoes to your doorstep can be cheaper than repairing your old ones. On Tuesday, Sweden’s ruling Social Democrat and Green Party coalition will submit a series of proposals to parliament. One would cut the tax rate on repairs to shoes, clothes, and bicycles from 25 to 12 percent, the Guardian reports. Another would allow half of the labor cost of repairing large appliances — fridges, ovens, dishwashers — to be claimed back on incomes taxes. That’s not all: There’s also a plan for a “chemical tax” on new computers and appliances to cover the environmental cost of those new, shiny, and often unrecyclable materials. The parliament will vote on all the proposals in December. “I believe there is a shift in view in Sweden at the moment,” Per Bolund, Sweden’s minister for financial markets and consumer affairs who spearheaded the new incentives, told the Guardian. “There is an increased knowledge that we need to make our things last longer in order to reduce materials’ consumption.” There Sweden goes again, making the rest of us look bad. read more Last week, we recommended reading literally anything that didn’t have to do with the election. This week, we’re (sort of) ready to think about why what happened … happened. In any case, it really happened. If you’re feeling depressed about that, read Grist’s Rebecca Leber on where to go from here. COP22 Though this year’s U.N. climate agenda was notably less ambitious than that of the 2015 Paris meeting, climate conferences always go long. You should know that. Write it down. But there are a few notable outcomes already ironed out, even if negotiators are still scrambling on the final text: thanks obama The Obama administration took a big step in protecting the Arctic Ocean from oil and gas exploration on Friday when it blocked the sale of new permits to drill in the Chukchi and Beaufort Seas off the Alaskan coast until 2022. The move was applauded by environmental groups that have long argued that drilling in the area will harm the Arctic’s fragile ecosystem and contribute to catastrophic climate change. “Given the unique and challenging Arctic environment and industry’s declining interest in the area, forgoing lease sales in the Arctic is the right path forward,” said Secretary of the Interior Sally Jewell in a statement. Last year, Royal Dutch Shell and other oil companies abandoned plans to drill in the Arctic, citing the high cost of exploration as well as the falling price of oil. (Public outcry may also have had something to do with it). This step by the Obama administration, however, may not last. President-elect Donald Trump has pledged to open up new lands to drilling and could ultimately reverse Obama’s decision. how crude An estimated 20 billion barrels of oil has been discovered in West Texas’s Permian Basin. This could be, according to the USGS, the largest supply of oil ever found in the United States, worth up to $900 billion. The timing could not be better for oil prospectors — and worse for the environment. President-elect Donald Trump, who thinks that climate change is a hoax, has pledged to dismantle environmental regulations and rubber stamp fossil fuel projects. There is, however, one silver lining to this discovery: The low price of oil, which is currently around $45 a barrel, means much of the Texas oil will likely remain underground, at least for the immediate future. “We are picking up a few rigs every now and then but we wont see it really take off until we get to that price in the $60 to $75 range,” said Morris Burns, former president of the Permian Basin Petroleum Association, on KWES TV. Standing Rock Mni Wiconi: The Stand at Standing Rock takes us to the scene of the standoff over the pipeline, where gathered protesters face police violence. The phrase Mni Wiconi, which means “water is life” in Lakota, has been used to rally support for the movement. The pipeline’s original route was rejected because it was a threat to Bismarck’s water supply, but it now poses that same risk to the neighboring Standing Rock Sioux. Despite recent developments that make approval for the pipeline likely, Winona LaDuke, founder of Honor the Earth, warns against despair in the short film: “Don’t operate out of fear; operate out of hope. Because with hope, everything is possible.” Vanishing Act Into the ocean, it seems. New satellite data show the total area of global sea ice dipping wayyy below the National Snow and Ice Data Center’s record for this time of year. In fact, Arctic sea ice has dropped well below the next-lowest seasonal extent ever observed (which was in 2012). That year’s all-time record low was narrowly avoided in September, the month when Arctic sea ice levels typically are at their lowest. But the fact that ice levels are lower now than they were this same time in 2012 is part of what makes this latest data so alarming. Meanwhile, Antarctic sea ice is also much lower than usual at the end of the Southern Hemisphere’s winter. Both the #Antarctic and #Arctic #seaice extents are abnormally small. That's the story. pic.twitter.com/nObJ4WqsUl — Aarne Granlund (@granlund_aarne) November 17, 2016  We’ve gotten somewhat used to broken records here, but watching sea ice levels flatten out when they should be peaking is well beyond normal understanding of record lows and highs. Meanwhile, the temperature at the North Pole right now is a not-cool 36 degrees F above average. Is this what the Upside Down feels like? Sometimes, all you need is the headline — especially when the headline is, “Pittsburgh Has a Naughty Rooster and Nobody Can Catch Him.” View more news briefs A Beacon in the Smog® © 1999-2016 Grist Magazine, Inc. All rights reserved. Grist is powered by WordPress.com VIP. Don't miss another green thing! Get Grist in your inbox. No thanks.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>23</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>24</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>195</end>
        <start>37</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>571</end>
        <start>196</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>806</end>
        <start>572</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>807</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1174</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1184</end>
        <start>1175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1357</end>
        <start>1185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1358</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1489</end>
        <start>1484</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1665</end>
        <start>1490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1782</end>
        <start>1666</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1783</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2022</end>
        <start>1796</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2205</end>
        <start>2023</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2653</end>
        <start>2206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2836</end>
        <start>2654</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2846</end>
        <start>2837</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3059</end>
        <start>2847</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3305</end>
        <start>3060</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3518</end>
        <start>3306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3747</end>
        <start>3519</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3761</end>
        <start>3748</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4016</end>
        <start>3762</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4183</end>
        <start>4017</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4432</end>
        <start>4184</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4446</end>
        <start>4433</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4619</end>
        <start>4447</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5001</end>
        <start>4620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5108</end>
        <start>5002</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5223</end>
        <start>5109</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5276</end>
        <start>5224</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5277</end>
        <start>5277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5458</end>
        <start>5278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5596</end>
        <start>5459</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5732</end>
        <start>5597</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5754</end>
        <start>5733</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5776</end>
        <start>5755</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5869</end>
        <start>5777</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5926</end>
        <start>5870</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5937</end>
        <start>5927</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Grist</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>627</end>
        <start>615</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>867</end>
        <start>808</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>998</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2367</end>
        <start>2207</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3654</end>
        <start>3520</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3955</end>
        <start>3942</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4431</end>
        <start>4341</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5731</end>
        <start>5673</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5276</end>
        <start>5109</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Briefly Sweden plans to give tax breaks for fixing stuff instead of throwing it away. We’ve got some weekend reading to help you face the post-election world. The Marrakech climate talks still aren’t over, but here’s what’s gone down so far. Obama halts new oil drilling in the Arctic — for now. Oh god, they’ve discovered even more oil in Texas. Watch people on the frontlines of the Dakota Access fight defend their water and their rights. Um, where did all of the Arctic and Antarctic sea ice just go?</title>
    <uri>http://grist.org/briefly/sweden-plans-to-give-tax-breaks-for-fixing-stuff-instead-of-throwing-it-away/?utm_content=buffer5b3f0&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=facebook.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
