<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2A2E18E500000578-3156216-image-a-18_1436557476865.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nationalreview.com/article/440412/democrats-hurt-blacks-low-expectations">
        <end>442</end>
        <start>432</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nationalreview.com/article/440412/democrats-hurt-blacks-low-expectations">
        <end>2328</end>
        <start>2311</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Progressive Democrats are the “helicopter parents” of America. They want to protect people so much that they end up doing more harm than good, and it’s keeping segments of the American population from being fully independent. This is NOT what our Founders envisioned when they set out to create our government.  One of the groups most negatively affected by liberal hand-holding is blacks. Don’t believe me? Just ask Thomas Sowell, who penned an amazing piece for National Review on this very subject. Back in the 1960s, as large numbers of black students were entering a certain Ivy League university for the first time, someone asked a chemistry professor — off the record — what his response to them was. He said, “I give them all A’s and B’s. To hell with them.” Since many of those students were admitted with lower academic qualifications than other students, he knew that honest grades in a tough subject like chemistry could lead to lots of failing grades, and that in turn would lead to lots of time-wasting hassles — not just from the students, but also from the administration. He was not about to waste time that he wanted to invest in his professional work in chemistry and the advancement of his own career. He also knew that his “favor” to black students in grading was going to do them more harm than good in the long run, because they wouldn’t know what they were supposed to know. Such cynical calculations were seldom expressed in so many words. Nor are similar cynical calculations openly expressed today in politics. But many successful political careers have been built on giving blacks “favors” that look good on the surface but do lasting damage in the long run. Sowell continues his piece, lamenting the creation and maintenance of the “welfare state,” a term used to describe a government that acts as a parent of the citizen. In 1960, before this expansion of the welfare state, 22 percent of black children were raised with only one parent. By 1985, 67 percent of black children were raised with either one parent or no parent. A big “favor” the Obama administration is offering blacks today is exemption from school behavior rules that have led to a rate of disciplining of black male students that is greater than the rate of disciplining of other categories of students. Read the full article here and be sure to share with your liberal friends so you can watch their heads explode! </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>310</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>311</end>
        <start>311</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>389</end>
        <start>312</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>501</end>
        <start>390</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>766</end>
        <start>502</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1088</end>
        <start>767</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1398</end>
        <start>1089</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1686</end>
        <start>1399</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1852</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2055</end>
        <start>1853</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2301</end>
        <start>2056</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2413</end>
        <start>2302</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2414</end>
        <start>2414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>49</end>
        <start>31</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>765</end>
        <start>718</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1250</end>
        <start>1245</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1616</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1776</end>
        <start>1762</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1250</end>
        <start>1245</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1686</end>
        <start>502</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2301</end>
        <start>1853</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The Lasting Damage Done by the Left’s ‘Favors’ to Blacks</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/lasting-damage-done-lefts-favors-blacks/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
