<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Mason Dixon</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/the-upper-cut-obama-gets-right/">
        <end>467</end>
        <start>454</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/20/obama-tells-united-nations-military-action-cannot-defeat-isis-video/">
        <end>549</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/diplomats-rebuke-obama-syrian/">
        <end>1139</end>
        <start>1130</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/carson-post-telling-hillary-who/">
        <end>1927</end>
        <start>1917</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>President Barack Obama has given what was supposed to be his final address to the U.N. General Assembly, and it was a defeatist doozy on the inadequacy of military power in the struggle against Islamist extremism in Syria and elsewhere. By extension, since the U.S. is the world’s preeminent military power, that would mean our president essentially said we can’t win. Noting the longstanding buildup of militant forces within Islam that have fueled the Islamic State group, Obama cast doubt on the viability of a military solution, The Daily Caller reported. “If we are honest, we understand that no external power is going to be able to force different religious communities or ethnic communities to coexist for long,” Obama said. The president said we must “be honest about the nature of these conflicts and our international community must continue to work with those who seek to build rather than to destroy.” While he granted that this process would have a military component, he also referred to “a place like Syria, where there’s no ultimate military victory to be won.” Obama recommended that we “pursue the hard work of diplomacy that aims to stop the violence and deliver aid to those in need and support those who pursue a political settlement and can see those who are not like themselves as worthy of dignity and respect.” You can watch here; the relevant portion of the video begins at 29:30.  We could be forgiven for wondering how any of this is supposed to work if we are led by liberal politicians who are reluctant to admit the often-obvious link between violence and radical Islam and who are more likely to criticize Christians than jihadists. We also wonder how any of this is supposed to work if we are led by liberal politicians who have so conspicuously failed to “see those who are not like themselves as worthy of dignity and respect.” It’s not going to work as long we call the good guys deplorable and the bad guys a religion of peace. Think about it between now and November. You’ll know what to do. Share this on Facebook and Twitter and let us know what you think of Obama’s remarks to the U.N. What do you think of Obama's outlook on our military potential? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>236</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>368</end>
        <start>237</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>559</end>
        <start>369</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>732</end>
        <start>560</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>914</end>
        <start>733</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>1079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1407</end>
        <start>1337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1408</end>
        <start>1408</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1665</end>
        <start>1409</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1863</end>
        <start>1666</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1864</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2030</end>
        <start>1966</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2127</end>
        <start>2031</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2221</end>
        <start>2128</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>719</end>
        <start>561</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>913</end>
        <start>761</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1077</end>
        <start>1004</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1335</end>
        <start>1106</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1335</end>
        <start>1264</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Obama Surrenders to ISIS in Front of Entire U.N.</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/obama-surrenders-to-isis-un/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-20&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
