<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://freedomdaily.com/black-rapper-tells-truth-black-lives-matter/">
        <end>27</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Cops-e1474976807685.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:DqQNfjf4zKAJ:www.forcescience.org/forcepresentation.ppt+&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us&amp;client=safari">
        <end>850</end>
        <start>835</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:DqQNfjf4zKAJ:www.forcescience.org/forcepresentation.ppt+&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us&amp;client=safari">
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>1295</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:DqQNfjf4zKAJ:www.forcescience.org/forcepresentation.ppt+&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us&amp;client=safari">
        <end>850</end>
        <start>835</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Cops1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As we watch police officers hunted down and assassinated, and we see riots rear up every time a black man is shot by police, we might want to take a moment to review the actual numbers behind these shootings. The number of lives lost by police using deadly force is minuscule. Since it is an act of last resort, it should be. Twice as many white suspects are killed in violent encounters with police, but you never hear about that. See the statistics below. If black lives mattered so much to the radicals out there, they would focus more on reducing crime and helping their communities. They don’t… the likes of Black Lives Matter, the New Black Panthers and the Nation of Islam riot, loot and kill, many times in their own neighborhoods. It’s the violence and chaos they want… not to rectify any injustice.  From Freedom Daily: 2013 U.S. population is 316,128,839 persons, here are annual percentages: ⦁ 0.012% of the U.S. population committed suicide ⦁ 0.011% of the U.S. population died in a vehicle crash ⦁ 0.004% of the U.S. population died in a criminal homicide ⦁ 0.00012% of the U.S. population died from police use of force ⦁ 0.00012% of the U.S. population was struck by lightning ⦁ 0.00009% of the U.S. population was legally killed by a private citizen in self-defense …that of the 1,491 persons that died from police use of force from 2009-2012: ⦁ 915 (61.4%) were white males ⦁ 481 (32.2%) were black males ⦁ 48 (3.2%) were males of other races ⦁ 28 (1.9%) were white females ⦁ 15 (1.1%) were black females ⦁ 4 (0.2%) were females of other races ⦁While only 6% of the U.S. population is identified as black and male, 57.9% of the persons legally killed by a private citizen in self-defense were black males. ⦁ However, 73.1% of the black males legally killed by a citizen in self-defense between 2009-2012 were killed by a black citizen. ⦁ 42.6% of victims of all solved criminal homicides from 2009-2012 were black males ⦁ 89.6% of black males killed in criminal homicides from 2009-2012 were killed by another black male ⦁ 40.6% of the police officers murdered in the line of duty from 2009-2012 were killed by black males* Police officers put their lives on the line each and every day they go out there to protect us. They never know if it will be their last. They have sworn an oath that all lives matter and they will protect people from those that are criminally inclined and evil. There are very few ‘bad’ cops and they are usually weeded out. The majority of officers are those who joined to help others and keep them from harm. You have about as much chance of being struck by lightning as you do being shot by a police officer. You really have to work at it to become a statistic. Those that are shot almost without fail are threatening police officers or not obeying commands. The statistics tell the story if anyone bothers to review them. Violence is out of control in the black community and overwhelmingly when a person is shot, it is justified. And it happens very rarely.    </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>457</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>808</end>
        <start>458</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>809</end>
        <start>809</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>829</end>
        <start>810</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1281</end>
        <start>830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1560</end>
        <start>1282</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2140</end>
        <start>1561</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2552</end>
        <start>2141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3004</end>
        <start>2553</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3005</end>
        <start>3005</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3006</end>
        <start>3006</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3007</end>
        <start>3007</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3008</end>
        <start>3008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2140</end>
        <start>830</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>If You Want The Truth About Whose ‘Lives Matter’- You Need To See This Video</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/black-lives-matter/want-truth-whose-lives-matter-need-see-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
