<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/19/us/politics/hillary-clinton-health.html">
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It seems as if our suspicions were correct from the onset. Hillary Clinton and her ‘physician’ are not telling the American people the truth about her health. This is the woman who claims transparency and as has never lied. In a recent report from the liberal leaning New York Times, Dr. Lawrence K. Altman M.D. brings it all out into the open. The doctor also makes sure to point out that what was released by Trump was not extensive enough too. Read the story below.  As Written By LAWRENCE K. ALTMAN, M.D. for the New York Times: The disclosure last week that Hillary Clinton was beingtreated for pneumonia thrust the health of both of the major parties’ presidential candidates and their running mates to the center of the campaign, and led to the release of more detailed medical histories from the two candidates seeking what is widely regarded as the world’s most demanding job. Mrs. Clinton, 68, the Democratic presidential nominee, who has had serious medical problems in recent years, released on Wednesday an update of a July 2015 letter from her doctor attesting to her overall good health and ability to serve a full four-year term as president. However, the doctor, Dr. Lisa Bardack of Mt. Kisco, N.Y., noted that Mrs. Clinton had developed two new medical conditions in 2016: a sinus and ear infection in the winter and pneumonia this month. Dr. Bardack wrote that she had regularly examined Mrs. Clinton this year for routine care and that she had been closely monitoring her pneumonia, which is improving. But doctors not connected with the candidate’s care say that the letters omit basic information like height and weight, and that a more detailed history of her blood clots and a 2012 concussion should be disclosed. Still, the information Mrs. Clinton has made public is more extensive than the details … Full Story Here: How Healthy Is Hillary Clinton? Doctors Weigh In – The New York Times</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>468</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>469</end>
        <start>469</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>532</end>
        <start>470</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>885</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1356</end>
        <start>886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1522</end>
        <start>1357</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1523</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1843</end>
        <start>1827</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1827</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>NYT: Crucial Details Omitted, Discordant Accounts On Hillary Health</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/nyt-crucial-details-omitted-discordant-accounts-on-hillary-health/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
