<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Posted by John Prager on 26 Sep 2016</author>
    <links href="http://www.thefiscaltimes.com/2015/03/25/478B-Infrastructure-Bill-Blocked-Senate-GOP">
        <end>545</end>
        <start>495</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Through the course of this election season, a dark cloud has hung over Trump’s campaign – OK, many dark clouds. Dark, racist, xenophobic, lying clouds. But the one we’re referencing here is “what the hell is going on with his taxes?” The simple answer, as Trump revealed during the first presidential debate, is that The Donald simply hasn’t paid any federal income tax. Trump blamed Clinton for “squandering” taxpayer dollars, thus depriving us of much-needed infrastructure improvements — the kind Republicans like Trump typically vote against. Clinton, of course, took the opportunity to get in a dig about the GOP nominee’s own taxes. “Maybe because you haven’t paid any federal income tax in a lot of years,” Clinton shot back, expertly placing the bait in the trap. And, of course, she didn’t have to wait long for Trump to try to grab the cheese. To emphasize his point, he accidentally admitted that she’s exactly right: “It would be squandered too, believe me.” Pay attention to the word “would.” Trump would not have said that if he had paid taxes, which he called “smart” earlier in the debate. Is this the reason he doesn’t want to reveal his taxes, which he says he will release “against his lawyer’s wishes” if Clinton releases deleted emails? Does Trump not want the voting public to know that he’s a deadbeat who absolutely does not pay his fair share? When Trump says “believe me,” believe him — not that his tax dollars would be “squandered” but that he believes they “would” if he had paid any. Watch the clip below:  Featured image via Getty Images/Drew Angerer</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>233</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>638</end>
        <start>234</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>928</end>
        <start>639</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>970</end>
        <start>929</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1105</end>
        <start>971</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1368</end>
        <start>1106</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1513</end>
        <start>1369</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1535</end>
        <start>1514</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1536</end>
        <start>1536</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1581</end>
        <start>1537</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Winning Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>232</end>
        <start>191</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>408</end>
        <start>397</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>712</end>
        <start>640</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>969</end>
        <start>930</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1004</end>
        <start>998</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>1076</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1220</end>
        <start>1193</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1397</end>
        <start>1386</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>952</end>
        <start>942</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>933</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>970</end>
        <start>929</start>
    </quotes>
    <title></title>
    <uri>http://winningdemocrats.com/whoa-trump-just-accidentally-admitted-he-has-not-paid-any-federal-income-taxes-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
