<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tim Brown</author>
    <links href="http://www.fairus.org/news/foia-request-by-fair-reveals-ice-low-balled-the-number-of-offenses-committed-by-released-criminals">
        <end>307</end>
        <start>301</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://judiciary.house.gov/press-release/judiciary-committee-releases-information-about-new-crimes-committed-by-freed-criminal-aliens/">
        <end>1009</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/homeland-security-documents-165900-convicted-criminal-illegals-released-into-us-by-obama-homeland-security/">
        <end>3402</end>
        <start>3353</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/sanctuary-cities-release-9000-criminal-illegals-in-9-months-dont-turn-them-over-to-feds-for-deportation/">
        <end>3556</end>
        <start>3512</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/report-obama-administration-released-75-illegals-rather-deport/">
        <end>1009</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/obama-administration-didnt-report-90-of-crimes-committed-by-illegal-criminal-aliens-it-released/">
        <end>3868</end>
        <start>3823</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>“Rather than end dangerous politically-driven policies that have put a total of 85,000 deportable criminal aliens back onto the streets in the last three years, ICE tried to hide them by providing grossly inaccurate information to Congress and the American people.” —Dan Stein, President of FAIR In a report released by the Federation of American Immigration Reform (FAIR), they have charged that the Obama administration “grossly misrepresented – by almost tenfold” the number of crimes that were committed by illegal, criminal aliens who were released from custody in fiscal year 2014. Now, if the term “illegal, criminal aliens” sounds like overkill, understand that the term illegal does refer to aliens who are in the united States illegally, which makes them criminals. However, applying the term criminal relates to the fact that they committed a crime while here illegals and were incarcerated, but not deported. “In response to an inquiry from the House Judiciary Committee in July 2015, ICE reported that the 30,558 criminal aliens it released, instead of deported, in FY 2014 were convicted of an additional 1,423 offenses,” read FAIR’s press release. “However, the ICE records that were requested by The Immigration Reform Law Institute (IRLI) on FAIR’s behalf show that the actual number of subsequent convictions racked up by the criminal aliens ICE released in FY 2014 was actually 13,288. It is important to note that not all criminal charges result in convictions. Thus, the number of offenses committed by criminal aliens ICE turned loose is likely significantly greater.” “The criminal aliens responsible for these 13,288 convictions were not considered sufficiently dangerous to be deported under ICE’s self-declared ‘priorities’ for removal,” the press release added. “The list of convictions for offenses committed by criminals ICE did not deem worthy of deportation in FY 2014 includes: homicide, kidnapping, assault, sexual assault, drunk driving, and other offenses. Yet despite the clear knowledge that its policies resulted in thousands of avoidable crimes, ICE doubled down in FY 2015—releasing nearly 20,000 additional deportable criminals.” “In recent years, the number of criminal aliens deported has plummeted, despite ample funds to remove many more. As a result of Obama administration policies that place protection of illegal aliens—including criminals—over the safety of the American public, thousands of people have been needlessly victimized,” charged Dan Stein, president of FAIR. “Rather than end dangerous politically-driven policies that have put a total of 85,000 deportable criminal aliens back onto the streets in the last three years, ICE tried to hide them by providing grossly inaccurate information to Congress and the American people,” added Stein. “Moreover, despite knowing the true extent of the criminal activities committed by the aliens they were releasing, DHS scrapped the Secure Communities program designed to allow ICE to take custody of criminal aliens who are being held by local police.” “Congress has to act. It is being lied to by an administration that is misrepresenting the facts and a president that refuses to enforce immigration laws in favor of manipulating policy for political gain,” Stein concluded. In March of 2015 Freedom of Information Act Documents exposed the fact that 165,900 convicted criminal illegals were released on the streets of the US by Homeland Security. They were not deported. In fact, so-called “sanctuary cities” released 9,000 criminal illegals in 9 months during 2015 who were supposed to be deported, but never were. In 2014, it was also reported the administration released 75% of illegals rather than deport them. It appears to me that DHS needs to be renamed the Department of Homeland IN-Security. What do you think? Reposted With Permission From Freedom Outpost  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>295</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>587</end>
        <start>296</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>920</end>
        <start>588</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1590</end>
        <start>921</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2170</end>
        <start>1591</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2520</end>
        <start>2171</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3052</end>
        <start>2521</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3276</end>
        <start>3053</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3618</end>
        <start>3277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3717</end>
        <start>3619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3822</end>
        <start>3718</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3868</end>
        <start>3823</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3869</end>
        <start>3869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4015</end>
        <start>3870</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4089</end>
        <start>4016</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>264</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>465</end>
        <start>423</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>535</end>
        <start>511</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1134</end>
        <start>922</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1589</end>
        <start>1164</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1762</end>
        <start>1592</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2169</end>
        <start>1790</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2481</end>
        <start>2172</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2785</end>
        <start>2522</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3051</end>
        <start>2801</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3258</end>
        <start>3054</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3510</end>
        <start>3494</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4051</end>
        <start>4039</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama Administration “Grossly Misrepresenting” Crimes Committed by Illegal Aliens!</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36833/obama-administration-grossly-misrepresenting-crimes-committed-by-illegal-aliens/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
