<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://www.toddstarnes.com/column/walmart-workers-refuse-to-make-cops-retirement-cake">
        <end>346</end>
        <start>311</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Man, at this rate I’m going to run out of places to shop. Walmart proved and admitted they have cop-hating asshats working for them. This one happened in Georgia… the daughter of an officer who is retiring went to get him a cake. On it, it said ‘Blue Lives Matter’ with a think blue line on a black background. What the hell is racist about that? Three workers (who should all be fired) refused to decorate the cake for the retirement party. These morons don’t seem to actually know the definition of ‘racist’. What’s worse is Walmart admits this happened. This officer served faithfully on the force, risking his life every day for 25 years. And these mush heads decided that they were too offended to do a cake for a police officer. “One of the bakers told me the design could be perceived as racist and nobody feels comfortable decorating the cake,” the police officer’s daughter said. Then they should not be working there. Shame on Walmart for not firing these three cop-haters. From Todd Starnes: Three Walmart workers in McDonough, Georgia refused to decorate a “thin blue line” cake for a police officer’s retirement party because they said it was racist. A number of my Georgia readers alerted me to the story and on Saturday night I spoke directly with the police officer’s daughter. She asked that I not divulge her name and I’ve agreed to honor her request. “I was so shocked,” she told me. “I didn’t know what to do or say or anything. I was trying not to lose my temper or make a scene.” “The baker told me the blue line cake was racist” — POLICE OFFICER’S DAUGHTER “I just wanted to make my dad a cake to show how much i appreciated him.” As an alternative, the officer’s daughter suggested a chocolate-frosted cake with a horizontal, frosted blue line. But that design was also rejected by Walmart’s cake decorator. “She said, ‘I don’t feel comfortable doing this,’” the cop’s daughter said. “I asked her, ‘Is there something wrong with cops?’” After being rejected for a third time, the 21 year-old told the bakers, “I’ll find another bakery, thank you.” That Walmart should be boycotted. It’s in McDonough, Georgia on Willow Drive for those of you who would like to let them know how you feel about this outrageous behavior. The officer’s daughter was far more polite than I would have been. I would have gladly made a huge, ongoing scene and then I would have called the media. Then I would have gone to social media with it. I would have shamed them to hell and back. “I was disappointed,” she told me. “I go to Walmart all the time — at least once a week spend hundreds of dollars. I just wanted to make my dad a cake to show how much I appreciated him.” This just pisses me off. A friend of the family did indeed put this on Facebook and what do you know… management called the police officer’s wife and daughter and apologized. Sort of. “He said he was so sorry,” the daughter said. “He offered to make the cake free of charge and he gave me a $50 gift card.” Walmart confirmed the story, but they did not admit their employees called the cake racist. Only that the employee made a ‘mistake’. Damn right they did… I’d still boycott them. Now, for the cherry on this cake. The manager offered to make and decorate a new cake. But there was just one problem — the cake decorators refused to comply. “So the manager told me that he would decorate it — but it looked terrible,” the police officer’s daughter said. “It doesn’t look professional.” In the end, the daughter did not have time to get a cake after all this. Walmart should be ashamed. “It irritates me that in Charlotte, North Carolina, the Walmart was looted and the cops were protecting them,” she said. “And you can’t make a cake for the people who are protecting you?” Walmart has hired a bunch of low class, anti-cop bigots. They need to be fired and Walmart needs to make this right.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>510</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>983</end>
        <start>511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1002</end>
        <start>984</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1163</end>
        <start>1003</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1369</end>
        <start>1164</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1501</end>
        <start>1370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1579</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1653</end>
        <start>1580</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2242</end>
        <start>1654</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2700</end>
        <start>2243</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3160</end>
        <start>2701</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3564</end>
        <start>3161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3752</end>
        <start>3565</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3869</end>
        <start>3753</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3870</end>
        <start>3870</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3871</end>
        <start>3871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>851</end>
        <start>736</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1084</end>
        <start>1070</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1388</end>
        <start>1371</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1404</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1550</end>
        <start>1503</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1652</end>
        <start>1581</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1881</end>
        <start>1833</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1959</end>
        <start>1909</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2070</end>
        <start>2034</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2508</end>
        <start>2489</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2674</end>
        <start>2524</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2885</end>
        <start>2861</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2981</end>
        <start>2907</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3395</end>
        <start>3321</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3463</end>
        <start>3434</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3674</end>
        <start>3566</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3751</end>
        <start>3687</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1003</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Walmart REFUSED To Make Officers ‘Racist’ Retirement Cake, Wait Till You See How “Racist” It Was!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/walmart-refused-make-officers-racist-retirement-cake-wait-till-see-racist/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
