<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="http://cnsnews.com/news/article/lauretta-brown/pro-abortion-leader-compares-hyde-amendment-restrictions-taxpayer-funded">
        <end>1420</end>
        <start>1405</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>You’ve probably seen the bumper stickers that say, “Don’t like abortion? Don’t have one!” Perhaps during the slavery debate in our country, a similar bumper sticker could have read, “Don’t like slavery? Don’t own one!” Proponents argue that abortion doesn’t affect most people, so people shouldn’t care. It’s between a woman and her doctor. They say that pro-lifers shouldn’t be able to force their worldview down everyone else’s throats. They shouldn’t be able – through legislation – to “force” childbirth on women who don’t want to have babies. So, since the issue isn’t affecting anyone, except the mother – and the baby who doesn’t get a say, but that’s beside the point – it should be left solely up to the woman and her right to do with her body what she wants. (Even though the baby isn’t her body.) You could say the same thing about slavery. It didn’t affect anyone except the slave owner – and the slave, but they didn’t view slaves as people then (kind of like how unborn babies aren’t people either) – so, if you didn’t like slavery, good for you. Don’t own any. And don’t force your worldview down everyone else’s throats. Well, here’s one activist and head of an abortion rights group who’s comparing abortion to slavery. Except, she’s arguing that not allowing federal funding for abortion is tantamount to slavery. And allowing federal funding for abortion would be “setting women free.” Here’s CNS News: Kierra Johnson, executive director of URGE: Unite for Reproductive and Gender Equity, testified Friday before the House Judiciary Committee examining the Hyde Amendment, which forbids the use of federal funds for abortion except in cases of rape and incest, and compared the amendment to slavery, saying that repealing the Hyde Amendment is about “setting us (women) free.” Johnson responded to a question on the impact of the Hyde amendment on low-income women, referencing an earlier comment from Rep. Trent Franks (R-Ariz.) in which he compared the Supreme Court’s Dred Scott decision to abortion, saying, “It’s interesting that we’re bringing up slavery in this space. When you own somebody’s decision-making, you own them.” “The Hyde amendment is about increasing coverage of insurance,” she argued. “It is about returning decision-making back to women. It’s about setting us free. “When you get to decide for them whether or not their body has value, you own them whether you decide they’re valuable as black or not, you actually don’t get to make that decision,” Johnson emphasized. “We are valuable, and women are valuable. The Hyde amendment simply says set us free,” she said. “We are not simple-minded. We are not being duped. Women are choosing to be pregnant and have children. The majority of women who have abortions are parents. They care, they care about their families.” “We should repeal the Hyde Amendment,” she concluded. There should be no federal funding for abortion, period, regardless of how the baby was conceived. In the vast majority of cases, people want abortion for convenience. They want sex without consequences. Even in the cases of rape and incest – while those instances are tragic – you don’t punish the baby. It wasn’t the baby’s fault. The baby merely becomes an innocent bystander. Instead of punishing the baby, the rapist should be the one to be aborted.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>218</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>547</end>
        <start>219</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>807</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1136</end>
        <start>808</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1421</end>
        <start>1137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1422</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2150</end>
        <start>1796</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2308</end>
        <start>2151</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2511</end>
        <start>2309</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2810</end>
        <start>2512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2864</end>
        <start>2811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3068</end>
        <start>2865</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3319</end>
        <start>3069</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3320</end>
        <start>3320</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3466</end>
        <start>3321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3540</end>
        <start>3467</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>88</end>
        <start>52</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>217</end>
        <start>183</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>392</end>
        <start>387</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1403</end>
        <start>1384</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1794</end>
        <start>1770</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2149</end>
        <start>2032</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2213</end>
        <start>2152</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2490</end>
        <start>2228</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2597</end>
        <start>2513</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2809</end>
        <start>2610</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2848</end>
        <start>2812</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1787</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3502</end>
        <start>3490</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Abortion Proponent Says Taking Away Federal Funding of Abortion is SLAVERY</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37031/abortion-proponent-says-taking-away-federal-funding-of-abortion-is-slavery/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
