<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d1Q73e">
        <end>1311</end>
        <start>1290</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2dbpl62">
        <end>1358</end>
        <start>1334</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2dj8X3X">
        <end>2708</end>
        <start>2686</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2dcRYnX">
        <end>2783</end>
        <start>2761</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1M75UbX">
        <end>2833</end>
        <start>2809</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://lat.ms/2dbytHw">
        <end>4028</end>
        <start>4007</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cS3ov5">
        <end>4900</end>
        <start>4876</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/clk/313631530;141405222;h">
        <end>5596</end>
        <start>5515</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://wapo.st/2cEXM4o">
        <end>6911</end>
        <start>6889</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cvLeP4">
        <end>8055</end>
        <start>8031</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://apne.ws/2dbqTN7">
        <end>8619</end>
        <start>8597</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.wsj.com/2cLxUZU">
        <end>8750</end>
        <start>8725</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://fxn.ws/2cEWB4O">
        <end>8918</end>
        <start>8897</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dcS6Uh">
        <end>8997</end>
        <start>8976</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cnn.it/2cIASuJ">
        <end>9660</end>
        <start>9639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://thebea.st/2d1YGLH">
        <end>10165</end>
        <start>10141</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cLftEw">
        <end>10540</end>
        <start>10519</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cnlYXO">
        <end>10707</end>
        <start>10686</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cMdvnz">
        <end>10777</end>
        <start>10756</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2d3oYeF">
        <end>11893</end>
        <start>11869</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d2Tju2">
        <end>13944</end>
        <start>13923</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://53eig.ht/2daFuIS">
        <end>14627</end>
        <start>14604</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.wsj.com/2cIb41M">
        <end>15384</end>
        <start>15359</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2dkgFNJ">
        <end>15584</end>
        <start>15563</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.time.com/athletes">
        <end>15610</end>
        <start>15589</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/clk/313631529;141405222;p">
        <end>15767</end>
        <start>15715</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2djIy8K">
        <end>18033</end>
        <start>18012</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.ft.com/2cIxUGH">
        <end>18794</end>
        <start>18770</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.wsj.com/2cNd7Fj">
        <end>20392</end>
        <start>20367</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://youtu.be/TwpuhCHppHk">
        <end>21205</end>
        <start>21177</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cWmGMy">
        <end>21236</end>
        <start>21215</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cMevI3">
        <end>21721</end>
        <start>21697</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2d3uQF3">
        <end>22132</end>
        <start>22108</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cIYBLj">
        <end>22331</end>
        <start>22310</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nbcnews.to/2cSfqTA">
        <end>22721</end>
        <start>22696</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://on.msnbc.com/2cWlGrG">
        <end>22757</end>
        <start>22730</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cpYu9i">
        <end>23418</end>
        <start>23397</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cnrgCN">
        <end>24433</end>
        <start>24412</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2ditCoM">
        <end>25290</end>
        <start>25269</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cMetQH">
        <end>26460</end>
        <start>26436</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27e678973237540b2c24276ad69c745b973abd98144e0c210a">
        <end>2833</end>
        <start>2809</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a2767f4940442aff97e7c066c727f9c20288dbf3b9a9c94af0b">
        <end>28418</end>
        <start>28394</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1OypFe9">
        <end>28462</end>
        <start>28438</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a274cd0c60878dc0107a2877730f30a3cf31907ea80300291ab">
        <end>28511</end>
        <start>28487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1Nhtq5v">
        <end>28563</end>
        <start>28539</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27c2d30196dfdcef3b79d2e10c2707bcce21999529adf1def8">
        <end>28610</end>
        <start>28586</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2bLvcPl">
        <end>28658</end>
        <start>28634</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1FZeLcw">
        <end>28705</end>
        <start>28681</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27f2079f7785f61ccb759e0f2b4aaa39da6b3d00c5a28d5b28">
        <end>2833</end>
        <start>2809</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Politico POLITICO's must-read briefing on what's driving the day in Washington ANOTHER SHOOTING IN CHARLOTTE -- With 47 days until Election Day, the national conversation is turning once again to a politically fraught set of interlocking issues: race, policing and urban crime. Late last night, Gov. Pat McCrory declared a state of emergency in North Carolina after more protests in Charlotte. One man was shot, and is on life support. National Guard and state highway patrolmen are assisting local police officers. -- CHARLOTTE OBSERVER: “[T]he unrest continued Wednesday night, with police using tear gas to disperse hundreds of protesters who blocked the intersection of Trade and Tryon streets in the heart of uptown, then occupied the EpiCentre entertainment complex. Pockets of the city were on edge late Wednesday afternoon, with some uptown businesses apparently sending workers home early over uncertainty about further protests. The Charlotte Chamber urged businesses in uptown and University City to ‘remove or chain down all tables, chairs, signs or planters.’ At about 4:30 Wednesday, a group of two dozen protesters stood in front of the Bank of America Tower at Trade and Tryon streets. They silently stood and held signs reading ‘Black Lives Matter’ and ‘Stop Killing Us.’” http://bit.ly/2d1Q73e Charlotte Observer A1 http://politi.co/2dbpl62 HEADLINE: “Violent protests return as city seeks answers” Story Continued Below --NYT’s Richard Fausset and Alan Blinder: “A second night of protests set off by the police killing of a black man spiraled into chaos and violence after nightfall here Wednesday when a demonstration was interrupted by gunfire that gravely wounded a man in the crowd. Law enforcement authorities fired tear gas in a desperate bid to restore order. The city said on its Twitter account that the unidentified man was on life support after what officials said was a ‘civilian on civilian’ confrontation. The authorities provided no further details. Charlotte officials had said earlier that the man had been killed in the unrest. The Police Department reported that four officers had injuries that were not life-threatening … “The gunshot victim lay motionless on the ground, his eyes open, as people surrounded him and blood pooled among their feet. He was taken into the nearby Omni Hotel, and a series of confrontations played out afterward as the police kept people from entering. There was sporadic looting. Twitter messages showed that the team store of the Charlotte Hornets of the N.B.A. had been broken into and gutted of merchandise. ‘We are working very hard to bring peace and calm back to our city,’ Mayor Jennifer Roberts said on CNN.” http://nyti.ms/2dj8X3X … A1 (lead story has large photo of gunshot victim) http://nyti.ms/2dcRYnX **SUBSCRIBE to Playbook: http://politi.co/1M75UbX TRUMP AT THE SEAN HANNITY/FOX NEWS TOWN HALL (taped yesterday) -- Q: “[T]here’s been a lot of violence in the black community. I wanted to know what you would do to help stop that violence, black-on-black crime.” TRUMP: “Right. Well one of the things I’d do … is I would do stop and frisk. I think you have to. We did it in New York, it worked incredibly well. And you have to be proactive. And you know you really help people sort of change their mind automatically … I see what’s going on here, I see what’s going on in Chicago...in New York City it was so incredibly, the way it worked. Now, we had a very good mayor. But New York City was incredible the way it worked. So I think that would be one step you could do.” (Airing of the town hall was pushed back due to the chaos in Charlotte.) CLINTON, IN ORLANDO -- Here’s what she said on the shooting in Charlotte and Tulsa, before last night’s violence in Charlotte: “We have two more names to add to a list of African Americans killed by police officers in these encounters … It’s unbearable. And it needs to become intolerable. … We are safer when communities respect the police and police respect the communities.” http://lat.ms/2dbytHw Good Thursday morning. THANK YOU to the people who showed up yesterday outside the Capitol South Metro to have breakfast with us at the PLAYBOOK FOOD TRUCK. We’re at 2nd and D streets N.E. from now until 10 a.m. REMINDER: Breakfast is free! Coffee, egg sandwiches and veggie breakfast burritos. Tomorrow we’ll be at 1700 K Street, NW. We also want to extend a BIG thank you to Rep. John Lewis (D-Ga.) for joining us for Playbook Cocktails last night. He filled a massive room in the W Hotel with hundreds of people on just a few days notice. The civil rights icon talked about his role in launching the National Museum of African American History and Culture, why he’s not interested in joining a Clinton administration and told us that he’s unafraid of Republicans punishing Democrats for the guns sit in on the House floor. Click here for more: http://politi.co/2cS3ov5 WHAT THE HILL WANTS TO KNOW -- When will Congress go home for its final campaign push? There’s still a lot of haggling over the stopgap spending bill, which will keep the government from closing at the end of the month. Jake’s guess is that they leave for the weekend, and come back next week and wrap things up. McConnell has basically signaled as much. Plus, who wants a weekend session when it’s going to be beautiful in Washington -- and members want to head back home to campaign? **** A message from BP: Over the past 10 years, no energy company has invested more in the U.S. than BP – $90 billion in total. Take 90 seconds to see what else we’re doing to help keep America moving forward. ****** STATE OF THE ART -- “Clinton makes an unusual push: To win over disabled people and their families,” by WaPo’s John Wagner and Abby Phillip in Orlando: “Democratic presidential nominee Hillary Clinton is pushing intensively to win over a group of voters who don’t typically get much attention during elections but who have become an increasingly potent political force: disabled people and their families. With the race tighter than it was a month ago and Clinton struggling to generate enthusiasm within the Democratic base, her appeal to disabled people and their families comes amid a broader effort to win over voters. After weeks of mostly attacking Republican Donald Trump, she is highlighting specific policy prescriptions while trying to show a more compassionate side and present an affirmative vision for the country. “Clinton is also targeting Hispanics, women, caretakers of the elderly and sick, and families of gun-violence victims, among other constituencies focused on specific issues. In the case of the disability community, which cuts across all partisan and demographic divides, Clinton may be trying to attract not only ­Democratic-leaning voters who are not excited by her candidacy, but also voters who may be leaning toward Trump -- notably disabled veterans.” http://wapo.st/2cEXM4o -- “Trump’s bizarre ad strategy: It’s less than 50 days until the election and the GOP nominee’s television advertisements have all but vanished,” by Steven Shepard: “Trump’s ads last ran nearly a week ago in four battleground states: Florida, North Carolina, Ohio and Pennsylvania. Since then, the GOP presidential nominee has ceded the airwaves to Hillary Clinton -- and is only poised to launch a limited, less-targeted ad campaign in the days before next week’s debate. “While his campaign announced a new ad on Tuesday, it’s only going to run on national cable news stations and during two Sunday morning public-affairs shows, according to data from The Tracking Firm, a company that monitors media buys. And even with that seemingly modest buy — the full extent of which wasn’t clear on Wednesday night — Clinton is still outspending him this week many times over. ‘It’s unprecedented for a major-party nominee in this century to have such an on-again, off-again TV buy,’ said Elizabeth Wilner, a former TV-network political director who, until last month, monitored political advertising for Kantar Media/CMAG.” http://politi.co/2cvLeP4 -- “Trump: I reversed birther stance ‘to get on with’ campaign,” by AP’s Jill Colvin in New York: “In a brief interview with an Ohio television station Wednesday, [Donald] Trump was asked why, after years as the chief proponent of the falsehood that the president was born outside the country, he decided to announce Friday that was no longer the case. What had changed his mind? ‘Well, I just wanted to get on with, you know, we want to get on with the campaign,’ the GOP nominee responded. ‘And a lot of people were asking me questions.’” http://apne.ws/2dbqTN7 POLLS -- CHOOSE YOUR NEWS -- WSJ/NBC: Hillary Clinton 43, Donald Trump 37, Gary Johnson 9, Jill Stein 3. http://on.wsj.com/2cLxUZU … FOX NEWS -- N.C.: Donald Trump 45, Hillary Clinton 40 … OHIO: Donald Trump 42, Hillary Clinton 37… NEVADA: Donald Trump 43, Hillary Clinton 40. http://fxn.ws/2cEWB4O … MONMOUTH -- N.H.: Hillary Clinton 47, Donald Trump 38. http://bit.ly/2dcS6Uh POLL TWEETS -- @mattmfm: “Clinton firewall (CO, VA, PA, NH) is holding, new @MonmouthPoll in New Hampshire confirms.” … @alexburnsNYT (referring to the WSJ poll): “Like 1992, but with 3rd party vote fractured.” --“Pence set to attend first presidential debate,” by CNN’s Elizabeth Landers: “Since presidential debates resumed in 1976, running mates have generally watched their top-of-the-ticket partners from a distance, such as at campaign headquarters or via television surrounded by friends, family and supporters. The adviser said the decision wasn’t so much a strategy move, as Pence ‘likes to be there for Mr. Trump in big moments.’” http://cnn.it/2cIASuJ -- @JamesPindell: “C-SPAN will have split-screen showing both candidates throughout the presidential debates.” HAPPENING TODAY -- Donald Trump is in Chester Township, Pennsylvania, for an evening rally. Mike Pence is in Colorado Springs, Colorado. Hillary Clinton has no public events scheduled. Tim Kaine is in Reno, Nevada, at the University of Nevada - Reno, Lincoln &amp; Meta Fitzgerald Student Services Building. JUST POSTED -- Daily Beast’s Olivia Nuzzi talks to Marla Maples! http://thebea.st/2d1YGLH VIDEOS DU JOUR -- “SAVE THE DAY” -- A bunch of celebrities -- including Robert Downey Jr., Leslie Odom Jr. and Neil Patrick Harris -- urge people to register to vote to stop Donald Trump. They don’t mention his name. Funny moment: They say Mark Ruffalo, a Bernie Sanders supporter who was in the video, will get naked in his next movie if Clinton wins. http://bit.ly/2cLftEw … @MarkHalperin: “These days everyone has their own @realDonaldTrump impression. Turns out he has just one for everyone else via @AlexanderTrow” http://bit.ly/2cnlYXO NEW AD – “Consensus” from March for Life Action http://bit.ly/2cMdvnz CLINTON INC. -- “Bill Clinton on CGI legacy: ‘You have to keep this alive’: The former president defends the Clinton Global Initiative’s work and urges supporters to carry on its mission,” by Louis Nelson and Annie Karni: “Bill Clinton doesn’t want his life's work to fade quietly into the night. In a personal speech defending his legacy at the Clinton Global Initiative — from its humble roots in his Harlem office to the international, star-studded conference it has become — the former president pleaded with the crowd Wednesday evening that the work couldn’t end. ‘You have to keep this alive,’ he said. “But in its current version, Clinton’s organization is dying. The former president's speech marked the official end of CGI, a glitzy, 12-year-old conference that convened Fortune 500 CEOs, movie stars, world leaders and nonprofit do-gooders in New York City during the United Nations meeting. There, they forged partnerships and made commitments to collaborate on projects such as saving elephants, improving AIDS relief in Africa and fighting for women’s rights across the globe.” http://politi.co/2d3oYeF ARTICLE OF THE DAY – “Barack Obama and Doris Kearns Goodwin: The Ultimate Exit Interview” – November’s Vanity Fair -- GOODWIN: “[W]hat F.D.R. used to say: ‘I think of the things that have come before me during the day and the decisions that I have made, I say to myself—well, I have done the best I could and turn over and go to sleep.” OBAMA: “Exactly. Another good example of that is the situation in Syria, which haunts me constantly. I would say of all the things that have happened during the course of my presidency the knowledge that you have hundreds of thousands of people who have been killed, millions who have been displaced, [makes me] ask myself what might I have done differently along the course of the last five, six years. The conventional arguments about what could have been done are wrong. The notion that if we had provided some more modest arms to Syrian rebels—that somehow that would have led to [Syrian president Bashar al-] Assad’s overthrow more decisively. The notion that if I had taken a pinprick strike when the chemical-weapons issue came out, as opposed to negotiating and getting all those chemical weapons out—that that would have been decisive. “All those things I tend to be skeptical about. But I do ask myself, Was there something that we hadn’t thought of? Was there some move that is beyond what was being presented to me that maybe a Churchill could have seen, or an Eisenhower might have figured out? So that’s the kind of thing that tends to occupy me when I have the time to think about it—mainly because I think that in this job one of the things you realize is there are problems that just end up being really hard and by definition the only problems that come to my desk are the ones that nobody else can solve. Usually, I’m pretty good about sorting through the options and then making decisions that I’m confident are the best decisions in that moment, given the information we have. But there are times where I think I wish I could have imagined a different level of insight.” http://bit.ly/2d2Tju2 CASH DASH – “The GOP’s Jewish Donors Are Abandoning Trump,” by Five Thirty Eight’s Eitan Hersh and Brian Schaffner: “In 2012, 71 percent of the $160 million that Jewish donors gave to the two major-party nominees went to President Obama’s re-election campaign; 29 percent went to Mitt Romney’s campaign, according to our analysis of campaign contributors, which used a predictive model to estimate which donors are Jewish based on their names and other characteristics. ... So far in 2016, of all the money given to major-party candidates by donors who appear to be Jewish, 95 percent has gone to Hillary Clinton and just 5 percent has gone to Donald Trump.” http://53eig.ht/2daFuIS FED WATCH -- “Yellen Says Fed Isn’t Playing Politics With Interest Rates,” by WSJ’s Kate Davidson: “[Federal Reserve Chairwoman Janet] Yellen, referring to prepared notes and not mentioning Mr. Trump by name, said the Fed doesn’t discuss politics at its policy meetings, nor does it take politics into account. Its decision to hold rates steady on Wednesday was based on economic factors, not political ones, she said. ‘I can say, emphatically that partisan politics plays no role in our decisions about the appropriate stance of monetary policy,’ she said. ‘We are trying to decide what the best policy is to foster price stability and maximum employment and to manage the variety of risks that we see as affecting the outlook.’” http://on.wsj.com/2cIb41M COVER DU JOUR – new TIME cover, “The Perilous Fight: National anthem protests led by Colin Kaepernick are fueling a debate about privilege, pride and patriotism.” See the cover: http://bit.ly/2dkgFNJ ... www.time.com/athletes **** A message from BP: We’ve donated $147 million to U.S. community programs over the past five years. Check out the programs we support in your community. ****** WASHINGTON INC. -- The American Legislative Exchange Council is publicly commenting after Enterprise Rental Car resigned immediately from the controversial conservative legislative group focused on state politics. Enterprise is just the latest company to head for the exits after sustained public shaming campaigns by multiple groups. “It’s true and unfortunate. They were forced to leave after sustained pressure. There was a month-long campaign: first article on 8/21; followed by petitions at moveon, change, color of change, and standuptoALEC; a ‘twitter storm;’ threats by CBC, Rashad Robinson and Sheldon Whitehouse; and, finally threats by unions to stop renting cars,” wrote ALEC’s Bill Meierling. “It’s a clear campaign to marginalize, harass and intimidate an effective organization of conservatives and get business out of policy. Washington, DC should be afraid of this new and clearly-documented strategy.” VALLEY WATCH -- “Tech Workers Wade Into Political Hot Zone,” by The Information’s Cory Weinberg: “For years, housing activists have blamed the fast-growing tech industry for causing housing shortages in the Bay Area. But now that tech employees are themselves struggling to pay high rents, they’re starting to get more politically active in dealing with housing issues. Take Adrian Fine, a city strategist with the social network Nextdoor, who is running for city council in his hometown of Palo Alto in November’s elections. As part of his agenda, Mr. Fine wants to make it easier for apartment buildings to get built in some parts of the town, expanding housing for tech employees and young transplants trying to start families. Separately, employees at Lyft and Postmates this year have started groups like ‘Tech for Housing’ advocating for housing development. And employees from Facebook and Palantir have won appointments to city planning commissions in Menlo Park, Redwood City and Palo Alto… “But increased tech involvement with local politics sets up a potential clash with increasingly intense anti-tech forces. Palo Alto’s mayor, Patrick Burt, for instance, has lately proposed banning tech firms from the city’s downtown. Mr. Burt has described the growth of tech companies in the city as ‘not healthy.’” http://bit.ly/2djIy8K --“Apple in talks with luxury carmaker McLaren,” by FT’s Matt Garrahan in NYC and Tim Bradshaw in SF: “Apple has approached McLaren Technology Group, the British supercar engineer and Formula One team owner, about a potential acquisition, in the clearest sign yet that the iPhone maker is seeking to transform the automotive industry. ... A tie-up with McLaren, whose expertise ranges from automotive engineering and on-board computer systems to novel chassis materials such as carbon fibre and aluminium, could accelerate Apple’s secretive automotive project. ... [The potential deal] would make it Apple’s biggest acquisition since the $3bn purchase of Beats Electronics, the audio group founded by Dr Dre and Jimmy Iovine, in 2014.” http://on.ft.com/2cIxUGH ON WALL ST. -- “SEC Accuses Leon Cooperman of Insider Trading: Regulators allege Omega Advisors chief made a total of more than $4 million in illegal profits,” by WSJ’s Juliet Chung, Aruna Viswanatha and Christopher Matthews: “The [SEC] accused hedge-fund manager Leon G. Cooperman and his firm, Omega Advisors Inc., of insider trading, marking the culmination of a five-year investigation into suspected securities fraud at one of the country’s best-known funds. The SEC alleged Wednesday that the 73-year-old Mr. Cooperman agreed to refrain from using information he received from a corporate executive but then went ahead and traded on it. Mr. Cooperman, who has kept his investors updated about the government’s investigation, has denied wrongdoing, saying, among other things, that the investment lost money. “‘It took me 50 years of hard work and playing by the rules to get where I got,’ Mr. Cooperman said Wednesday on a conference call with investors, where he mounted a defense. ‘I’m not going to let these people destroy my legacy.’ ... The SEC alleged … Mr. Cooperman, as well as others for which he directed trading, made a total of more than $4 million in illegal profits by trading in Atlas Pipeline Partners LP. Mr. Cooperman … used his status as one of Atlas Pipeline’s largest shareholders to gain access to a corporate executive and obtain confidential details about an asset sale. When the company publicly announced the sale of the facilities in Elk City, Okla., in July 2010, Atlas Pipeline’s stock price jumped more than 31%, according to the SEC.” http://on.wsj.com/2cNd7Fj MAYOR OF THE WORLD -- “As Bill Clinton marked the official end of CGI, Bloomberg Philanthropies and the U.S. Department of Commerce co-hosted the second U.S.-Africa Business Forum on Wednesday at New York’s Plaza Hotel to focus on trade and investment opportunities on the continent for U.S. and African business leaders and heads of state from the U.S. and Africa. President Obama and nearly 40 heads of state attended, plus hundreds of CEOs (including IBM, Cargill, Visa &amp; Caterpillar among others), three U.S. Cabinet Secretaries (Jack Lew, John Kerry, Penny Pritzker) and of course Mike Bloomberg. Big deals were announced: More than $9B in U.S./Africa trade and investment deals were unveiled, including a $300M investment by Blackstone in an African Oil Pipeline.” Video recap: https://youtu.be/TwpuhCHppHk ... Pics http://bit.ly/2cWmGMy MEDIAWATCH -- “POLITICO Announces New POLITICO Pro Health Care Expansion and Partnerships”: “Pro Health Care is hiring three new reporters in California, Boston, and the southeast region who will be responsible for bringing state-level health care news to a national audience, joining our nine Washington-based reporters. Additionally, Pro Health Care is excited to announce a year-long polling partnership with the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health.” http://politi.co/2cMevI3 -- “Corey Lewandowski to be paid severance by Trump campaign through 2016,” by Kelsey Sutton and Hadas Gold: “Donald Trump’s former campaign manager, Corey Lewandowski, will continue to be paid severance by the campaign through the end of 2016, prolonging concerns of a conflict of interest for CNN, which controversially hired Lewandowski in June to serve as a political commentator.” http://politi.co/2d3uQF3 GENIUS GRANT WINNERS -- The 2016 class of MacArthur “genius grant” winners has been announced. Sarah Stillman, a D.C. native and New Yorker staff writer, is one of the winners. http://bit.ly/2cIYBLj CHUCK TODD “sat down with Iran President Rouhani [yesterday] in an exclusive interview, the only U.S. television interview the president is doing. Of note, Chuck asked him ‘Can Iran live with a Syria that is not headed by Assad?’ And Rouhani replied that ‘Syria doesn’t have a military solution. And the Syrians’ problems must certainly be resolved politically.’” http://nbcnews.to/2cSfqTA … Video http://on.msnbc.com/2cWlGrG SPOTTED: Sens. Ted Cruz and Marco Rubio walking into a Rubio fundraiser last night at the NRSC. “It was not awkward at all,” according to one Playbooker … Justice Elena Kagan yesterday “looking like she was carefully listening to the conversation over lunch with younger-looking group of 5 people at Zaytinya.” ... Jim Messina last night at Joe’s Seafood, Prime Steak &amp; Stone Crab near the White House with a glass of wine while waiting at the bar. WELCOME TO THE WORLD – @Senjohnthune posts on Instagram: “It’s official: We’re grandparents. Say hello to Henley Joy Hargens. She’s a little early but Larissa and baby girl doing fine.” Pic http://bit.ly/2cpYu9i REMEMBERING REP. STEVE LATOURETTE -- Tuesday afternoon a memorial service was held in honor of former Rep. Steve LaTourette (R-Ohio) at Temple Ref Shalom in Falls Church. Eulogists include Rep. Bill Shuster (R-Pa.) and Rep. Pat Tiberi (R-Ohio), and Emerson and Henry LaTourette, children of Steve and his wife, Jennifer. Steve was first elected to the Congress in 1994 and retired from the House in 2013, and served as president of the Main Street Partnership. SPOTTED: Sen. Roy Blunt (R-Mo.), House Minority Whip Steny Hoyer (D-Md.), Kim Dorgan; Linda Daschle, MB Savary Taylor and Emily Porter of the Nickles Group, Fred Graefe, Lori Rowley of the Lugar Center. -- On Tuesday night at the Landmark E Street Cinema, the Red Cross presented Tom Donahue’s documentary “Thank You For Your Service” about the veteran suicide crisis. Sens. Angus King and Joe Donnelly were in attendance and CBS News’ National Security Correspondent David Martin moderated the Q&amp;A following the screening. Trailer http://bit.ly/2cnrgCN --NARAL held its fourth-annual #MenForChoice party last night at Baby Wale. The cocktail of the evening was the Ruth Bader Ginsburg, “fruity blend of sloe gin, cava, and fresh lemon.” SPOTTED: Montana Sen. Jon Tester, David Brock, Ilyse Hogue, WaPo’s Danielle Paquette, Niels Lesniewski, the DCCC’s Jenn Ridder, Molly Murphy, Tyler Law, John Neffinger, Will Robinson, Alexandra Khoo, Steve Kerrigan, Kimball Stroud, John Liipfert, Ralph Burns, Suzi Emmerling, Leah Chandler, Ron Bracco, Tony Massaro, Emily Pomeranz, Alexa Combelic, Scott Fay, and Bradley Beychock. HAPPENING TODAY -- Taxpayers for Common Sense is holding an event this afternoon marking the 30th Anniversary of the Tax Reform Act of 1986. “Showdown at Gucci Gulch Revisited: Lessons Learned from 1986 Tax Reform” today from 4 to 6 p.m. at B338 Rayburn Building. RSVP http://bit.ly/2ditCoM ENGAGED: LA Times’ California delegation reporter Sarah Wire proposed to her boyfriend of seven years John Bethel, who is in kitchen and bathroom remodeling, over the weekend. The two met at the University of Missouri and Wire writes “have stuck together moving from Missouri to Arkansas to Washington three years ago. Proposal happened on the balcony of our Bloomingdale apartment with the aid of our hound Penny.” TRANSITIONS -- Meredith McGehee, policy director at the Campaign Legal Center and a top political ethics advocate, is joining Issue One beginning Oct. 3 as chief of policy, programs and strategy. (She will continue as an advisor at Campaign Legal Center.) --CLINTON ALUMNI – “Two of the nation’s leading event production firms are merging to form Peak XV, a global event and communications team. Chris Wayne and Mark Poncher, the creative and production minds behind some of this decade’s most memorable largescale political and sports events, will lead the new entity. ... Wayne served in the Clinton Administration as a special assistant to the president, where he managed President Clinton’s official events for seven years.” http://politi.co/2cMetQH BIRTHDAYS: “Campaign” Carl Cameron, a dean of the presidential election press corps and one of the hardest-working reporters on the trail, is forever young at 55 (h/t Nick Kalman) … Amy Chozick, the pride of the Lower East Side (h/t Bushwick) … Politico’s Sarah Cabrera ... TJ Ducklo, comms director for Bloomberg Politics, is 28 (h/t Sam Newton, filing from Jamestown in New York’s 23rd congressional district) ... MFA’s EVP and COO Marc Charon ... Rita Medina, pride of the Inland Empire now the immigration campaign manager at CAP Action (h/t Michael Prather) ... Rep. Robert Goodlatte (R-Va.) is 62 ... Caroline Schaberg, “social velocity” at Bloomberg ... Natalie Daly, daughter of Brendan … Tommy “The Bull” Burr … Katie McBreen, National Retail Federation V.P. of comms and public affairs and a Chamber alum … Jon Romano, DOT’s senior advisor for strategic comms, branding fanatic and a MWW alum (h/ts Jennifer (Paolino) Romano and son Leo) … Outside magazine’s Molly Mirhashem, a National Journal alum (h/t Colby Bermel) ... … TJ Helmstetter, DNC’s deputy director of regional and specialty media ... Justin Germany, a McCain and Bush alum now at Outlaw Media, is 37 ... Lavin Gartland ... Shannon Graves ... Lynn Reed … Rahlyn Gossen … Jack Pagano … Hayley Zachary … Stacy Kerr, assistant V.P. for comms. at Georgetown, and a Bill Bradley and DCCC alum … Lois Cassano ... Jennifer Bishop (h/ts Teresa Vilmain) … Chelsie Paulson, a CRAFT alum and #DcInsider gone #Sydneysider, per her Twitter … Diana McLellan ... Tandy Dickerson ... CNN State dept. producer Jamie Crawford … Mike Rossetti … Jennifer Donahue … Nick Everhart … Brett Broesder … Lenox Robb Finlinson … Marco Nunez … Laurel-Manette Hanna ... Ghafoor Bazai ... Michael Masley is 64 ... Brian Wright O’Connor is 6-0 ... Heather Dawn Thompson ... Scott Baio is 56. SUBSCRIBE to the Playbook family: POLITICO Playbook http://politi.co/1M75UbX ... New York Playbook http://politi.co/1ON8bqW … Florida Playbook http://politi.co/1OypFe9 ... New Jersey Playbook http://politi.co/1HLKltF ... Massachusetts Playbook http://politi.co/1Nhtq5v ... Illinois Playbook http://politi.co/1N7u5sb ... California Playbookhttp://politi.co/2bLvcPl ... Brussels Playbook http://politi.co/1FZeLcw ... All our political and policy tipsheets http://politi.co/1M75UbX</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>78</end>
        <start>9</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>515</end>
        <start>79</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1416</end>
        <start>516</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1438</end>
        <start>1417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2161</end>
        <start>1439</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2783</end>
        <start>2162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2833</end>
        <start>2784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3628</end>
        <start>2834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4028</end>
        <start>3629</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4900</end>
        <start>4029</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5386</end>
        <start>4901</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5603</end>
        <start>5387</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6431</end>
        <start>5604</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6911</end>
        <start>6432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7385</end>
        <start>6912</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8055</end>
        <start>7386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8619</end>
        <start>8056</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8997</end>
        <start>8620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9208</end>
        <start>8998</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9660</end>
        <start>9209</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9771</end>
        <start>9661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10075</end>
        <start>9772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10165</end>
        <start>10076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10707</end>
        <start>10166</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10777</end>
        <start>10708</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11386</end>
        <start>10778</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11893</end>
        <start>11387</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>12230</end>
        <start>11894</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>13075</end>
        <start>12231</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>13944</end>
        <start>13076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>14627</end>
        <start>13945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15384</end>
        <start>14628</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15610</end>
        <start>15385</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15774</end>
        <start>15611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>16694</end>
        <start>15775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>17694</end>
        <start>16695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>18033</end>
        <start>17695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>18794</end>
        <start>18034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>19608</end>
        <start>18795</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20392</end>
        <start>19609</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21236</end>
        <start>20393</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21721</end>
        <start>21237</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22132</end>
        <start>21722</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22331</end>
        <start>22133</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22757</end>
        <start>22332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>23206</end>
        <start>22758</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>23418</end>
        <start>23207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>23879</end>
        <start>23419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24082</end>
        <start>23880</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24433</end>
        <start>24083</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24999</end>
        <start>24434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>25290</end>
        <start>25000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>25706</end>
        <start>25291</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>25962</end>
        <start>25707</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>26460</end>
        <start>25963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>27493</end>
        <start>26461</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>28294</end>
        <start>27494</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>28773</end>
        <start>28295</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1288</end>
        <start>540</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1415</end>
        <start>1370</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2684</end>
        <start>1482</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3045</end>
        <start>2904</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3554</end>
        <start>3055</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4005</end>
        <start>3757</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5703</end>
        <start>5625</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6887</end>
        <start>5757</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7057</end>
        <start>6916</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8029</end>
        <start>7079</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8119</end>
        <start>8060</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8595</end>
        <start>8155</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9114</end>
        <start>9024</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9207</end>
        <start>9162</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9258</end>
        <start>9212</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9637</end>
        <start>9289</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9770</end>
        <start>9680</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10197</end>
        <start>10185</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10684</end>
        <start>10559</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10727</end>
        <start>10718</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10965</end>
        <start>10795</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11867</end>
        <start>11001</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11982</end>
        <start>11916</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12229</end>
        <start>12022</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>13921</end>
        <start>12239</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>14003</end>
        <start>13958</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>14602</end>
        <start>14062</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>14701</end>
        <start>14642</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15357</end>
        <start>14728</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15546</end>
        <start>15418</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16450</end>
        <start>16111</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16693</end>
        <start>16482</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16754</end>
        <start>16712</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18010</end>
        <start>16793</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18081</end>
        <start>18037</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18768</end>
        <start>18137</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18953</end>
        <start>18811</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>20365</end>
        <start>19022</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21162</end>
        <start>20416</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21326</end>
        <start>21252</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21695</end>
        <start>21330</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21796</end>
        <start>21726</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22106</end>
        <start>21832</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22198</end>
        <start>22186</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22694</end>
        <start>22344</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22881</end>
        <start>22855</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>23067</end>
        <start>22944</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>23391</end>
        <start>23265</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24213</end>
        <start>24187</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24616</end>
        <start>24568</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>25213</end>
        <start>25142</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>25705</end>
        <start>25526</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>26434</end>
        <start>25983</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>25771</end>
        <start>25763</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>27103</end>
        <start>27088</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>27173</end>
        <start>27165</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>STATE OF EMERGENCY IN CHARLOTTE -- What THE HILL wants to know -- Doris Kearns Goodwin’s ‘ultimate’ OBAMA exit interview -- B’DAY: ‘Campaign’ Carl Cameron</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/tipsheets/playbook/2016/09/state-of-emergency-in-charlotte-what-the-hill-wants-to-know-doris-kearns-goodwins-ultimate-obama-exit-interview-bday-campaign-carl-cameron-216449?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
