<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nathan Wellman</author>
    <mainText>A Louisiana police officer has been fired and arrested after being caught on camera repeatedly beating a burglary suspect while he was handcuffed and lying facedown. Footage of Officer Robert Wallow was found in which he punched 21-year-old Carlos Gustavo in the face after successfully arresting him. Wallow then handcuffed Pineda and then kick him three more times in the head and the side. Gustavo’s arrest occurred on April 22nd, but since Pineda or his attorney did not report any use of excessive force, the incident was not discovered by authorities until Wallow was a subject of an internal inquiry in relation to another case. “It all had been documented,” said Police Chief Arthur Lawson. “It just did not move as quickly as it should have.” Wallow was placed on administrative leave and then fired the next day. The department quickly opened a criminal investigations into Wallow’s cruel tactics. He has been charged with battery and malfeasance in office. “This is not one of the brightest days of the Gretna Police Department,” said Lawson. You can see the footage of the arrest here:       </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>165</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>392</end>
        <start>166</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>635</end>
        <start>393</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>636</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>967</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1053</end>
        <start>968</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1097</end>
        <start>1054</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1098</end>
        <start>1098</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1099</end>
        <start>1099</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1100</end>
        <start>1100</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>1101</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1102</end>
        <start>1102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1103</end>
        <start>1103</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1104</end>
        <start>1104</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>637</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>700</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1039</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Louisiana cop caught on tape kicking handcuffed suspect</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/news/louisiana-cop-caught-tape-kicking-handcuffed-suspect/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
