<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Stephen D Foster Jr</author>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/megyn-kelly-just-threw-serious-shade-at-hannity-during-his-trump-interview/">
        <end>47</end>
        <start>36</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://addictinginfo.org/2016/07/24/watch-sean-hannity-loses-his-sht-because-jon-stewart-humiliated-him-on-colbert/">
        <end>488</end>
        <start>472</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://addictinginfo.org/2016/08/05/sean-hannity-throws-hissy-fit-after-real-reporter-calls-him-dumbest-anchor-on-fox-news/">
        <end>694</end>
        <start>680</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://addictinginfo.org/2016/08/11/the-washington-post-nails-hannity-for-lying-about-trump-rescuing-marines/">
        <end>771</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://addictinginfo.org/2016/08/14/watch-brian-stelter-slams-sean-hannity-for-his-disturbing-lies-about-hillary-clinton-video/">
        <end>894</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://addictinginfo.org/2016/08/15/hannity-gets-his-a-kicked-by-newsweek-for-lying-constantly-and-insulting-people-with-epilepsy/">
        <end>962</end>
        <start>947</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Fox News host Megyn Kelly seemed to take a shot at Sean Hannity on Monday night after the much anticipated first presidential debate when she had to throw the live coverage to an interview between her colleague and Republican nominee Donald Trump. Hannity has been a prime target for just about everyone ever since Trump was formally nominated during the last night of the Republican National Convention in July. Former host Jon Stewart got the ball rolling that night by torching Hannity for being a complete hypocrite when it comes to how he has covered President Obama in the past to how he treats Donald Trump now. Not long after that, foreign affairs columnist Bret Stephens called Hannity the “dumbest anchor on Fox News,” and the followed up by calling Hannity out for lying about Trump coming to the rescue of U.S. Marines. Then CNN’s Brian Stelter piled on by nailing Hannity for lying about Hillary Clinton, and reporter Kurt Eichenwald slammed Hannity for claiming that Hillary suffers seizures. And now Hannity is getting shade from one of his own colleagues. During the post-debate analysis on Fox News, Kelly had to introduce Hannity’s interview with Donald Trump. And as she introduced the interview, Kelly wondered if Trump would be talking to the actual journalists in the room afterward. ”We’ve got Trump speaking to our own Sean Hannity. We’ll see whether he speaks to the journalists in this room after that interview.” Here’s the video via YouTube.  Trump and Hannity proceeded to trash Hillary Clinton, but it looks like the main focus will be on Kelly for basically telling a lying commentator like Hannity to go f*ck himself. And he definitely deserved the shade. After all, Hannity is not a real journalist. He ignores facts and peddles bullshit and frankly shouldn’t be allowed anywhere near the airwaves. Hannity is Trump’s puppet and he clearly cannot be fair and balanced as the network he works for advertises. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>247</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>618</end>
        <start>248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>831</end>
        <start>619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1006</end>
        <start>832</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>1007</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1305</end>
        <start>1072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1439</end>
        <start>1306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1469</end>
        <start>1440</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1470</end>
        <start>1470</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1649</end>
        <start>1471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1940</end>
        <start>1650</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1941</end>
        <start>1941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>727</end>
        <start>700</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1438</end>
        <start>1306</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WATCH: Megyn Kelly Takes A Shot At Hannity By Wondering When Trump Will Talk To A Real Journalist</title>
    <uri>http://author.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/27/watch-megyn-kelly-takes-a-shot-at-hannity-by-wondering-when-trump-will-talk-to-a-real-journalist/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
