<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://thehill.com/policy/defense/297324-top-us-general-troubling-iran-military-to-get-us-cash">
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1525</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford, is troubled by the cash payments to Iran. You have to agree: You don’t want your enemy to be enabled to fight you harder, stronger, or longer. In his rush to create a legacy, President Obama has created, instead, this problem that our military must face. Read the article below.  As Written By Kristina Wong for The Hill: Marine Gen. Joseph Dunford, the nation’s top military officer, said Thursday that reports that U.S. payments to Iran will go to the Iranian military are “troubling.” “It certainly is troubling. The more funds that they have available, obviously the more effective they’ll be in spreading malign influence,” the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff told the Senate Armed Services Committee. He was responding to questioning by Sen. Kelly Ayotte (R-N.H.), a member of the committee, who referenced recent reports that the Iranian government has approved a law that would allocate to the military the $1.7 billion the U.S. paid Iran this year to settle a failed arms deal from the 1970s. The administration has argued the payment was not a “ransom,” as critics have claimed, but that an international nuclear accord signed in January paved the way for the payment and a release of prisoners at the same time. Since the signing of the accord, U.S. military leaders say Iranian naval forces have stepped up their harassment of U.S. forces in the Persian Gulf. Dunford also said Iran continues to be one of the lead ….. Full Story Here: Top US general: ‘Troubling’ that Iran military will get US cash | TheHill</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>349</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>350</end>
        <start>350</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>392</end>
        <start>351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>558</end>
        <start>393</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>783</end>
        <start>559</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1299</end>
        <start>1079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1448</end>
        <start>1300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1507</end>
        <start>1449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1524</end>
        <start>1508</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1525</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>557</end>
        <start>547</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>698</end>
        <start>560</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1139</end>
        <start>1132</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1508</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Our Nation’s Top General Troubled By U.S. Cash to Iran</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/our-nations-top-general-troubled-by-u-s-cash-to-iran/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
