<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/crime/bs-md-ci-stabbing-arrests-20160916-story.html">
        <end>1527</end>
        <start>1518</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I don’t know what it’s like to be dumb. I have been a thinking individual my entire life. So being able to relate to 18-yr-old Zannay Laws and Dakei Perry and why they filmed themselves beating up and robbing an old man to post on social media will be a challenge. Based on their actions I can only say they were probably both dropped on their heads at birth and since then joined the Black Lives Matter movement. They seem to share the same mentality. A 64-year-old man was reading a book at 5 p.m. in the North Baltimore park near the Johns Hopkins University, little did he know that he was about to get the shock of his life. A group of young thugs found him and decided to rob him, but not in the normal robber way of “give me all your money”, they wanted to have some ‘fun’ with it. These millennials decided to film the whole thing for ‘prosperity’ or something (doubt they know the definition of the word). The first suspect held a gun to his head demanding his stuff like cellphone and money. The second stabbed the poor old man in his lower back. Even thought the man was incapacitated and had a gun on him, the third decided to spray mace in his face. Someone stabbed him again, this time in the right arm and the suspects took his iPhone, backpack and $60. All THIS while LIVE streaming on Facebook. Wow… brilliant folks we got here. They filmed their entire crime and put it out there for people to see, did they not know they created the best evidence to land themselves in jail? Serious asshats! Police spokesman T.J. Smith said, “Criminals do some crazy things. They record themselves committing crimes, and we thank them for it. We encourage the criminals to continue to record your acts, and encourage citizens to continue to send us information when you find the criminal wrongdoing on camera and on social media.” Smith said detectives were working to confirm the identities of the other two suspects, but said they believe the group has committed a series of crimes in the area. Smith called it a “little crime spree.” This group is suspected of other similar type crimes in the neighborhood and one in custody has already started singing. Would you at any age or stage in your life think stabbing and mace-ing an old man was fun? I’m just curious if this is only a Black Lives Matter thing. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>452</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>914</end>
        <start>453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1510</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2039</end>
        <start>1511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2312</end>
        <start>2040</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2313</end>
        <start>2313</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>746</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1832</end>
        <start>1546</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2038</end>
        <start>2019</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2039</end>
        <start>1511</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Dumbass Thugs Post Video On FaceBook Of Them Violently Robbing Old Man</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/dumbass-thugs-post-video-on-facebook-of-them-violently-robbing-old-man/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
