<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2016/09/18/candidates-who-dont-back-trump-may-not-be-allowed-to-run-again-rnc-chairman-says.html">
        <end>2093</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>If you are one of the GOP candidates who is still saying #NeverTrump, you have been warned. Republican National Committee Chairman Reince Priebus on Sunday suggested he could say “never mind” to the “Never Trump” candidates should they try to make another run for the presidency. That is one way to get your troops to fall in line. Will the big heads get the message?  As Written, Reported and seen first on Fox News: Republican National Committee Chairman Reince Priebus on Sunday suggested he could say “never mind” to the “Never Trump” candidates should they try to make another run for the presidency. Priebus said the former primary challengers who’ve refused to support Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump could face consequences if they fail to back Trump in the stretch-run to Election Day. “Those people need to get on board,” Priebus told “Face the Nation.” “And if they’re thinking they’re going to run again some day, I think that we’re going to evaluate the process – of the nomination process and I don’t think it’s going to be that easy for them.” Priebus didn’t specifically name the group, but Ohio Gov. John Kasich, Texas Sen. Ted Cruz and former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush are the most prominent ex-GOP primary candidates to refuse to support Trump. Cruz and Bush were locked in particularly nasty verbal spats during the campaign with Trump, who termed his opponents “Lyin’ Ted” and “Low-Energy Jeb.” Though Kasich and Trump rarely went toe-to-toe, Kasich was the last Trump challenger to drop out of the race, and despite the Republican National Convention being held in Cleveland, the Ohio governor didn’t set foot in Quicken Loans Arena. Cruz spoke at the convention, but he was booed off the stage when he told the assembled, largely pro-Trump crowd to “vote your conscience.” Despite the intra-party squabbles, however, Priebus made his case by pointing to a pledge that each primary candidate signed vowing to support the eventual Republican nominee….. Full Story Here: Candidates who don’t back Trump may not be allowed to run again, RNC chairman says | Fox News</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>367</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>368</end>
        <start>368</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>417</end>
        <start>369</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>605</end>
        <start>418</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>807</end>
        <start>606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>808</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1272</end>
        <start>1072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1804</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1982</end>
        <start>1805</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1999</end>
        <start>1983</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2093</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>190</end>
        <start>180</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>211</end>
        <start>200</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>190</end>
        <start>180</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>211</end>
        <start>200</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>843</end>
        <start>809</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>875</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1070</end>
        <start>878</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1401</end>
        <start>1392</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1423</end>
        <start>1408</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1803</end>
        <start>1782</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2093</end>
        <start>1983</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>GOP ‘Never Trump’ Candidates get a Warning</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/gop-never-trump-candidates-get-a-warning/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
