<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>McIntosh</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/demetrick-pennie.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A cop from Dallas, Texas has filed a lawsuit against a number of individuals he feels is directly responsible for inciting a number of attacks on law enforcement across the nation. He’s sick of the cops being gunned down and murdered. Targeted outright. Much like what BLM claims is happening to them, yet lacking in the proof. Speaking of Black Lives Matter, they are one of the groups being sued…and for all the right reasons.  Sgt. Demetrick Pennie, who is a 17-year veteran of the Dallas Police Department, filed a civil complaint in federal court on Friday, Sept. 16th against the Black Lives Matter movement as well as a bunch of other political figures that have taken advantage of the turmoil and escalated it. Two of these political figures include Obama and Hillary Clinton. Now that’s some high ground he’s aiming for. Rev. Al Sharpton, Louis Farrakhan and evil crony capitalist George Soros are also named as defendants in the filing. According to this Texas cop, these individuals and groups have participated in “threats and attacks” against police officers nationwide, including the murders of five Dallas officers at a Black Lives Matter protest on Jul. 7th. “…repeatedly incited their supporters and others to engage in threats of and attacks to cause serious bodily injury or death upon police officers and other law enforcement persons of all races and ethnicities.” Attorney Larry Klayman of Freedom Watch is representing Sgt. Pennie.   Will anything happen from this? I have a very hard time believing so. This feat might be too big for one person to file against. It might be a show type lawsuit and if it is, God bless the man for taking a stand against tyranny from both the government and the mobs…but I won’t hold my breath. …well, maybe just a little…a man can dream, can’t he? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>428</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>429</end>
        <start>429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>718</end>
        <start>430</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>829</end>
        <start>719</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>946</end>
        <start>830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1174</end>
        <start>947</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1385</end>
        <start>1175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1454</end>
        <start>1386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1455</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1456</end>
        <start>1456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1750</end>
        <start>1457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1804</end>
        <start>1751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1805</end>
        <start>1805</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1046</end>
        <start>1027</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1384</end>
        <start>1176</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BOOM! Black Dallas Cop SUING Obama, Hillary AND BlackLivesMatter For “Inciting” War On BLUE LIVES! [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/boom-black-dallas-cop-suing-obama-hillary-blacklivesmatter-inciting-war-blue-lives/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
