<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Cassy Fiano</author>
    <links href="http://truthfeed.com/brilliant-charlotte-official-instantly-silence-rioters-with-1-epic-announcement/25798/">
        <end>432</end>
        <start>408</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The rioting in Charlotte has practically crippled the city. Businesses were looted, windows were smashed. So-called protesters have committed any number of crimes, from arson and assault, to murder. North Carolina Governor Pat McCrory was forced to declare a state of emergency and called in the National Guard to get the situation under control. And now, government officials have had enough too. They just made a huge announcement that will have people thinking twice before they start protesting again.   Officials just released a proclamation that says any people caught rioting, looting, destroying property or otherwise being violent in any unlawful manner will have their government benefits permanently revoked. But it doesn’t end there — any minor children who participate in the violence will face the same repercussions… and so will their parents. The parents of minors caught rioting will not only be held accountable for their child’s actions, but they could face losing their state benefits as well. They could also face referrals to social services and could potentially lose custody of their children. “Parents are responsible for their children. If they are allowing them to engage in lawless behaviors there will be consequences for them as parents,” city official Wilson Stewart said during a press conference. “Many of the individuals we have detained are high school students. We urge parents out there to know where their children are at all times until tensions are quelled. Have them adhere to the mandatory curfew. Make them aware that participation in looting, destruction of property and violently demonstrating on any level will come with severe penalties.”   Will this keep protesters from turning violent? Will it prevent thugs from exploiting a tragic death so they can have an excuse to riot and loot and attack people? Only time will tell, but at least now they will know that there are serious consequences to their actions. Parents may also be more inclined to keep an eye on their kids and you know… act like parents. Let’s be real, if your kid is caught rioting and looting, then there’s a good chance you’re not doing a good job at parenting. Officials have also put a curfew into place as they work to restore peace and order in Charlotte.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>505</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>506</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>507</end>
        <start>507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>508</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1685</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1686</end>
        <start>1686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1687</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2180</end>
        <start>1688</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2278</end>
        <start>2181</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2279</end>
        <start>2279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2280</end>
        <start>2280</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2281</end>
        <start>2281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1267</end>
        <start>1119</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1684</end>
        <start>1331</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BOOM! Charlotte Officials FINALLY Silence Rioters With One E P I C Announcement! [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/black-lives-matter/boom-charlotte-officials-finally-silence-rioters-one-e-p-c-announcement/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
