<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Lisa Smith</author>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton had a major slip up on Thursday. In a public video message to American laborers, Democrat presidential candidate Hillary Clinton put her true personality on full display! It was just what would expect from the little she-devil: shrill, manic and apt to inspire shudders of trepidation in little children. “‘Why aren’t I 50 points ahead?’ you might ask,” Hillary bellowed like an asylum patient. “Well, the choice for working families has never been clearer. I need your help to get Donald Trump’s record out to everybody.” “Nobody should be fooled!” she snidely added in a voice so ear-splittingly loud that even deaf laborers most likely heard it. Throughout the rest of the video, she maintained that same flair — the unnecessary indignation for her opponent, GOP candidate Donald Trump. To her demise, instead of directing her rage at him, she inadvertently wound up unleashing it upon the very people she wanted to bubble her name in on the ballot. You can watch a snippet of the video below, just a tip, don’t watch it in front of your kids, lest they go to sleep tonight complaining about the “Hillary bogeywoman” hiding in their closets:  That is one frightening old lady!! Does she actually think that’s going to win her votes? Take note to this version of Hillary Clinton compared to the one usually seen of her. When speaking at campaign events or with the media, she attempts (rather unsuccessfully) to present herself as amiable, humble and, of course, likable.  The Hillary depicted in the clip above is much more like the version of her described by her former Secret Service escorts. Take for example former agent Gary Byrne, who described the former first lady as “erratic, uncontrollable and occasionally violent.” This Hillary definitely fits the bill of the heartless Benghazi murdering type we have read so much about! Even Byrne admitted that Hillary often screamed obscenities at Secret Service agents, White House staff and even her own husband, former President Bill Clinton. And everyone lived in fear of her next crazy outburst. That sounds spot on….  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>186</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>320</end>
        <start>187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>538</end>
        <start>321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>539</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>805</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>806</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1160</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>1161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1489</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1490</end>
        <start>1490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1854</end>
        <start>1491</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2070</end>
        <start>1855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2092</end>
        <start>2071</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2093</end>
        <start>2093</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2094</end>
        <start>2094</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>368</end>
        <start>322</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>537</end>
        <start>412</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>564</end>
        <start>540</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1134</end>
        <start>1116</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1746</end>
        <start>1697</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WATCH: The REAL Hillary Just Got Captured on Camera… Arms Flailing, Eyes Bulging, Furious Voice</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/09/23/watch-the-real-hillary-just-got-caught-on-tape-arms-flailing-eyes-bulging-furious-voice/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
