<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Hannah Bleau (Red Dawn)</author>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/breaking-huma-abedin-announces-her-separation-from-anthony-weiner/">
        <end>74</end>
        <start>27</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/anthony-weiner-sexts-while-his-young-son-is-nearby/">
        <end>114</end>
        <start>100</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/anthony-weiner-offered-position-as-social-media-director-at-bunny-ranch-brothel/">
        <end>296</end>
        <start>246</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3790824/Anthony-Weiner-carried-months-long-online-sexual-relationship-troubled-15-year-old-girl-telling-hard-asking-dress-school-girl-outfits-pressing-engage-rape-fantasies.html">
        <end>326</end>
        <start>322</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.chicksontheright.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ew.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3790824/Anthony-Weiner-carried-months-long-online-sexual-relationship-troubled-15-year-old-girl-telling-hard-asking-dress-school-girl-outfits-pressing-engage-rape-fantasies.html">
        <end>4102</end>
        <start>4092</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton’s top aide Huma Abedin recently separated from her husband, Anthony Weiner, after a photo surfaced of Weiner sexting some random chick with their son right next to him. The Bunny Ranch legal brothel responded by offering Weiner a full time position as the director of social media, and we all laughed. But this? This is no laughing matter. It’s sick. According to that sourcelink, Weiner carried out a months-long online sexual relationship with a 15-year-old girl. She claims he asked her to dress up in “school-girl” outfits and allegedly “pressed her to engage in ‘rape fantasies.'” The girl, whose name is being withheld by DailyMail.com because she is a minor, said the online relationship began last January while she was a high school sophomore and before Weiner’s wife, Hillary Clinton’s aide Huma Abedin, announced she was ended their marriage.   Weiner was aware that the girl was underage, according to DailyMail.com interviews with the girl and her father, as well as a cache of online messages. He knew this and sent her completely disgusting, inappropriate messages anyway. He sent her “bare-chested” photos of himself, called her “baby,” complimented her body and even told her he woke up “hard” thinking about her.  In one particularly lewd message, he told the teen: ‘I would bust that tight p***y so hard and so often that you would leak and limp for a week.’ The teen said she originally reached out to Weiner on Twitter in January. She said she was interested in politics and heard about his sexting scandals and wanted to know more about him. It was clear from the messages that she was encouraging Weiner to engage with her in a sexual manner. She told DailyMail.com she didn’t consider Weiner her boyfriend, but thought the relationship was a ‘romantic’ one.  She acknowledged during interviews that she had developed an obsession with Weiner, and sought him out on Twitter in January while trying to write a book about him. She said she continued to write the book as their relationship developed.  ‘Why did I message you [in January]?’ the girl wrote in an email to Weiner last week. ‘I was studying you- for a book of course. You were my Hannibal Lecter.  ‘I wanted to know what made you tick. As we chatted, I pretended to not know EVERYTHING about you. I didn’t want to appear suspicious.’  She also told Weiner: ‘I was obsessed with you.’  Weiner quickly messaged her back, and they struck up a conversation about the large snowstorms that had hit New York and the girl’s home state. From there, he sent her a friend request on Facebook, and the rest is history. The girl told DailyMail.com that she and Weiner first started talking on Skype a few days into the relationship. ‘[Weiner’s] son was in the bathtub at the time just downstairs,’ she said. ‘So he would yell at his son to check on him, and then he asked me to take my clothes off, and just started saying these really sexual things.’  Afterward, Weiner sent her a message with a heart-eyed emoji, writing ‘I caught a glimpse of your body’ and indicating he would like to keep talking over Skype.  She claimed the conversations grew more explicit as time went on, with Weiner allegedly asking her to undress and encouraging her to masturbate over video chat.  She said Weiner would not get fully nude, but was usually shirtless and wearing boxers.  ‘He would tell me to say his name as I was touching myself,’ said the girl. ‘He would ask me to take my clothes off.  ‘He would just have his shirt off. Sometimes he would grab his lower region, but that was about it,’ she added. Weiner didn’t deny messaging the teen and refused to address the specific allegations. “I have repeatedly demonstrated terrible judgement about the people I have communicated with online and the things I have sent,” Weiner said. ” I am filled with regret and heartbroken for those I have hurt.” Weiner just got 195 times more disgusting. I know. I didn’t think it was possible either. If only his first name was Bill and his last name was Clinton. Then everyone would laugh about these sexual escapades. h/t Daily Mail</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>184</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>366</end>
        <start>185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>601</end>
        <start>367</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>870</end>
        <start>602</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>871</end>
        <start>871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1023</end>
        <start>872</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1246</end>
        <start>1024</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1247</end>
        <start>1247</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1393</end>
        <start>1248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1579</end>
        <start>1394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1797</end>
        <start>1580</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1798</end>
        <start>1798</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2037</end>
        <start>1799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2038</end>
        <start>2038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2196</end>
        <start>2039</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2197</end>
        <start>2197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2333</end>
        <start>2198</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2334</end>
        <start>2334</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2383</end>
        <start>2335</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2384</end>
        <start>2384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2528</end>
        <start>2385</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2607</end>
        <start>2529</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2720</end>
        <start>2608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2939</end>
        <start>2721</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2940</end>
        <start>2940</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3101</end>
        <start>2941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3102</end>
        <start>3102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3263</end>
        <start>3103</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3264</end>
        <start>3264</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3352</end>
        <start>3265</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3353</end>
        <start>3353</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3470</end>
        <start>3354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3471</end>
        <start>3471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3583</end>
        <start>3472</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3670</end>
        <start>3584</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3878</end>
        <start>3671</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3968</end>
        <start>3879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4087</end>
        <start>3969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4102</end>
        <start>4088</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Chicks On The Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>533</end>
        <start>522</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>600</end>
        <start>558</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1129</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1167</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1225</end>
        <start>1221</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3798</end>
        <start>3672</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>419</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1393</end>
        <start>1248</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>942</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>969</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Anthony Weiner Carried On A Months-Long Online Sexual Relationship With A 15-Year-Old Girl</title>
    <uri>http://www.chicksontheright.com/anthony-weiner-carried-on-a-months-long-online-sexual-relationship-with-a-15-year-old-girl/?utm_source=RWN&amp;utm_medium=RWN&amp;utm_campaign=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
