<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>100% FED Up</author>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3635882/Hillary-Clinton-called-disabled-children-Easter-egg-hunt-f-ing-ree-tards-referred-Jews-stupid-k-s-Bill-called-Jesse-Jackson-damned-n-r-claims-Bill-s-former-lover.html#ixzz4C8V8fCpm">
        <end>1677</end>
        <start>1667</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Dolly Kyle has written a scathing “tell all” book exposing the sickening hidden truth about Bill and Hillary Clinton. Hillary’s war on just about anyone who is beneath her, or who would dare to get in the way of her ascent to the White House. When will the media do their job and report the truth about this horrible opportunist? Dolly Kyle – who was just 11 when she first crossed paths with Bill, dated him through high school and began sleeping with him once they graduated – published the claims about the Clinton couple’s racial epithets and politics in her new book, Hillary: The Other Woman, published by WND Books. She writes of one occasion, when developmentally challenged children were having difficulty picking up the eggs at a traditional Easter egg hunt on the grounds of the governor’s mansion during Bill’s tenure in the Arkansas state house. Reluctant hostess Hillary had enough. ‘The frustrated Me-First Lady demanded, “When are they going to get those f*****g ree-tards out of here?”‘ Dolly writes. When Hillary arrived in Arkansas, Dolly writes, she looked down her nose at what she viewed as ‘ignorant hillbillies’. She was raised in a middle-class suburb in Illinois and considered herself above the southerners – unless she was campaigning in New York state where she declared herself to be a lifelong Yankees fan. Hillary didn’t belong in Arkansas but here she was’.  In the governor’s mansion for eight years, Bill and Hillary were both getting tired of the routine and frustrations of the small Southern state and Bill opted out of running for reelection in 1990. He was marking his time until he could make a move for the White House. Via: Daily Mail </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>329</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>622</end>
        <start>330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>896</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1017</end>
        <start>897</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1136</end>
        <start>1018</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1337</end>
        <start>1137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1390</end>
        <start>1338</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1391</end>
        <start>1391</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1589</end>
        <start>1392</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1677</end>
        <start>1590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1678</end>
        <start>1678</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>100 Percent Fed Up</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>43</end>
        <start>35</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1001</end>
        <start>938</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>HILLARY ON DISABLED CHILDREN During Easter Egg Hunt: “When are they going to get those f*****g ree-tards out of here?”</title>
    <uri>http://100percentfedup.com/hillary-on-disabled-children-during-easter-egg-hunt-when-are-they-going-to-get-those-fg-ree-tards-out-of-here/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
