<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/What.gif">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/angelina-jolie-brad-pitt.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2637237.main_image.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Another celebrity files for divorce, and this one shocked us more than all the rest! We have seen many couples file for divorce over the past several months but this one might have shocked us more than any other. TMZ reported that Angelina Jolie filed for divorce from Brad Pritt, and the reasoning will astound you.  Apparently Angelina filed for the divorce on Monday and cited irreconcilable differences. The reasoning for the divorce request was that she didn’t appreciate the way Brad interacted with his children. We don’t really know the details behind the story, but what we do know is she wants OUT. Not only that but after filing for the divorce, Angelina requested full physical custody of all of their children. She did request that Brad get visitation rights, but she does NOT want to have joint physical custody of the children – assuming it has something to do with the conflict behind the divorce.  Sources close to the couple shared with TMZ that Angelina was not happy with the way that Brad was parenting their children. Apparently she was really disappointed in the methods he was using to parent. Laura Wasser who is ripping Jolie stated that the separation date was September 15, 2016. She stated that Jolie is not asking for spousal support. The couple has been together for over 12 years and has been married for 2!  We have been swooning over this couple since the debut of their big film “Mr. and Mrs. Smith” and it is heartbreaking to see them throw in the towel so soon. Their divorce was a total shock to all of us and we almost can’t believe it! They seemed so happy together! Please keep this family in your prayers as they trudge through this sad divorce. Especially for all of their beautiful children!  THIS IS SO HEARTBREAKING! I LOVE BRANGELINA!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>84</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>316</end>
        <start>85</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>317</end>
        <start>317</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>608</end>
        <start>318</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>913</end>
        <start>609</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>914</end>
        <start>914</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1339</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1340</end>
        <start>1340</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1606</end>
        <start>1341</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1735</end>
        <start>1607</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1736</end>
        <start>1736</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1781</end>
        <start>1737</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1433</end>
        <start>1415</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Iconic Holllywood Couple Just Called It Quits After 12 Years</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/celebrity-news/breaking-iconic-holllywood-couple-just-called-it-quits-after-12-years/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Brad+and+Angelina%2F9%2F20&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2FBrad+and+Angelina%2F9%2F20</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
