<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/andrewkaczynski/in-2002-donald-trump-said-he-supported-invading-iraq-on-the">
        <end>214</end>
        <start>205</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.esquire.com/news-politics/a37230/donald-trump-esquire-cover-story-august-2004/">
        <end>998</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>“Donald supported the invasion of Iraq” — Clinton “Wrong.” — Trump Trump was supportive of the Iraq invasion as far back as 2002, according to interviews the Donald did with Howard Stern, which were first uncovered by BuzzFeed. Stern asks Trump if he agreed with the Bush administration trying to sell the war. He said, “Yeah, I guess so.” The argument between Clinton and Trump then spilled over into a clash of words between Trump and moderator Lester Holt. Holt insisted Trump had supported the war, referencing the Stern interview. Trump then claimed he'd had arguments with Fox News televsion host Sean Hannity, in which he argued against the war. He also said the argument that he supported the war was a media "lie." He also cited a 2004 Esquire interview that mentioned his criticism of the Iraq invasion as proof of his opposition. That interview took place after the start of the war, and Esquire has since attached a note to the article arguing that Trump is misrepresenting its contents.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>49</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>50</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>339</end>
        <start>67</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>535</end>
        <start>340</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>723</end>
        <start>536</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>999</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>38</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>57</end>
        <start>51</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>338</end>
        <start>321</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump [again] says he opposed the Iraq War. That's still false.</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/2016-presidential-debate-fact-check/2016/09/trump-still-wrong-about-his-iraq-war-support-228734?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
