<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/LeAnn-Rimes1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.music-news.com/news/UK/100369/LeAnn-Rimes-dealt-with-breakdown-in-graceful-manner">
        <end>639</end>
        <start>624</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/leann-rimes-79.jpeg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/LeannHusbandDefends.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>LeAnn Rimes opens up about the truth behind her divorce, and depression. I had no idea she went through all of this! LeAnn Rimes life looks pretty perfect if you take a glance at her success or her social media accounts, but the truth is that it isn’t always roses and rainbows for the country star. In fact, it hasn’t been that way at all for her. Even now after getting ready for her new album release she has shared some of the most intimate secrets that none of us knew about. She has been through a lot over the years, and of course all of it was extremely public which didn’t make it any easier.  In an interview with Hello! magazine she opened up about all of the hardships she has been over the past couple of years and it broke our hearts. One thing you may not know is that she took her former manager and her father into court for stealing money from her. It was already hard enough for LeAnn having all of the pressure from the public, but when her father betrayed her it was a harder pill to swallow. That wasn’t all that she has been through though. After her divorce with Dean Sheremet she ended up checking herself into rehab for depression.  The country star had an affair on her husband with her now current husband Dean Sheremet and it was one of the most publicized scandals in music at the time. She has struggled with all of these circumstances over the past years and she quit making new music. Now the country star is ready to come out with her new album “Remnant” and she opened up about how all of these life events have made her into the woman she is today. She says that this record isn’t going to be like any other. This album is going to be her “tell-all”. She is going to walk her fans through the past ten years of her life and how it has all helped her grow as a person – it is the most vulnerable album of hers to date. “This is a powerful record for me. I’m in my 30s now and whether it’s in your 30s or at some other point in your life, everyone will go through a kind of crumbling of sorts and for me it was about trying to do that as gracefully as possible…There is a real beauty in allowing that to happen as you get to pick up the piece and rebuild them to find out who you really are. Starting in the music industry so young, there were so many influences that weren’t truly me, but this album comes from the inside out.”  She added that many women will be able to relate to it, and she is excited for the release. “I know I’m not the only one that’s been through heartache and that so many women can relate to it. The last album was coming from chaos and this one if coming from love. I feel very settled now…”  We are so proud of LeAnn! So many women will be able to relate to this!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>116</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>348</end>
        <start>117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>601</end>
        <start>349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>602</end>
        <start>602</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>866</end>
        <start>603</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1157</end>
        <start>867</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1158</end>
        <start>1158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1417</end>
        <start>1159</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1418</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1853</end>
        <start>1645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2362</end>
        <start>1854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2363</end>
        <start>2363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2455</end>
        <start>2364</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2652</end>
        <start>2456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2653</end>
        <start>2653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2725</end>
        <start>2654</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1487</end>
        <start>1480</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1684</end>
        <start>1676</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2361</end>
        <start>1855</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2651</end>
        <start>2457</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2362</end>
        <start>1854</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2652</end>
        <start>2456</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>LeAnn Rimes Reveals The Truth On Her Divorce, This Is Hard To Watch</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/leann-rimes-reveals-the-truth-weve-all-been-waiting-for/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Leann+Rimes%2F9%2F22&amp;utm_content=Right+Wing+News%2FLeann+Rimes%2F9%2F22</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
