<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8136">
        <end>1254</end>
        <start>1177</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In advance of Constitution Day, Campus Reform interviewed students at Georgetown University, many of whom suggested that the founding document should be eliminated or replaced because it is too old and “vague.” Several students expressed frustration over the extent to which the Constitution factors into political debates because it includes limitations on the powers of government. Friday is Constitution Day, so Campus Reform stopped by Georgetown University to speak with students about their opinions of the document upon which our nation was founded. When asked about the modern relevance of the Constitution, most students made their opinion clear: the Constitution isn’t something to take too seriously. “People definitely take it too seriously, it’s not 250 years ago,” one student complained. “It’s maybe not as important as it was when it was written… times have obviously changed,” concurred another. Echoing the sentiment that the Constitution has lost relevance with age, another student observed that “when it was written, it was vague and using language we don’t really use anymore…” Still another student opined that the document actually limits our nation’s… Please go to Campus Reform to read the rest of the story and watch the VIDEO…  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>210</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>383</end>
        <start>211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>556</end>
        <start>384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>711</end>
        <start>557</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>802</end>
        <start>712</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>912</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1099</end>
        <start>913</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1176</end>
        <start>1100</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1254</end>
        <start>1177</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1255</end>
        <start>1255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1401</end>
        <start>1256</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1475</end>
        <start>1402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>209</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>777</end>
        <start>713</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>892</end>
        <start>804</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1098</end>
        <start>1017</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1437</end>
        <start>1425</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>College Students Argue Constitution “Too Old,” Should be Eliminated [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36837/college-students-argue-constitution-too-old-should-be-eliminated-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
