<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>By Daniella Diaz, CNN</author>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/21/media/joss-whedon-robert-downey-jr-donald-trump-vote/index.html">
        <end>621</end>
        <start>553</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/04/29/politics/allison-janney-cj-cregg-white-house/">
        <end>1006</end>
        <start>958</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Washington (CNN)The cast of "The West Wing" is back -- but this time, instead of the fictional Jed Bartlet, they're backing a different Democrat for president. Members of the massively popular NBC drama will appear with Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton at several events in Ohio on Saturday and Sunday. Actors Richard Schiff, Allison Janney, Bradley Whitford, Dulé Hill, Joshua Malina and Mary McCormack will make campaign stops in the Mahoning Valley, Cleveland, Sandusky and Toledo areas on Saturday, and in the Dayton and Columbus areas on Sunday. Joss Whedon's Avengers take shots at Trump in get out the vote video The actors will talk about why they're supporting Clinton and encourage the public to register to vote, according to a campaign statement. This isn't the first time "West Wing" -- the plot of which centers on a Democratic presidential administration -- clashes with real life. Janney, who played White House press secretary C.J. Cregg, made an unexpected appearance in the White House press briefing room in April. The surprised press corps had been expecting actual White House spokesman Josh Earnest for their usual press briefing. The Emmy Award-winning show has been off the air since 2006, but remains popular even a decade later. </mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>159</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>304</end>
        <start>160</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>552</end>
        <start>305</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>621</end>
        <start>553</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>760</end>
        <start>622</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>898</end>
        <start>761</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1155</end>
        <start>899</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1257</end>
        <start>1156</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1258</end>
        <start>1258</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>CNN</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>42</end>
        <start>29</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>42</end>
        <start>33</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>'West Wing' cast to campaign for Clinton</title>
    <uri>http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/21/politics/west-wing-hillary-clinton-2016-election/index.html?sr=fbpol092216west-wing-hillary-clinton-2016-election0303PMVODtopPhoto&amp;linkId=29080306</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
