<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8153">
        <end>378</end>
        <start>365</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>From the “You Just Can’t Make This Up” Department comes this story about the latest words that anti-free speech progressive leftists want to eliminate from the lexicon because of some contrived grievance or offense. Now, believe it or not, the term “American BBQ” has been determined to somehow be offensive by a college full of numbskulls. The fine people over at Campus Reform, who are keeping track of this kind of idiocy, report: Students at Ramapo College were recently forced to change the theme of an “American BBQ” because the administration deemed it too “offensive.” According to emails obtained by Campus Reform, Ariana Rivera, the Assistant Residence Director of Bischoff Hall, sent an email to the College Republicans and the College Democrats on August 17 inviting the groups to co-sponsor an American-themed BBQ with Bischoff and Mackin Halls. What in the hell is offensive about “American BBQ?” Can you think of anything? Me neither. However, according to emails obtained by Campus Reform, the term was somehow determined to be “military and recruitment-oriented.” No kidding. Maybe it’s the term “American” that bothers these idiots. It’s getting pretty obvious that the Left wants all speech banned — all speech that they disagree with. Does political correctness know no bounds?    Email Subscribe</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>215</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>340</end>
        <start>216</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>433</end>
        <start>341</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>576</end>
        <start>434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>577</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>949</end>
        <start>859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1080</end>
        <start>950</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1297</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1299</end>
        <start>1298</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1300</end>
        <start>1300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1306</end>
        <start>1301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1316</end>
        <start>1307</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politistick</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>37</end>
        <start>10</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>262</end>
        <start>250</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>262</end>
        <start>250</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>575</end>
        <start>565</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>909</end>
        <start>896</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1079</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>258</end>
        <start>250</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>858</end>
        <start>434</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The hardest-hitting political news.</title>
    <uri>http://politistick.com/progressive-leftists-deem-term-american-bbq-offensive/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
