<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>April Hamlin</author>
    <links href="http://www.theroot.com/articles/news/2016/09/report-disabled-black-man-shot-dead-by-police-while-reading-in-the-car/">
        <end>260</end>
        <start>246</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/CMPD">
        <end>1103</end>
        <start>1098</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/WBTV_News">
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/JwHMixy9m7">
        <end>1154</end>
        <start>1128</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/SarahBlakeWBTV/status/778359782700908545">
        <end>1214</end>
        <start>1196</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wsoctv.com/news/local/official-1-taken-to-hospital-after-shooting-in-university-city/448050164">
        <end>1249</end>
        <start>1226</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Protests have erupted in Charlotte, North Carolina after another African-American man was shot and killed by police on Tuesday afternoon. The victim was reportedly disabled and was reading a book in his car when cops approached him. According to police reports, officers came across Keith Lamont Scott while they were at his apartment complex to serve a warrant to someone else. Police claim that Scott had a gun and “posed an imminent deadly threat to the officers,” but family and witnesses dispute that claim. A woman identifying herself as the victim’s daughter, Lyric Scott, said that her father didn’t have a gun, he had a book. “He sits in the shade, reads his book, does his studies, and waits on his kid to get off the bus,” the woman said. “He didn’t have no gun. He wasn’t messing with nobody. All they did, them ‘jumpout boys,’ them undercover detectives, they jumped out their truck, they said, ‘Hands up he got a gun, he got a gun, pow pow pow pow.’ That’s it.” You can see her video below: Here’s the man’s sister. She says he did not have a gun. @CMPD says he did. @WBTV_News pic.twitter.com/JwHMixy9m7 — Sarah-Blake Morgan (@SarahBlakeWBTV) September 20, 2016 Protesters poured onto the streets of Charlotte on Tuesday night, chanting “Black lives matter” and “Hands up don’t shoot.” Police turned out in riot gear and have deployed tear gas to control the crowds. Meanwhile, the number of protesters continues to grow. You can watch video of the protests below:  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>232</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>644</end>
        <start>233</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1007</end>
        <start>645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1036</end>
        <start>1008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1154</end>
        <start>1037</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1214</end>
        <start>1155</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1484</end>
        <start>1215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1527</end>
        <start>1485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1528</end>
        <start>1528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1529</end>
        <start>1529</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1213</end>
        <start>1037</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Protests Erupt In Charlotte After Cops Kill Disabled Black Man Who Was Reading A Book In His Car</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/20/protests-erupt-in-charlotte-after-cops-kill-disabled-black-man-who-was-reading-a-book-in-his-car/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
