<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tiffiny Ruegner</author>
    <links href="https://youtu.be/4r7wHMg5Yjg">
        <end>81</end>
        <start>69</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I love Texas! I mean I really love their attitude. They are like the honey badger, they just don’t give a damn about what everyone else thinks. Governor Abbott is the quintessential Texan because he stands up and defends the citizens of his state EVEN if it means spitting in the face of Barack Obama.   Governor Abbott told Obama on Wednesday that Texas would no longer participate in his current refugee program because of the massive security concerns. Abbott has a right to be concerned since we had 4+ terrorist attacks over the weekend in the United States. Abbott doesn’t want to take chances that the hardly screened refugees settling in his state would have terroristic ideals. The Texas State Refugee Coordinator gave their 120 days notice of their intention to withdraw. The Office of Refugee Resettlement said in a statement its services to help integrate newcomers into U.S. society are only provided after they complete stringent US security screenings. Currently the US Refugee Settlement Processing protocol is riddled with security holes and has already let dozens of extremist refugees into the US. “The federal government’s refugee settlement program is riddled with serious problems that pose a threat to our nation,” the governor said in a statement. “The director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the director of national intelligence have repeatedly declared their inability to fully screen refugees from terrorist-based nations. Even with the inability to properly vet refugees from Syria and countries known to be supporters or propagators of terrorism, President Obama is now ineptly proposing a dramatic increase in the number of refugees to be resettled in the U.S.” “While many refugees pose no danger, some pose grave danger, like the Iraqi refugee with ties to ISIS who was arrested earlier this year after he plotted to set off bombs at two malls in Houston,” Abbott said. “Despite multiple requests by the state of Texas, the federal government lacks the capability or the will to distinguish the dangerous from the harmless, and Texas will not be an accomplice to such dereliction of duty to the American people,” he added. “Therefore, Texas will withdraw from the refugee resettlement program. I strongly urge the federal government to completely overhaul a broken and flawed refugee program that increasingly risks American lives.” So take THAT Mr. President!   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>301</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>302</end>
        <start>302</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>303</end>
        <start>303</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>781</end>
        <start>304</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1704</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1914</end>
        <start>1705</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2377</end>
        <start>1915</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2405</end>
        <start>2378</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2406</end>
        <start>2406</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2407</end>
        <start>2407</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2408</end>
        <start>2408</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1236</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1703</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1900</end>
        <start>1706</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2156</end>
        <start>1916</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2376</end>
        <start>2169</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2377</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>What Texas Just Did Will Make You PROUD! – Obama Has 120 Days To Comply…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/just-in-texas-revolts/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
