<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>McIntosh</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/anthony_weiner3.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The Weiner is back, yet again, in the news and if you thought he couldn’t get any more disgusting, well you would be stupid…I mean, come on. It’s Anthony “Douche” Weiner…I like the sound of that. Anyways, back in January, Anthony Weiner, 51, who at the time wasn’t in the process of divorce with top Hillary Clinton aide Huma Abedin, supposedly engaged in a months-long online sexual relationship with a troubled 15 year-old girl whose name is being withheld for obvious reasons.  “I have repeatedly demonstrated terrible judgement about the people I have communicated with online and the things I have sent,” stated Weiner as he was interviewed on FoxNews Online. The details are this. Back in January of 2016, Weiner had developed a knowing online sexting relationship with a 15 year-old girl. We know that he knew she was 15 because using the KIK, a popular social media app, he had asked the girl what high school she went to. Yeah, that kind of drains all doubt that he didn’t know she was underage. Let’s not forget, this man is married. So sexting with anyone but his wife still reveals that he’s just as horrible a person as ever…except now we know just how disgusting and evil this piece of turd is. Both the girl and Weiner sent sexually charged pictures and texts back and forth. Weiner also eventually ended up at the girl’s home when her father wasn’t there. The girl claims that he prodded her into deeper sexual conversation until she stated she wasn’t comfortable with where it was heading and he immediately stopped.   The girl’s father is justifiably enraged by what has transpired and claims his daughter’s mental health is in jeopardy. “If there’s anybody out there that has a similar story that they can come forward, maybe use my daughter’s example to have the courage to come forward, I agreed because her mental health is in jeopardy and I didn’t want to exacerbate anything that she has mentally going on,” he continued. She’s gone through some depression, we’ve sought counseling and been able to help her work through it, he said. She’s a bright girl, very smart, so this has somewhat dulled the light that she had previous to this…it’s gut-wrenching to see somebody take that away.” Alright Dad. Wiener is a scumbag and he is a sexual predator, no doubt…but let’s give some sense of responsibility to where it’s due. Your daughter engaged in the relationship. She is not some innocent angel you believe she is. How the hell does Weiner end up inside your home? Did he break in? Just be honest about it. Weiner’s a sick piece of trash that most likely will serve jail time. About time. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>195</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>479</end>
        <start>196</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>480</end>
        <start>480</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>481</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1004</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1208</end>
        <start>1005</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1533</end>
        <start>1209</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1534</end>
        <start>1534</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1535</end>
        <start>1535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1655</end>
        <start>1536</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2210</end>
        <start>1656</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2505</end>
        <start>2211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2530</end>
        <start>2506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2612</end>
        <start>2531</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2613</end>
        <start>2613</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>161</end>
        <start>155</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>608</end>
        <start>482</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1930</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WEINER Gets Caught AGAIN! This Time With A 15 Yr-Old!? [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/weiner-gets-caught-time-15-yr-old/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
