<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Charlotte?src=hash">
        <end>839</end>
        <start>829</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/Kwya2xXerk">
        <end>965</end>
        <start>942</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/OutFrontCNN/status/779102210567335936">
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>995</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>According to Charlotte Police, about 70% of protesters in the area are not only out-of-staters, but are “criminals.” “This is not Charlotte that’s out here,” a spokesman for the Charlotte-Mecklenburg Fraternal Order of Police said. “These are outside entities that are coming in and causing these problems. These are not protestors, these are criminals.” “I’m not saying all the people, but we’ve got the instigators that are coming in from the outside. They were coming in on buses from out of state. If you go back and look at some of the arrests that were made last night. I can say probably about 70% of those had out-of-state IDs. They’re not coming from Charlotte.” In fact, according to police, these troublemakers were bused in from out of state just to wreak havoc on the city. We saw the same thing happen in Ferguson. #Charlotte police: 70% of arrested protesters had out of state ID’s, outside entities are causing these problems https://t.co/Kwya2xXerk — OutFrontCNN (@OutFrontCNN) September 22, 2016  These people are purportedly protesting systemic racism in law enforcement. While that is something that might be worthy of discussion – definitely not worth looting a Walmart over – what’s interesting is that the cop who shot Keith Scott was a black man himself. According to Scott’s family, he didn’t have a gun and claimed that he was reading a book while waiting for his son. However, after Keith Scott was shot, police recovered no book from the scene, but did recover a small, loaded handgun. Here’s cell phone footage that Keith Scott’s wife took during the incident. Warning: Language       The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>116</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>671</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>828</end>
        <start>672</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>965</end>
        <start>829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>966</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1014</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1513</end>
        <start>1279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1589</end>
        <start>1514</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1607</end>
        <start>1590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1608</end>
        <start>1608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1610</end>
        <start>1609</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1612</end>
        <start>1611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1613</end>
        <start>1613</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1759</end>
        <start>1614</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1833</end>
        <start>1760</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>115</end>
        <start>105</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>156</end>
        <start>118</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>353</end>
        <start>233</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>670</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>529</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1783</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Charlotte Police: 70% of ‘Protesters’ are Out-of-State CRIMINALS</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36995/charlotte-police-70-of-protesters-are-out-of-state-criminals/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
