<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/donald-trump-press-pool-228258">
        <end>484</end>
        <start>458</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The Donald Trump campaign has improved logistics for the traveling press following the candidate, putting the journalists in the motorcade and on a dedicated chase plane. Though reporters covering the Republican nominee will not necessarily travel at all times on the same plane as Trump, they will now be in a dedicated "chase" plane and will drive within the Trump motorcade. These moves will significantly improve travel for the media covering Trump, who last week were left behind when reporters got stuck in New York City traffic trying to get a different airport than the one Trump, whose motorcade cuts through traffic, was flying out of for an event in New Hampshire. Despite requests to wait for the traveling press, Trump started the event without his traveling press corps and mocked them for being late. Reporters will travel with Trump on his plane "when logistically feasible," the campaign said, according to one member of Trump's traveling press corps. Trump campaign spokeswoman Hope Hicks, when asked whether the improved logistics were in reaction to last week's problems, said the move "has been in the works for weeks." Neither campaign has a full protective pool, meaning reporters cover the candidate as the president is covered by the White House press corps, from leaving their residence to return. Hillary Clinton's press corps have a quasi-protective pool, and have been traveling with her on her plane and within her motorcade since the Labor Day holiday. However, her press corps is not with her at all times as was evidenced earlier this month when Clinton fell ill and left a 9/11 memorial service early, leaving the press corps behind and without information for nearly two hours.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>170</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>815</end>
        <start>171</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>816</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1140</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1712</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Trump campaign improves press pool logistics</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/on-media/2016/09/trump-campaign-improves-press-pool-logistics-228357?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
