<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Onan Coca</author>
    <links href="http://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2016/09/19/clinton_trump_rhetoric_giving_aid_and_comfort_to_enemies.html">
        <end>652</end>
        <start>618</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ZekeJMiller/status/777874988913352704">
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/2016-presidential-race/2016/09/19/hes-the-republican-obama-trump-raises-100-million-from-small-donors-in-less-than-three-months/">
        <end>1705</end>
        <start>1682</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-shatters-gop-records-with-small-donors-228338">
        <end>2043</end>
        <start>2034</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailysurge.com/2016/09/wake-latest-terrorist-attack-donald-trump-hits-new-highs/">
        <end>2385</end>
        <start>2339</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>“I’ve never seen anything like this. He’s the Republican Obama in terms of online fundraising.” — A Senior GOP operative about Donald Trump Across the Internet many political observers are wondering if Donald Trump has become the Republican version of Barack Obama. Over the weekend, Mr. Trump stood up to decry the obvious acts of terrorism in New Jersey and New York. For his efforts he was attacked, criticized, and derided by liberals and their partners in the media. As New York Governor Andrew Cuomo (D-NY) and New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio (D-NY) refused to call the terrorism what it was, Hillary Clinton attacked Trump for his “rhetoric.” Arguing that by talking tough, Mr. Trump was somehow giving “aid and comfort to the enemy.” “I don’t want to speculate but here’s what we know about I think it is important for voters to hear this and weigh it in making their choice in November,” Clinton said. “We know that a lot of the rhetoric used by Donald Trump is being seized upon by terrorists.“ Clinton says Trump's rhetoric has "given aid and comfort" to terrorists. Phrase is definition of treason. — Zeke Miller (@ZekeJMiller) September 19, 2016  In fact, the left, almost as one, decried Trump’s comments as problematic and insinuated that he was encouraging Muslim terrorism by condemning the attacks. However, most Americans seem to have agreed with Mr. Trump, and by Monday most liberals in and out of the media had also come to realize that Trump’s early comments were correct. We don’t yet know how the weekend’s events will play into the upcoming election, but we can look at a few other indicators that give Trump and his supporters reason to be optimistic. Fundraising for example. Donald Trump has already, with 7 weeks left before Election Day, outraised both John McCain and Mitt Romney among “small donors.” Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump has raised as much as $100 million from small-dollar donors contributing $200 or less to his campaign — in less than three months. Trump’s campaign has surpassed a “threshold no previous Republican has ever achieved in a single campaign,” according to Politico, which looked over Federal Election Commission filings and spoke with operatives familiar with the campaign’s fundraising efforts. All of this also shows what could be a building Trump tsunami…   Read the Rest of the Story at the Daily Surge… </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>139</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1007</end>
        <start>140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1113</end>
        <start>1008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>1114</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1162</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1319</end>
        <start>1163</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1681</end>
        <start>1320</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1836</end>
        <start>1682</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2012</end>
        <start>1837</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2273</end>
        <start>2013</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2336</end>
        <start>2274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2338</end>
        <start>2337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2385</end>
        <start>2339</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2386</end>
        <start>2386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Constitution</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>94</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>651</end>
        <start>642</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>743</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>898</end>
        <start>746</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1835</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2119</end>
        <start>2047</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>1008</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>After New York Attack, Donald Trump Hits New Highs!</title>
    <uri>http://constitution.com/new-york-attack-donald-trump-hits-new-highs/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
