<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Antiphon Freeman</author>
    <mainText>Trump’s Campaign Manager was interrupted on CNN by Anderson Cooper after she said, “you’ve got all these little baby girls being killed just because they’re girls in this country.” Without letting her finish, Anderson immediately stopped her: “Wait, what Excuse me, where is that happening?” She then went on and tried to back up her statement by citing Planned Parenthood data, which was supposedly collected by the Guttmacher Institute report. But, Anderson Cooper wasn’t buying it. “But statistically, there’s not really much evidence that that is actually occurring in the United States,” Cooper said. “Amongst some immigrant groups in small numbers it may be occurring but in no statistical measure is it significant.” Then – right after commercial break – Anderson Cooper again came back in order to set the record straight. The only thing Trump’s campaign manager could do was force a fake smile. “Before the break, Kellyanne, you mentioned the Guttmacher Institute information on sex-selective abortion in the United States,” Cooper said. “Here’s what they actually say in a May 30 press release titled ‘Sex Selective Abortion Bans: A Disingenuous New Strategy to Limit Women’s Access to Abortion.’” “The study acknowledges the practice does go on overseas, as we mentioned, and perhaps in certain Asian-American communities in the United States in small numbers,” Copper continued. “But, quote, ‘In the United States, meanwhile, there is limited data indicating that sex-selective abortion may be occurring in some Asian communities. Although the U.S. sex ratio at 1.05 males for every female is squarely within biologically normal parameters.’ So I just wanted to put that out there.” </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>190</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>252</end>
        <start>191</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>305</end>
        <start>253</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>459</end>
        <start>306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>500</end>
        <start>460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>749</end>
        <start>501</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>936</end>
        <start>750</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1256</end>
        <start>937</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1755</end>
        <start>1257</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1756</end>
        <start>1756</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>305</end>
        <start>253</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>749</end>
        <start>501</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1755</end>
        <start>937</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WATCH: Trump’s Manager Gets Instantly Shut Down For Saying ‘Baby Girls Are Killed For Their Sex’</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/watch-trumps-manager-gets-instantly-shut-down-for-saying-baby-girls-are-killed-for-their-sex/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
