<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rika Christensen</author>
    <links href="http://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/donald-trumps-stop-and-frisk-policy-raises-eyebrows?cid=sm_fb_maddow">
        <end>981</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In discussing shootings and crime in the first of three presidential debates, Donald Trump not only greatly exaggerated the number of shootings in Chicago, and claimed that stop and frisk was both constitutional and effective, he also advocated taking guns away from people without due process. Of course, he thinks that the police would take guns away from criminals, and that the Constitution is different for criminals, but  has a constitutional right to due process. Doesn’t matter to Trump, though: “We have to take guns away…from bad people that shouldn’t have them.” Those were Trump’s words in the debate, where he defended stop-and-frisk as constitutional despite the fact that it was literally ruled otherwise, and has also been deemed ineffective. How the NRA can support a candidate that would take guns away from anybody at all without due process is beyond us. That’s especially true given the fact that this isn’t the first time Trump has said this: “[Police officers are] proactive, and if they see a person possibly with a gun or they think they have a gun, they will see the person and they’ll look and they’ll take the gun away. They’ll stop, they’ll frisk and they’ll take the gun away, and they won’t have anything to shoot with.” The 2nd Amendment cannot exist without due process. The NRA is literally supporting a candidate who would take guns away from law-abiding citizens. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>507</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>585</end>
        <start>508</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>982</end>
        <start>586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1285</end>
        <start>983</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1433</end>
        <start>1286</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>584</end>
        <start>508</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1284</end>
        <start>983</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Literally Just Said He’d Take Guns Away From Anyone Without Due Process</title>
    <uri>http://addictinginfo.org/2016/09/26/trump-literally-just-said-hed-take-guns-away-from-anyone-without-due-process/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
