<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Vera</author>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/pro-trump-pastor-walks-out-of-cnn-interview-after-being-called-out-for-exaggerating-his-bio/">
        <end>1344</end>
        <start>1314</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Montel Williams isn’t afraid to express his absolute disgust and disdain for Republican nominee Donald Trump – he’s made it perfectly clear in the past that he would never support or vote for him, and continuously speaks out against the business mogul. That’s why there was nothing unusual about what Williams did over the weekend, when the radio talk show host called out one of Trump’s biggest supporters – Pastor Mark Burns. When Williams saw Burns complaining about the media’s hesitance to call the weekend explosions in New York City a terror attack, he couldn’t just let it slide. Twitter Burns was merely echoing what Trump himself had said, when the GOP presidential candidate jumped to conclusions and immediately called the explosion a ‘bomb’ even before officials could investigate or confirm it. Fed up with the baseless fear mongering the Trump campaign has been become infamous for doing, Williams flat-out told Burns he’d had “enough of your crap.” Twitter Little did Burns know when he responded to Williams, that he’d just started a Twitter fight that he had no chance of winning: Twitter Williams was not going to back down, and as the day continued the men continued to take shots at each other, with Williams continuously calling the Trump-loving pastor out for falsifying details of his past and stating that Burns was “not even a real pastor.” What resulted was a seemingly never-ending stream of back and forth tweets, in which Burns was clearly on the losing side: Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Twitter Williams had ripped Burns a new one and exposed all of his flaws for all of social media to see. Several hours later, Williams ended his feud with Burns on a high note, reminding his followers that Burns had gotten himself into this mess: Twitter Twitter </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>258</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>603</end>
        <start>259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>611</end>
        <start>604</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>992</end>
        <start>612</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1128</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1136</end>
        <start>1129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1525</end>
        <start>1137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1533</end>
        <start>1526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1541</end>
        <start>1534</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1549</end>
        <start>1542</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1557</end>
        <start>1550</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1565</end>
        <start>1558</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1573</end>
        <start>1566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1581</end>
        <start>1574</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1589</end>
        <start>1582</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1597</end>
        <start>1590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1605</end>
        <start>1598</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1613</end>
        <start>1606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1621</end>
        <start>1614</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1860</end>
        <start>1622</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1868</end>
        <start>1861</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1876</end>
        <start>1869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1877</end>
        <start>1877</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <title>Montel Williams DESTROYS Pro-Trump Pastor In INSANE Twitter Fight (TWEETS)</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/19/montel-williams-destroys-pro-trump-pastor-in-insane-twitter-fight-tweets/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
