<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Victoria</author>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/online/trump-ohio-chairwoman-says-there-was-no-racism-before-obama/">
        <end>147</end>
        <start>122</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.hamptoninstitution.org/systemisntbroken.html#.V-Pl5DuSClI">
        <end>1740</end>
        <start>1710</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.bloomberg.com/features/2016-america-divided/education/">
        <end>1925</end>
        <start>1912</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.ascd.org/publications/books/109074/chapters/How-Poverty-Affects-Behavior-and-Academic-Performance.aspx">
        <end>2624</end>
        <start>2607</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/kathy-miller-mahoning-trump-chair-resigns-racism">
        <end>3248</end>
        <start>3240</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Trump’s campaign chair of Mahoning County, Ohio, one of the most crucial counties in the state, made what might be the most delusional statement of the week. She insisted that racism was literally non-existent before Obama was elected. Wow, it doesn’t take much to tear apart how this assertion is completely absurd, but we’re going to take the time to do it anyway. In an interview with The Guardian, Kathy Miller, the campaign chair in question, made the following shocking statement: “I don’t think there was any racism until Obama got elected.  We never had problems like this.” She must mean that white people were relatively shielded from being forced to face the fact that racism is, in fact, abound in white culture.  Even though that, in all honestly, is a load of bunk too. She went on to make some extremely offensive statements to the black community overall, willfully remaining ignorant of how many hardships Black Americans face every. single. day: “If you’re black and you haven’t been successful in the last 50 years, it’s your own fault.  You’ve had every opportunity, it was given to you.  You’ve had the same schools everybody else went to.  You had benefits to go to college that white kids didn’t have.  You had all the advantages and didn’t take advantage.  It’s not our fault, certainly.” *Cringe* Seeing as apparently this isn’t evident to people like Kathy Miller, and arguably much of Trump’s voter base, let’s just go through why this is completely bogus and extremely offensive. She even went so far as to say that racism didn’t exist when she grew up…in the 1960s.  What?!  Segregation?!?! Black people have had to deal with a racist criminal justice system which unfairly targets their community, damaging their families and placing their children at a disadvantage from the very beginning. Black children have primarily had to go to schools which are dominated by a white power structure, a power structure which has certainly not gotten rid of its racist roots to this day.  Either that, or they often go to a school which is worse off economically. Black people were literally enslaved or cut off from the resources and wealth of the white by law for centuries.  The racist nature within that legal system wasn’t just erased with the end of segregation.  Has it improved?  Sure, but that hasn’t addressed the structural racism within our socio-political and economic paradigm. Because of a history of oppression, black people have been economically much worse off.  And children who come from poor families, as study after study shows, statistically do worse in school.  They also can’t afford skyrocketing college tuition when they get out of high school. Black children are often disproportionately punished in schools, which harms their potential for academic success. Honestly, I could go on and on, and I’m not even black, so I don’t know the half of it. This lady is delusional, her beliefs are dangerous to the health of our society, and the fact that we have this kind of racism so prevalent in the Trump campaign, a United States presidential campaign, is horrifying. But it’s all Obama’s fault, right? UPDATE: Kathy Miller resigned after blowback from these comments.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>160</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>238</end>
        <start>161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>373</end>
        <start>239</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>493</end>
        <start>374</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>596</end>
        <start>494</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>799</end>
        <start>597</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>979</end>
        <start>800</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1353</end>
        <start>980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1362</end>
        <start>1354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1554</end>
        <start>1363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1672</end>
        <start>1555</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1874</end>
        <start>1673</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2136</end>
        <start>1875</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2471</end>
        <start>2137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2755</end>
        <start>2472</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2870</end>
        <start>2756</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2962</end>
        <start>2871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3179</end>
        <start>2963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3218</end>
        <start>3180</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3284</end>
        <start>3219</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>596</end>
        <start>494</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1353</end>
        <start>980</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Campaign Chair In Ohio Insists Racism Didn’t Exist Before Obama Was Elected</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/trump-campaign-chair-in-ohio-insists-racism-didnt-exist-before-obama-was-elected/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
