<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>By Daniella Diaz, CNN</author>
    <links href="https://www.scribd.com/document/324821200/16804-NBCWSJ-September-Poll-9-21-Release?secret_password=gKkeD7pKqo5rYoSPNmfU">
        <end>284</end>
        <start>256</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/21/politics/hillary-clinton-police-shootings-terence-crutcher-keith-lamont-scott/index.html">
        <end>531</end>
        <start>444</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Washington (CNN)Hillary Clinton is leading Donald Trump by 6 points ahead of the first debate on Monday, according to a new national poll released Wednesday. A four-way matchup shows Clinton has 43% support of likely voters while Trump has 37%, in the new NBC/Wall Street Journal poll. Libertarian Party nominee Gary Johnson is at 9% and the Green Party's Jill Stein is at 3%. In a two-way matchup, Clinton leads Trump by 7 points, 48% to 41%. Clinton on police shootings: 'too many people have lost their lives who shouldn't have' The poll was conducted after a rough patch for Clinton, highlighted by her temporarily leaving the campaign trail after she was diagnosed with pneumonia. Despite a recent effort to court African-American voters, Trump garners just 7% support compared to Clinton's 81% with the voting bloc. On the issues, Trump has the advantage with voters when it comes to the economy -- 46% to 41%. But Clinton leads when it comes to being in charge of nuclear weapons (51% to 25%), being a good commander in chief (48% to 33%) and on immigration (50% to 39%). Trump and Clinton are virtually tied when it comes to terrorism and homeland security (44% to 43%). A new CNN Poll of Polls, including the NBC/WSJ data, finds Clinton's edge over Trump has inched up by 1 point. The Poll of Polls averages the results of the five most recent nationwide telephone polls of presidential preference among likely voters and finds her ahead, 43% to 40%. The NBC/WSJ poll surveyed 992 likely voters between September 16-19 and has a margin of error of plus or minus 3.2 percentage points. </mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>157</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>376</end>
        <start>158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>443</end>
        <start>377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>531</end>
        <start>444</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>685</end>
        <start>532</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>821</end>
        <start>686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1178</end>
        <start>822</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1459</end>
        <start>1179</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1593</end>
        <start>1460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1594</end>
        <start>1594</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>CNN</portal>
    <title>National poll: Clinton leads Trump by 6 points</title>
    <uri>http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/21/politics/nbc-wsj-poll-hillary-clinton-donald-trump-2016-election/index.html?sr=fbpol092216nbc-wsj-poll-hillary-clinton-donald-trump-2016-election0105AMVODtopLink&amp;linkId=29057375</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
