<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Harris</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/jimmy-fallon-wrecked-campaign/">
        <end>52</end>
        <start>30</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/trump-refuses-board-plane-epic/">
        <end>421</end>
        <start>390</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.drudgereport.com">
        <end>551</end>
        <start>538</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/michelle-obama-truth-clintons/">
        <end>45</end>
        <start>38</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Democrat presidential nominee Hillary Clinton’s camp requested to have the most embarrassing piece of equipment to help her stand tall against Donald Trump during the debate on Monday — a step stool so that she would not be dwarfed by Republican rival Donald Trump’s 6’2″ frame. Hillary, standing at only 5’4″, was apparently worried that she would look short and weak standing next to the Republican presidential nominee, but the commission for the debate basically said tough luck as the rejected her request. Instead, according to the Drudge Report, they will be making a custom podium that will help accommodate for the differences in height. But wait, there’s more! Hillary’s camp also reportedly questioned whether there would be any commercial breaks during the 90-minute showdown. The answer was a resounding no. In fact, Debate moderator Lester Holt does not even have the authority to cut away from the stage during the debate — even if Hillary faints or has another coughing spell. It was also noted that microphone audio for both Trump and Clinton was not to be manipulated, so everything will be out in the open — warts and all. Can Hillary Clinton make it through another speaking engagement, this time actually having to stand up against Trump, without having her health interfere? Monday’s debate was reportedly expected to draw 100 million viewers, which would make it the biggest political event in history. If Team Hillary can’t rise to the task, it could spell doom for her campaign. Hillary Clinton recently had a 4-minute coughing fit at an rally stop in Ohio, for example. If something like that happens, or worse — she looses her footing for any reason — that could seriously be the end for her. Monday’s debate is sure shaping up to be quite the show. Share this story on Facebook and Twitter and be sure to add your opinion to the comments below. Do you think Hillary should receive special treatment because of her health? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>278</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>511</end>
        <start>279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>646</end>
        <start>512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>820</end>
        <start>647</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>992</end>
        <start>821</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1296</end>
        <start>1142</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1503</end>
        <start>1297</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1719</end>
        <start>1504</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1776</end>
        <start>1720</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1872</end>
        <start>1777</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1979</end>
        <start>1873</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <title>BREAKING: Hillary Demands Embarrassing Piece of Equipment for Debate… Gets Rejected</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/hillary-demands-gets-rejection/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-23&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
