<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>iPatriot</author>
    <links href="http://cesrusc.org/election/">
        <end>36</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ipatriot.com/beyond-daily-polls/">
        <end>991</end>
        <start>945</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The LA Times/USC Daily Tracking Poll began reporting results on July 10. Daily poll numbers represent an average of randomly sampled polling if a control group over the prior seven days. These data provide interesting perspectives of the presidential race not readily noted by just following changes in the daily poll numbers. Here are a few of those perspectives based on data up to and including September 20: These observations reveal that since August 13 there has been a steady movement in support from Clinton to Trump. Daily Averages Since August 13 Looking at averages to date since August 13, Figure 1 shows a net swing in poll averages of 6% (from 4.7% in favor of Clinton on August 13 to 1.3% in favor of Trump on September 20). A logarithmic trend best fits the history of daily averages and suggests the slow and steady trend in favor of Trump will likely continue. Daily Deviations from Averages to September 20 In Figure 2 below… Read the rest of the story at www.iPatriot.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>186</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>411</end>
        <start>187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>525</end>
        <start>412</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>556</end>
        <start>526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>739</end>
        <start>557</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>878</end>
        <start>740</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>925</end>
        <start>879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>944</end>
        <start>926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>992</end>
        <start>992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1138</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1212</end>
        <start>1139</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1174</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Analyzing the LA Times Daily Tracking Poll</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36957/analyzing-the-la-times-daily-tracking-poll/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
