<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Posted by Jenna LeFever on 21 Sep 2016</author>
    <links href="http://www.heraldmailmedia.com/news/breaking/hagerstown-police-dispute-claims-of-abuse-against-girl-in-facebook/article_f52636b6-8025-11e6-9647-136e6df6cdf9.html">
        <end>74</end>
        <start>46</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/FickerLawOffices/videos/854866354614145/">
        <end>575</end>
        <start>561</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/FickerLawOffices/videos/854866354614145/">
        <end>569</end>
        <start>561</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Police protected and served the hell out of a teen girl in Hagerstown, Md. in a chilling incident that took place on Sunday. The 15-year-old biracial girl was riding her bike when she was hit by a car. She laid unconscious on the pavement for about 30 seconds and when she came to, she checked herself for injuries and decided to ride her bike home. Witnesses urged her to wait for the ambulance and police to show up, but the girl said she was fine and wanted to leave the scene. That’s when the police showed up and the situation went from bad to worse. In a Facebook video posted online, an onlooker caught the police manhandling the girl, slamming her into a wall, handcuffing her, shoving her into the back of a police car then pepper-spraying her in the face. For being hit by a car and trying to leave the girl was slapped with disorderly conduct, two counts of second-degree assault, possession of marijuana and failure to obey a traffic device. An attorney for the girl named Robin Ficker recounted the incident: She was dazed, then she got up and realized she was OK.” Ficker says when paramedics arrived the girl refused medical assistance and when she tried to ride away on her bike, police pulled the 5 foot 105 lbs girl off her bike. At this point, Ficker says the police lifted both her arms above her head and slammed her face first into a wall, adding: Her face hit the windowsill.” Ficker said at this point his client became terrified and struggled with police as they shoved her into the back of a police car. She refused to pull her feet into the car. That’s when the video begins. The cop warns her to pull her feet in or she’ll get pepper sprayed. In the video, the girl begs the white officers to call “Zack” who was a black officer she was apparently familiar with. A bystander then intervenes and questions the police over why they are treating the girl so roughly, the officer responds: “What happens…when she’s like, ‘I’m fine,’ right, and has a brain injury or something like that, and then she could die later? And she’s going to come over here and fight us when all we want to do is make sure she’s OK.” At this point, the police close the door on the girl’s feet and through a cracked window gas the backseat with pepper spray while the girl screams that she can’t breathe. Despite the police’s insistence, the girl had to be evaluated by a hospital for her injuries, rather than take her to the ER or turn her over to the paramedics, they take her straight to the police station and booked her on multiple charges. It took three hours for the girl to be released from jail, where her father drove her straight to the hospital to get the burning chemicals flushed from her eyes. Ficker says: The only treatment she got (from police) was slamming, abuse and Mace.” The girl is an honor student and never had a run-in with the law until Sunday. The Hagerstown police say they are reviewing body cam footage of the incident, but found the girl to be at fault for the bicycle accident. Featured Image via Facebook (Screen Capture)</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>124</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>480</end>
        <start>125</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>555</end>
        <start>481</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>953</end>
        <start>556</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1021</end>
        <start>954</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>1022</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1369</end>
        <start>1079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1399</end>
        <start>1370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1790</end>
        <start>1400</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2134</end>
        <start>1914</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2547</end>
        <start>2135</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2710</end>
        <start>2548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2723</end>
        <start>2711</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2795</end>
        <start>2724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2874</end>
        <start>2796</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3013</end>
        <start>2875</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3058</end>
        <start>3014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Winning Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1731</end>
        <start>1727</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2133</end>
        <start>1915</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>1022</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1399</end>
        <start>1370</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2134</end>
        <start>1914</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2795</end>
        <start>2724</start>
    </quotes>
    <title></title>
    <uri>http://winningdemocrats.com/watch-cops-tackle-and-pepper-spray-a-handcuffed-biracial-girl-after-she-was-hit-by-a-car-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
