<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rusty</author>
    <links href="https://8ch.net/pol/res/7541894.html">
        <end>462</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/M7khmkEek0">
        <end>978</end>
        <start>955</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/KqHJhiRerY">
        <end>1005</end>
        <start>979</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/kerpen/status/777880432721395712">
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>1030</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/nz13MqzWth">
        <end>1374</end>
        <start>1351</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MAGA?src=hash">
        <end>1380</end>
        <start>1375</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/qQII96JI76">
        <end>1407</end>
        <start>1381</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/GOPPollAnalyst/status/777691379971612672">
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>1030</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Lauren_Southern">
        <end>1858</end>
        <start>1842</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Cernovich">
        <end>1869</end>
        <start>1859</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/KZ9trBVpys">
        <end>1892</end>
        <start>1869</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/SMOKeMON_TRAINR/status/777909281370808320">
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>1030</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.reddit.com/r/exchangeserver/comments/2bmm4l/remove_or_replace_tofrom_address_on_archived/">
        <end>1992</end>
        <start>1979</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nypost.com/2016/09/18/inside-the-scramble-to-cover-up-clintons-private-email-server/">
        <end>2902</end>
        <start>2884</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Paul Combetta, an IT specialist who helped Hillary Clinton wipe her server clean of evidence requested from federal authorities, took to online forums to find advice on how to commit the crime. Combetta cited his Fifth Amendment rights in refusing to answer questions before a congressional committee last week, but was pretty talkative when trying to find out information from fellow IT experts on how to forge Clinton’s e-mails. Under a posting on 8chan titled “Here is clear proof that Hillary sought to destroy evidence,” Combetta can be seen posting under a username he uses multiple times across multiple platforms, ‘stonetear.’ In a screenshot of the discussion, Combetta (or stonetear) can be seen telling others “I need to strip out a VIP’s (VERY VIP) email address from a bunch of archived emails.” Presumably, that VIP would be Secretary of State Clinton. Whoa. HRod’s now immunity-protected BleachBitter Paul Combetta on REDDIT two years ago. https://t.co/M7khmkEek0 pic.twitter.com/KqHJhiRerY — Phil Kerpen (@kerpen) September 19, 2016    Later on in the thread, Combetta asks if there’s a way to “rewrite” the e-mails for his ‘VIP.’ One user tries to warn Combetta that changing the e-mails is not possible as it “could result in major legal issues.” SMOKING GUN: “BleachBit” Paul Combetta ASKED TO STRIP OR REPLACE VIP’s EMAIL ADDRESS! https://t.co/nz13MqzWth #MAGA pic.twitter.com/qQII96JI76 — Katica (@GOPPollAnalyst) September 19, 2016    As word began circulating that Combetta had been caught red-handed asking how to illegally forge Hillary’s e-mails, the man known as ‘stonetear’ began deleting his messages on the forum. Twitter user Erik Jones took video in which he refreshed his screen to show the messages disappearing. Watch … Hillarys bleackbit specialist Paul Combetta deleting all of his reddit posts on video. @Lauren_Southern @Cernovichhttps://t.co/KZ9trBVpys — Erik Jones (@SMOKeMON_TRAINR) September 19, 2016  Hillary’s IT guy made the post on July 24, 2014 and can be read in it’s entirety below: [July 24, 2014] Hello all- I may be facing a very interesting situation where I need to strip out a VIP’s (VERY VIP) email address from a bunch of archived email that I have both in a live Exchange mailbox, as well as a PST file. Basically, they don’t want the VIP’s email address exposed to anyone, and want to be able to either strip out or replace the email address in the to/from fields in all of the emails we want to send out. I am not sure if something like this is possible with PowerShell, or exporting all of the emails to MSG and doing find/replaces with a batch processing program of some sort. Does anyone have experience with something like this, and/or suggestions on how this might be accomplished? It’s important to note the date, which was within 24 hours of a recent New York Post report that showed Combetta at that time trying to ship archived data to Clinton Executive Services Corp., or CESC, which handles logistics for Hillary and Bill Clinton. Was this the same data he was trying to forge or strip of evidence? Combetta would eventually delete the archive of Clinton emails and scrub them from the server, knowing full-well the House Committee on Benghazi had requested retention of the information. Combetta has reportedly been given immunity by the Obama Justice Department and was not charged. Comment: Is this the smoking gun of intent that FBI Director James Comey said he couldn’t find in allowing Hillary to avoid indictment? Tell us your thoughts below.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>194</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>431</end>
        <start>195</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>635</end>
        <start>432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>809</end>
        <start>636</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>867</end>
        <start>810</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1006</end>
        <start>868</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1049</end>
        <start>1007</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1050</end>
        <start>1050</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1052</end>
        <start>1051</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1147</end>
        <start>1053</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1265</end>
        <start>1148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1408</end>
        <start>1266</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1454</end>
        <start>1409</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1455</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1457</end>
        <start>1456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1458</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1755</end>
        <start>1645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1893</end>
        <start>1756</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1944</end>
        <start>1894</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1945</end>
        <start>1945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2033</end>
        <start>1946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2466</end>
        <start>2034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2640</end>
        <start>2467</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2748</end>
        <start>2641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3003</end>
        <start>2749</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3071</end>
        <start>3004</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3260</end>
        <start>3072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3357</end>
        <start>3261</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3522</end>
        <start>3358</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3523</end>
        <start>3523</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3524</end>
        <start>3524</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Political Insider</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>524</end>
        <start>464</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>807</end>
        <start>722</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>1111</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1263</end>
        <start>1228</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>912</end>
        <start>903</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>867</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1453</end>
        <start>1265</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1943</end>
        <start>1755</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2747</end>
        <start>2033</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Site Navigation BOMBSHELL: Hillary’s IT Guy Caught Asking How To Destroy Evidence!</title>
    <uri>http://www.thepoliticalinsider.com/hillary-email-it-guy-caught-asked-destroy-evidence/?source=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
