<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bigot?src=hash">
        <end>568</end>
        <start>562</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HillaryRottenClinton?src=hash">
        <end>590</end>
        <start>569</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HillaryKKK?src=hash">
        <end>602</end>
        <start>591</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/67FOLtTuCu">
        <end>629</end>
        <start>603</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ed_hooley/status/769623651855413248">
        <end>671</end>
        <start>656</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://endingthefed.com/must-watch-viral-video-finally-exposes-how-hillary-really-treats-black-people.html#.V96hRB9Ss7Q.facebook">
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1813</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As Hillary Clinton would have you think, she is an advocate for the black community. However, she is really more of a snake. She not only takes their voted for granted but she also belittles them. How? She believes that all the black Americans want is more things for free. One young black American decided to take a stand against Hillary though, because she does not agree with her. Watch below as Hillary blatantly disrespects this woman, simply because she questions Hillary’s motives. INSULTER HILLARY! Hillary Clinton Insults A Young African American Voter #bigot #HillaryRottenClinton #HillaryKKK pic.twitter.com/67FOLtTuCu — Ted Hooley (@ed_hooley) August 27, 2016  Hillary warmly greeted the young woman, but her smile quickly faded when the woman brought up Clinton’s “super predator” remark as young black protesters have in the recent past. The former First Lady pointed out that during the early stages of her campaign, she professed to believing that racial profiling is wrong.   The Minnesota voter remained both unimpressed and undeterred in her quest to find out if the black community could count on Hillary Clinton to not flip-flop her belief system again if elected. Hillary was quick to say it is not true that she isn’t a friend to black Americans, and she directed the young woman to take a look at her history as a proffer of her commitment. “I don’t think that’s true. [I’ve looked] at your history and that’s not what happened,” the unidentified woman challenged again. “I will have a very comprehensive agenda to deal with a lot of the problems” was Hillary’s career politician, doublespeak non-answer. Hillary, if you cannot defend yourself against an unscripted question from a young American, then what makes you think you can beat Donald Trump at an on stage debate? For more, click here.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>273</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>383</end>
        <start>274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>488</end>
        <start>384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>629</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>671</end>
        <start>630</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>672</end>
        <start>672</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>851</end>
        <start>673</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>990</end>
        <start>852</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>992</end>
        <start>991</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1628</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1796</end>
        <start>1629</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1818</end>
        <start>1797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Trump Truck</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>792</end>
        <start>778</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1452</end>
        <start>1366</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1570</end>
        <start>1496</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>671</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1628</end>
        <start>852</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary Exposed: Have You Seen How She Really Treats Black People?</title>
    <uri>http://thetrumptruck.com/hillary-exposed-have-you-seen-how-she-really-treats-black-people/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
