<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Cassy Fiano</author>
    <links href="http://www.infowars.com/trump-slams-cnn-for-editing-out-clinton-bomb-quote-disgusting-disgraceful/">
        <end>438</end>
        <start>410</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump">
        <end>1800</end>
        <start>1784</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/EG2Yy63B4y">
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/foxandfriends/status/777830541328474112">
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1947</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>This weekend, a bombing in New York City rocked the nation as Americans everywhere wondered if we were under attack again. Donald Trump responded to the attack almost immediately, accurately describing it as a “bombing/” CNN, for some inexplicable reason, criticized him for that — even though Hillary Clinton described the attack the exact same way. So CNN edited out Hillary’s wording. And Donald Trump just ripped them a new one for it. In the CNN footage, they only showed Clinton responding to a question from a reporter, where she agreed that Trump was “insensitive” for calling the Chelsea bombing a “bombing.” Jake Tapper played the same footage a second time and again criticized Trump for jumping to conclusions. Both times, the network did not air Clinton’s own description of the attack as a bombing, even though it happened just seconds before she answered the reporter’s question.   Trump was interviewed on Fox and Friends and he held nothing back. “CNN is disgusting and disgraceful,” he declared. “These people are the most dishonest people, CNN is so disgusting and dishonest, and I watch it, it’s so unfair, they call it the Clinton news network. She used the word ‘bombs’ also by the way… I was criticized for calling it correctly – what I said was exactly correct.” He also pointed the finger at “stupid” leaders going soft on terrorism. “Well it’s a mess and it’s a shame and we’re going to have to be very tough,” he said. “I think we’re going to see a big change over the last couple of days, I think this is something that will happen more and more all over the country.” He explained that “because we’ve been weak, out country’s been weak, we’re letting people in by the thousands and the tens of thousands, and as I’ve been saying you’ve got to stop it.”  .@realDonaldTrump slams "dishonest" CNN for editing out Clinton reference to NYC explosion as 'bombing' pic.twitter.com/EG2Yy63B4y — FOX &amp; Friends (@foxandfriends) September 19, 2016   Obama was heavily criticized by Trump for his plan to accept over 110,000 Syrian refugees in 2017 — and Hillary wants to make that number even higher, according to Trump. “Hillary Clinton wants to increase what he’s letting in and he’s letting in thousands of thousands of people… they can’t be properly vetted,” said Trump. “He let in over 100,000 additional people and now Hillary Clinton is raising it by 550 per cent… thousands of people are pouring into our country and we have no idea what we’re doing. Our leaders are – I don’t even say weak – I say stupid.” </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>441</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>896</end>
        <start>442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>897</end>
        <start>897</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>898</end>
        <start>898</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1288</end>
        <start>899</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1783</end>
        <start>1289</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1784</end>
        <start>1784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1915</end>
        <start>1785</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1967</end>
        <start>1916</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1968</end>
        <start>1968</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1969</end>
        <start>1969</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2535</end>
        <start>1970</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2536</end>
        <start>2536</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>219</end>
        <start>211</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>571</end>
        <start>560</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>616</end>
        <start>608</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>999</end>
        <start>965</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1285</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1324</end>
        <start>1318</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1435</end>
        <start>1360</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1595</end>
        <start>1447</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1780</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2279</end>
        <start>2140</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2532</end>
        <start>2294</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1965</end>
        <start>1783</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>CNN FURIOUS and Embarrassed After Trump Called Them Out For One Major Thing</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/donald-trump/cnn-furious-embarrassed-trump-called-them-one-major-thing/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
