<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Walter White</author>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/19/exclusive-clinton-foundation-aids-program-distributed-watered-down-drugs-to-third-world-countries/">
        <end>436</end>
        <start>420</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Over the past several months, the American public has become increasingly aware of the massive corruption that has taken place at the Clinton Foundation since Hillary Clinton was Secretary of State. Well, a new report suggests that the foundation is in even more trouble than previously thought. According to the Daily Caller, the foundation, AIDS program distributed “watered down” drugs to third-world countries. From The Daily Caller: Former President Bill Clinton and his Clinton Health Access Initiative (CHAI) distributed “watered-down” HIV/AIDs drugs to patients in sub-Saharan Africa, and “likely increased” the risks of morbidity and mortality, according to a draft congressional report obtained by The Daily Caller News Foundation. — The CHAI program to help AIDS victims is considered one of the Clinton Foundation’s most important contributions and is probably its best known initiative. — The possibility that CHAI distributed adulterated and diluted AIDS drugs to Third World victims could shake the foundations of the Clinton charity and spark a new round of scrutiny in the final weeks of presidential candidate Hillary Clinton’s campaign. — The congressional study also highlighted the unseemly ties between Bill and two controversial Indian-Americans who have been investigated and sanctioned by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and the Securities and Exchange Commission. The most troubling revelations concern the Clinton Foundation’s vigorous promotion of Ranbaxy despite mounting evidence the Indian firm had persistently poor quality control and attempted to cover it up through either faulty or fraudulent reporting to the FDA. It is unclear at this juncture how many AIDS patients received the “watered-down” drugs. This latest report proves that the Clinton Foundation should be SHUT DOWN immediately rather than serve as a means of enriching Bill and Hillary! Do you think that the Clinton Foundation should be shut down immediately before it continues to harm more and more people around the world? Share your thoughts below!   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>199</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>415</end>
        <start>200</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>438</end>
        <start>416</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>742</end>
        <start>439</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>744</end>
        <start>743</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>900</end>
        <start>745</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>902</end>
        <start>901</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1156</end>
        <start>903</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1158</end>
        <start>1157</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1397</end>
        <start>1159</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1658</end>
        <start>1398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1747</end>
        <start>1659</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1893</end>
        <start>1748</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2061</end>
        <start>1894</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2062</end>
        <start>2062</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2063</end>
        <start>2063</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Political Insider</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>381</end>
        <start>369</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>541</end>
        <start>529</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>614</end>
        <start>598</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>541</end>
        <start>529</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1746</end>
        <start>438</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Site Navigation Bill And Hillary Clinton Have A MAJOR AIDS Scandal!</title>
    <uri>http://www.thepoliticalinsider.com/clinton-aids-bill-hillary-major-scandal/?source=RWN</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
