<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Onan Coca</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/FoxNews/status/777753710524977152">
        <end>661</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://constitution.com/terror-attacks-apparently-arent-terrorism/">
        <end>709</end>
        <start>691</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/19/number-individuals-in-custody-after-authorities-stop-vehicle-interest-in-chelsea-bombing.html">
        <end>1086</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YquUrglB1uQ">
        <end>1927</end>
        <start>1897</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/19/person-interest-to-named-in-nyc-bombing.html">
        <end>2074</end>
        <start>2037</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/kuiR1Q6LUF">
        <end>2184</end>
        <start>2161</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/fYYurIZIeu">
        <end>2211</end>
        <start>2185</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/NBCNewYork/status/777894574459006977">
        <end>661</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/on-air/fox-and-friends/">
        <end>3570</end>
        <start>3554</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://constitution.com/breaking-news-another-bomb-explodes-new-jersey-early-monday-morning/">
        <end>3617</end>
        <start>3571</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>This is hot off the presses folks – something dangerous is going on in the New York City metro area. At around 12:40 AM Monday morning police were alerted to a suspicious backpack near a trashcan in an Elizabeth, New Jersey trashcan. The men who reported it said they could see a pipe and wires sticking out of the bag. When police arrived they discovered FIVE different devices but when a bomb squad robot approached the bag one of the devices exploded, fortunately no one was injured. UPDATE: Elizabeth, NJ mayor says five devices found in bag near train station. One exploded while bomb squad robot tried to disarm it — Fox News (@FoxNews) September 19, 2016  The latest bomb scare comes just one day after two other bombs exploded (one in Seaside Park, New Jersey and one in Manhattan) and three more were found by authorities before they could be detonated. Late Sunday evening authorities announced that they believed all five bombs from Saturday were the work of the same people, then later in the night they announced that they had made five arrests in connection with the bombs. Federal authorities conducted a traffic stop of a “vehicle of interest” in the Chelsea bombing Sunday night in Brooklyn. A law enforcement source told Fox News that a “number of individuals” who are possibly connected to the explosion were taken into custody. Law enforcement officials told the Associated Press that at least 5 men were being questioned. The two officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to talk about an ongoing investigation. The FBI said in a statement that no one had been charged with any crime and the investigation was ongoing. There is no word yet if the latest group of bombs found in Elizabeth, are connected to the just detained persons of interest. Elizabeth, New Jersey Mayor, Christian Bollwage speaking to the media about the bomb (you can see more video from the scene here):  UPDATE: The man sought in connection with the bombings in Manhattan and Seaside Park, New Jersey has been captured after a shootout with police. NEW PHOTO: Ahmad Rahami captured in Linden, NJ, senior law enforcement official says https://t.co/kuiR1Q6LUF pic.twitter.com/fYYurIZIeu — NBC New York (@NBCNewYork) September 19, 2016  Ahmad Khan Rahami is a Muslim man of Afghani origin who was living in Elizabeth, New Jersey (the city where the bombs were found late last night/early this morning). Authorities had launched a dragnet earlier Monday in search of the 28-year-old Afghan-born man, whom they described as being “armed and dangerous” A naturalized U.S. citizen, Rahami was wanted for questioning regarding the Saturday night blast in New York’s Chelsea neighborhood, an explosion in New Jersey’s Seaside Park on Saturday morning and a foiled bomb attack Sunday night near a train station in Elizabeth, NJ. An eyewitness to Rahami’s capture in Linden, NJ told Fox News that he saw a man walking down a street with a gun in his hand. A police car pulled up next to him and the man fired at cops 4-6 times. The shooter then began running down the street with several police cars trailing him, the witness, Peter Bilinskas, said. After days of pretending that the bombings were not the work of Islamic terrorists it seems that New York’s liberals are finally beginning to understand the truth. If a bomb goes off on American soil, it is more likely than not the work of Muslim terrorists. “Today I believe we’re going to find out that [the bombing] was influenced by foreign sources,” Gov. Andrew Cuomo said Monday on “Fox &amp; Friends.” Reposted With Permission From Constitution.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>100</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>486</end>
        <start>101</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>620</end>
        <start>487</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>661</end>
        <start>621</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>662</end>
        <start>662</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>862</end>
        <start>663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1087</end>
        <start>863</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1347</end>
        <start>1088</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1672</end>
        <start>1348</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1798</end>
        <start>1673</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1929</end>
        <start>1799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1930</end>
        <start>1930</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1938</end>
        <start>1931</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2075</end>
        <start>1939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2211</end>
        <start>2076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2259</end>
        <start>2212</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2260</end>
        <start>2260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2426</end>
        <start>2261</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2573</end>
        <start>2427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2845</end>
        <start>2574</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3165</end>
        <start>2846</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3424</end>
        <start>3166</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3570</end>
        <start>3425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3617</end>
        <start>3571</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3618</end>
        <start>3618</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3764</end>
        <start>3619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3838</end>
        <start>3765</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1158</end>
        <start>1139</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1277</end>
        <start>1256</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2572</end>
        <start>2553</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3519</end>
        <start>3426</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3569</end>
        <start>3555</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>661</end>
        <start>487</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>929</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2259</end>
        <start>2076</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3165</end>
        <start>2427</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3570</end>
        <start>3425</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3800</end>
        <start>3788</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Another Bomb Explodes in New Jersey…UPDATE: Suspect Arrested</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36865/breaking-another-bomb-explodes-in-new-jersey-update-suspect-arrested/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
