<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/breaking-reddit-users-find-proof-hillarys-company-researching-delete-emails-without-trace/">
        <end>1411</end>
        <start>1398</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MAGA?src=hash">
        <end>1536</end>
        <start>1531</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/m5fYUmibpT">
        <end>1560</end>
        <start>1537</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/RepStevenSmith/status/777692226361057280">
        <end>1617</end>
        <start>1599</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/nz13MqzWth">
        <end>1887</end>
        <start>1864</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MAGA?src=hash">
        <end>1536</end>
        <start>1531</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/qQII96JI76">
        <end>1920</end>
        <start>1894</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/GOPPollAnalyst/status/777691379971612672">
        <end>1617</end>
        <start>1599</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/09/us/politics/hillary-clinton-emails-investigation.html?_r=0">
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>1981</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/breaking-reddit-users-find-proof-hillarys-company-researching-delete-emails-without-trace/">
        <end>2353</end>
        <start>2322</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://archive.is/NGGzn">
        <end>2532</end>
        <start>2484</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Back in August, after showing up an hour late to her first campaign event in Nevada, Hillary was used by Ed Hendy “The FBI believes you tried to wipe the entire server. Did you try to wipe the entire…so there could be no email–no personal, no official; wipe the whole thing?” Hillary acted puzzled in her reply, interpreting the question literally; “Like with a cloth or something?” I say she was acting because she had previously wiped her server with BleachBit, a tool so good for deleting emails permanently that “even God can’t read them,” as Trey Gowdy put it in a committee meeting. He cited it as “further proof that Clinton had something to hide in deleting personal emails from the private email system she used during her tenure as Secretary of State.” I’m inclined to think the same, given Hillary’s lengthy history of dishonesty. Now, we’ve just uncovered PROOF that Hillary has researched how to delete emails permanently without leaving a trace. Paul Combetta, an IT specialist who helped Hillary Clinton wipe her server clean of evidence requested from federal authorities, took to online forums to find advice on how to commit the crime. Combetta cited his Fifth Amendment rights in refusing to answer questions before a congressional committee last week, but was pretty talkative when trying to find out information from fellow IT experts on how to forge Clinton’s e-mails. As the Gateway Pundit reported: BREAKING: Citizen Journalist breaks HUGE Clinton email story PROVING Hillary ORDERED EMAILS TO BE STRIPPED! #MAGA https://t.co/m5fYUmibpT — Rep. Steven Smith (@RepStevenSmith) September 19, 2016  This exchange took place on Reddit and involves Paul Combetta, an employee with Platte River Networks, the company in charge of Hillary Clinton’s home server. SMOKING GUN: “BleachBit” Paul Combetta ASKED TO STRIP OR REPLACE VIP’s EMAIL ADDRESS! https://t.co/nz13MqzWth #MAGA pic.twitter.com/qQII96JI76 — Katica (@GOPPollAnalyst) September 19, 2016  Combetta was granted immunity from Obama’s Department of Justice in their investigation of Clinton. Combetta was the employee who deleted all of Hillary Clinton’s emails. According users on Reddit, Combetta asked for assistance in July 2014 from Reddit users on how to purge emails and how to strip VIP’s email address from “a bunch of archived emails.” Read the entire exchange here.  After the Gateway Pundit broke this story, a number of comments from the Reddit thread in question suspiciously went missing, but Archive.is has a link of the deleted reddit post. And just a random thought: how stupid do you have to be to get advice on committing a Federal crime on Reddit? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>382</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>841</end>
        <start>383</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>959</end>
        <start>842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1153</end>
        <start>960</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1390</end>
        <start>1154</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1422</end>
        <start>1391</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1560</end>
        <start>1423</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1617</end>
        <start>1561</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1618</end>
        <start>1618</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1777</end>
        <start>1619</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1920</end>
        <start>1778</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1966</end>
        <start>1921</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1967</end>
        <start>1967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2067</end>
        <start>1968</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2138</end>
        <start>2068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2321</end>
        <start>2139</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2353</end>
        <start>2322</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2533</end>
        <start>2354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2644</end>
        <start>2534</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2645</end>
        <start>2645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>274</end>
        <start>115</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>381</end>
        <start>350</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>542</end>
        <start>517</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>761</end>
        <start>605</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>462</end>
        <start>453</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2320</end>
        <start>2293</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1617</end>
        <start>1423</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>700</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1966</end>
        <start>1778</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Hillarys IT Firm Asked Reddit Users How to Wipe Server Clean of ‘VIP Email Name’</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/breaking-hillarys-firm-asked-reddit-users-wipe-server-clean-vip-email-name/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
