<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/160927122545-state-trooper-prays-exlarge-169.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.gofundme.com/2ra7cggc">
        <end>2395</end>
        <start>2387</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Very rarely does a cop’s good deed ever make it into the headlines. It’s just not provocative enough for most in the mainstream media, so they have no reason to run it. But we do. With all of the pain that Americans are facing with the riots and the hatred of men and women who are sworn to protect the public, we at Right Wing News are dedicated to balancing out the seemingly endless stream of anger.  Mark Ross wasn’t shy about admitting that he disliked police officers, but when a tragic event struck his family, an officer turned out to be the best friend he’d never expected to have. You see, Ross received a phone call that nobody ever wants to get; the call telling him that his sister had passed away after getting into a car accident. Doing what any of the rest of us would do, he hopped into a car with his friend at the wheel and they sped toward Detroit. While passing through Ohio, they were pulled over for speeding. The driver was taken to the local jail and the car was impounded. So what happened to Ross? He began explaining to the officer the reason for the traffic infraction. As he told the officer about the loss of his sister, he broke into tears and began sobbing. Instead of leaving him on the side of the road, or taking him to the closest bus stop, the officer decided to do what he knew was right. The officer reached out to Ross and prayed for him and his family. He also drove him 100 miles to the prison where his friend was being held so he could get bailed out, and to get Ross closer to Michigan. Ross posted the above photo on his Facebook page with the following message: At 3am I got a phone call stating that my sister had been killed in a car accident due to some young dumb punk! I haven’t slept and instantly got on the road. Of course we were speeding, trying to get back to Detroit. And we got pulled over in Ohio. I knew I was going to Jail due to a petty warrant. The police called Wayne county and they refused to come get me because of the distance. I explained to the officer that my sister had died and that I needed to get to my mother asap. I broke down crying and he saw the sincerity in my cry. He REACHES OVER AND BEGAN PRAYING OVER ME AND MY FAMILY. He offered to bring me 100 miles further to Detroit because they towed the vehicle. Everybody knows how much I dislike Cops but I am truly Greatful for this Guy. He gave me hope A GoFundMe has been set up to help pay for his sister’s funeral expenses. If you have an extra dollar hanging around, please consider donating it to this family in this time of grief. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>168</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>179</end>
        <start>169</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>402</end>
        <start>180</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>403</end>
        <start>403</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>590</end>
        <start>404</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>868</end>
        <start>591</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>998</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1190</end>
        <start>999</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1327</end>
        <start>1191</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1532</end>
        <start>1328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1609</end>
        <start>1533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2384</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2568</end>
        <start>2385</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2569</end>
        <start>2569</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2384</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Heroic cop drives grieving man 100 miles after traffic stop</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/heroic-cop-drives-grieving-man-100-miles-traffic-stop/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
