<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-debate-babe-ruth-conway-228636">
        <end>889</end>
        <start>867</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>KENDALL, Fla. -- Tim Kaine isn’t playing the lowered expectations game for Hillary Clinton ahead of the first presidential debate. The Democratic vice presidential nominee all but guaranteed a win by his running mate on Monday in New York, predicting Clinton will shine and Donald Trump will fumble when asked about specifics, the Trump Foundation and Trump University. Story Continued Below “When the lights are bright like they are now she brings the A-plus game. She’ll be very, very good tomorrow. Donald Trump’s a performer and an entertainer, I’m not taking that away from him,” Kaine said at a rally here on a campus of Miami-Dade College. “But he can't get away with the 15-second thing and then walking away. … No, it’s 90 minutes, mano y mano.” Kaine’s bullish view of the world came just hours after Trump campaign manager Kellyanne Conway called him the “Babe Ruth of debating." It’s a counterintuitive political strategy: Raising expectations ahead of what may be the most-watched debate in history is a risky proposition for both sides when the race is so tight. In 2012, President Barack Obama gave a rusty performance in his first debate that jolted the race and alarmed Democrats nationwide. The Virginia senator himself acknowledged that things had gotten closer than many Democrats had hoped, repeatedly calling Clinton’s lead “narrow.” But he suggested that Monday night could change all that. “You’re going to see him have to get into specifics and Hillary too. But we’re going to see who can answer the specific questions. I mean Donald Trump hasn’t answered a basic question that’s been asked of presidential candidates: show us your tax returns,” Kaine said. “Donald Trump’s had problems with the specifics so far, tomorrow night we’re going to see: Can he give some specifics?” Kaine barely mentioned Mike Pence, Trump’s running mate, even though the two will debate in just over a week. His only knock on Pence was that he was too easy on Russian President Vladimir Putin.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>130</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>369</end>
        <start>131</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>391</end>
        <start>370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>754</end>
        <start>392</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1208</end>
        <start>755</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1209</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1802</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1998</end>
        <start>1803</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>583</end>
        <start>393</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>753</end>
        <start>648</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1354</end>
        <start>867</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1669</end>
        <start>1415</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1801</end>
        <start>1684</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Kaine raises debate expectations for Clinton</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/tim-kaine-hillary-clinton-debate-expectations-228652?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
