<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2016/09/24/bill-clinton-accuser-gennifer-flowers-accepts-donald-trumps-invitation-to-attend-debate/">
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>1085</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/andrewkaczynski/gennifer-flowers-agrees-to-join-trump-at-presidential-debate?utm_term=.nuaMgYO0Z#.vmYwZW9MV">
        <end>1383</end>
        <start>1353</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/25/us/politics/gennifer-flowers-debate-trump-clinton.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;module=first-column-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;_r=0">
        <end>1488</end>
        <start>1468</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Before the debate has begun, Clinton has been out-trumped. Apparently Clinton will have billionaire Mark Cuban sitting in the front row of the debate. Some believe this move would intimidate Trump, though the two billionaires don’t really have much of a past together. Cuban recently challenged Trump to a “sit down” to discuss policy for 4 hours with no Clinton-bashing. If Trump accepted, Cuban agreed to donate $1 million to charity. Why Cuban has decided to jump in the presidential fray, since he is as significant in the discussion as navel lint. One might believe that with the ineffectiveness of Hillary Clinton’s “not so secret weapon,” Bill Clinton, that Cuban has become her surrogate. Other than ignore Cuban, if I were Trump, I would have donated $1 million to my own charity, then proclaimed victory over Cuban. My statement would be, “Mark Cuban is a publicity seeker who needs me to be relevant.” As for Hillary Clinton bringing Cuban, this strategy will backfire. To some degree it already has, as in Trump’s response, Hillary Clinton has already been out-trumped. As reported by the Washington Post: Gennifer Flowers, who revealed a sexual relationship with Bill Clinton in the 1990s, is saying she will attend Monday night’s debate between Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton as Trump’s guest. Flowers’s assistant confirmed the decision to BuzzFeed’s Andrew Kaczynski Saturday afternoon, and Flowers herself told the New York Times in a text message, “Yes, I will be there.” The decision was the latest play in a bizarre bit of gamesmanship between the Clinton and Trump campaigns over the debate. Clinton’s camp confirmed this week that it would invite billionaire mogul Mark Cuban, a Trump antagonist, to the debate. First, Cuban is insignificant. It would be different if Trump hadn’t already marginalized Cuban. Cuban said Trump wasn’t wealthy, then later retracted the statement after more careful examination of Trump’s finances. Cuban is kooky. Sure he’s successful, but not as successful as Trump. Next, by bringing in Cuban, Hillary Clinton opened herself up for LOTS of damage. Trump has already responded by bringing in Jennifer Flowers, a move sure to open more moves. But this may be only the beginning. But Trump has many more “mind-screws” he can do on Hillary and it can all happen before the debate. For example, Trump could invite Anita Broderick, and reference her when Hillary discusses the war on women. He could invite Linda Tripp, and have Linda appear with the infamous “blue dress.” Or Trump could go for the jugular and invite Monica Lewinsky. Perhaps Trump could invite the families of the Benghazi victims, or a few Bernie or Bust supporters. Hillary Clinton has let the genie out of the bottle, and this genie is not her friend. Hillary Clinton has out-trumped herself. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>58</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>268</end>
        <start>59</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>552</end>
        <start>269</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>696</end>
        <start>553</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>912</end>
        <start>697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>913</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>1082</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1309</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1490</end>
        <start>1310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1491</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2021</end>
        <start>1735</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2232</end>
        <start>2022</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2585</end>
        <start>2233</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2686</end>
        <start>2586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2814</end>
        <start>2687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2815</end>
        <start>2815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>The Black Sphere</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>315</end>
        <start>307</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>644</end>
        <start>623</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>911</end>
        <start>850</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1489</end>
        <start>1468</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2269</end>
        <start>2258</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2522</end>
        <start>2511</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1734</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary Clinton Out-Trumped Before Debate</title>
    <uri>http://theblacksphere.net/2016/09/hillary-clinton-out-trumped-before-debate/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
