<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Blair Patterson</author>
    <links href="http://insider.foxnews.com/2016/09/21/newt-gingrich-charlotte-anti-police-unrest-keith-scott-american-tragedy">
        <end>1997</end>
        <start>1982</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Here we go again. Cop shoots thug, Black Lives Matter morons riot, cause mass destruction, and cause harm to businesses and people. This is the world we live in, folks,and it’s happening in front of our very eyes…again. And nowhere to be found is our do-nothing president who consistently sides with all the rioters. He couldn’t care less as his racially charged agenda is to divide the US so much that we’re sent back to the civil right movement. Or so it would seem. New Gingrich just called out BLM and Obama for this decay of race relations. It’s put square on their shoulders and we agree with him! Watch below.  “Fifty-three years after Martin Luther King’s ‘I Have A Dream’ speech; eight years after the election of an African-American president…race relations are decaying in this country.” “Schools that don’t work, neighborhoods with no jobs, random violence, a sense of being powerless even though there is an African-American president,” Gingrich said. But there’s another problem here. Whenever there is a riot, Obama speaks out in favor of BLM saying that we need to reform our police and they need to take more responsibility for their actions. However, when countless thousands are killed in inner city black on black crime across the country, specifically in Chicago, Obama’s hometown, he doesn’t bat an eye. Because it doesn’t fit his agenda. He lamented the fact that major Democratic leaders have not intently reacted to repeated events of anti-police protests and urban violence. “Over 3,000 people shot in Chicago…but no national reaction: Obama doesn’t notice it, Clinton doesn’t notice it.” “The country at large will not tolerate this kind of random violence. People will not tolerate looting…closing Interstate 85– burning things.” What we need is someone who can restore order to things. This must end. Police must be vigilant and arrest anyone who riots. We need a president who can stop all this, not Obama who only ads fuel to the quite literal fires. Read more here… </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>219</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>603</end>
        <start>220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>616</end>
        <start>604</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>617</end>
        <start>617</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>798</end>
        <start>618</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>964</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1360</end>
        <start>965</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1614</end>
        <start>1501</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1757</end>
        <start>1615</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1981</end>
        <start>1758</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1997</end>
        <start>1982</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1998</end>
        <start>1998</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Yes Im Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>797</end>
        <start>619</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>948</end>
        <start>800</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1613</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1756</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>964</end>
        <start>618</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1757</end>
        <start>1361</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Newt’s Response To The Charlotte Riots Is Black Lives Matter’s Worst Nightmare</title>
    <uri>http://www.yesimright.com/newts-response-to-the-charlotte-riots-is-black-lives-matters-worst-nightmare/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
