<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="https://www.thereligionofpeace.com/pages/quran/wife-beating.aspx">
        <end>1951</end>
        <start>1933</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.usc.edu/org/cmje/religious-texts/hadith/muslim/004-smt.php#004.2127">
        <end>2009</end>
        <start>1992</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Muslim Somali asylum seeker, Abdullah, in Sundsvall, Sweden is a bastard! Abdullah is well-known by police for his multiple convictions of violent crimes, assaults and molestations. This aggressive piece of garbage has been collecting welfare benefits and committing crimes since he came to Sweden 5 years ago. His most recent crime wasn’t to any stranger this time it was to his wife. He had gone out to party with friends one night after a long hard day of doing nothing but living off taxpayers money. Before he left he commanded (not suggested) his wife that her niece she was babysitting MUST be gone before he returned from his night of pleasure. Because he beat her regularly she knew that he meant it. The story takes a sad turn when he returns home and sees that the niece is still there so his Muslim right to punish his PREGNANT wife for her disobedience comes into play. He forced her to the ground so he could kick her in the head and stomach. He then proceeded to humiliate her further by pouring beer all over her. That is strange to me since Muslims aren’t supposedly suppose to have alcohol, I wonder why it was there in the first place. He then finished off her humiliation by pulling down his pants and soaking her hair and body with his urine. Thank you Mohammad for your wise words on how to treat a ‘disobedient’ woman. Especially when pregnant. Quran 4:34 — So righteous women are devoutly obedient, guarding in [the husband’s] absence what Allah would have them guard. But those [wives] from whom you fear arrogance – [first] advise them; [then if they persist], forsake them in bed; and [finally], strike them. But if they obey you [once more], seek no means against them. Indeed, Allah is ever Exalted and Grand. Just in case there was any doubt as to the proper interpretation of “beat them,” the Islamic prophet Muhammad modeled it literally, telling a visibly battered woman to return to her husband and fulfill his sexual desires and later striking his favorite wife in the chest. I wonder where it says you can pick and choose WHICH edicts from the Quran and hadith you want to obey? This guy is swilling alcohol and abandoning his wife at night but gets to come home and beat her with his hands and fists. I believe the Quran instructs to only beat her with a switch but I guess this nasty louse missed going to mosque too many times OR someone is writing yet another instruction book of terror for Muslims which he is following. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>385</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>709</end>
        <start>386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1263</end>
        <start>710</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1738</end>
        <start>1264</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2010</end>
        <start>1739</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2461</end>
        <start>2011</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2462</end>
        <start>2462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1818</end>
        <start>1808</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2010</end>
        <start>1739</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>SICK! Muslim Refugee Beats, Urinates On Pregnant Woman After Seeing What She Has</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/sick-muslim-refugee-beats-urinates-on-pregnant-woman-after-seeing-what-she-has/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
