<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="https://assets.donaldjtrump.com/Trump_Economic_Plan.pdf">
        <end>772</end>
        <start>736</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newsmax.com/Finance/StreetTalk/donald-trump-hillary-clinton-wilbur-ross-GDP/2016/09/26/id/750188/">
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1832</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump has economic advisers that have helped him develop a plan that will grow the economy. It is in great contrast to the socialist economy the Hillary has planned for you. It addresses the current regulatory burden, energy, and trade in a manner that will meet your approval. Read some of the specifics for yourself.    As Written By Newsmax: Donald Trump’s economic plan will “significantly increase America’s real GDP growth rate” – resulting in trillions of dollars of additional revenues, according to a new study authored by investor Wilbur Ross and Peter Navarro, a top economist at the University of California. “When evaluated as a single integrated whole, the Trump plan is revenue neutral and fiscally conservative,” Ross and Navarro write in the study. Ross, one of the nation’s most respected private equity investors, and Navarro serve as senior economic policy advisers for Trump’s campaign. “It grows the economy much faster than Hillary Clinton’s plan to raise taxes, increase regulation, stifle our energy sector, and perpetuate chronic trade deficits,” the study finds. Meanwhile, Trump’s economic plan “proposes tax cuts, reduced regulation, lower energy costs, and eliminating America’s chronic trade deficit,” Ross-Navarro say. The authors conclude that “Hillary Clinton’s economic plan will inhibit growth.” Hillary Clinton “proposes higher taxes, more regulation, and further restrictions on fossil fuels that will significantly raise energy and electricity costs,” the report states. “Clinton will also perpetuate trade policies and trade deals she has helped put in place that have led to chronic trade deficits and reduced economic growth.” The economists write that Trump’s reforms in trade, regulations and energy would result in revenue gains of $2.374 trillion, making the …. Full Story Here: Wilbur Ross, Economist Navarro: Trump’s Plan Grows GDP Much Faster Than Hillary’s</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>325</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>326</end>
        <start>326</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>328</end>
        <start>327</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>351</end>
        <start>329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>627</end>
        <start>352</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>772</end>
        <start>628</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>914</end>
        <start>773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1096</end>
        <start>915</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1257</end>
        <start>1097</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1338</end>
        <start>1258</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1516</end>
        <start>1339</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1675</end>
        <start>1517</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1814</end>
        <start>1676</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1831</end>
        <start>1815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1832</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>440</end>
        <start>387</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>734</end>
        <start>629</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>916</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1238</end>
        <start>1131</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1337</end>
        <start>1285</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1496</end>
        <start>1356</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1674</end>
        <start>1518</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1913</end>
        <start>1815</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Top Economists ‘Trump Will Grow US Much Faster Than Hillary’</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/top-economists-trump-will-grow-us-much-faster-than-hillary/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
