<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Jeff Dunetz</author>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2016/09/18/obama-says-its-personal-insult-if-black-voters-dont-back-clinton.html">
        <end>292</end>
        <start>276</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.census.gov/content/dam/Census/library/publications/2016/demo/p60-256.pdf">
        <end>1255</end>
        <start>1236</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://lidblog.com/obama-its-a-personal-insult-if-black-voters-dont-back-clinton/">
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1510</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Barack Obama is planning on leaving office the same way he came in, making things all about him.  Speaking to a Congressional Black Caucus event on Saturday Night, the narcissist-in-chief said he would take it as a personal insult if Black voters didn’t turn out and vote for Hillary Clinton. I will consider it a personal insult, an insult to my legacy if this community lets down its guard and fails to activate itself in this election. You want to give me a good send-off, go vote. (…) Obama also sought to blunt Trump’s recent efforts to reach out to black voters, saying Trump at one point in the race had said there’s never been a worse time to be a black person. “I mean, he missed that whole civics lesson about slavery and Jim Crow, but we’ve got a museum for him to visit,” Obama said, a reference to next week’s opening of the National Museum of African American History and Culture. “We will educate him.” Obama may have been referring to an ABC interview with Trump in 2015 when he asserted the nation’s first black president had done “nothing” for African-Americans. “They are worse now than just about ever,” he said. While it is not the worst time ever for African Americans, it’s been pretty bad.  The chart below uses Census Bureau data to show what has happened to household income African American and all U.S. households under Obama. It shows median household income for every year from Bush #43’s final year (2008-in red) through 2015. Each Obama year is compared to the final Bush year. Read the Rest of the Story and See the Census Bureau CHART at Jeff Dunetz’s Blog The Lid  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>292</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>484</end>
        <start>293</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>669</end>
        <start>485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>917</end>
        <start>670</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1132</end>
        <start>918</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1509</end>
        <start>1133</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1598</end>
        <start>1510</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1599</end>
        <start>1599</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1745</end>
        <start>1600</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1819</end>
        <start>1746</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>782</end>
        <start>671</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>916</end>
        <start>896</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1056</end>
        <start>1049</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1122</end>
        <start>1082</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1132</end>
        <start>293</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1781</end>
        <start>1769</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Median Income Among Black Households Has FALLEN Since Obama Took Office</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36859/median-income-among-black-households-has-fallen-since-obama-took-office/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
