<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>John Prager</author>
    <mainText>After Monday’s debate, Donald Trump almost certainly wishes he had been covered in honey, placed on top of a colony of fire ants, and kicked in his surely gold-plated testicles repeatedly as someone reads “Twilight” to him rather than face Hillary Clinton in a head-to-head matchup. Moderator Lester Holt reminded Trump that he said Clinton doesn’t have a “presidential look” and asked him what he meant by that. “She doesn’t have the look,” Trump replied. “She doesn’t have the stamina. I said she doesn’t have the stamina and I don’t believe she does have the stamina. To be President of this country, you need tremendous stamina.” Clinton, who was an absolute badass the entire debate, just stood there. And laughed. And smiled. And let him talk. Then, when it was her turn, she turned the burn up to 9,000 degrees: “Well, as soon as he travels to 112 countries and negotiates a peace deal, a ceasefire, a release of dissidents, or even spends 11 hours testifying in front of a congressional committee, he can talk to me about stamina.” Watch Clinton bring down the hammer below:  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>288</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>424</end>
        <start>289</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>662</end>
        <start>425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>847</end>
        <start>663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1072</end>
        <start>848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1115</end>
        <start>1073</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>1116</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>848</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Donald Trump Attacked Clinton’s ‘Stamina’ And Her Response Was Absolutely Brilliant (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://addictinginfo.org/2016/09/26/donald-trump-attacked-clintons-stamina-and-her-response-was-absolutely-brilliant-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
