<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tom Cahill</author>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/RBReich/">
        <end>66</end>
        <start>54</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/RBReich/posts/1311195112226415">
        <end>659</end>
        <start>633</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In a viral status update posted to his Facebook page, Robert Reich perfectly explained how to get through to a Donald Trump supporter. The Berkeley professor and U.S. Secretary of Labor recently wrote about an encounter with a voter supporting the GOP presidential nominee, and how he managed to convince the would-be Trump supporter to reconsider his support of the blustery billionaire. The post has caught fire, garnering nearly 25,000 shares in roughly three hours as of this writing. I finally found a Trump supporter — this morning when I went to buy coffee. (I noticed a Trump bumper sticker on his… Posted by Robert Reich on Monday, September 19, 2016 The post begins with Reich patronizing a local coffee shop, and encountering a man with a Trump bumper sticker on his car. When Reich asked the man if he was a Donald Trump supporter, the man defensively responded in the affirmative. Rather than attempting to preach to the Trump supporter, the former U.S. Secretary of Labor engagefd him in dialogue and asked him why he was supporting the GOP nominee. After the man told Reich he was voting for Trump due to his business acumen, Reich reminded him that Trump inherited most of his wealth, and invested it poorly. The man was silent by the time Reich told him about Trump’s real estate empire being largely built on the backs of taxpayers with nearly $900 million in public dollars. Reich’s account of the conversation is a perfect example of how to politely plant seeds of doubt in the minds of Trump’s supporters in the last 50 days before the general election: “I know he’s a little bit much,” said the Trump supporter. “But he’s a successful businessman. And we need a successful businessman as president.” “How do you know he’s a successful businessman?” I asked. “Because he’s made a fortune.” “Has he really?” I asked. “Of course. Forbes magazine says he’s worth four and a half billion.” “That doesn’t mean he’s been a success,” I said. “In my book it does,” said the Trump supporter. “You know, in 1976, when Trump was just starting his career, he said he was worth about $200 million,” I said. “Most of that was from his father.” “That just proves my point,” said the Trump supporter. “He turned that $200 million into four and a half billion. Brilliant man.” “But if he had just put that $200 million into an index fund and reinvested the dividends, he’d be worth twelve billion today,” I said. The Trump supporter went silent. “And he got about $850 million in tax subsidies, just in New York alone,” I said. More silence. “He’s not a businessman,” I said. “He’s a con man. “Hope you enjoy your coffee.” Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton will meet for their first presidential debate next Monday.        </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>134</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>488</end>
        <start>135</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>606</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>659</end>
        <start>607</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1063</end>
        <start>660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1574</end>
        <start>1064</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1721</end>
        <start>1575</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1779</end>
        <start>1722</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1810</end>
        <start>1780</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1836</end>
        <start>1811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1906</end>
        <start>1837</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1955</end>
        <start>1907</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2003</end>
        <start>1956</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2150</end>
        <start>2004</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2280</end>
        <start>2151</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2416</end>
        <start>2281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2449</end>
        <start>2417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2531</end>
        <start>2450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2545</end>
        <start>2532</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2626</end>
        <start>2546</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2718</end>
        <start>2627</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2720</end>
        <start>2719</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2721</end>
        <start>2721</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2722</end>
        <start>2722</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2723</end>
        <start>2723</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2724</end>
        <start>2724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2725</end>
        <start>2725</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2726</end>
        <start>2726</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1606</end>
        <start>1576</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1720</end>
        <start>1635</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1769</end>
        <start>1723</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1809</end>
        <start>1781</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1812</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1905</end>
        <start>1838</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1946</end>
        <start>1908</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1976</end>
        <start>1957</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2105</end>
        <start>2005</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2149</end>
        <start>2116</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2178</end>
        <start>2152</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2279</end>
        <start>2207</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2407</end>
        <start>2282</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2522</end>
        <start>2451</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2570</end>
        <start>2547</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2625</end>
        <start>2581</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>659</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2626</end>
        <start>1575</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Robert Reich Confronts a Trump Supporter with Facts and It’s Going Viral</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/politics/robert-reich-how-to-school-a-trump-supporter/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
