<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/isis-sex-slaves-auctioned-off-saudi-arabia-hillarys-top-donor-country/">
        <end>49</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/1604988/escaped-isis-sex-slave-says-blonde-blue-eyed-girls-are-particularly-popular-amongst-jihadis/">
        <end>694</end>
        <start>673</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ISIS1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.jihadwatch.org/2016/09/islamic-state-sex-slaves-auctioned-off-in-ukus-ally-saudi-arabia">
        <end>1209</end>
        <start>1198</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/1604988/escaped-isis-sex-slave-says-blonde-blue-eyed-girls-are-particularly-popular-amongst-jihadis/">
        <end>1776</end>
        <start>1765</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ISIS-1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Why in the hell do we still support Saudi Arabia? We don’t need their oil… we would make do. The majority of the 9/11 terrorists came from Saudi Arabia, as does the Bin Laden family. The Saudi deputy crown prince told reporters in June the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia has funded 20% of Hillary Clinton’s campaign. She’s taking money from a stone cold enemy and that’s not the only one by any means. You do not consort or take money from those who intend to destroy your country… period. That goes for Middle Eastern countries such as Saudi Arabia, Russia, China, Iran and North Korea. It also includes any dictatorship or communist strongman. We never learn our lesson, do we? Now it comes to light that Saudi Arabia is selling ISIS sex slaves off to the highest bidder at public auctions. Iraqis, Syrians, Saudis and WESTERNERS all bought slaves at the auction. This is monstrous and going on right out in the open. It should be stopped cold… whatever it takes. Britain needs to stop selling the Saudis weapons and we need to pull our politicians out of the Saudi bedroom and back home. They are killing us and enslaving women and children. How can we silently stand by while this evil goes on?  From Jihad Watch: It isn’t news that the Islamic State has long been abusing and trafficking sex slaves – especially Yazidi girls – but it has been now discovered that the sex slaves of IS are being “sold in horrifying auctions to UK ally Saudi Arabia.” An eyewitness reported: Dozens of women were being held in a large room, and it was not only Iraqis and Syrians trading women but also Saudis and Westerners, whose actual nationality was not clear. Western women have also been reported to be among the victims in keeping with the Islamic State’s practice of enslaving kafir women: The Islamic State’s human trafficking operation includes enslaving women who they consider to be ‘kafir’, non-Muslim people like Yazidis and Christians, before selling them for money. The depraved thugs are also involved in the radicalisation of young women all over the world and try to tempt them to come to their caliphate with false promises of wealth, marriage and forgiveness of sin. As these women are ‘rescued’ from ISIS, they are not being given freedom. They are being sold on the auction block into a hellish existence. These are the people that Hillary Clinton takes money from, makes deals with and hobnobs with. Monsters of a feather. I have said for a long time, not only are the Saudis sponsoring ISIS, so are the Russians. We are being played. Our own president is complicit. Let’s not elect another corrupt demon who cares nothing of women and children being sold to rapists. After all, Hillary Clinton is married to one.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>672</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1191</end>
        <start>673</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1192</end>
        <start>1192</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1210</end>
        <start>1193</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1470</end>
        <start>1447</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1471</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1777</end>
        <start>1645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2167</end>
        <start>1778</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2426</end>
        <start>2168</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2717</end>
        <start>2427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2718</end>
        <start>2718</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2719</end>
        <start>2719</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1445</end>
        <start>1393</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2167</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary’s TOP Donor Country Just Auctioned Off ISIS Sex Slaves…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/hillary-clinton-2/hillarys-top-donor-country-just-auctioned-off-isis-sex-slaves/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
