<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tony Elliott</author>
    <links href="http://rare.us/story/when-hillary-clinton-emerged-after-her-fainting-incident-the-internet-was-very-suspicious-of-her-appearance/">
        <end>384</end>
        <start>329</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://heavy.com/news/2016/09/hillary-clinton-body-double-conspiracy-theory-health-death-teresa-barnwell-impersonator-twitter/">
        <end>641</end>
        <start>624</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rense.com/general96/doublefnl.htm">
        <end>721</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://31.media.tumblr.com/41dd193be5ec052b90962860dbd7da84/tumblr_inline_n3s1eiTzhu1ra32oq.jpg">
        <end>821</end>
        <start>810</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://31.media.tumblr.com/41dd193be5ec052b90962860dbd7da84/tumblr_inline_n3s1eiTzhu1ra32oq.jpg">
        <end>1025</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>  After collapsing just before trying to step into her van after being removed from the 9-11 ceremony in New York City, Hillary Clinton emerged from her daughter’s apartment seeming like a new person. Too new to be believed as a matter of fact, since the Hillary at Chelsea Clinton’s apartment was noticeably well and energetic. Even more unbelievable was the difference in appearance such as her being many pounds lighter, more vibrant, and apparently having a sort of drive through type rhinoplasty preformed in the short amount of time she was in the apartment. The nose on the Hillary Clinton double at the apartment is clearly different than all pictures of Hillary in the past. The different nose is a dead giveaway, in the identification of nose types, the real Hillary Clinton has what is known as the Nordic nose, which is quite common and straight. The clone has a distinctively different nose that slightly curves downward at the tip and has a slight elevated area along the bridge, this being more of a Roman type. Aside from the different nose types, the clone Hillary rather appears to be a younger version of the original with much less aging apparent. Hillary’s stand in also has no mole above her right lip, Hillary Clinton does. Since the real Hillary Clinton obviously has such bad health issues that practically prevents her from even campaigning, we must assume that her clone stand in will do most of the appearances she is scheduled to do before the election, aside from those Bill Clinton will do himself. The question we must ultimately ask ourselves is, will Hillary actually be physically capable of doing any debates with Donald Trump that are coming up? Or will she elect to have her double stand in at some or all of the debates? What we need to look for immediately is her appearance. If she appears to be much thinner, younger, or without a cough and hoarseness, we should know, this is not the real Hillary Clinton. If she appears to be right on the mark, without any incidents of brain freeze or forgetfulness, this is the clone, not Hillary Clinton. The biggest speculation that we all should be concerned about is, will the real Hillary Clinton ever be seen or heard as President of the United States? Or will her double conduct all public appearances, meetings with foreign dignitaries, State of the Union addresses, and speeches? It could be possible that if she wins the election, it will be her double that participates in the inauguration in every aspect, including the Swearing In. It is a very big possibility that the real Hillary Clinton may not even play a part of a new Clinton Administration and all decisions will be made by her cabinet from the direction of her clone via an invisible entity. If anyone thought President Obama may not be who he claims he is, such a Clinton Administration being conducted entirely without Hillary herself would make any speculation we may have about Obama seem inconsequential. The American people are being played to go one step further than what we already have in Barack H Obama who remains a mystery man in all respects since he has his personal records sealed, to accept an idea as President. Hillary Clinton may be the first Administration in US history where she is only a figurehead, or an idea, but not in charge of anything.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>683</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1026</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1246</end>
        <start>1027</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1529</end>
        <start>1247</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1759</end>
        <start>1530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2084</end>
        <start>1760</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2523</end>
        <start>2085</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2742</end>
        <start>2524</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2960</end>
        <start>2743</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3317</end>
        <start>2961</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3318</end>
        <start>3318</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3464</end>
        <start>3319</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3538</end>
        <start>3465</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>3500</end>
        <start>3488</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>A Hillary Clinton Administration May be Entirely Run by a FIGUREHEAD</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36880/a-hillary-clinton-administration-may-be-entirely-run-by-a-figurehead/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
