<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Stephen D Foster Jr</author>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/president-obama-discrimination-concern-americans-violence-advance/story?id=42296545">
        <end>464</end>
        <start>429</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump thinks African-Americans are worse off now than they have ever been, and President Obama just took him to the woodshed for it. During a rally, Trump declared that “African-American communities are absolutely in the worst shape than they’ve ever been in before.” The assertion suggests that slavery was a picnic for black people and that Jim Crow was heaven on earth. But President Obama set Trump straight during an interview with Good Morning America at the Smithsonian National Museum of African American History and Culture. “You know, I think even most 8-year-olds’ll tell you that whole slavery thing wasn’t very good for black people,” Obama told Robin Roberts. “Jim Crow wasn’t very good for black people. What we have to do is use our history to propel us to make more progress in the future.” Here’s the video via ABC.  President Obama also slammed those who think racism no longer exists in this country simply because he was elected to the presidency or because some black people make a lot of money. “It’s unrealistic to think that somehow that all just completely went away, because the Civil Rights Act was passed or because Oprah’s making a lot of money or because I was elected president. You know, that’s not how society works. And if you have hundreds of years of racial discrimination it’s likely that the vestiges of that discrimination linger on. And we should acknowledge that and own that.” As President Obama said, Donald Trump could learn a lot from a visit to this museum. To think that black people had it easy as slaves is offensive and it’s almost as if Trump thinks they would be better off going back to being slaves. So he’s definitely on a slippery slope, and while that may get his white supremacist supporters frothing at the mouth, it does nothing to help him get black people to vote for him. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>139</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>274</end>
        <start>140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>379</end>
        <start>275</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>540</end>
        <start>380</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>814</end>
        <start>541</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>840</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>841</end>
        <start>841</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1024</end>
        <start>842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1426</end>
        <start>1025</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1842</end>
        <start>1427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1843</end>
        <start>1843</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>273</end>
        <start>177</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>653</end>
        <start>542</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>682</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1425</end>
        <start>1026</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1425</end>
        <start>1025</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WATCH: President Obama HAMMERS Trump For Claiming Black People Are Worse Off Today</title>
    <uri>http://author.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/23/watch-president-obama-hammers-trump-for-claiming-black-people-are-worse-off-today/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
