<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="http://www.zerohedge.com/news/2016-09-15/us-war-terror-has-cost-5-trillion-and-increased-terrorism-6500">
        <end>1086</end>
        <start>1071</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.commondreams.org/news/2016/09/13/post-911-wars-have-cost-nearly-5-trillion-and-counting-report">
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>1110</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.usgovernmentdebt.us/">
        <end>1407</end>
        <start>1393</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://readersupportednews.org/opinion2/277-75/32339-focus-despite-14-years-of-the-us-war-on-terror-terror-attacks-have-skyrocketed-since-911">
        <end>1579</end>
        <start>1571</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newsweek.com/nigeria-no-longer-africas-top-oil-producer-militants-cut-production-460676">
        <end>2203</end>
        <start>2189</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-37045276">
        <end>2290</end>
        <start>2275</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://truthinmedia.com/reality-check-ted-cruz-middle-east-war-on-terror/">
        <end>2348</end>
        <start>2309</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The government’s answer to every failed program or ineffective federal department is to dump more taxpayer money in it. Ever since government education has become the norm, kids are dumb and dumber. But big government advocates claim that the problem is that they just don’t have enough money. So, they throw more money at it, and the problems only get bigger. Ever since the War on Drugs was declared, we’ve spent over $1.5 trillion, and drug use remains unchanged or even worse. But instead of questioning the policy or considering the Constitutionality of the issue, their answer is to throw more money at it, in hopes that they’ll finally stamp out illegal drug usage once and for all. But it only gets worse. The same is true with the “War on Terror.” The U.S. government dumped $5 trillion into it, terrorism has increased by leaps and bounds. But instead of reevaluating our foreign policy – especially pertaining to the Middle East – the politicians’ answer is to expand our foreign policy, and of course, throw more money at it. And terrorism continues to grow. From Zero Hedge: According to a report released by Dr. Neta Crawford, professor of political science at Brown University, spending by the United States Departments of Defense, State, Homeland Security, and Veteran Affairs since 9/11 is now close to $5 trillion USD. Before we have the chance to ask how a country that has racked up over $19.3 trillion USD in debt can spend $5 trillion USD on war, the focus of this article is to ask: What has all of this spending achieved? As Reader Supported News reported at the end of last year, terrorism has increased 6,500 percent since 2002 (they probably should rename it “the war of terror”). In 2014, the outlet noted, it was reported that 74 percent of all terror-related casualties occurred in Iraq, Nigeria, Afghanistan, Pakistan, or Syria. As stated by Paul Gottinger, a staff reporter for Reader Supported News, out of the aforementioned countries, “only Nigeria did not experience either U.S. air strikes or a military occupation in that year.” Omitted from that assessment is the fact that the U.S. has been meddling in Nigeria for some time now. Why wouldn’t they? Until recently, Nigeria was Africa’s largest oil producer, as well as the continent’s largest economy until last month. And look at this shocker from Ben Swann: “Before the 2003 U.S. invasion, do you know how many suicide attacks there were in Iraq? None. In the country’s history there had never been one. But since the 2003 invasion, there have been 1,892. “In Iraq, prior to the start of the Iraq war, there were reportedly just over 1.5 million Christians living in that country. And yet shortly after the war started, more than one million of them fled to Syria. That didn’t work out well. Today fewer than half a million Christians remain and yet are being exterminated by groups like ISIS.” The more terrorism grows and is a threat to our national security, the more laws the U.S. government passes that not only continually erode away at our freedoms, but do nothing to protect us.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>119</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>713</end>
        <start>120</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1087</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1545</end>
        <start>1088</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2066</end>
        <start>1546</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2308</end>
        <start>2067</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2349</end>
        <start>2309</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2547</end>
        <start>2350</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2886</end>
        <start>2548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3078</end>
        <start>2887</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3079</end>
        <start>3079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3225</end>
        <start>3080</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3299</end>
        <start>3226</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>755</end>
        <start>741</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1704</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2065</end>
        <start>1971</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2885</end>
        <start>2351</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1565</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2886</end>
        <start>2350</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3261</end>
        <start>3249</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>U.S. Spends $5 TRILLION on War on Terror…Terrorism Increases by 6,500%</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36845/u-s-spends-5-trillion-on-war-on-terror-terrorism-increases-by-6500/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
