<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://freebeacon.com/national-security/texas-withdraw-obama-admin-refugee-program-terror-threat/">
        <end>897</end>
        <start>877</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Republican Gov. Greg Abbott is a stud. He knows how to govern which is not something I can say for the POTUS (President of the United States). Gov. Abbott, representing Texas, informed the Office of Refugee Resettlement that they would be withdrawing from the program on Jan. 31, 2017. This past weekend there were several terrorist attacks in the United States (of which Obama has yet to have any decent response) that have given pause to any thinking leader in our nation to allow Muslim refugees into their state. The biggest issue for Gov. Abbott is that Obama hasn’t been able to ensure the states that the refugees being sent are not terrorists or do not pose a terror threat. He had his Texas administration draft a plan that would require federal national security officials to provide assurances that none of the individuals being resettled pose a terror threat. “The federal government’s refugee settlement program is riddled with serious problems that pose a threat to our nation,” the governor said in a statement. “The director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the director of national intelligence have repeatedly declared their inability to fully screen refugees from terrorist-based nations. Even with the inability to properly vet refugees from Syria and countries known to be supporters or propagators of terrorism, President Obama is now ineptly proposing a dramatic increase in the number of refugees to be resettled in the U.S.” “While many refugees pose no danger, some pose grave danger, like the Iraqi refugee with ties to ISIS who was arrested earlier this year after he plotted to set off bombs at two malls in Houston,” Abbott said. “Despite multiple requests by the state of Texas, the federal government lacks the capability or the will to distinguish the dangerous from the harmless, and Texas will not be an accomplice to such dereliction of duty to the American people,” he added. “Therefore, Texas will withdraw from the refugee resettlement program. I strongly urge the federal government to completely overhaul a broken and flawed refugee program that increasingly risks American lives.” Can you blame a Governor whose main goal is to protect his constituents? I’m pretty sure Liberals think he is evil and will paint him to be a villain, racist who selfishly refuses to share his resources with poor refugees with nowhere else to turn. But the thing he’s not willing to share are the lives of women and children sitting in a shopping mall drinking an Orange Julius unprepared for a suicide bomber to sit at the table next to them. This is America, let’s keep it that way. If other countries want their citizens to live in terror, it is their right. It is also our right to implement strategies of security. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>516</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>871</end>
        <start>517</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1459</end>
        <start>872</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1669</end>
        <start>1460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2132</end>
        <start>1670</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2752</end>
        <start>2133</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2753</end>
        <start>2753</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>873</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1458</end>
        <start>1028</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1655</end>
        <start>1461</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1911</end>
        <start>1671</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2131</end>
        <start>1924</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2132</end>
        <start>872</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Texas Just Gave Obama The FINGER Over Refugee Program And It’s AWESOME!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/texas-something-say-obama-muslim-refugee-program-awesome/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
