<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton got a major boost in August from some of her richest and most loyal supporters, with 11 seven-figure checks to fuel a spending surge from the main super PAC supporting her candidacy. Priorities USA Action raised $23.4 million in August, more than half of which came from its top five donors, according to its monthly report filed Tuesday with the Federal Election Commission. It was the super PAC's best fundraising month by far, more than doubling July's take. Story Continued Below Slim-Fast founder Daniel Abraham and Newsweb chairman Fred Eychaner each gave $3 million. Billionaire financier George Soros kicked in $2.5 million, and investor Donald Sussman and Laurene Powell Jobs' Emerson Collective both added $2 million. Sussman's latest gift brings his tally for the cycle to $13 million, the most of any of Clinton's benefactors. Working for Working Americans, the Service Employees International Union Committee On Political Education, the National Air Traffic Controllers Association PAC, investor Henry Laufer and his wife, Marsha, all gave $1 million. The super PAC took advantage of the influx to step up its spending, dropping $20.6 million and ending the month with $41.5 million on hand, according to the report. It paid BuzzFeed $1 million for digital ads, $405,400 to Global Strategy Group for research and consultant travel, $247,600 to Ralston Lapp Media for video production and media consulting, and $234,400 to Shorr Johnson Magnus for the same. The report showed a $28,000 payment to CrowdStrike, the cybersecurity firm that has also been serving the Democratic National Committee in the aftermath of its email hack. The PAC spent $15,600 at the Ritz Carlton Philadelphia, where top donors and fundraisers stayed during the Democratic National Convention. Priorities USA transferred $6.5 million to five other political groups: Immigrant Voters Win PAC, Latino Victory Fund, Planned Parenthood Action Fund, VoteVets and Women Vote.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>198</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>477</end>
        <start>199</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>499</end>
        <start>478</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>743</end>
        <start>500</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>854</end>
        <start>744</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1080</end>
        <start>855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1245</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1485</end>
        <start>1246</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1657</end>
        <start>1486</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1796</end>
        <start>1658</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1972</end>
        <start>1797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Big money fuels Clinton super PAC surge</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-super-pac-funds-228433?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
