<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/wow-islamist-wounds-9-knife-attack-st-cloud-mall-police-chief-warns-public-reprisal-attacks/">
        <end>1112</end>
        <start>1098</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2016/09/st-cloud-isis-stabber-identified-dahir-adan-knifed-8-people-shot-dead/">
        <end>1154</end>
        <start>1144</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MinnesotaMall?src=hash">
        <end>1425</end>
        <start>1411</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/StCloud?src=hash">
        <end>1450</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/J8Y7pFCALn">
        <end>1477</end>
        <start>1451</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/LisaDaftari/status/777517527287099392">
        <end>1526</end>
        <start>1508</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>You can’t make this stuff up. We live in an age where there’s an Islamist attack – and the media rushes to make sure that Muslims are OK. The very same people who are all too happy to call for gun control and demonize law abiding gun owners following a mass shooting will do everything they can to protect the sensibilities of Muslims following an Islamist attack. Yes, guns are misused, and Islam has its radicals, but radical Islam is much more damaging than guns ever could be. According to the Pew Research Center, roughly 10 percent of Muslims globally hold what we would deem “extremist” views (those who would condone violence against non-Muslims). If ten percent of gun owners were “extremists,” there wouldn’t be any people left! On Saturday there were two bombings, one in NJ and another in NY. Today we found out that the killer was a radical Muslim (shocking!). Another stabbing attack was carried out in Minnessota – whereas nine were injured but none killed. The attacker was shot to death by an off-duty police officer. Now police are warning about attacks…… against Muslims. As the Gateway Pundit reported: On Saturday Islamist Dahir Adan went on a stabbing rampage at Crossroads Mall in St. Cloud, Minnesota. Adan was screaming, “Allahu Akbar!” during the attack. ISIS claimed responsibility for the St. Cloud knife attack. BREAKING: Islamic State’s Amaq news posts claim of responsibility for #MinnesotaMall stabbing attack #StCloud pic.twitter.com/J8Y7pFCALn — Lisa Daftari (@LisaDaftari) September 18, 2016  Dahir Adan was born in Somalia. After the attack Police Chief Wm. Blair Anderson Issued a warning…. to watch out for reprisal attacks. Perhaps they should be on the lookout for other attacks against innocent Americans by crazed Islamists so they can be thwarted like the one in Elizabeth, New Jersey, where, just this morning, multiple bombs were found at a rail station. Had the bombs not been discovered, they could have detonated during the Monday morning commute, injuring thousands.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>364</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>738</end>
        <start>365</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1034</end>
        <start>739</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1090</end>
        <start>1035</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1122</end>
        <start>1091</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>1123</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1340</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1477</end>
        <start>1341</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1526</end>
        <start>1478</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1527</end>
        <start>1527</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1559</end>
        <start>1528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1560</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2015</end>
        <start>1663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2017</end>
        <start>2016</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2018</end>
        <start>2018</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>592</end>
        <start>583</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>702</end>
        <start>691</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1260</end>
        <start>1247</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1526</end>
        <start>1341</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Wow! After Islamist Wounds 9 in Knife Attack, Police Chief Warns Muslims of… Retaliatory Attacks (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/wow-islamist-wounds-9-knife-attack-police-chief-warns-muslims-retaliatory-attacks-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
