<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Zach Cartwright</author>
    <links href="http://www.omaha.com/huskers/football/video-michael-rose-ivey-says-i-cannot-hide-from-responsibilities/article_9373dcb6-8412-11e6-a435-1fee8a3e78ba.html">
        <end>568</end>
        <start>525</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.omaha.com/huskers/football/video-michael-rose-ivey-says-i-cannot-hide-from-responsibilities/article_9373dcb6-8412-11e6-a435-1fee8a3e78ba.html">
        <end>1914</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In a powerful statement, a University of Nebraska football player opened up about the racism he experienced in response to kneeling during the national anthem. Before their game with Northwestern this past Saturday, Nebraska Cornhuskers players Michael Rose-Ivey, DaiShon Neal, and Mohamed Berry all took a knee during the national anthem in a silent protest of police brutality, as NFL quarterback Colin Kaepernick and other athletes across the country have done. In a press conference with local media on Monday, Rose-Ivey detailed the horrific racism he experienced as a result of his protest. “I am still referred to on Facebook and Twitter as a ‘clueless, confused nigger’ by former high school classmates, peers, and even [Nebraska] Husker fans. Some believe DaiShon, Mohamed, and myself should be kicked off the team or suspended, while some say we deserve to be lynched or shot just like other black people who have died recently,” Rose-Ivey said. “Another believe that since we didn’t want to stand for the anthem, that we should be hung before the anthem before the next game,” he added, after a long pause. However, Rose-Ivey said he felt obligated to take a knee, saying he was using his platform on the roster of one of the nation’s most prestigious college football programs to bring awareness to the injustice suffered by black Americans on a daily basis. “While you may disagree with the method, these reactions underscore the need for these protests and gives us just a small glimpse into the problem of racism in this country and the divisive mentality of some Americans,” Rose-Ivey said. “As Dr.King said, injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere. the hottest place in hell is reserved for those who remain neutral in times of great moral conflict. An individual who accepts evil without protesting against it is really cooperating with it.” Mohamed Barry told the Omaha World-Herald that while the players experienced racism, the overwhelming majority of responses were positive. “Our fans, they agree with it, they see the injustice, and for the most part they support us,” Barry said. However, if Rose-Ivey’s passionate statement is any indicator, the silent protest during the national anthem won’t stop anytime soon. “There are issues in this country that need to be addressed. There are issues in this country that can no longer be pushed off onto the backs of another generation.” Watch the full video of Michael Rose-Ivey’s statement below:             </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>159</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>596</end>
        <start>160</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>955</end>
        <start>597</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>956</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1370</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1872</end>
        <start>1371</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2011</end>
        <start>1873</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2118</end>
        <start>2012</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2252</end>
        <start>2119</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2418</end>
        <start>2253</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2479</end>
        <start>2419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2480</end>
        <start>2480</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2482</end>
        <start>2481</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2484</end>
        <start>2483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2485</end>
        <start>2485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2487</end>
        <start>2486</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2488</end>
        <start>2488</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2489</end>
        <start>2489</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2490</end>
        <start>2490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2491</end>
        <start>2491</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2492</end>
        <start>2492</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>598</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1086</end>
        <start>957</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1589</end>
        <start>1372</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1871</end>
        <start>1608</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2105</end>
        <start>2013</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2417</end>
        <start>2254</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Fans said I ‘should be hung before the anthem’: Emotional college linebacker reveals racist threats</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/college-linebacker-anthem-racism/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
