<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Jeff Dunetz</author>
    <links href="https://8ch.net/pol/res/7541894.html">
        <end>687</end>
        <start>671</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Csrp9J6WEAAyubT.jpg">
        <end>1314</end>
        <start>1267</start>
    </links>
    <links>
        <end>1332</end>
        <start>1315</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.etsy.com/people/stonetear">
        <end>1414</end>
        <start>1377</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://archive.is/P45cY">
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1423</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://lidblog.com/hillarys-tech-guy-was-on-reddit-asking-how-erase-email-evidence/">
        <end>1613</end>
        <start>1557</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Paul Combetta, is the tech guy who helped Hillary Clinton bleach her server clean of the evidence requested from federal authorities, seems to have gone to online forums to find advice on how to commit the evil deed. Last week Combetta pled the fifth when testifying before the house oversight committee last week, but wasn’t as tight-lipped when trying to find out information on how to strip Clinton’s e-mail address from already sent and archived emails from fellow IT experts on Reddit. In the end a fellow tech guy told him the only thing he could do is delete the emails The evidence was first posted at 8chan, it consisted of Reddit posts from two years ago.  The thread was titled  “Here is clear proof that Hillary sought to destroy evidence,”  Here is the guy who wiped Hillary’s server asking about how to do it on Reddit. Yes. Seriously. He also asks how to replace real emails with fake ones. His post happens right about the same time congress was requesting Clinton’s emails. He specifically said it was for a big name client who everybody would recognize. A Reddit post has been found from Paul Combetta (the IT guy who got FBI immunity and deleted Hillary’s emails) proving they were covering up for Hillary. First, notice Paul’s email address here: https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Csrp9J6WEAAyubT.jpg [email protected] He uses the same username on his Etsy page: https://www.etsy.com/people/stonetear (Backup http://archive.is/P45cY ) Now look at the username of this Redditor asking how to strip the name of a “VERY VIP” from email archives… Read the rest of the story at Jeff Dunetz’s blog The Lid  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>576</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>753</end>
        <start>577</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>905</end>
        <start>754</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>906</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1225</end>
        <start>1072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1266</end>
        <start>1226</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1314</end>
        <start>1267</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1332</end>
        <start>1315</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1376</end>
        <start>1333</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1448</end>
        <start>1377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1556</end>
        <start>1449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1613</end>
        <start>1557</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1614</end>
        <start>1614</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1760</end>
        <start>1615</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1834</end>
        <start>1761</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>691</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1534</end>
        <start>1526</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1147</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1796</end>
        <start>1784</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary’s IT Guy Went to REDDIT to Ask How to Delete Emails!</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36888/hillarys-it-guy-went-to-reddit-to-ask-how-to-delete-emails/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
