<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>By Tal Kopan, CNN</author>
    <mainText>Washington (CNN)Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton are in a tight race in in Georgia, a traditionally deep red state, according to a new poll. The Republican candidate has 45% to Clinton's 42% in the Monmouth University poll, within the poll's margin of error. Libertarian Gary Johnson had the support of 8% of likely voters. Trump is underperforming previous GOP candidates. Mitt Romney won the state by 8 points in 2012 over President Barack Obama. The incumbent Republican senator is also out-polling Trump. Sen. Johnny Isakson has a 16-point lead over challenger Jim Barksdale, 50% to 34%. Clinton's strength comes from the Atlanta area, where she leads Trump 55% to 35%. But Trump leads her 51% to 33% elsewhere in the Peach State. She leads 88% to 4% among the state's black voters, but trails 20% to 66% among white voters. Clinton and Trump have similar favorability ratings in the state. Clinton is viewed 32% favorably and 56% unfavorably. Trump is viewed favorably by 33% of likely voters and unfavorably by 50%. Monmouth surveyed 401 like Georgia voters from September 15 to 18 for the poll, which has a margin of error of plus or minus 4.9 percentage points. </mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>140</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>323</end>
        <start>141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>448</end>
        <start>324</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>591</end>
        <start>449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>828</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1021</end>
        <start>829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1169</end>
        <start>1022</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1170</end>
        <start>1170</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>CNN</portal>
    <title>Georgia poll: Donald Trump, Hillary Clinton in tight race</title>
    <uri>http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/19/politics/georgia-monmouth-poll-donald-trump-hillary-clinton/index.html</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
