<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Vera</author>
    <links>
        <end>1007</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump">
        <end>1150</end>
        <start>1134</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/avrV9WKG9T">
        <end>1300</end>
        <start>1274</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/VicenteFoxQue/status/780814887190540288">
        <end>1360</end>
        <start>1342</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/fox-business-lets-f-bomb-slip-through-when-fmr-mexican-prez-doubles-down-on-trumps-wall/">
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1806</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Mexicoâs former President, Vicente Fox, isnât shy at all about his disdain for Republican nominee Donald Trump â and he really turned things up a notch after last nightâs presidential debate. Anyone who watched the debate (or has access to the internet) knows by now that Trump blew it. His performance was so weak and he was so unprepared, even Republican pundits have admitted that Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton won by a landslide â and Fox wasnât afraid to point this out. On Tuesday, Fox decided to go after Trump while itâs going to hurt the most, knowing full well that the business mogulâs ego is likely suffering from embarrassment. On Twitter, Fox teased Trump mercilessly for his horrendous performance, directly asking Trump âwhat does losing feel like?â on Twitter. To rub this in even more, Fox posted a screenshot of one of Trumpâs pathetic fundraising emails, proving to the world that Trumpâs campaign is still struggling and begging for money: [email protected] you have no shame, I just got another e-mail begging for help. Tell me what does losing feels like? Have a little dignity!â @realDonaldTrump you have no shame, I just got another e-mail begging for help. Tell me what does losing feels like? Have a little dignity! pic.twitter.com/avrV9WKG9T â Vicente Fox Quesada (@VicenteFoxQue) September 27, 2016  Continuing to pourÂ salt into the wound, Fox also praised Clinton for showing âcapacity, compassion and wisdomâ while bashing Trump for looking âafoul.â The attack was brutal: Twitter Twitter Itâs been awhile since Fox has been in the media for attacking Trump, but he sure knows how to make an appearance. This election cycle, the former President of Mexico has repeatedly made headlines for slamming Trump and publicly stating that Mexico willÂ not pay for hisÂ âf*cking wall.âÂ Fox has also said that Trump âreminds me of Hitlerâ and even challenged Trump to a debate once (which Trump was too cowardly to accept). We can only expect that over the next few weeks, Fox is going to support Clinton to the fullest, and do whatever he can to convince Americans not to vote for Trump. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>199</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>661</end>
        <start>200</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>989</end>
        <start>662</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1133</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1300</end>
        <start>1134</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1360</end>
        <start>1301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1361</end>
        <start>1361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1545</end>
        <start>1362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1553</end>
        <start>1546</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1561</end>
        <start>1554</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2162</end>
        <start>1562</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2163</end>
        <start>2163</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1132</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1359</end>
        <start>1134</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Mexicoâs Former President Unleashes Brutal Insults On Trump After Debate (TWEETS)</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/27/mexicos-former-president-unleashes-brutal-insults-on-trump-after-debate-tweets/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
