<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Ben Marquis</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/paul-ryan-sees-change-in/">
        <end>290</end>
        <start>282</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-first-debate-performance-paul-ryan-228784">
        <end>424</end>
        <start>416</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/trump-asks-why-lester-holt/">
        <end>1173</end>
        <start>1151</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>To say that the relationship between Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump and House Speaker Paul Ryan is a bit tepid would be nothing short of an understatement. Nevertheless, for all of their differences that have been repeatedly highlighted by the liberal media, Ryan has endorsed Trump over Democrat rival Hillary Clinton, and that didn’t change following Monday night’s presidential debate. According to Politico, Ryan broke from some other seemingly disappointed Republicans on Capitol Hill to offer high praise for Trump’s debate performance. “I saw Donald Trump give a spirited voice to those of us who don’t like the status quo, and I see emerging in front of us the potential for what a unified Republican government can get you, which can be the solutions,” Ryan stated Tuesday morning at a press conference. “I think he passed a number of thresholds … and showed that for 90 minutes he could go toe-to-toe with Hillary Clinton,” he added. Other GOP members thought Trump could have done better, though, and several lamented the many “missed opportunities” where Trump could have landed damaging blows against Clinton over a host of problem issues for her — except that he didn’t even take a swing. Nevertheless, Trump was not hung out to dry by his fellow Republicans after the debate, and the high praise from Ryan showed that at least some in the GOP establishment have apparently come to terms with Trump as potentially the next president. In other words, don’t believe all the stories about disunity from a left-leaning media that fears victory by a consolidated Republican Party. Please share this on Facebook and Twitter so that everyone can see what Speaker of the House Paul Ryan had to say about Donald Trump following the first presidential debate. What do you think of what Speaker Paul Ryan had to say about Donald Trump after the presidential debate? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>169</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>402</end>
        <start>170</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>556</end>
        <start>403</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>826</end>
        <start>557</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>957</end>
        <start>827</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1216</end>
        <start>958</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1461</end>
        <start>1217</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1603</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1777</end>
        <start>1604</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1912</end>
        <start>1778</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>774</end>
        <start>558</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>946</end>
        <start>828</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1073</end>
        <start>1053</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Paul Ryan Stuns Voters With Bombshell Announcement After Debate</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/paul-ryan-stuns-after-debate/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-27&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
