<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>By Betsy Klein, CNN</author>
    <links href="https://www.yahoo.com/amphtml/katiecouric/kaine-previews-debate-for-voters-dont-get-tricked-by-trump-092621895.html?client=safari">
        <end>340</end>
        <start>311</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/19/politics/gary-johnson-bill-weld/">
        <end>585</end>
        <start>523</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/16/politics/johnson-stein-fail-to-qualify-for-first-debate/">
        <end>1158</end>
        <start>1102</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/23/politics/mcclatchy-marist-national-poll-before-debate/index.html">
        <end>1684</end>
        <start>1620</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>(CNN)Democratic vice presidential nominee Tim Kaine has a message for voters considering a third-party candidate: They're going to lose. "The argument against the ticket is, I think, everybody knows that they're not going to win," Kaine said of the Gary Johnson and Bill Weld Libertarian ticket in an interview with Yahoo News' Katie Couric this week. Hillary Clinton's running mate pointed to the 2000 election as evidence that a protest vote for a third-party candidate can affect the outcome of the race -- and history. RELATED: Gary Johnson: Running mate Bill Weld not dropping out "My argument against the (Johnson-Weld) ticket is the Al Gore-George W. Bush race in 2000. The third party candidacy of Ralph Nader cost Gore electoral votes in New Hampshire and Florida. And if Gore had been president, we probably wouldn't had a war in Iraq," he said. "Casting a vote, a protest vote, for a third-party candidate that's going to lose may well affect the outcome. It may well lead to a consequence that is deeply, deeply troubling. That's not a speculation, we've seen it in our country's history." RELATED: Johnson, Stein fail to qualify for first debate As the race tightens nationally and in key swing states, Kaine cautioned against a protest vote, but acknowledged he and Clinton need to make that case to voters who may be considering Johnson. "We're going to make the affirmative case for Hillary, we're going to draw the contrast with Donald Trump, but we're also going to tell people, the way you make a difference to your nation is not by doing a protest vote. It's picking the next leader of the country." RELATED: National poll: Clinton leads Trump by 6 ahead of debate </mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>136</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>351</end>
        <start>137</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>522</end>
        <start>352</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>585</end>
        <start>523</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1101</end>
        <start>586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1158</end>
        <start>1102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1352</end>
        <start>1159</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1619</end>
        <start>1353</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1684</end>
        <start>1620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1685</end>
        <start>1685</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>CNN</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>229</end>
        <start>138</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>845</end>
        <start>587</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1100</end>
        <start>857</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1618</end>
        <start>1354</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Tim Kaine on Libertarian ticket: 'Everybody knows they're not going to win'</title>
    <uri>http://edition.cnn.com/2016/09/23/politics/tim-kaine-libertarian-ticket/index.html?sr=fbpol092316tim-kaine-libertarian-ticket0631PMVODtopLink&amp;linkId=29131969</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
