<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton clashed over how much help Trump received with his business dealings, moments after the first presidential debate of the general election began. “You know, Donald was very fortunate in his life and that's all to his benefit,” Clinton said, soon after the debate kicked off at Hofstra University in Hempstead, N.Y. “He started his business with $14 million, borrowed from his father, and he really believes that the more you help wealthy people, the better off we'll be and that everything will work out from there. I don't buy that. I have a different experience.” Story Continued Below She went on to describe her Midwestern upbringing, which she portrayed as middle class, needling Trump in the process over how much he received assistance in getting his real estate career underway. But in the candidates’ first clash of the evening, Trump insisted that he was given a much smaller advantage as he began his business dealings. “Well, for one thing, and before we start on that, my father gave me a very small loan in 1975 and I built it into a company that's worth many, many billions of dollars with some of the greatest assets in the world and I say that because that's the kind of thinking our country needs.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>177</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>597</end>
        <start>178</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>619</end>
        <start>598</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>962</end>
        <start>620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>257</end>
        <start>179</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>596</end>
        <start>348</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1247</end>
        <start>964</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton hits Trump over '$14 million' from father</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/clinton-trump-father-inherit-228706?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
