<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Bq0GiOMIMAAuCN8.jpg-large.jpeg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/palmer-ike-1-31-13-4_3.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/gty_164622168_55005977.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/UlyfpIBOL2">
        <end>2976</end>
        <start>2950</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/status/780244157625278464">
        <end>3022</end>
        <start>3004</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/skehUsQgww">
        <end>3170</end>
        <start>3144</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/jacknicklaus/status/780222860258344960">
        <end>3022</end>
        <start>3004</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>We still can’t believe this devastating news!!! As of Sunday evening, we have lost one of the most legendary men in our nation. Arnold Palmer has passed away at the age of 87 years old. Many people were shocked upon hearing this news. The golfing community is obviously devastated by the loss of such a legendary man. Upon hearing the news, the U.S. Golf Association released a saddening yet inspirational statement. “We are deeply saddened by the death of Arnold Palmer, golf’s greatest ambassador, at age 87,. Arnold Palmer will always be a champion, in every sense of the word. He inspired generations to love golf by sharing his competitive spirit, displaying sportsmanship, caring for golfers and golf fans, and serving as a lifelong ambassador for the sport.  Our stories of him not only fill the pages of golf’s history books and the walls of the museum, but also our own personal golf memories.  The game is indeed better because of him, and in so many ways, will never be the same.” He was known as “the King of Golf”, but was known for much more than that. Palmer received many awards in the sport as well as outside the sport.  Awards with high honors such as the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the Congressional Gold Medal, and more.  Every time Palmer accepted these awards, he offered some golf tips to whoever presented him with the awards…which was most of the time the President of the United States!  Anyone who came into contact with him, golfer or not, immediately encountered a good time. He knew how to relate to everyone, no matter the age, occupation or position they were in life. Palmer started out as an avid pilot who loved to play the game of golf. He attended Wake Forest College on a golf scholarship, which only grew his love for the sport even more. Palmer won his first tour during his rookie season in 1955, and the rest is history. Palmer brought a new attitude to golf. Unlike the other players, he took risks and tried things that ultimately may have made him look crazy from time to time. He wasn’t your average straight laced golfer, and that’s what made him rise to stardom as well as success in the golf world.  Palmer had a major influence on practically every golfer in the world. Upon hearing the devastating news, American golfer, Tiger Woods, expressed how impactful Palmer has been over the years. “Arnold meant everything to golf. Are you kidding me?. I mean, without his charisma, without his personality in conjunction with TV — it was just the perfect symbiotic growth. You finally had someone who had this charisma, and they’re capturing it on TV for the very first time. Everyone got hooked to the game of golf via TV because of Arnold.” Arnold will be missed by many people from many walks of life, as numerous people of high status and beyond have already started to mourn. Here's to The King who was as extraordinary on the links as he was generous to others. Thanks for the memories, Arnold. pic.twitter.com/UlyfpIBOL2 — President Obama (@POTUS) September 26, 2016  I just got the news at about 8:45 that Arnold had passed. I was shocked to hear that we lost a great friend (continued) pic.twitter.com/skehUsQgww — Jack Nicklaus (@jacknicklaus) September 26, 2016  We’re praying for the many friends and family Arnold has left behind. Long live the legend who did way more than just play the sport of golf. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>47</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>234</end>
        <start>48</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>416</end>
        <start>235</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1137</end>
        <start>992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1138</end>
        <start>1138</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1417</end>
        <start>1139</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1418</end>
        <start>1418</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1605</end>
        <start>1419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1867</end>
        <start>1606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2152</end>
        <start>1868</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2153</end>
        <start>2153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2345</end>
        <start>2154</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2691</end>
        <start>2346</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2829</end>
        <start>2692</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2976</end>
        <start>2830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3022</end>
        <start>2977</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3023</end>
        <start>3023</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3170</end>
        <start>3024</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3221</end>
        <start>3171</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3222</end>
        <start>3222</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3365</end>
        <start>3223</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>990</end>
        <start>418</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1025</end>
        <start>1009</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2690</end>
        <start>2347</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>991</end>
        <start>417</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2691</end>
        <start>2346</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3022</end>
        <start>2830</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3221</end>
        <start>3024</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>An American Legend Has Just Passed Away, May God Be With Arnold Palmer’s Family</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/celebrity-news/breaking-an-american-legend-has-just-passes-away-may-god-be-with-arnold-palmers-family/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Arnold+Palmer%2F9%2F26&amp;utm_content=Right+Wing+News%2FArnold+Palmer%2F9%2F26</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
