<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Doug Giles</author>
    <links href="http://clashdaily.com/2016/09/uh-okay-black-cop-kills-black-man-rioters-loot-walmart-attack-truckers/">
        <end>196</end>
        <start>179</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://clashdaily.com/2016/09/watch-white-people-f-cking-devils-charlotte-rioters-promise-kill-whites/">
        <end>269</end>
        <start>242</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.caintv.com/sorry-media-black-charlotte-ch">
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>1317</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Please disable your Ad Blocker in order to interact with the site. The Media (D) loves to tell the unarmed black man shot by cop story. The problem is, this isn’t that story. The riot in Charlotte was huge and escalated quickly. You know how Keith Lamont Scott’s family has been saying he had no gun and he was holding a book? That was a lie. Watch the News Report: Now watch the Charlotte Police Chief, Kerr Putney: …the media caused all this. More than 1,000 people heard on the news that a guy holding a book was shot by police, and even though these people didn’t know the guy who was shot, they came out anyway and rioted. And yet none of what they heard was true. A man with a gun was told by police to drop his gun, and he did not comply with that request. I hate to tell you this, but that is going to get you shot every time. Not only that, but in this case – contrary to the media’s racist-white-cops narrative, it was a black cop who felt threatened and fired his weapon, and a black police chief who backed up what his officers had to do. Do #BlackCopLivesMatter? …The media’s recklessness unleashed mayhem in Charlotte, for no reason whatsoever. And these malevolent fools will pay no price for what they’ve done. Only the people who had to suffer through this chaos will be paying any price. Read more: Herman Cain The Media needs to slow down and get the actual facts before reporting half-a-story that fits the narrative. Share if you think the Media stoked the flames of racism and are accomplices to the riot in Charlotte </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>174</end>
        <start>67</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>228</end>
        <start>175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>326</end>
        <start>229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>342</end>
        <start>327</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>365</end>
        <start>343</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>416</end>
        <start>366</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>627</end>
        <start>417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1050</end>
        <start>628</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1075</end>
        <start>1051</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>1076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1437</end>
        <start>1329</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1539</end>
        <start>1438</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Clash Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>417</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WATCH: The RIOT in Charlotte Was Because Media Reported the LIE The Family Tweeted</title>
    <uri>http://clashdaily.com/2016/09/watch-riot-charlotte-media-reported-lie-family-tweeted/?utm_source=referral&amp;utm_medium=facebook.com&amp;utm_campaign=lasmpfb</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
