<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="http://nypost.com/2016/09/21/cuomo-weiner-could-face-jail-time-for-sexting-with-teen/">
        <end>542</end>
        <start>529</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Huma Abedin dumped her then-husband Anthony Weiner when it was revealed that he had carried on a sexting relationship with another woman – one of many – in which he had sent a risqué picture of himself, and in the picture, he was accompanied by his young son. But unbeknownst to his then-wife and the rest of the world – but certainly not surprisingly – he was carrying on another relationship during this time with a 15-year-old girl in North Carolina. From January to July, he sent photos and vulgar texts to her. I’ll let the New York Post fill you in on the dirty details: The 15-year-old high school student went public with a trove of lurid come-ons she got from Weiner, who exchanged his “Carlos Danger” persona for the alias “T Dog” to send her kinky texts and shirtless selfies over a cell-phone messenger app. Weiner repeatedly told the unidentified teen how “hard” and horny he was, at one point boasting that after sex with him she would, “limp for a week,” the Daily Mail reported. Weiner — whose serial sexting cost him his seat in Congress and a comeback bid for mayor — also shared pornographic videos with her, asked her to get naked and masturbate for him over Skype, and even told her about “rape fantasies” that grossed her out. The girl said Weiner tried to cover up the sexual nature of their relationship by pressuring her to write a letter to her father and a teacher in whom she had confided, “and tell them what I said was false.” Even liberal Democrat Governor Andrew Cuomo is disgusted with Weiner. “If the reports are true, it’s possibly criminal and it is sick,” he said. “And frankly, I’ve heard enough about Anthony Weiner, and I think that goes for all New Yorkers.” If Weiner is charged at the federal level with sexual exploitation of children, it carries with it a minimum of 15 years in prison, and a maximum of 30 years. At the state level, disseminating indecent material and promoting the sexual performance of a child could each get him 7 years in jail. In response, Weiner said that he has “likely been the subject of a hoax,” but as the Post pointed out, he didn’t deny any of the allegations against him. In a prepared statement, Weiner said, “I have repeatedly demonstrated terrible judgement [sic] about the people I have communicated with online and the things I have sent. I am filled with regret and heartbroken for those I have hurt…. I have no one to blame but me for putting myself in this position. I am sorry.”  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>259</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>576</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>819</end>
        <start>577</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>994</end>
        <start>820</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>995</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1456</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1699</end>
        <start>1457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1994</end>
        <start>1700</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2148</end>
        <start>1995</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2464</end>
        <start>2149</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2465</end>
        <start>2465</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2611</end>
        <start>2466</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2685</end>
        <start>2612</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>709</end>
        <start>696</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>739</end>
        <start>734</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>874</end>
        <start>870</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>952</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1225</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1419</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1591</end>
        <start>1528</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1698</end>
        <start>1603</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2067</end>
        <start>2033</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2463</end>
        <start>2188</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1228</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2647</end>
        <start>2635</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Huma Abedin’s Ex Caught Sexting AGAIN…This Time With a 15-YEAR-OLD</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36934/huma-abedins-ex-caught-sexting-againthis-time-with-a-15-year-old/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
