<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <links href="http://americanmilitarynews.com/2016/09/blm-activist-calls-for-more-police-protection-after-being-a-victim-of-armed-robbery/">
        <end>47</end>
        <start>41</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A well known Black Lives Matter activist called police for help when he was the victim of an armed robbery. Ironically, he is now called for a larger police presence in the form of intervention and protection in his neighborhood. The man is Jerry Ford Jr. whose a new graduate of the University of Houston. He has spent most of his time speaking out against police brutality. But he certainly wasn’t when he called for help.    A firearm ready criminal robbed him right outside of his apartment complex where he lives just a few blocks away from his college campus. Now he’s calling on the police and the university as well as other local authorities to increase the level of police in the area. Specifically, the area between the campus and the living complex. Many students from the school live there. Ford said he thought the robber was originally a student. Ford stated the man asked if he had a key and he responded that he did and then proceeded to open the door. When he turned around he was staring down the barrel of the gun the criminal was holding. He told the media, “I reach in right here to open the door, and I turn back around and he has the gun right there in my face.” The criminal is also a thief because he stole Ford’s cell phone and wallet. He demands now that police patrol the area since local and university police do not. The greatest part is that he claims he is not anti-police he is just anti-bad police. That’s a really good cop out when you need the help of the people you’ve been bashing for years. Ford also insists he isn’t just doing this for himself but also for the safety of everyone in his complex including other students. “It’s becoming a pattern. I hope they would take a bigger stance and put more security over here because you have a lot of people walking back and forth to class.” You’ve got to love the liberal logic behind that. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>107</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>229</end>
        <start>108</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>424</end>
        <start>230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>426</end>
        <start>425</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>427</end>
        <start>427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>803</end>
        <start>428</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1078</end>
        <start>804</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1186</end>
        <start>1079</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1530</end>
        <start>1187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1531</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1876</end>
        <start>1827</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1877</end>
        <start>1877</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1185</end>
        <start>1080</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1825</end>
        <start>1664</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Anti-Cop Black Lives Activist Gets Robbed, Instantly Calls For More Police Protection</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/anti-cop-black-lives-activist-gets-robbed-instantly-calls-for-more-police-protection/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
