<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://www.famousdc.com/2016/08/24/congratulations-rina-shah/">
        <end>623</end>
        <start>617</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/mckaycoppins/evan-mcmullin-turns-racist-voicemail-from-trump-suppporter-i?utm_term=.vurK60zro#.deZXYKBxq">
        <end>905</end>
        <start>897</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuckservative">
        <end>2080</end>
        <start>2071</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://youtu.be/aoNM7ftdYVw">
        <end>2211</end>
        <start>2205</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoNM7ftdYVw&amp;feature=youtu.be">
        <end>2329</end>
        <start>2324</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Supporters of Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump were not pleased when Rina Shah appeared on Fox News for Independent presidential candidate Evan McMullin last Friday, September 16, 2016. And one of them left a hateful, racist voice mail for her at McMullin’s campaign office. Ms. Shah and the McMullin campaign turned this awful-tasting lemon into lemonade – in the form of a campaign ad. Evan McMullin was a Republican. At the beginning of August, he announced his Independent candidacy for president as an alternative to Republican nominee Donald Trump. Rina Shah is a political and media consultant who joined McMullin’s campaign staff as Communications Director in mid-August 2016. Shah was born in West Virginia to Indian American parents.  She has been a commentator on the PBS program “To the Contrary” and she founded Rilax Strategies, a political consulting firm. Shah said to BuzzFeed that this wasn’t the first time she’s received such messages: “I could send you, I’m not kidding, hundreds of emails I’ve received … You know, ‘You’re a Muslim,’ ‘You’re a C-U-N-T’ — I get a lot of, ‘Go back to your country.’” The caller identified himself only as “Alan.” BuzzFeed tracked him down and learned that his name is Alan Pryce. Once the transcript of the message was read to him, Pryce claimed it and said he: “…Stands by every word.”   Mr. Pryce seems to have the same loose relationship with the truth as the candidate he supports. He did not know, for example, that Ms. Shah was born in the United States. His reaction: “Really? Well, she’s absolutely a first-gen whatever. Look, I didn’t do a biography on her.” He continued: “Clearly, she’s an anti-American supporter of a pathological, lying criminal. Anyone who supports [Hillary Clinton], either actively or tacitly, is anti-American scum in my mind.” BuzzFeed reported that Pryce says he was disabled by an undocumented immigrant. He would not give any details, so BuzzFeed could not confirm his story. Pryce had some choice words for McMullin, too (“cuckservative,” which is straight from the alt-right‘s racist playbook). But he doesn’t mind at all being part of the McMullin campaign’s ad. He thinks it’s “hysterical.” Watch the ad with Alan’s message, but be warned that it’s language is quite graphic:  Featured Image: Screenshot Via YouTube Video.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>288</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>401</end>
        <start>289</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>568</end>
        <start>402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>885</end>
        <start>569</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>969</end>
        <start>886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1134</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1329</end>
        <start>1135</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1354</end>
        <start>1330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1355</end>
        <start>1355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1356</end>
        <start>1356</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1542</end>
        <start>1357</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1635</end>
        <start>1543</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1649</end>
        <start>1636</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1829</end>
        <start>1650</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1981</end>
        <start>1830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2200</end>
        <start>1982</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2285</end>
        <start>2201</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2286</end>
        <start>2286</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2332</end>
        <start>2287</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Liberal America</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>819</end>
        <start>804</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1131</end>
        <start>969</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1177</end>
        <start>1172</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1351</end>
        <start>1329</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1542</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1649</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2042</end>
        <start>2028</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2197</end>
        <start>2186</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>RABID Trump Supporter Leaves Racist Voicemail For McMullin, Candidate Turns It Into Campaign Ad (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://www.liberalamerica.org/2016/09/22/rabid-trump-supporter-racist-voicemail-mcmullin-campaign-ad-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
