<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/GettyImages-599848564-640x480.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/texas/2016/09/21/texas-threatens-withdrawal-refugee-resettlement-program/">
        <end>549</end>
        <start>539</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>If you’re ever looking for a dose of national commonsense, look no further than the great state of Texas. They are what the rest of the United States secretly wants to be, even California and New York. Governor Greg Abbot has put his foot down on “refugee resettlement” in his state and has made some very simple demands. Want to keep bringing Muslims into Texas? We need better security measures. Don’t feel like implementing such measures? Then we will no longer accept your refugees. Now THAT is leadership!  In a statement obtained by Breitbart, Abbot lays into the FBI and the refugee program. “The federal government’s refugee settlement program is riddled with serious problems that pose a threat to our nation,” Governor Abbott said in a statement obtained by Breitbart Texas. “The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Director of National Intelligence have repeatedly declared their inability to fully screen refugees from terrorist-based nations. Even with the inability to properly vet refugees from Syria and countries known to be supporters or propagators of terrorism, President Obama is now ineptly proposing a dramatic increase in the number of refugees to be resettled in the U.S.” I fully expect this same attitude to be adopted by all Republican states that aren’t run by progressives. This is something that needs to be shared across the United States and taken up by the federal government. There is no reason why the people we elected to protect us from foreign enemies should be importing people who could be putting us at risk. Abbot’s reaction wasn’t in response to the latest bombings in the United States, though I’m thoroughly convinced that was at the very least in the back of his mind. Instead, his comments came after the Texas Health and Human Services Commission wrote a letter to the head of the U.S. Office of Refugee Resettlement. In follow up to our request for approval of our application for an amended State Plan, I write to express the state of Texas’ intentions should you not unconditionally approve our application by September 30, 2016. The 2016 State Plan will no longer be current and continue in effect after September 30, 2016. That date is quickly approaching, and the Office of Refugee Resettlement has not yet approved our application for an amended State Plan. If you do not approve our State Plan as amended by September 30, 2016, we will interpret your silence as a rejection of the application. If our application is rejected -whether explicitly or by silence – the Health and Human Services Commission will be unable to certify that its State Plan is current and in effect, and will exit the Refugee Resettlement Program. We will notify contractors and impacted stakeholders that services and benefits will be provided for 120 days beyond October 1, 2016, or until January’ 31, 2017. America is a nation of immigrants, but we’re not (yet) a nation of idiots. While we should strive to help the people of the world in any way we can, we should not feel obliged to do so if it leaves us open to harm. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>201</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>486</end>
        <start>202</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>510</end>
        <start>487</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>511</end>
        <start>511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>598</end>
        <start>512</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1217</end>
        <start>599</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1570</end>
        <start>1218</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1886</end>
        <start>1571</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2101</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2860</end>
        <start>2102</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3075</end>
        <start>2861</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3076</end>
        <start>3076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>268</end>
        <start>248</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>718</end>
        <start>600</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1216</end>
        <start>786</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1217</end>
        <start>599</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2860</end>
        <start>1887</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>TEXAS SAYS ENOUGH! Threatens To Withdraw From Refugee Resettlement Program If…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/texas-says-enough-threatens-withdraw-refugee-resettlement-program/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
