<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-black-community-problems-defense-228467">
        <end>1279</end>
        <start>1255</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Rep. John Lewis, a civil rights icon, on Wednesday blasted Donald Trump’s statements about the state of the black community and America’s inner cities. “I don’t know what Mr. Trump is talking about to say that the situation for African-Americans is worse than it’s ever been,” the Georgia Democrat said when asked by MSNBC’s Andrea Mitchell about Trump’s comments. “Is he talking about worse than slavery? Worse than the system of segregation and racial discrimination — when we couldn’t take a seat at the lunch counter and be served? Worse than being denied the right to register to vote, to participate in the democratic process and live in certain neighborhoods and communities?” Story Continued Below Lewis was responding to comments Trump made during a campaign event Tuesday in North Carolina. “We’re going to rebuild our inner cities because our African-American communities are absolutely in the worst shape they’ve ever been in before. Ever, ever, ever,” Trump said. It’s part of a broader case Trump has been making to black voters, arguing that their situation is dire due to Democratic policies and that they should vote for Republicans because their circumstances could not be worse. A surrogate for the New York businessman's campaign said Trump was not suggesting that African-Americans are worse off now than under Jim Crow segregation. "I don't think he's talking about the days of Jim Crow, even the days of the civil rights movement of the '60s and obviously not slavery. But he's saying the African-American community is at times being outpaced by other communities," Joseph Borelli, a New York City council member, told CNN on Wednesday. Lewis wasn't the only prominent member of the African-American community to harshly criticize Trump's comments Wednesday. Cornell William Brooks, President of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, ripped Trump on CNN's "The Situation Room" for ignoring in his comments racial injustices from the slavery and Jim Crow eras. “For anyone to assert that the African-American community is in the worst shape ever, ever, ever … is to demonstrate an insulting degree of ignorance and insensitivity,” he said. “We expect more from our presidential candidates.” Cristiano Lima contributed to this report.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>151</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>683</end>
        <start>152</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>705</end>
        <start>684</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>800</end>
        <start>706</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>976</end>
        <start>801</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1197</end>
        <start>977</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1353</end>
        <start>1198</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1659</end>
        <start>1354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1781</end>
        <start>1660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2008</end>
        <start>1782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2238</end>
        <start>2009</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2281</end>
        <start>2239</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>275</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>366</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>963</end>
        <start>802</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2177</end>
        <start>2010</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2237</end>
        <start>2189</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>John Lewis blasts Trump's 'worst shape ever' comments</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/john-lewis-criticize-trump-228477?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
