<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sonja Bochow</author>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/2016-presidential-race/2016/09/25/exclusive-kathleen-willey-clinton-sex-victims-fill-entire-audience-presidential-debate/">
        <end>47</end>
        <start>17</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Kathleen Willey, one well known former mistress of Bill Clinton, among an estimated 2,000 women over the course of his political career, was asked if she would attend Monday’s Presidential debate if invited by Trump. Her response? “I would refrain for now. Let her do herself in on her own.” She continued, explaining that if every woman Bill Clinton had an affair with over the years was present at the debates, it would fill the hall. See her comment below: “Most of us are well known and our stories have been repeated several times over the years, but what concerns me the most are the voices of my sisters who are still afraid to come out of the darkness. I have communicated with a number of them and they are still terrified of publicly sharing their experiences with the Clintons. The real story here is not one of our presence in the front row at any of these debates, but the unhindered lust for power that the Clintons have displayed for decades. Hillary Clinton has lied, cheated and stolen our lives from us. People have died in her wake of deceit. We could fill the entire audience. I would like to see the day when these women can step into the light and share their stories of brutality, terror and intimidation without the kind of fear of intimidation and recrimination that we have experienced for far too many years.” The Clinton machine has spent years terrorizing Bill’s mistresses. And much of that was orchestrated by Hillary, who, for all intents and purposes is the attack dog that keeps her husband from having to answer for his sleazy lifestyle.   Hillary would be a shameful President and an exceedingly poor example to our daughters. She models the “break the rules to get ahead” mentality. Just being a woman does not make her a good role model. American women and girls deserve better. They deserve a woman President who is honest. And Hillary certainly isn’t. No matter who sits in the front row at the debate, Hillary will still be there; lying, fabricating, screeching and coughing…and that’s just the introductions. Trump will wipe the floor with Wicked Hillary. And all those women victimized by Bill and Hillary over the years will be laughing hysterically. What goes around, comes around. And you, Mrs. Bill Clinton, are overdue for some karma. Never Hillary.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>293</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>461</end>
        <start>294</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>790</end>
        <start>462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1063</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1338</end>
        <start>1064</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1574</end>
        <start>1339</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1575</end>
        <start>1575</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1576</end>
        <start>1576</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1893</end>
        <start>1577</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2299</end>
        <start>1894</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2300</end>
        <start>2300</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2301</end>
        <start>2301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2302</end>
        <start>2302</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>290</end>
        <start>232</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1335</end>
        <start>461</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1707</end>
        <start>1679</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>460</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Boom! Kathleen Willey Says Clinton’s Victims Could Fill Entire Audience At Debate [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/boom-kathleen-willey-says-clintons-victims-could-fill-entire-audience-at-debate/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
