<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Ben Marquis</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/hillary-medical-video-angle/">
        <end>238</end>
        <start>196</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://theconservativetreehouse.com/2016/09/25/hillarys-instantaneous-health-morph-unanticipated-pool-reporter-surprises-secretary-clinton/">
        <end>763</end>
        <start>741</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/mXxBbMiVcu">
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>1055</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ABCLiz/status/780169835657519104">
        <end>1123</end>
        <start>1105</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As most of our readers are well aware, there has been immense speculation recently regarding the health status of Democrat presidential nominee Hillary Clinton. Following in the wake of Clinton’s near collapse at the 9/11 memorial service earlier this month, some have suggested that Clinton may be suffering from some sort of neurological disorder that is causing her to have dizzy spells and difficulty walking or standing, particularly when dealing with steps. There is sure to be renewed speculation in that regard following a bit of video that emerged Sunday via a Twitter post from Clinton pool reporter and ABC News journalist Liz Kreutz, who happened to catch Clinton as she was leaving a building in New York City, according to the Conservative Treehouse. Clinton was exiting the Appleseeds Kids Center and preparing to descend a set of stairs when Kreutz approached, camera rolling, and began to ask questions of the candidate.  Clinton just left "Apple Seeds" kids center in Flatiron. Feeling good about debate? "Getting ready, getting ready!" pic.twitter.com/mXxBbMiVcu — Liz Kreutz (@ABCLiz) September 25, 2016  As can be seen in the video, Clinton seemingly ignored the reporter’s first questions, instead remaining intently focused on grabbing the handrail and her footing on the steps as she descended. Once she was about three-quarters of the way down the stairs, only then did Clinton turn her attention to the reporter, flashing a sudden smile but continuing to ignore the questions, replying with only “Getting ready” when pressed about her preparedness for the first presidential debate Monday evening. She then carefully hoisted herself up into her special campaign van, without any assistance, though a Secret Service agent stood ready to perhaps lend a hand right behind her. While it is entirely plausible that Clinton didn’t see or hear the reporter until she had reached the bottom of the steps, this video clip will likely still serve as further proof that she is suffering from some sort of medical issues that make it difficult for her to walk up and down stairs. The video certainly reinforces the supposition that Clinton suffers from selective hearing, picking and choosing which questions she will acknowledge and answer while ignoring others that may prove difficult or too revealing for her. Please share this on Facebook and Twitter so that everyone can see Hillary Clinton seemingly struggle in her effort to successfully descend a flight of stairs, so much so that she virtually ignored a reporter standing and watching in close proximity. What do you think of the apparently extra-careful manner in which Hillary Clinton was spotted descending a small set of stairs? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>160</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>463</end>
        <start>161</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>764</end>
        <start>464</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>937</end>
        <start>765</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>938</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1123</end>
        <start>1082</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1124</end>
        <start>1124</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1318</end>
        <start>1125</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1623</end>
        <start>1319</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1799</end>
        <start>1624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2093</end>
        <start>1800</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2327</end>
        <start>2094</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2578</end>
        <start>2328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2736</end>
        <start>2579</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1037</end>
        <start>1024</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1123</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Reporter Ambushes Hillary on Steps, Catches What She’s Hiding ON TAPE</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/reporter-hillary-steps-tape/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-26&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
