<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Zach Cartwright</author>
    <links href="http://kfor.com/2016/09/22/tulsa-district-attorney-discusses-details-related-to-officer-involved-shooting-of-terence-crutcher/">
        <end>269</end>
        <start>216</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Tulsa?src=hash">
        <end>506</end>
        <start>500</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BettyShelby?src=hash">
        <end>560</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TerenceCruther?src=hash">
        <end>580</end>
        <start>565</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/h4PC6EBWwm">
        <end>617</end>
        <start>591</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/TiffanyAlaniz/status/779055879807115264">
        <end>670</end>
        <start>652</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newson6.com/story/33132173/us-attorney-city-leaders-crutcher-shooting-will-be-properly-thoroughly-investigated">
        <end>1129</end>
        <start>1104</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newson6.com/story/33132173/us-attorney-city-leaders-crutcher-shooting-will-be-properly-thoroughly-investigated">
        <end>1897</end>
        <start>1876</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newson6.com/story/33132173/us-attorney-city-leaders-crutcher-shooting-will-be-properly-thoroughly-investigated">
        <end>1980</end>
        <start>1944</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/gruesome-video-shows-tulsa-police-killing-unarmed-terence-crutcher-hands-air/">
        <end>2427</end>
        <start>2381</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A local prosecutor in Tulsa, Oklahoma has brought charges against Betty Shelby, the officer who shot and killed Terence Crutcher. In a press conference Thursday afternoon, the Tulsa County District Attorney’s office announced a warrant for Officer Betty Shelby’s arrest on the charge of felony manslaughter in the first degree. Shelby fired the shot that killed 40-year-old Terence Crutcher, who was unarmed and had his hands raised throughout his fatal encounter with police last weekend. BREAKING: #Tulsa DA files 1st degree manslaughter charges #BettyShelby for #TerenceCruther shooting. pic.twitter.com/h4PC6EBWwm — Tiffany Alaniz (@TiffanyAlaniz) September 22, 2016  “I don’t know why things happen in this world the way they do,” said District Attorney Steve Kunzweiler. “We need to pray for wisdom and guidance on each of our respective paths in life. Each of us at the end of our days will have to account for our own actions. The only way I know to walk my path is to try every day to pray and to serve my fellow citizens so that he or she may be lifted up.” Tulsa’s top law enforcement officer appealed to the community to allow the judicial system to do its work. Tulsa police chief Chuck Jordan has contacted the United States Department of Justice (DOJ), asking them to conduct their own separate civil rights investigation into the shooting. “I want to assure our community and assure all of you, and people across the nation looking at this, we will achieve justice,” Jordan said. Shelby is arguing that she had a right to shoot Crutcher because he allegedly failed to obey her commands. Her attorney, Scott Wood, said Shelby was a drug recognition expert and believed Crutcher was under the influence of drugs when she encountered him. “By the end of the incident, Officer Shelby was screaming at him to stop. He did not obey one single command given to him,” Wood told local media. Newson6.com reported that Officer Shelby had two prior excessive force complaints lodged against her during the course of her career, though both were unfounded. U.S. Attorney Danny Williams said the DOJ will thoroughly investigate whether or not Crutcher’s civil rights were infringed upon. “Will devote whatever resources necessary to ensure all allegations of serious civil rights violations are fully and completely investigated,” Williams said. Crutcher, a father of four, was on his way home from a community college class when his SUV broke down. When officers responded, Crutcher, who had his hands up, was shot when he walked toward his driver side window. Officers did not find a weapon on Crutcher’s person or in his vehicle.        </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>129</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>489</end>
        <start>130</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>617</end>
        <start>490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>670</end>
        <start>618</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>671</end>
        <start>671</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>672</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1355</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1495</end>
        <start>1356</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1751</end>
        <start>1496</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1898</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2190</end>
        <start>1899</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2348</end>
        <start>2191</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2635</end>
        <start>2349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2637</end>
        <start>2636</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2638</end>
        <start>2638</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2639</end>
        <start>2639</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2640</end>
        <start>2640</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2641</end>
        <start>2641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2642</end>
        <start>2642</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2643</end>
        <start>2643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>734</end>
        <start>673</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1066</end>
        <start>778</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1481</end>
        <start>1357</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1874</end>
        <start>1753</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2332</end>
        <start>2192</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>670</end>
        <start>490</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Tulsa Cop Betty Shelby charged with manslaughter in shooting death of Terence Crutcher</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/news/officer-betty-shelby-charged-first-degree-murder-killing-terence-crutcher/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
