<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Posted by John Prager on 21 Sep 2016</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Montel_Williams">
        <end>1594</end>
        <start>1587</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-21_23-42-30.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-09-21_23-41-39.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/lIVRyuY9-1.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://winningdemocrats.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/0xDWZ_2i.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>On Wednesday, talk show legend Montel Williams posed a very simple question for conservatives: when are you going to take responsibility for their role in helping to create the violent situation in Charlotte, North Carolina? Just hours after Donald Trump proposed nationwide “Stop and Frisk” — a policy that was declared unconstitutional in New York. Responding to a question about “black-on-black crime,” Trump said he would “do stop-and-frisk” to solve the problem. “We did it in New York,” he said. “It worked incredibly well and you have to be proactive.” Stop-and-frisk did not, in fact, “work incredibly well.” In 2011, for example, black and Latino residents made up about 90 percent of people stopped, and 88 percent of those were innocent. Even in predominantly white neighborhoods, blacks and Latinos were stopped more than whites. “Donald Trump is having trouble with the facts,” New York City Council Speaker Melissa Mark Viverito said in a statement regarding Trump’s remarks. “Stop and frisk as it was applied in New York City was unconstitutional, it didn’t reduce crime and it severely corroded the relationship between the police and the communities they serve.” Yes, “stop-and-frisk” is a racist practice, but his suggestion that it should be implemented nationwide really resonates with some of Trump’s die-hard supporters — namely white supremacists. “When are conservatives going to own their damn part in this? That asshole Trump just proposed national stop and frisk?” Williams, who has also been critical of protesters who have chosen to become violent, asked on Twitter. “WTF?” One of Trump’s “deplorables” calling himself “Big Daddy” climbed out of his basket and once again proved Hillary Clinton’s assessment of The Donald’s meth-fueled legion of ignoramuses correct. “He will control n*ggers unlike you cucks,” Big Daddy informed Williams. Naturally, more of Trump’s “deplorables” came out to play:  But Trump’s acolyte apparently did not know to whom he was speaking. “And now we know why these white supremacist bumpkins with no teeth married to their cousins love Trump,” Williams shot back:  “Big Daddy” has since slithered back into the basket and closed it, changing his name and protecting his tweets presumably because he realized that when you say racist things on the internet, people notice.  It’s interesting how “brave” Trump’s paper tigers are until someone puts them in their place. Featured image via screengrab  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>350</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>559</end>
        <start>351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>841</end>
        <start>560</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1179</end>
        <start>842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1370</end>
        <start>1180</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1602</end>
        <start>1371</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1868</end>
        <start>1603</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1927</end>
        <start>1869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1928</end>
        <start>1928</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2123</end>
        <start>1929</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2124</end>
        <start>2124</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2331</end>
        <start>2125</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2332</end>
        <start>2332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2426</end>
        <start>2333</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2456</end>
        <start>2427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2458</end>
        <start>2457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Winning Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>290</end>
        <start>276</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>404</end>
        <start>383</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>444</end>
        <start>427</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>491</end>
        <start>469</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>558</end>
        <start>503</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>615</end>
        <start>594</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>889</end>
        <start>843</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1178</end>
        <start>991</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>444</end>
        <start>430</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1490</end>
        <start>1372</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1601</end>
        <start>1597</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1630</end>
        <start>1619</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1658</end>
        <start>1649</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1838</end>
        <start>1797</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1630</end>
        <start>1619</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2102</end>
        <start>1999</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1658</end>
        <start>1649</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2360</end>
        <start>2355</start>
    </quotes>
    <title></title>
    <uri>http://winningdemocrats.com/montel-williams-response-when-a-trump-fan-calls-him-a-n-is-perfect-screenshots/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
