<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tiffiny Ruegner</author>
    <mainText>Harassment is known in Arabic as ‘taharrush’. Mass sexual assault of women in public has been documented in Egypt since 2005 and they recently began calling it the game of ‘taharrush’. Muslim men rape and assault women in public while hiding under protective cover of large gatherings. The Muslim men feel it’s their right because of the misogynistic ideology that women shouldn’t be leaving the house alone and deserve to be shamed using sexual violence. Assailants will create multiple rings around the woman to keep out anyone who tries to rescue them. It’s a really sick practice and women experiencing it could be groped, stripped, beaten, bitten, penetrated with fingers and raped. These Muslim gang rapes have grown and spread since 2012 when large protests in Egypt took place punishing women for attending such protests.   So, it stands to reason that a mass flood of Muslim men who feel that the taharrush of women is okay into Western countries would result in lots of gang rape. This particular story is of an illegal Algerian immigrant who beat a woman unconscious in an attempted rape, who was arrested and explained to the judge what he was doing in Austria. He told the court that he came to Australia to “f*ck the women.” Based on his actions and his previous convictions across Europe, he most likely means to rape women as is the custom of some young Muslim men. After the gang rape, the woman was left lying unconscious in bushes near the bus stop. She had some serious injuries and is considered to be psychologically scarred permanently. Luckily, she found a student who helped her. That student testified that, “The woman came up to me and was covered in blood. You could not see her face. She said to me: ‘I was raped.’” This wave of sexual assaults in Austria and Europe is only going to increase as the migrant population swells.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>829</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>830</end>
        <start>830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>831</end>
        <start>831</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>832</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1744</end>
        <start>1382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1745</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1857</end>
        <start>1857</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1858</end>
        <start>1858</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1237</end>
        <start>1222</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1743</end>
        <start>1635</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Migrant Reveals Sick Reason He Left…’to F*ck the Women’</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/migrant-reveals-sick-reason-left-fck-women/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
