<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Gary DeMar</author>
    <links href="http://www.cdc.gov/msmhealth/STD.htm">
        <end>837</end>
        <start>795</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cdc.gov/std/">
        <end>882</end>
        <start>846</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I was watching a local news show about a business called “Out of the Closet.” They are a series of thrift stores to benefit AIDS Healthcare Foundation. Not only can you purchase second-hand and consignment merchandise, but you can get free HIV and STD tests.  I found this rather curious. Why would a pro-homosexual advocacy business like “Out of the Closet” be offering HIV and STD tests? What is it about the sexual practices of homosexuals that they would need to be tested for sexual diseases?  I don’t need to be tested for HIV and STDs. The only people who would need to be tested are those who engaged in behaviors that lead to HIV and STDs. If two people are married and only engage in sex with one another, neither of them would ever get HIV or an STD. The following is reported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): “Sexually Transmitted Diseases (STDs) have been increasing among gay and bisexual men, with recent increases in syphilis being documented across the country. In 2012, men who have sex with men (MSM) accounted for 75% of primary and secondary syphilis cases in the United States. MSM often are diagnosed with other STDs, including chlamydia and gonorrhea infections.” One would think the AIDS scare of the 1980s would have been an empirical indicator that same-sex relationships, as well as shared drug needles, are destructive behaviors. We were told that anyone could get AIDS. There’s a commercial running today that makes this claim. If this is true, then all stores should be offering tests. But they don’t because it would be a massive insult to the vast majority of people who do not engage in same-sex sexual activity. Another empirical indicator that same-sex relationships are abnormal is that there is no chance of procreation. Homosexuals have to be artificially inseminated or adopt. When morality, science, and common sense conflict with liberal ideology, you can always count on governments to use force in order to make people comply.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>258</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>259</end>
        <start>259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>497</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>498</end>
        <start>498</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>761</end>
        <start>499</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>844</end>
        <start>762</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1211</end>
        <start>845</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1382</end>
        <start>1212</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1670</end>
        <start>1383</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1840</end>
        <start>1671</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1994</end>
        <start>1841</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1995</end>
        <start>1995</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2141</end>
        <start>1996</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2215</end>
        <start>2142</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>76</end>
        <start>58</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>75</end>
        <start>58</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1210</end>
        <start>846</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1211</end>
        <start>845</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2177</end>
        <start>2165</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Why do Homosexuals Need to be Tested for HIV and AIDS, Since Their Behavior is Normal and Healthy?</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36839/why-do-homosexuals-need-to-be-tested-for-hiv-and-aids-since-their-behavior-is-normal-and-healthy/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
