<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Antiphon Freeman</author>
    <mainText>In a particularly tense interview on CNN, Trump was called out for saying that Hillary Clinton is a “bigot.” When he was asked for any particular reasons on why, he just couldn’t explain himself. He tried to pivot away from the question at hand and made himself look really foolish. Here is the exchange:  Anderson Cooper: You’ve previously called Hillary Clinton  a bigot. How is she a bigot? Trump: Well, she’s a bigot. Anderson Cooper: But, how is she bigoted? Bigotry is having a hatred towards a particular group. Trump: She’s not doing anything for those communities. Anderson Cooper: (Again) So, you’re saying she has hatred or dislike of black people? Trump: Her policies are bigoted. Anderson Cooper: But, you said her policies are “personally bigoted.” Trump: Oh she is. Of course she is. She’s totally bigoted there’s no question about that. Anderson Cooper: But, it does imply that she has antipathy, that she has hatred toward, I guess in this case you’re talking about African-Americans, but I don’t want to put words in your mouth. But, is hatred at the core of that? Or dislike of African-Americans? Trump: Or maybe she’s lazy.    </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>289</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>311</end>
        <start>290</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>404</end>
        <start>312</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>434</end>
        <start>405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>531</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>588</end>
        <start>532</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>676</end>
        <start>589</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>709</end>
        <start>677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>783</end>
        <start>710</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>877</end>
        <start>784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1144</end>
        <start>878</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1174</end>
        <start>1145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1175</end>
        <start>1175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1178</end>
        <start>1176</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1179</end>
        <start>1179</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1174</end>
        <start>312</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Has Meltdown On CNN, Gets Called Out For Saying Hillary’s A ‘Bigot’ – Can’t Explain Why</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/trump-has-meltdown-on-cnn-gets-called-out-for-saying-hillarys-a-bigot-cant-explain-why/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
