<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tom Cahill</author>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/education/wp/2016/09/20/school-lunch-worker-quits-after-being-forced-to-refuse-hot-meal-to-poor-student/?tid=sm_fb">
        <end>456</end>
        <start>411</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/stacy.myersyannazzo/posts/1244432282254306">
        <end>646</end>
        <start>626</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wtae.com/news/canon-mcmillan-school-cafeteria-worker-quits-lunch-shaming/41743496">
        <end>1181</end>
        <start>1158</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wtae.com/news/canon-mcmillan-school-cafeteria-worker-quits-lunch-shaming/41743496">
        <end>1827</end>
        <start>1801</start>
    </links>
    <links>
        <end>2455</end>
        <start>2437</start>
    </links>
    <links>
        <end>2455</end>
        <start>2438</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/stacy.myersyannazzo">
        <end>2649</end>
        <start>2620</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/stacy.myersyannazzo/posts/1244432282254306">
        <end>2681</end>
        <start>2653</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A cafeteria worker in a Pennsylvania school district just quit her job, saying the district’s new lunch policy is morally bankrupt. Stacy Koltiska turned in her resignation letter after being forced to throw away a child’s hot meal in front of a full cafeteria because his parents owed more than $25 to the Canon-McMillan school district, south of Pittsburgh. According to the Washington Post, the school board recently adopted the controversial new policy this fall to recoup thousands of dollars in debt owed to the district. “His eyes welled up with tears. I’ll never forget his name, the look on his face,” Koltiska wrote on her Facebook page after turning in her resignation. Koltiska, who worked the cash register at Wylandville Elementary School in Eighty Four, Pennsylvania, said the total cost of the hot meal was just $2.05, and that the policy required her to throw out the child’s hot meal and replace it with a sandwich made of two slices of white bread and a cold slice of government cheese. However, the student’s lunch account is still charged the standard $2.05 for the meal even if they had their hot lunch taken away. High school students don’t get a meal at all, under the new policy. “God is love, and we should love one another and be kind,” Koltiska told the . “There’s enough wealth in this world that no child should go hungry, especially in school. To me this is just wrong.” Koltiska blasted the policy as immoral, and the board members who passed it as indifferent to the plight of hungry children. “They’re suits at a board meeting,” she said. “They are not the ones facing a child and looking them in the eye and taking their food away.” Matthew Daniels, the superintendent of the Canon-McMillan district, told WTAE-TV the policy isn’t intended to shame hungry children, but to recoup lost revenue. Before the policy was implemented, Daniels said more than 300 families owed approximately $60,000 to $100,000 on their lunch accounts, collectively. Now, fewer than 70 families owe roughly $20,000. Daniels added that students on free or reduced lunch programs aren’t subject to the new policy. “There has never been the intent with the adoption of this policy to shame or embarrass a child,” he said. In a viral Facebook post, Koltiska implored readers to email Superintendent Daniels and Joni Mansmann, the district’s director of business and finance, and to ask them to repeal the policy. Their emails are @[email protected]  and [email protected] , respectively. ATTENTION ALL PARENTS WHO HAVE CHILDREN IN THE CANON McMILLAN SCHOOL DISTRICT!!! I need to inform you about a new… Posted by Stacy Myers Yannazzo Koltiska on Thursday, September 15, 2016        </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>131</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>527</end>
        <start>132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>680</end>
        <start>528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1204</end>
        <start>681</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1401</end>
        <start>1205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1526</end>
        <start>1402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1667</end>
        <start>1527</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2122</end>
        <start>1668</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2229</end>
        <start>2123</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2494</end>
        <start>2230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2609</end>
        <start>2495</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2681</end>
        <start>2610</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2683</end>
        <start>2682</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2684</end>
        <start>2684</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2685</end>
        <start>2685</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2686</end>
        <start>2686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2687</end>
        <start>2687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2688</end>
        <start>2688</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2689</end>
        <start>2689</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>609</end>
        <start>529</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1262</end>
        <start>1206</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1400</end>
        <start>1285</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1561</end>
        <start>1528</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1666</end>
        <start>1574</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2219</end>
        <start>2124</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2681</end>
        <start>2495</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>School lunch worker quits in disgust after being forced to refuse meals to poor students</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/class-war/lunch-lady-quits-forced-throw-away-hot-meal-front-hungry-child/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
