<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Lisa Smith</author>
    <links href="http://www.thefederalistpapers.org/us/wikileaks-reveals-financial-connection-between-hillary-and-isis">
        <end>36</end>
        <start>27</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>In another revelation from WikiLeaks we find even more information! Hillary has accepted donations from the head of a company who has also accepted donations from ISIS…good gosh, just when you think this vile woman couldn’t get any worse!   The company is French industrial giant Lefarge, from which Hillary accepted over $100,000.  Let us also not forget this:  What is also shocking is that the City of Paris signed contracts with this company, despite information linking them to the Islamic State. TheCanary.Co reported on this shocking discovery: Documents obtained by several journalistic investigations reveal that Lafarge has paid taxes to the terror group to operate its cement plant in Syria, and even bought Isis oil for years. Yet according to the campaign group, SumOfUs, Lafarge is the corporate partner and sand provider to the City of Paris for this summer’s Paris-Plages urban beach event. The project run by Office of the Mayor of Paris, Anne Hidalgo, will create artificial beaches along the river Seine in the centre and northeast of Paris. Lafarge also has close ties to Democrat presidential candidate Hillary Clinton. Apart from being a regular donor to the Clinton Foundation, Clinton herself was a director of Lafarge in the early 1990s, and did legal work for the firm in the 1980s. During her connection to Lafarge, the firm was implicated in facilitating a CIA-backed covert arms export network to Saddam Hussein. The report went on to confirm that the company’s Paris office was well aware of the operations conducted with the Islamic State for cement and oil transactions. Lafarge bought oil for its own operations, but also allegedly supplied the Islamic State with cement for its operations. You can’t sit on the fence with a terrorist organization, you’re either with them, or you’re not. You can’t have a middle ground because if you try to they will OBLITERATE YOU. You don’t mess around with terrorists unless you are in clear support of them. Hillary has borrowed over $100,000 from the very company who’s in support of ISIS, you know the group of crazy Muslims that want us all dead. Hillary Clinton is a traitor.  Unfortunately, the laws don’t apply to Hitler…I mean Hillary.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>238</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>239</end>
        <start>239</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>240</end>
        <start>240</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>331</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>332</end>
        <start>332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>333</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>362</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>501</end>
        <start>363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>502</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>738</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1060</end>
        <start>739</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1441</end>
        <start>1061</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1723</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2151</end>
        <start>1724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2152</end>
        <start>2152</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2214</end>
        <start>2153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1479</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: WikiLeak STRIKES Again- REVEALS Financial Connection Between Hillary And ISIS!</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/08/02/breaking-wikileak-strikes-again-reveals-financial-connection-between-hillary-and-isis/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
