<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Conservative Byte</author>
    <links href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/26/tech-really-wants-to-fix-this-election/">
        <end>803</end>
        <start>765</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/california/2016/09/26/silicon-valley-report-tech-wants-fix-election/">
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1569</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Silicon Valley is afraid that their worst dreams will be realized if Donald Trump defeats Hillary Clinton in November. To bolster their cause they have jumped in to the registration process with some big bucks. We are talking millions. Company’s  like Facebook and Google are among the supporters of Hillary Clinton, and are totally involved supporting these liberal registration groups.  As Written By Joel B. Pollack for Breitbart:  The popular tech blog TechCrunch reported Monday that Silicon Valley giants are so worried about the rising prospects of Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump that they are scrambling to find and fund ways to encourage more people to register to vote — presumably for Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton. In a story titled “Tech really wants to fix this election,” TechCrunch reporter Kate Conger reports that “tech companies from Google all the way down to small startups like Sam Altman’s VotePlz, which launched a million dollar registration sweepstakes today, are trying to” boost registration. Moreover, “although most claim to be nonpartisan,” Conger notes, “it’s clear that Donald Trump’s unusual campaign has ignited investors and pushed them to act.” She adds: VotePlz lets people check their voter registration status online, helps them register by guiding them through the online registration process or printing and mailing the registration form in states that require registration-by-mail, and gamifies the entire process with a leader-board that tracks how many friends have been referred by ……   Full Story Here: Report: Silicon Valley ‘Wants to Fix This Election’ – Breitbart</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>387</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>388</end>
        <start>388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>434</end>
        <start>389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>745</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1039</end>
        <start>746</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1210</end>
        <start>1040</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1549</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1551</end>
        <start>1550</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1568</end>
        <start>1552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1569</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Byte</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>804</end>
        <start>765</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1018</end>
        <start>852</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1089</end>
        <start>1051</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1199</end>
        <start>1106</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1549</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1552</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Tech Giants Scrambling they ‘Really want to fix this election’</title>
    <uri>http://conservativebyte.com/2016/09/tech-giants-scrambling-they-really-want-to-fix-this-election/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
