<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Lisa Smith</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Trump?src=hash">
        <end>686</end>
        <start>680</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MAGA?src=hash">
        <end>763</end>
        <start>758</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/Kp4ta0hAng">
        <end>790</end>
        <start>764</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JxhnBinder/status/777615162568220678">
        <end>840</end>
        <start>822</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A Donald Trump supporter showed up to the Hillary headquarters to survey the scene, but what he saw there was very very amusing. There was not a soul in sight. At Hillary Clinton’s Ohio campaign headquarters, volunteers were supposed to come in droves to knock on doors for the Democratic presidential nominee. Not to anyone’s surprise…the place looked about as desolate as water in the Nevada desert! In fact, the only Hillary supporters at the offices were the staff running the headquarters, and even then, makes you wonder how much they were paid. When the man disclosed who he was, a Trump supporter and asked where all the volunteers were, they quickly showed him the door. #Trump supporter goes to Hillary Clinton's Ohio offices, finds NO VOLUNTEERS. #MAGA pic.twitter.com/Kp4ta0hAng — John Binder 👽 (@JxhnBinder) September 18, 2016  Does Hillary really have zero enthusiasm among her supporters? It sure appears that way! I guess this shouldn’t be too shocking, considering Hillary had to pay people just to show up at her DNC convention a couple weeks ago. How very interesting, it’s a good thing this video was taken to show just how little people support this horrid woman. The people here seemed so happy that at least one person showed up, too bad it was Trump supporter! Love it.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>128</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>159</end>
        <start>129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>401</end>
        <start>160</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>679</end>
        <start>402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>790</end>
        <start>680</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>840</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>841</end>
        <start>841</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>930</end>
        <start>842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1066</end>
        <start>931</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1294</end>
        <start>1067</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>840</end>
        <start>680</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary’s Ohio Office Has ‘Door-Knocking’ Event” Trump Supporter Shows, What He Finds There, Disturbs Many!</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/09/19/hillarys-ohio-office-has-door-knocking-event-trump-supporter-shows-what-he-finds-there-disturbs-many/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
