<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/truck-driver.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.theblaze.com/stories/2016/09/21/charlotte-police-chief-officers-warned-black-man-to-drop-gun/">
        <end>920</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>There has been a lot of speculation and anger surrounding the shooting of a black man by Charlotte police. Such anger, in fact, has bred more riots in North Carolina, which led to looting, theft of private property and the shutdown of I-85.  But all we’re being told is the side of things where the man was an innocent little cupcake on his way to volunteer at a soup kitchen before he read stories to blind, homeless children and donated all of his paycheck to the local animal shelter. What is the story coming from the police officers involved in the shooting? Does anyone care? Does it even matter what the cops say happened? The riots have already started and the hatred is already coursing through the veins of people who are just looking for a reason to take to the streets, so will this change anything? To those of us who actually uses our brains in these situations, it could make all the difference. The Blaze posted the statement of the Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Chief on the incident. Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Chief Kerr Putney said during a news conference Wednesday morning that officers were searching for a suspect Tuesday when they saw 43-year-old Keith Lamont Scott exit a vehicle with a handgun. He says the officers told him to drop the gun and that he got out of the vehicle a second time still carrying the gun. He says the man was shot because he posed a threat. “It’s time to change the narrative, because I can tell you from the facts that the story’s a little bit different as to how it’s been portrayed so far, especially through social media,” he said. As an officer, you’re hearing about your brothers and sisters in blue being shot by thugs who have a chip on their shoulder. You hear this and then you see a man get out of his vehicle with a firearm. You tell him to put the gun down, and he refuses. Are you supposed to wait until he shoots first? If a man breaks into your house, are you supposed to wait until he actually harms you before you protect yourself? How does that even make sense? Oh that’s right, it doesn’t. Of course, that doesn’t stop progressives from declaring that they know exactly how things should be happening. You know, with their degrees in women’s studies and art history, they’re clearly the most qualified people to be criticizing the actions of our law enforcement. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>240</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>241</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>487</end>
        <start>242</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>488</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>910</end>
        <start>812</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>911</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1393</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1588</end>
        <start>1394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2033</end>
        <start>1589</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2335</end>
        <start>2034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2336</end>
        <start>2336</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1578</end>
        <start>1395</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1588</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Charlotte Police REVEAL What They Said To Black Man Just Moments Before Shooting…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/charlotte-police-reveal-said-black-man-just-moments-shooting/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
