<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/foo10_b.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://gma.yahoo.com/blue-bell-voluntarily-recalls-select-ice-cream-products-075300681--abc-news-wellness.html">
        <end>543</end>
        <start>524</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/920x1240.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.bluebell.com/the_little_creamery/press_releases/bb-am-kol">
        <end>1957</end>
        <start>1951</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/WuzAGUSpH0">
        <end>2605</end>
        <start>2579</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/ILoveBlueBell/status/777933555808673793">
        <end>2663</end>
        <start>2645</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Blue Bell just did the one thing we all hoped would never happen again, this is a nightmare. In 2015 we were all devastated when our favorite ice cream had a HUGE recall taking it off the shelves for months. This was their first recall in over 100 years! Eventually toward the end of 2016 we started seeing Blue Bell back out on the shelves, but now there has been another recall on the products!  The company is now voluntarily recalling several of their ice-cream products because they are concerned that they may contain “listeria bacteria”. Unfortunately, they have recalled two of their products that contain chocolate chip cookie dough. Blue Bell stated that the dough was being made by a third party known as Aspen Hills Inc. The good news is that there haven’t been any reports of illness from the ice cream but Blue Bell is wanting to take precautions before their are any. The company posted the recall on their Facebook yesterday. “Out of an abundance of caution, we are voluntarily recalling select products that contain a chocolate chip cookie dough ingredient. Aspen Hills, Inc., who supplies us with this ingredient, has issued a voluntary recall on select lots of chocolate chip cookie dough supplied to Blue Bell. No illnesses have been reported to date, but Blue Bell is taking this step because we remain committed to producing a safe, high-quality, great-tasting ice cream for you and your family to enjoy.”  Apparently the ice cream was distributed in 10 states: Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee and Virginia. Blue Bell also posted a list of recalled products to ensure that no one is eating them. Blue Bell Ice Cream Half Gallons: Code Dates Blue Bell Chocolate Chip Cookie Dough 082618226 Blue Bell Cookie Two Step 080418222, 081818224 Blue Bell Ice Cream Pints: Code Dates Blue Bell Chocolate Chip Cookie Dough 081518242, 082418242 Aspen Hills Inc. wrote a letter about the recall stating that the contaminated cookie dough could cause fever, headaches, stiffness, nausea, abdominal pain and diarrhea. Not only that but if you are pregnant the infection can cause miscarriages and still-births. Blue Bell was sold in over 30 states before their huge recall last year, and some of those places are barely getting the ice cream back out on the shelves. One store in particular recited their shipment of Blue Bell only two days before the big recall! We’re all smiles in Raleigh, NC, because Blue Bell is back! Look for it in stores in Raleigh, Durham, Chapel Hill and surrounding areas. pic.twitter.com/WuzAGUSpH0 — Blue Bell Ice Cream (@ILoveBlueBell) September 19, 2016  This is so sad!! Share this with everyone you know!!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>92</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>396</end>
        <start>93</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>397</end>
        <start>397</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>642</end>
        <start>398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>941</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1427</end>
        <start>942</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1428</end>
        <start>1428</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1688</end>
        <start>1429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1733</end>
        <start>1689</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1781</end>
        <start>1734</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1828</end>
        <start>1782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1866</end>
        <start>1829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1925</end>
        <start>1867</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2188</end>
        <start>1926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2441</end>
        <start>2189</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2605</end>
        <start>2442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2663</end>
        <start>2606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2664</end>
        <start>2664</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2717</end>
        <start>2665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>542</end>
        <start>525</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1426</end>
        <start>943</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1427</end>
        <start>942</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2663</end>
        <start>2442</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Blue Bell Just Announced Another Massive Recall</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/news/breaking-blue-bell-just-announced-another-massive-recall/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Blue+Bell%2F9%2F23&amp;utm_content=Right+Wing+News%2FBlue+Bell%2F9%2F23</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
