<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://thefederalistpapers.org/us/breaking-details-of-secret-deal-between-fbi-and-cheryl-mills-exposed">
        <end>37</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nypost.com/2016/09/04/meet-the-mastermind-behind-clintons-massive-email-coverup/">
        <end>545</end>
        <start>532</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Hillary-8-e1474663491547.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/U/US_FBI_CLINTON_EMAILS?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2016-09-23-11-28-54">
        <end>1288</end>
        <start>1272</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>You’ve got to be freaking kidding me. This is just simply unbelievable. Not only was the Hildabeast’s IT guy granted immunity, they gave immunity to Cheryl Mills and two other staff members. No wonder they couldn’t convict her. The revelations of the immunity granted left Republicans in utter shock. Then they got furious, but I guess they got out-maneuvered on this one. I told you these people aren’t stupid. There were a myriad of ways that Mills herself violated the law or at a minimum assisted Clinton in skirting it. In the New York Post earlier this month, Paul Sperry bluntly accused Mills of being the evil mastermind behind the Clinton email coverup: … Mills ultimately made the determinations about which emails should be preserved before she and Clinton decided to delete the rest as “personal” … Mills was the one who ordered the server host to move the emails from the server to a laptop where she could screen them … And Mills may have been a key player in the game of hide-and-seek.  From The Federalist Papers Project: Another top aide to Hillary Rodham Clinton was granted immunity by President Barack Obama’s Department of JusticeInjustice during the FBI’s investigation into the former Secretary of State’s use of a private email server, reported theAssociated Press. Specifically, the FBI provided Clinton’s former chief of Staff, Cheryl Mills, and two other staff members with immunity. The bombshell revelation reportedly left congressional Republicans in utter shock. “No wonder they couldn’t prosecute a case,” remarked Rep. Jason Chaffetz, chairman of the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee. “They were handing out immunity deals like candy.” Consider also why the FBI granted immunity — to procure more evidence to use against Secretary Clinton. Yet the Department ultimately failed to acquire enough evidence to pursue charges against her, as Director James Comey tried to explain two months ago:   Every official in and out of the FBI involved in this whole investigation should be brought to account for this and should at the very least, lose their jobs, if not go to prison. According to the final House Benghazi Committee Report released three months ago, as reported by Politico, Mills also tainted “the findings of an internal State Department review of the 2012 Benghazi terrorist attack.” Why in the hell would you grant this woman immunity? Oh, I know why! You never had any intention of prosecuting ANYONE involved. Instead the FBI was so corrupt they handed out immunity deals like candy and everyone walked. The FBI is no longer viable. They need to be gutted and rebooted. Seriously. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>411</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>662</end>
        <start>412</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>810</end>
        <start>663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>933</end>
        <start>811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>934</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1001</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1037</end>
        <start>1002</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1410</end>
        <start>1290</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1493</end>
        <start>1411</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1683</end>
        <start>1494</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1939</end>
        <start>1684</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1940</end>
        <start>1940</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1941</end>
        <start>1941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2121</end>
        <start>1942</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2563</end>
        <start>2122</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2640</end>
        <start>2564</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2641</end>
        <start>2641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>807</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1536</end>
        <start>1495</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1682</end>
        <start>1634</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2339</end>
        <start>2249</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>663</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1939</end>
        <start>1038</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>EXPOSED: Secret Between FBI And Cheryl Mills Has Been Discovered… [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/corruption/exposed-secret-fbi-cheryl-mills-discovered-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
