<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Lisa Smith</author>
    <links href="http://www.allenbwest.com/michellejesse/just-benghazi-emails-recovered">
        <end>7</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton, former, Secretary of State, has stuck to her story that she handed over all of her work-related emails. Even though, she wiped her computer with the equivalent of electronic bleach, not a simple cloth, yeah…she has absolutely nothing to hide! The best part, Hillary holds fast to her claim, even as new batches of emails are recovered. Emails, that were not included in her alleged “complete” batch, she’d originally turned over. Now, 30 emails that had been previously wiped off the face of the earth, were recovered. Unfortunately for Hillary, they were related to Benghazi, but she knew that didn’t she?  FBI investigators recovered 30 emails from Hillary Clintonâs wiped server which discussed Benghazi, government lawyers said in federal court on Tuesday. The disclosure was made during a hearing before U.S. District Court Judge Amit Mehta in a case involving a lawsuit filed by the watchdog group Judicial Watch. Government lawyers told U.S. District Court Judge Amit P. Mehta Tuesday that an undetermined number of the emails among the 30 were not included in the 55,000 pages previously provided by Clinton to State. The agency said it would need until the end of September to review the emails and redact potentially classified information before they are released. Government lawyers revealed in a court filing last week that some of the emails recovered by FBI investigators from her email server contained âsearch termsâ related to Benghazi. Clinton gave the State Department more than 30,000 of her work-related emails in Dec. 2014. Of those, the State Department released 296 emails related to Benghazi and Libya. The agency asserted that those were all of the Clinton emails it had pertaining to Benghazi. But in September, the State Department discovered another 925 Benghazi-related emails. Those were handed over to the House Select Committee on Benghazi. But it was revealed last month that Clinton deleted âseveral thousandâ work-related emails from her server. Do they really need a full day to prepare per email that was recovered? Must be some pretty good stuff in there… Hmmm</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>259</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>446</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>623</end>
        <start>447</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>624</end>
        <start>624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>779</end>
        <start>625</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>780</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1477</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1897</end>
        <start>1478</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2009</end>
        <start>1898</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2122</end>
        <start>2010</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2127</end>
        <start>2123</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>408</end>
        <start>400</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2009</end>
        <start>625</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: They Did It- Deleted Benghazi Emails RECOVERED!</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/08/31/breaking-they-did-it-deleted-benghazi-emails-recovered/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
