<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>iPatriot</author>
    <links href="http://www.iPatriot.com">
        <end>58</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3795264/Homemade-IED-injured-29-Manhattan-NO-ISIS-connection-says-Governor-Cuomo-s-early-investigation.html">
        <end>498</end>
        <start>488</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ipatriot.com/left-still-cannot-say-word-terrorism/">
        <end>1819</end>
        <start>1773</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Join the Citizen Journalist Revolution at www.iPatriot.com Terrorism is terrorism, regardless of the source, and two American cities felt the sting of it over the weekend. Is it really that hard to say? Apparently. And if someone on the left does summon up the word, it must always be supplemented with a descriptor. One of two terrorist attacks, a bombing, occurred this weekend in Manhattan, N.Y. “No-one has come forward to admit to planting the device, which exploded in a dumpster,” Cuomo said, but citizens should make no mistake: “a bomb exploding in New York is an act of terrorism.” Got that. At the time he stated (Sunday morning), that no one, or group, had claimed responsibility. Yet he was quick to insist it was not the work of ISIS, or any specific group. However, he also added that, “We’re not going to let them win. They want to make you afraid. We’re not going to let them instill fear.” Okay – so Cuomo admitted he/we don’t know who the bomber is, yet he knows for a fact it is definitely not ISIS, but we can’t let THEM win. If he/we don’t know who the bomber is – may I ask who THEM is? Knowing that even in the face of tragedy, democrats consider everything through a political lens – is the definitely “not ISIS” exclamation by Governor Cuomo a veiled attempt not to tie Obama’s mass immigration of Muslims to the U.S.? I don’t know, but I wouldn’t doubt it. The Manhattan bomber may not be the work of an Islamist, but the attack at a Minnesota mall on Saturday sure was. As I stated, regardless of the source, the two acts were terrorism none the less. It is not hard to say – terrorism, unless you’re NYC Mayor Bill de Blasio, who, like many apologists on the left, just couldn’t bring himself to utter the word. When pressed, he merely stated… Read the rest of the story at www.iPatriot.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>58</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>316</end>
        <start>59</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>591</end>
        <start>317</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>771</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>907</end>
        <start>772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1109</end>
        <start>908</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1383</end>
        <start>1110</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1579</end>
        <start>1384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1772</end>
        <start>1580</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1819</end>
        <start>1773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1820</end>
        <start>1820</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1966</end>
        <start>1821</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2040</end>
        <start>1967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>486</end>
        <start>400</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>590</end>
        <start>538</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>906</end>
        <start>802</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1018</end>
        <start>1010</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2002</end>
        <start>1990</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Terrorism: The Word Liberals are TERRIFIED Of</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36863/terrorism-the-word-liberals-are-terrified-of/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
