<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Davis</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/what-was-behind-clintons-podium/">
        <end>29</end>
        <start>4</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/hillarys-top-5-lies-of-the-debate/">
        <end>201</end>
        <start>173</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/badly-injured-iraqi-war-hero/">
        <end>505</end>
        <start>497</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.usapoliticstoday.com/breaking-the-debate-was-rigged-neil-cavuto-just-exposed-lester-holts-lies/">
        <end>578</end>
        <start>560</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/media-doc-hillary-diagnosis/">
        <end>1711</end>
        <start>1695</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The first presidential debate between Democrat nominee Hillary Clinton and Republican rival Donald Trump was fully of fiery exchanges between the two candidates, as well as several questionable moments. NBC’s Lester Holt, the moderator for the debate, started getting flak before the debate was over after he repeatedly interrupted Trump to “fact-check” him, except that his fact-checks were more or less wrong. In one of the more contentious exchanges, Holt insisted that Trump had supported the Iraq War from the beginning, but Trump continuously denied it, USA Politics Today reported. Rather than ask Clinton why she voted for the war, Holt continued to press Trump, saying that in an interview with Fox News’ Neil Cavuto, Trump expressed his support for the war. After the debate was over, Cavuto aired the interview in question and showed that Trump wasn’t all gung-ho about invading Iraq before we went in — he had his reservations. “You know, what happened to the days of Douglas MacArthur? I mean he would go in and attack. He wouldn’t talk. I mean we have to, you know, it’s sort of like either do it or don’t do it,” Trump said. “Well, he’s (Bush) either got to do something or not do something perhaps. Because perhaps he shouldn’t be doing it yet. Perhaps we should be waiting for the United Nations. You know, he’s under a lot of pressure,” said Trump, clearly unsure if invading Iraq was the right choice. You can see it here:  Instead of hammering Trump for his alleged “support” for the Iraq War, the moderator really should have asked Clinton why she voted to authorize the war when she had access to much more information than Trump did. It shouldn’t surprise anyone that the mainstream media turned what could have been a substantive debate into a chance to try to smear Trump’s name. Luckily, Trump held his own and showed that he could stand up to both Clinton and her media pals at the same time. Share this on Facebook and Twitter and let us know what you thought of the debate on Monday night. Do you think that the debate was rigged? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>202</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>411</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>588</end>
        <start>412</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>767</end>
        <start>589</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>939</end>
        <start>768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1139</end>
        <start>940</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1420</end>
        <start>1140</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1441</end>
        <start>1421</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1442</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1656</end>
        <start>1443</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1804</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1919</end>
        <start>1805</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2018</end>
        <start>1920</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2089</end>
        <start>2019</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>352</end>
        <start>342</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1126</end>
        <start>941</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1353</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>490</end>
        <start>483</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Cavuto Just Exposed Lester Holt’s Lies During Debate</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/lester-holt-lies-during-debate/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-27&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
