<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>A.F. Branco</author>
    <links href="http://comicallyincorrect.com/2016/09/24/cascade-mall-shooting/">
        <end>1046</end>
        <start>1010</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A note from our resident cartoonist A.F. Branco: Sadly, a painful and horrific nightmare was inflicted on my community last night when a supposed lone shooter (still at large) shot and killed 5 people at the Cascade Mall in Burlington, Washington last night. This is a place where my wife and I routinely shop and go to the movies. My wife’s brother and niece were in the mall when the chaos started. Another close relative was working in Macy’s along with other close relatives in the mall at the time of the shooting. They were all evacuated to safety without harm. While we are relieved and so grateful that they all made it back to their homes safely last night, our hearts are extremely heavy and go out to those who were lost last night and to their families in this senseless act of violence. Please pray for our community during this incredibly difficult time. Please also pray for our first responders and the law enforcement officers that are still trying to find this person. A.F. Branco and Family Crossposted From Comically Incorrect  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>48</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>331</end>
        <start>49</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>799</end>
        <start>332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>986</end>
        <start>800</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1009</end>
        <start>987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1046</end>
        <start>1010</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1047</end>
        <start>1047</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1193</end>
        <start>1048</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1267</end>
        <start>1194</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1229</end>
        <start>1217</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>A.F. Branco: Cascade Mall Shooting “Hits Close to Home”…Actually, it WAS Home</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37059/a-f-branco-cascade-mall-shooting-hits-close-to-home-actually-it-was-home/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
