<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8153">
        <end>1493</end>
        <start>1450</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Student groups at Ramapo College were allegedly forced to change the theme of an “American BBQ” because the administration deemed it too “offensive.” The event was to be co-hosted by the College Republicans and two residence halls, but one residence hall director reported that flyers advertising the event were deemed too “military and recruitment-oriented” because they featured Uncle Sam. Students at Ramapo College were recently forced to change the theme of an “American BBQ” because the administration deemed it too “offensive.” According to emails obtained by Campus Reform, Ariana Rivera, the Assistant Residence Director of Bischoff Hall, sent an email to the College Republicans and the College Democrats on August 17 inviting the groups to co-sponsor an American-themed BBQ with Bischoff and Mackin Halls. The proposal called for the CRs and CDs to run tables for their respective organizations at the event, as well as encouraging students to register to vote, and CR President Taylor Gilson responded almost immediately to affirm that her group would participate.  However, on September 14, just two days before the scheduled event, Rivera wrote to Gilson, again, this time regretfully explaining that Bischoff Hall would no longer be co-sponsoring with the CRs because the American theme was “considered offensive.” Rivera subsequently reported that the event would not be entirely cancelled, after all, but that it would have to be a… Read the rest of the story at Campus Reform  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>149</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>391</end>
        <start>150</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>534</end>
        <start>392</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>816</end>
        <start>535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1076</end>
        <start>817</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1077</end>
        <start>1077</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1329</end>
        <start>1078</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1449</end>
        <start>1330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1493</end>
        <start>1450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1494</end>
        <start>1494</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1640</end>
        <start>1495</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1714</end>
        <start>1641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>94</end>
        <start>82</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>148</end>
        <start>138</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>357</end>
        <start>324</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>94</end>
        <start>82</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>148</end>
        <start>138</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>1307</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1676</end>
        <start>1664</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>College Groups Deem America-Themed BBQ Too “Offensive”</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36897/college-groups-deem-america-themed-bbq-too-offensive/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
