<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/BREAKING-NEWS-Tony-Stewart-to-Return-to-Racing-This-Weekend-in-Richmond-Article-Photo.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/56505.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Tony Stewart is still fighting to remain in the Chase, and so far it doesn’t look very promising. Tony Stewart has had an interesting season to say the least. What started out not very promising thanks to a back injury has now turned into him being in the running towards a championship. Over the years Smoke has been involved in many controversial things. From being accused and admitting to wrecking people intentionally to being involved with a man being hit on the track, resulting in the end of his life. Overall, Tony has seen some pretty harsh things. And that can take a toll on a guy. However, he still manages to give back to people in the most amazing ways!  In a recent event, it looks like Smoke’s giving saved a life. According to a racing team first responder, Jay Masur, Tony Stewart’s lending of equipment saved his life. Masur has been a first responder for years. He’s seen first hand just how dangerous racing is. He’s also been in instances where Tony Stewart is the one he’s responding to. Now it looks like the roles have reversed. Masur was responding to an incident on a dirt track when he lost control of his four wheeler, causing him to fly off into the air and on the ground.  Now you may be wondering where Tony Stewart fits into all of this. A few years before this incident, Masur responded to one of Smoke’s wrecks and reportedly saved his life. That’s how Tony felt at least. So after everything was said and done, Smoke bought Masur and his team top of the line equipment. That equipment, including a helmet, is what Masur claims saved his life. “I believe I swerved to miss something and flew off the four wheeler and ended up hitting my head pretty hard. I believe this helmet probably saved my life, there’s no doubt. We all feel like, we’re bullet proof, we all feel, in the jobs we do, it can’t happen to us, because we’re pretty good at our stuff, but no matter how much we prepare, how much we plan, things happen, and at the end of the day, love your family, treat every day like it’s the last day on earth, because it may be. We saved [Tony’s] life and I truly believe he had a huge part in saving mine.” WOW! That’s amazing. Tony has yet to speak out about this incident, but we can only imagine how he feels. Our thoughts and prayers go out to Jay Masur and his family as he continues to heal from this incident!   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>97</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>287</end>
        <start>98</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>509</end>
        <start>288</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>668</end>
        <start>510</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>669</end>
        <start>669</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>838</end>
        <start>670</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1011</end>
        <start>839</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1203</end>
        <start>1012</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1204</end>
        <start>1204</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1506</end>
        <start>1205</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1579</end>
        <start>1507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2147</end>
        <start>1580</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2253</end>
        <start>2148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2358</end>
        <start>2254</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2360</end>
        <start>2359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2146</end>
        <start>1581</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2147</end>
        <start>1580</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Tony Stewart Hit With Life Threatening Situation, I Can’t Believe This Is Happening</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/celebrity-news/tony-stewart-hit-life-threatening-situation-cant-believe-happening/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Tony+Stewart%2F9%2F26&amp;utm_term=Right+Wing+News%2FTony+Stewart%2F9%2F26</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
