<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://www.fury.news/2016/08/watch-insane-moment-police-rush-child-suicide-bomber-seconds-pushing-button/">
        <end>364</end>
        <start>351</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>This is just plain sad. Muslim extremists are training children to be suicide bombers. Iraqi news station Kurdistan News 24 caught this child suicide bombers capture on film and it went viral. At 2 minutes 17 seconds into the video you can see the child’s face. It’s a haunting look of horror and defiance on his face. The Kurdish news source BasNews reported that ISIS has recently opened a child jihadi training center in Mosul called the “Cubs of the Caliphate,” where tiny children are brainwashed with ISIS ideology, taught suicide tactics, and receive instruction on combat training The barbaric Islamic State is doing anything it takes to spread their caliphate across the globe. Child suicide bombers is the new horrific trend of Muslim extremists. In the past 6 months ISIS has trained over 1,000 children to become suicide bombers. It is only the very base of humanity who has ever used children in warfare and ISIS is the lowest of them all. I want you to imagine WHAT kind of training is used to get a child to strap a bomb onto themselves then walk into a crowded place and detonate it. Let THAT sink it… religion of peace indeed. A child suicide bomber detonated a bomb in his vest at a Turkish wedding just last week. Over a hundred were maimed or killed in the incident. The young boy in the video below was caught by Iraqi police who thought he was acting suspiciously. This footage below is of the police removing the bomb from his body. Anyone who uses children in such a way is going to hell and I am surprised that the Muslim Imams aren’t saying that. This sickening culture is spreading across Europe and the United States as men roam the streets raping women and children as young as 5-yrs-old (that’s been reported) because it’s part of the culture. It is no surprise then that these same ‘men’ would use children to spread their campaign of terror and death.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>318</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>588</end>
        <start>319</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1143</end>
        <start>589</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1883</end>
        <start>1144</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1884</end>
        <start>1884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1885</end>
        <start>1885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>464</end>
        <start>442</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>588</end>
        <start>319</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>WATCH: Insane Moment Police Rush Child Suicide Bomber SECONDS From Pushing Button</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/watch-insane-moment-police-rush-child-suicide-bomber-seconds-from-pushing-button/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
