<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=7585">
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>1204</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://georgiastatesignal.com/undocumented-students-sue-usg-banning-georgias-top-universities/">
        <end>1328</end>
        <start>1318</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.uscis.gov/humanitarian/consideration-deferred-action-childhood-arrivals-daca">
        <end>1587</end>
        <start>1571</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8159">
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1594</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Two law firms are suing the University System of Georgia on behalf of three illegal immigrants who were denied admission because they are not lawfully present in the country. The suit alleges that the policy violates the Equal Protection Clause of the Constitution, arguing that their clients are covered by constitutional protections because they were granted DACA status. The Department of Homeland Security, however, denies that DACA confers lawful status, saying it only pertains to prosecutorial decisions regarding deportation. Two law firms are suing the University System of Georgia on behalf of three illegal immigrants over its policy barring persons not lawfully present in the United States from qualifying for admissions. The Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF) and Horsley Begnaud LLC are defending their clients by citing USG’s policy as a violation of the Equal Protection Clause of the Constitution. Although the guarantee of equal protection under the law only applies to lawful citizens, MALDEF’s attorneys are arguing that their clients, as individuals who have been granted Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) status, are in fact lawfully present. [RELATED: UC system pledges $25 million for illegal-immigrant scholarships]  Birth Lopez, a MALDEF attorney, told The Signal that there’s no question that his clients are lawfully present, claiming that “[DACA individuals] are among the best and brightest in the state of Georgia and have continuously demonstrated that.” However, the Department of Homeland Security explicitly notes that… Please read the rest of the story at Campus Reform  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>174</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>373</end>
        <start>175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>533</end>
        <start>374</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>734</end>
        <start>534</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>941</end>
        <start>735</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1203</end>
        <start>942</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>1204</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1525</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1593</end>
        <start>1526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1594</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1645</end>
        <start>1645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1791</end>
        <start>1646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1865</end>
        <start>1792</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1524</end>
        <start>1408</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1827</end>
        <start>1815</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>University of Georgia SUED by 3 Illegal Immigrants For Denying Them Admission</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36952/university-of-georgia-sued-by-3-illegal-immigrants-for-denying-them-admission/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
