<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.budget.senate.gov/chairman/newsroom/press/chairman-enzi-announces-senate-budget-committee-staff">
        <end>375</end>
        <start>366</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-christie-transition-228053">
        <end>1021</end>
        <start>1005</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Eric Ueland, a veteran Republican Capitol Hill aide and top staffer on the Senate Budget Committee, is advising Donald Trump's presidential transition team, according to three sources. Ueland is the Republican staff director on the Budget Committee, a position he has held since 2013, when he was hired by Sen. Jeff Sessions, then the panel's ranking member. Ueland stayed on as staff director when Sen. Mike Enzi became chairman of the committee in 2015. Story Continued Below Sessions has emerged as an influential figure in Trump's universe, with several former Sessions aides taking prominent positions in Trump's transition and campaign. Before returning to Capitol Hill in 2013, Ueland was a vice president at the Duberstein Group. He was previously a top staffer for former Sens. Don Nickles and Bill Frist. Ueland and the Trump campaign declined to comment. The Trump transition, which is being led by New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie, is rapidly expanding its pool of policy advisers, with sources telling POLITICO it is setting up a series of policy-specific teams on issues like financial services, taxes and energy. The Clinton and Trump transition must also begin preparing a budget, which would be submitted to Congress soon after the next president takes office. While it's unclear exactly what role Ueland is playing on the Trump transition, his budget expertise is seen as an asset for Trump's team.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>184</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>455</end>
        <start>185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>477</end>
        <start>456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>642</end>
        <start>478</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>814</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>865</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1125</end>
        <start>866</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1414</end>
        <start>1126</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Sources: Top GOP budget aide working on Trump transition team</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/eric-ueland-donald-trump-transition-228545?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
