<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tom Cahill</author>
    <links href="http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/freddie-gray/bs-md-ci-freddie-gray-autopsy-20150623-story.html">
        <end>474</end>
        <start>445</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/cops-charged-freddie-gray-death-hailed-right-wing-gala-article-1.2807711">
        <end>558</end>
        <start>523</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/freddie-gray/bs-md-ci-freddie-gray-autopsy-20150623-story.html">
        <end>1650</end>
        <start>1614</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Three of the Baltimore police officers previously charged in the death of Freddie Gray were recently treated like war heroes at a right-wing media gala. Deneen Borelli, a regular contributor to Fox News, gave a speech at the Media Research Center’s annual black tie gala lauding the officers Garrett Miller, Edward Nero, and Brian Rice in front of panelists like Rush Limbaugh, Monica Crowley, and Cal Thomas. 25-year-old Freddie Gray’s death — which was ruled as a homicide — was only mentioned once, as an afterthought. According to the New York Daily News, Borelli blamed the Baltimore riots not on the six officers charged in Freddie Gray’s death, but on “the left, political agitators, and the national media” who were out to “advance the anti-police narrative.” “These five men and one woman, all veteran police officers, were now in handcuffs, fighting for their lives, their careers destroyed, bankrupted, humiliated,” Borelli said. ““No one thanked them for their service or recognized their honor. Who will thank these officers? Who will thank all police officers…at a time they are being so vilified? Tonight, ladies and gentlemen, we will.” Officer Garett Miller, who remains under administrative duty pending an internal affairs investigation into Gray’s death, complained that the police officer profession was “hurting,” and asked for “prayers.” “We’re losing officers at an incredible rate. Not just from gunfire but because they’re tired of it. They quit. Our department is short. Everywhere is short. Nobody wants to be a police officer anymore,” Miller said. As the Baltimore Sun reported, Gray suffered a fatal injury to his spine after taking a blow to the lower-left side of his head while being transported in a Baltimore police van. Officers restrained Gray’s hands and ankles, and didn’t belt him in before transporting him, which is a violation of Baltimore Police Department policy. “The assisting officer opened the doors and observed Mr. Gray lying belly down on the floor with his head facing the cabin compartment, and reportedly he was asking for help, saying he couldn’t breathe, couldn’t get up, and needed a medic,” the autopsy report read. All six officers charged in Freddie Gray’s death were ultimately cleared of all charges earlier this year.          </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>152</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>521</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>767</end>
        <start>522</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1152</end>
        <start>768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1360</end>
        <start>1153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1577</end>
        <start>1361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1909</end>
        <start>1578</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2175</end>
        <start>1910</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2282</end>
        <start>2176</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2284</end>
        <start>2283</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2285</end>
        <start>2285</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2287</end>
        <start>2286</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2288</end>
        <start>2288</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2289</end>
        <start>2289</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2290</end>
        <start>2290</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2291</end>
        <start>2291</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2292</end>
        <start>2292</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>713</end>
        <start>660</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>766</end>
        <start>732</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>925</end>
        <start>769</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1151</end>
        <start>942</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1334</end>
        <start>1326</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1359</end>
        <start>1351</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1563</end>
        <start>1362</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2149</end>
        <start>1911</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Cops Who Killed Freddie Gray Honored and Praised as Heroes at Conservative Gala</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/cops-killed-freddie-gray-honored-praised-heroes-conservative-gala/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
