<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.adweek.com/news/television/presidential-debates-could-bring-largest-audience-ever-173640">
        <end>1845</end>
        <start>1824</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.adweek.com/news/television/presidential-debates-could-bring-largest-audience-ever-173640">
        <end>3858</end>
        <start>3852</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bev4NZEFsCQ&amp;feature=youtu.be">
        <end>181</end>
        <start>179</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://variety.com/2016/tv/news/cnn-clinton-trump-debate-epix-tv-advertising-1201870081/">
        <end>4267</end>
        <start>4236</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thewrap.com/cnn-record-profits-2017-time-warner-howard-averill-turner/">
        <end>6634</end>
        <start>6625</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The preliminary numbers are in, and they suggest that the first presidential debate of 2016 between Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump will be the most watched debate going back decades. With the first presidential debate of 2012 averaging 70 million viewers, last night is looking like a massive night for TV news. The numbers from all the channels will be made available by Nielsen over the course of the day. All told, the early numbers continue to show that 2016 just seems to keep getting better for TV news channels. And with the presidential campaign nearing its final stretch, the first forecasts are coming in for just how good the Trumped-up 2016 presidential campaign has been to them. With the 2016 election’s pivotal events delivering record ratings moments every few months (highest rated primary debate, highest rated primary election night coverage, etc), CNN and Fox News are poised to have the most-watched years in their respective histories, stretching back to 1980 for CNN and 1996 for Fox News. MSNBC has a chance to do so as well. Many networks reported that they’d “sold out” their first debate night early, and are expecting the same for the next three. Story Continued Below And that means money. According to data from media and communications data firm SNL Kagan, a division of SMP Global Market Intelligence, the three major cable news networks are set to make nearly $2 billion in ad revenues, and the three main business networks are set to add another $458 million in ad revenue from just the 2016 calendar year. “We’ve been outselling our election packages for a year now,” said Katrina Cukaj, EVP of Portfolio Sales &amp; Client Partnerships for Turner Ad Sales, which includes CNN. “We are close to selling out for the rest of the [election related] days; there is very high demand. Very high.” Fox News is expecting a “multimillion dollar revenue night” when all the money is counted. According to the Wall Street Journal, CNN is selling debate and election night ad packages with minimums of $800,000 to $1 million, with 30 second ads for the presidential debates going for more than $55,000. Other cable news channels are selling similar bundled ad packages. And those kinds of numbers take into account that there are no ad interruptions during the debate – all those ads are sold against pre- and post-game analysis and panels. “There is considerably higher demand in this election cycle with higher price points compared to the other election cycles,” an NBC source said. According to SNL Kagan, CNN, Fox News and MSNBC will combine for approximately $1.96 billion in gross ad sales in 2016. Compare that to $1.72 million in calendar year 2015 (which saw a number of high-profile primary debates), and $1.56 million in calendar year 2012, the last presidential election year. The ad revenue makes sense when you look at the numbers. The first Republican debate in August of 2015 brought in a record-breaking 24 million viewers for Fox News. Fox News’ March debate in Detroit, Michigan averaged just under 17 million viewers. Through March and April, big primary nights would draw an average of 10-12 million viewers across cable news and on 10 p.m. broadcast specials. Those sorts of ratings are typically reserved for major sporting events like NFL games, or huge hit shows like NCIS. This election cycle has been delivering them with regularity, even if they are spread out across a number of channels. The election is also broadening the types of advertisers who are hoping to catch the eyeballs of the big election audiences. Cukaj said she’s seen an uptick in entertainment and movie advertisements. “Movie studios and entertainment has been very, very active in these big election events, they enjoy the nice big ratings these live events do,” Cukaj said. Fox News EVP of advertising sales Paul Rittenberg told AdWeek “there's substantially more demand from [advertisers] who didn't used to buy a lot of news; we even have a beer [company].” That company is Tecate, which was running a debate-specific ad about a “wall” on Fox News, Univision and Telemundo during the pre and post-debate shows. (In fact, the wall never came up in the debate.) Among the entertainment advertisers is Epix, which aired a faux-cable news segment before last night’s debate, featuring cable news regulars Michael Steele, Amy Holmes and Barney Frank. CNN had to run a gold banner over the “segment” to ensure viewers knew it was not CNN content. For the broadcast networks, the 2016 campaign has largely been a boon, even if election-related programming has occasionally competed with or preempted more lucrative entertainment and sports programming (at $200,000 per 30 second spot, the debate programming would be very similar to what standard entertainment fare would bring in). Still, this broadcast season, news programming has been one of the few bright spots, with most entertainment and sports programming seeing ratings declines compared to last year. The broadcast networks CBS and NBC are selling 30 second ads for more than $200,000 each, according to the Journal. Advertising rates for the presidential debates may not be as high as some primary debates were, as they do not have commercial breaks, so all ads run before and after the debate when the channels are doing pre- and post-debate analysis (in case you were wondering why there is so much of it, the answer is: inventory!) For the networks, that eats into valuable prime-time real estate, where entertainment programming can command higher premiums. There’s another reason debates like the one last night aren’t quite as valuable as they could be: Scarcity, or lack thereof. With the debate airing on more than 10 TV channels, and streaming on hundreds of websites, the audience will be massive, but highly fragmented. In fact, despite the massive 2016 haul, the picture for television news continues to be bleak. For one thing, news networks these days are making less than half their money from advertising, so "big years" don't have nearly the lasting effect they might otherwise. Where does the rest of their revenue come from? For big networks like CNN, a lot of it comes from “carriage fees” – the lucrative contracts the big news networks sign with cable providers like Comcast, Time Warner Cable and Charter Communications in return for allowing their channel to appear on the carriers’ channel line-ups. These deals – which can be contentious and result in channel blackouts with individual providers but usually, ultimately go the TV networks' way – are often negotiated in multi-year terms. Time Warner CFO Howard Averill said that next year, 2017, will deliver record profits for CNN, beating 2016 despite this year’s election boost. Previously negotiated carriage fee increases guarantee that result, even if the channel sees a steep ratings decline. And that’s just one place where the connection between audience size and revenue is deteriorating. In fact, while 2016 may top the revenue charts, the three big cable news networks have actually been on the rebound since 2013, with all three increasing ad revenue every year since then. These good signs are generally taken with a grain of salt behind the closed doors of the TV businesses’ executive suites. The chief worries: Television audiences are aging out of the TV news ecosystem, and not being replaced by younger viewers coveted by advertisers. Over time, this will also depress audience numbers, as those aging viewers are replaced by fewer young viewers growing into engagement with TV news. And indeed, not everyone has shared in the big bounty of 2016. Local ad revenue, which relies heavily on political spending, has not been as strong as anticipated. SNL Kagan downgraded their projected income of $3.3 billion for local television down to $3.1 billion partly as a result of Trump not spending as much on advertising. Sinclair Broadcasting, the country’s largest owner of TV stations, warned investors last week that 2016 political ad spending was falling short of expectations. Ironically, the presence of Donald Trump in the 2016 campaign, often discussed as if it were the reason this election is such a television draw, is a factor in that slump. “While we previously anticipated a decline in presidential ad spending in the third quarter based on the late fund-raising by the Trump campaign, we have yet to see significant spending, even at the levels we initially anticipated,” Sinclair CFO Chris Ripley said at a conference hosted by Goldman Sachs. CBS CEO Les Moonves told attendees at the same conference that his local station revenue was on track, but much of that was coming in from local and statewide races and issue campaigns. As far as the presidential campaign, there was one big reason Moonves pointed to to describe the unexpected slump: “To generalize, [there is not as much spending from] the top of the tickets, because Mr. Trump does not appear to be spending as much as people thought.” — Additional reporting by Kelsey Sutton</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>694</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1176</end>
        <start>695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1198</end>
        <start>1177</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1542</end>
        <start>1199</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1823</end>
        <start>1543</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2361</end>
        <start>1824</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2506</end>
        <start>2362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2810</end>
        <start>2507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3439</end>
        <start>2811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3639</end>
        <start>3440</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3796</end>
        <start>3640</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3982</end>
        <start>3797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4184</end>
        <start>3983</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4465</end>
        <start>4185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4979</end>
        <start>4466</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5541</end>
        <start>4980</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5810</end>
        <start>5542</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6075</end>
        <start>5811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6855</end>
        <start>6076</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7142</end>
        <start>6856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7559</end>
        <start>7143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7622</end>
        <start>7560</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8051</end>
        <start>7623</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8223</end>
        <start>8052</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8528</end>
        <start>8224</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8983</end>
        <start>8529</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9023</end>
        <start>8984</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1096</end>
        <start>1088</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1603</end>
        <start>1544</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1822</end>
        <start>1712</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1882</end>
        <start>1849</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2485</end>
        <start>2363</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3783</end>
        <start>3641</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3981</end>
        <start>3860</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4059</end>
        <start>4055</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4267</end>
        <start>4260</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6188</end>
        <start>6175</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8455</end>
        <start>8225</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8982</end>
        <start>8831</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Cable news’ election-year haul could reach $2.5 billion</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/media/story/2016/09/media-tv-numbers-004783?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
