<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/unassuming-hero-minnesota-mall-attack-speaks/story?id=42216363">
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>1110</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It’s been said that the only thing that stops a bad guy with a gun is a good guy with a gun, but in the case of the Minnesota mall attacker, to quote another cliche, he brought a knife to a gun fight. Last Saturday set the bar for the poorest execution of a terrorist attack to date. Five explosives were planted around the tri-State area, killing nobody. One bomb was supposed to detonate during a 5k race for veterans – but detonated before the race even began. Another explosive went off in NYC that night, but despite injuries, nobody was killed.  Also occurring on Saturday was a machete attack in a mall in Minnesota. Nine were injured during the attacks, where the attacker was shouting “Allah Akbar” during (but the media still thought there was a debate over the motives for the attack). Eventually he was shot numerous times and killed. The man who killed him was an off-duty police officer, an instructor of a concealed carry class, and a competitive shooter. In other words, a good guy with a gun that even Allah couldn’t save him from. For the first time since the incident, he’s speaking out. As ABC News reported: The off-duty police officer who shot and killed the knife-wielding Minnesota mall attacker said he is staying out of the spotlight until the investigation is over but is grateful for all the messages of support he has received. Jason Falconer, who has been hailed a hero by many Americans, including the president, went right back to work after bravely intervening in Saturday’s stabbing attack at the Crossroads Center mall in St. Cloud, Minnesota, according to local ABC News affiliate KSTP-TV. Dahir Ahmed Adan, 20, began stabbing people at the shopping center; 10 suffered injuries. None of the injuries are life-threatening, authorities said. Falconer shot Adan dead, and authorities believe his quick action saved lives. Falconer spoke to KSTP-TV at Tactical Advantage, a firearms shop where he is an employee. He said he was at the mall on Saturday “buying his son’s birthday present,” which he was able to take home, despite the horrific scene that unfolded. Falconer said he shot at Adan “to stop the threat.” Countless others were spared from being hacked, potentially to death, thanks to Falconer’s actions. Japanese Marshal Admiral and the commander-in-chief of the Combined Fleet during World War II Isoroku Yamamoto once famously stated that you can’t invade mainland America, “because there would be a rifle behind every blade of glass.” Unlike our neighbors across the sea in Europe, we’re armed to the teeth, and any Jihadi who tries to wreck havok is in for one hell of a surprise. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>200</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>550</end>
        <start>201</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>551</end>
        <start>551</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1128</end>
        <start>847</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1356</end>
        <start>1129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1625</end>
        <start>1357</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1626</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1945</end>
        <start>1856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2095</end>
        <start>1946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2147</end>
        <start>2096</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2481</end>
        <start>2148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2628</end>
        <start>2482</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2629</end>
        <start>2629</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>706</end>
        <start>695</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2020</end>
        <start>1986</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2146</end>
        <start>2127</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2480</end>
        <start>2421</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1403</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Unassuming Hero In The Minnesota Mall Attack Speaks Out – WATCH</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/unassuming-hero-minnesota-mall-attack-speaks-watch/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
