<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/699472-nc-state-troopers-take-a-knee-in-charlotte-to-pray-before-putting-themselves-into-the-chaos/">
        <end>141</end>
        <start>100</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Prayer-e1474652368217.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/697913-witnesses-confirm-charlotte-police-chiefs-claim-keith-lamont-scott-was-armed-with-gun-not-book/">
        <end>1050</end>
        <start>1032</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Prayer1.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/125573547461727/photos/a.272893276063086.70980.125573547461727/1301912386494498/?type=3&amp;theater">
        <end>380</end>
        <start>360</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Prayer2.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Prayer3.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Prayer4.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Prayer5.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As idiots like Colin Kaepernick took a knee to protest prejudice against blacks by police officers, cops in Charlotte, NC took a knee to pray before going to confront protesters. That says a lot and shows a huge difference. One is self-centered and obsessed over perceived slights, the other focuses on faith and God. A picture was taken by the North Carolina Troopers Association of these officers praying. It went viral almost immediately and with good reason. This is who we are. Radicals were bused into Charlotte to create havoc and violent chaos. They were also bused into Tulsa yesterday. We were fortunate here in that prayer prevailed and the protests were mostly peaceful. Charlotte was not so fortunate. I saw good people stand between the protesters and police trying to stop the radicals. I saw them kneel in the street praying that it would stop. Faith in God is colorblind… racism and violence are not of God.  From the Independent Review Journal: But after an officer-involved shooting in Charlotte left 43-year-old Keith Lamont Scottdead, another photo of people “taking a knee” began to circulate on social media. These people weren’t on their knees in protest, however. They were on their knees in prayer.  The photo, originally posted by the North Carolina Troopers Association, was shared nearly 100,000 times in less than 24 hours and included the following caption: “North Carolina State Troopers having a word of fellowship and prayer before being deployed on the streets of Charlotte. Please keep them in your thoughts and prayers as they work to protect us and help the city rebuild.” And the troopers weren’t alone. There were a number of people who took a knee in the streets, filling the gap between protesters and police:  People in Memphis knelt and bowed their heads as well. There were prayers said across the country and you know what? Race didn’t matter. There are a few people making this ugly and rioting in the streets. They are for the most part useful idiots egged on and controlled by Marxists whether they know it or not. I was heartened to see the Rapid Response Team from Billy Graham’s ministry there… they are good people of faith and are greatly needed in Charlotte right now. We need to turn away from this hate and division and turn towards God. He is the only one who will lead us out of this. I’m so very proud of these police officers… they have their priorities straight. Black Lives Matter is not a good group… they prefer violence and hatred, as opposed to prayer and faith.    </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>482</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>924</end>
        <start>483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>925</end>
        <start>925</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>962</end>
        <start>926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1131</end>
        <start>963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1224</end>
        <start>1132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1225</end>
        <start>1225</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1388</end>
        <start>1226</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1610</end>
        <start>1389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1751</end>
        <start>1643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1752</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2063</end>
        <start>1753</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2529</end>
        <start>2064</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2530</end>
        <start>2530</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2531</end>
        <start>2531</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2532</end>
        <start>2532</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2533</end>
        <start>2533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1094</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1609</end>
        <start>1390</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>786</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>NC State Troopers Take A Knee Before Protecting Charlotte – But It Wasn’t To Protest The National Anthem…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/black-lives-matter/nc-state-troopers-take-knee-protecting-charlotte-wasnt-protest-national-anthem/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
