<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="http://projectveritas.com/2016/09/19/hidden-cam-university-of-houston-facilitates-emotional-first-aid-kits-for-students/">
        <end>787</end>
        <start>762</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8168">
        <end>1858</end>
        <start>1784</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>A University of Houston professor agreed to distribute “emotional first-aid kits” to students, apparently not realizing it was a satirical ploy by James O’Keefe. The emotional first-aid kits contain a baby blanket, chocolates, a plush kitten, a bag containing the smell of lavender, ear plugs, a genderless pastel teddy bear, hand written notes, and a pacifier. Prof. Schindler did, however, express reservations about the pacifiers, which she feared might be taken the wrong way, and suggested advising students to suck their thumbs instead. An assistant professor at the University of Houston recently agreed to distribute “emotional first-aid kits” to students, apparently not realizing it was a satirical ploy by James O’Keefe. O’Keefe, who is undercover in the Project Veritas video, claims he is a member of the “99.9 percent,” a group created for students who are “emotionally disturbed by opinions which differ from their own.” His correspondent, Philosophy department advisor Bobbie Sue Schindler, agreed without hesitation to the idea of “emotional first-aid kits,” even offering her assistance to help assemble them. “The stress of school gets to them,” Schindler observed to O’Keefe regarding the emotional distress that students face, “like a bad grade, a missed class, being late, a microaggression, uh whatever…” To help students deal with such burdens, the emotional first-aid kits contain a baby blanket, chocolates, a plush kitten, a bag containing the smell of lavender, ear plugs, a genderless pastel teddy bear, hand written notes, and a pacifier. Only the pacifier gave Schindler any pause, though only out of concern that students might take them the wrong way. Instead, she suggested that the kit just contain a note encouraging students to suck their thumbs… Read the rest of the story and watch the hidden cam VIDEO at Campus Reform  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>161</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>542</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>731</end>
        <start>543</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>732</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1327</end>
        <start>1128</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1568</end>
        <start>1328</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1783</end>
        <start>1569</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1858</end>
        <start>1784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1859</end>
        <start>1859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2005</end>
        <start>1860</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2079</end>
        <start>2006</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>80</end>
        <start>56</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>80</end>
        <start>56</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>832</end>
        <start>819</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>934</end>
        <start>872</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1074</end>
        <start>1049</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1163</end>
        <start>1129</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1326</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2041</end>
        <start>2029</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hidden Cam: University Professor Agrees to Hand Out “Emotional First-Aid Kits”</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37011/hidden-cam-university-professor-agrees-to-hand-out-emotional-first-aid-kits/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
