<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://deadline.com/2016/09/lester-holt-steve-burke-nbc-universal-hillary-clinton-donald-trump-1201826728/">
        <end>347</end>
        <start>338</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/lester-holt-debate-clinton-trump-228751">
        <end>963</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-reacts-to-first-debate-performance-228766">
        <end>271</end>
        <start>267</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Steve Burke, the CEO of NBCUniversal, praised NBC Nightly News anchor Lester Holt for his performance moderating Monday night’s presidential debate between Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump. Speaking at the Royal Television Society Conference in London Tuesday, Burke said that Holt “ended up doing a very good job” moderating the debate, according to Deadline. “The environment is so tough right now for anybody moderating anything to try and make sure that it’s a fair debate,” Burke said, adding that he and other NBCU brass were “very worried and concerned for Lester” before the debate began. Burke also estimated that the contentious debate may have been watched by 100 million viewers in the U.S., according to Comcast set-top box data that showed about 35% if U.S. households tuning in. Holt received mixed reactions for moderating the debate between Clinton and Trump, during which he mostly let the candidates hash out the issues without his interference. Trump initially praised Holt for his performance, but by Tuesday morning, he and his surrogates said that Holt unfairly asked Trump “hostile questions” and was not critical enough of Clinton.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>189</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>360</end>
        <start>190</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>596</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>793</end>
        <start>597</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>964</end>
        <start>794</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1156</end>
        <start>965</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>313</end>
        <start>283</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>477</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>570</end>
        <start>533</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1115</end>
        <start>1098</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>NBCU CEO: Lester Holt ‘ended up doing a very good job’ at debate</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/on-media/2016/09/nbcu-chief-lester-holt-ended-up-doing-a-very-good-job-at-debate-228776?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
