<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>V Saxena</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/obama-devoid-of-character/">
        <end>235</end>
        <start>214</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://hamptonroads.com/2015/09/chesapeake-school-board-chiefs-facebook-post-sparks-concern-muslim-groups">
        <end>473</end>
        <start>454</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://wavy.com/2015/09/16/facebook-photo-shared-by-chesapeake-official-sparks-hurt/">
        <end>580</end>
        <start>573</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://static.conservativetribune.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Christie-New-Craig-Facebook-Post.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://madworldnews.com/school-board-muslims-question/">
        <end>2034</end>
        <start>2020</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>When Chesapeake School Board Chairwoman Christie New Craig shared a provocative political cartoon to her personal Facebook page last month, Muslims in her state of Virginia immediately used it as an opportunity to complain about racism, discrimination and Islamophobia. “Muslims hate pork, beer, dogs, bikinis, Jesus, and freedom of speech,” the cartoon read. “My question is, what the hell do they come to America for?!” When questioned by reporters at The Virginian-Pilot, Craig maintained that she did not share the cartoon “maliciously.” “I merely shared it,” she told WAVY-TV. “I did not make a comment, and I’m just shocked with everything going on in our country — police officers are losing their lives, people are homeless and people don’t have jobs — that a political cartoon would cause this much stir.” And yet it created so much controversy that the Council on American-Islamic Relations accused Craig of propagating “anti-Muslim bigotry” and demanded that school board members investigate her post. “Only by addressing this issue can the board uphold its stated commitment ‘to the principle of equal opportunity for all and does not permit discrimination or harassment on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, age, disability, military or veteran status, genetic information, or any other characteristic protected by applicable law,'” the council wrote.  Furthermore, M’hammed Abdous, president of the Muslim Community of Tidewater, questioned the accuracy of the cartoon and asked Craig to apologize for sharing it. Craig did eventually apologize, though she made it abundantly clear that this was the furthest she was willing to go — that she would not resign. Craig clearly never once discriminated against anyone. She simply shared a political cartoon or meme on her private Facebook account. Judging by the way local Muslims responded to her innocuous post, however, it is clear that the cartoon was 100 percent right about one thing: Muslims really do hate freedom of speech. H/T Mad World News Do you find it ironic that the Muslims complaining about this cartoon are inadvertently proving that the cartoon is right? Please share this post on Facebook or Twitter and let us know what you think! What do you think? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>269</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>421</end>
        <start>270</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>541</end>
        <start>422</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>814</end>
        <start>542</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1012</end>
        <start>815</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1387</end>
        <start>1013</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1388</end>
        <start>1388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1550</end>
        <start>1389</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1696</end>
        <start>1551</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1830</end>
        <start>1697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2015</end>
        <start>1831</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2034</end>
        <start>2016</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2235</end>
        <start>2035</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2284</end>
        <start>2236</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>340</end>
        <start>271</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>420</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>540</end>
        <start>528</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>562</end>
        <start>543</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>583</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>950</end>
        <start>931</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1367</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Member of School Board Asks Muslims 1 Question… Immediately All Hell Breaks Loose</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/member-asks-muslims-question/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-18&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
