<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/696094-fbi-releases-wanted-poster-for-28-year-old-ahmad-khan-rahami-in-connection-with-chelsea-bombing/">
        <end>25</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/19/fbi-launches-raid-at-nj-apartment-where-man-linked-to-bombings-lived.html">
        <end>721</end>
        <start>695</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/FBI-e1474292808157.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/FBI1.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/FBI2.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/19/number-individuals-in-custody-after-authorities-stop-vehicle-interest-in-chelsea-bombing.html">
        <end>1704</end>
        <start>1675</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The FBI has just released their snazzy new Wanted Poster for the terrorist who is behind the Chelsea bombing in Manhattan. He is a natural born Afghani and considered armed and extremely dangerous. Ahmad Khan Rahami is 28 years-old and they have his face everywhere now. It has been reported that he has left notes and made calls that indicate there will be more bombings. I’m sure they are looking into his connections with the five bombs found in New Jersey this morning – one of which exploded when a robot approached it. I heard yesterday that they believe the same individual who made the bombs in Manhattan also did the ones in New Jersey. The apartment where this man lived in New Jersey has been raided by the FBI. Undercover agents and members of the FBI’s Joint Terrorism Task Force were taking part in the raid above a chicken restaurant. The home was roughly one mile from the site where investigators found the five suspicious devices in a backpack, one of which exploded, outside a train station.  From the Independent Journal Review: Law enforcement released the name and photo Monday of 28-year-old Ahmad Khan Rahami, who is “being sought in connection” with this weekend’s New York City bombing, according to NYPD Spokesman Peter Donald:  The attack injured 29 people in New York City, although fortunately all of those wounded have already been released from hospitals.According to ABC News: Ahmad Khan Rahami, DOB 1/23/88, is wanted by the FBI in connection with at least one NYC-area bombing, the FBI says. The address of a home being searched by FBI agents in Elizabeth, New Jersey is linked to a person with a similar name. The wanted poster is below:  Federal authorities conducted a traffic stop of a “vehicle of interest” in the Chelsea bombing Sunday night in Brooklyn. A law enforcement source told Fox News that a “number of individuals” who are possibly connected to the explosion were taken into custody. It’s laughable that de Blasio and others are now calling it terrorism, but say there is no connection to international terrorists. These guys are liars and deeply stupid. Rahami is the man captured on surveillance footage planting the bombs. There is other physical evidence linking Rahami to the devices that have gone off or been found in New York and New Jersey. The pipe bombs were filled with shrapnel and were meant to create many casualties. We are very lucky no one has died yet. There is now a search on for this guy nationwide and the clock is ticking. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>645</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1010</end>
        <start>646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1011</end>
        <start>1011</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>1012</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1254</end>
        <start>1049</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1255</end>
        <start>1255</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1409</end>
        <start>1256</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1645</end>
        <start>1410</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1673</end>
        <start>1646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1674</end>
        <start>1674</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1934</end>
        <start>1675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2105</end>
        <start>1935</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2497</end>
        <start>2106</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2498</end>
        <start>2498</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1168</end>
        <start>1142</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1745</end>
        <start>1726</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1864</end>
        <start>1843</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>622</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: FBI Releases Wanted Poster For Terrorist Of Chelsea Bombing!</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/terrorism/breaking-fbi-releases-wanted-poster-terrorist-chelsea-bombing/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
