<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://thefederalistpapers.org/us/female-muslim-american-olympian-bashes-u-s-a-claims-she-feels-unsafe">
        <end>427</end>
        <start>405</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Well tell us how you really feel. Normally when a Muslim bashes the USA, you wouldn’t think that they’re an American themselves. Such wasn’t the case when it came to American Olympian fencer Ibtihaj Muhammad,who became the first American to compete in an Olympic games wearing a Hijab. As it turns out, she has some nasty things to say about the country she’s representing. According to her, as quoted by The Federalist Papers: [I feel unsafe] all the time. I had someone follow me home from practice and try to report me to police. And this is right on 28th and 7th in New York City… I want people to know that as hard as [these racist incidents] are on me, they don’t come even close to things we’ve seen like the shooting in North Carolina or the rhetoric around the Khan family at the DNC. It’s ridiculous and we as a country have to change and I feel like this is our moment.” How terrible – but let’s not pretend that we live in an “Islamophobic” country when the number of hate crimes against Jews is a multiple of those against Muslims.  If she thinks America is so terrible, why doesn’t she move to a Muslim country? I think we all know the answer – because no where else in the world do Muslims have it as good as they do in America. She’s not going to be stoned to death in America. She’s not going to have her genitals mutilated in America. She’s not going to be prevented from drinking alcohol in America. She’s not going to have her hand cut off if she were caught stealing in America. When that’s what she faces if she were to live in a Muslim country, I think she can deal with a single incident of racial profiling. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>33</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>285</end>
        <start>34</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>373</end>
        <start>286</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>427</end>
        <start>374</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>584</end>
        <start>428</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>793</end>
        <start>585</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>881</end>
        <start>794</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1044</end>
        <start>882</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1045</end>
        <start>1045</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1243</end>
        <start>1046</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1499</end>
        <start>1244</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1500</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1633</end>
        <start>1633</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>951</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>838</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Female Muslim-American Olympian Bashes U.S.A. —Goes Off The Hinges About Why America Sucks!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/female-muslim-american-olympian-bashes-u-s-a-goes-off-the-hinges-about-why-america-sucks/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
