<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Colin Taylor</author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/2016-presidential-debate-fact-check/2016/09/trump-is-wrong-stop-and-frisk-was-ruled-unconstitutional-228729">
        <end>364</end>
        <start>348</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/JPeterDonald">
        <end>742</end>
        <start>727</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Donald Trump, the supposed “law and order” candidate, painted a very bleak picture of what life in the “inner cities” was like. “We have a situation where we have inner cities, African-Americans, Hispanics are living in hell because it’s so dangerous” said the Republican nominee a few hours earlier. He cited former New York Mayor Rudy Giuliani’s unconstitutional and discriminatory “stop-and-frisk” policy as a solution for crime in urban centers. But his account didn’t match up with the facts, and he was called out by the police department in his own city for his blatant falsehoods and the implication that the NYPD isn’t good at their jobs. The Assistant Commissioner for Communication &amp; Public Information of the NYPD, J. Peter Donald, fact-checked Trump during the debate, and has this to say about the racist Republican’s proposals to reinstate stop-and-frisk after it was ended by Mayor Bloomberg in 2011:   Trump is trying to position himself as “tough on crime” but the reality is his proposals are nothing but dog-whistles for his racist white supremacist followers. Not only was “stop-and-frisk” ineffective, it was very obviously discriminatory against minorities – and after it was ended, crime drastically decreased thanks to new reforms in policing techniques. Trump is trying to sell the American people an apocalyptic vision of America that just doesn’t exist – and the policemen whose support he’s courting aren’t buying it either.  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>449</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>916</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>917</end>
        <start>917</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>918</end>
        <start>918</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1453</end>
        <start>919</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1454</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Occupy Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>41</end>
        <start>28</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>116</end>
        <start>104</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>250</end>
        <start>129</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>399</end>
        <start>385</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>973</end>
        <start>959</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>399</end>
        <start>385</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Furious NYPD Defiantly Live Fact-Checked Trump’s “Stop-and-Frisk” Lies At Debate</title>
    <uri>http://occupydemocrats.com/2016/09/27/nypd-defiantly-live-fact-checked-trumps-stop-frisk-lies-debate/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
