<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Oliver Carroll</author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/chris-spillane/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>25</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/sarah-wheaton/">
        <end>152</end>
        <start>139</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/chris-spillane/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>25</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/chris-spillane/">
        <end>39</end>
        <start>25</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/benjamin-oreskes/">
        <end>505</end>
        <start>489</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/michael-crowley/">
        <end>634</end>
        <start>619</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nahal-toosi/">
        <end>650</end>
        <start>639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/michael-kruse/">
        <end>790</end>
        <start>777</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/ryan-heath/">
        <end>954</end>
        <start>944</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/tara-palmeri/">
        <end>968</end>
        <start>956</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/harry-cooper/">
        <end>982</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/quentin-aries/">
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>987</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/harry-cooper/">
        <end>982</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/tom-mctague/">
        <end>1164</end>
        <start>1153</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/ivo-oliveira/">
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1407</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/elana-schor/">
        <end>1621</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/kyle-cheney/">
        <end>1634</end>
        <start>1623</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/louis-nelson/">
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nicholas-vinocur/">
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/florian-eder/">
        <end>2012</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/janosch-delcker/">
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>2017</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/anthony-skinner/">
        <end>2237</end>
        <start>2222</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/charlie-cooper/">
        <end>2344</end>
        <start>2330</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/barbara-surk/">
        <end>2690</end>
        <start>2678</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/madeline-conway/">
        <end>3324</end>
        <start>3309</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cristiano-lima/">
        <end>3499</end>
        <start>3485</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/bryan-bender/">
        <end>3623</end>
        <start>3611</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nicholas-vinocur/">
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1752</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/tim-king/">
        <end>3992</end>
        <start>3984</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/nahal-toosi/">
        <end>650</end>
        <start>639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/shane-goldmacher/">
        <end>4240</end>
        <start>4224</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/andrew-restuccia/">
        <end>4261</end>
        <start>4245</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/jacopo-barigazzi/">
        <end>4418</end>
        <start>4402</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/edward-isaac-dovere/">
        <end>4537</end>
        <start>4518</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/janosch-delcker/">
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>2017</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/konstantin-richter/">
        <end>4966</end>
        <start>4948</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/paul-dallison/">
        <end>5076</end>
        <start>5063</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/brent-griffiths/">
        <end>5206</end>
        <start>5191</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/maia-de-la-baume/">
        <end>5249</end>
        <start>5233</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/louis-nelson/">
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1639</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/carter-stoddard/">
        <end>5551</end>
        <start>5536</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/laurens-cerulus/">
        <end>5679</end>
        <start>5664</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/hortense-goulard/">
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1273</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/paul-dallison/">
        <end>5076</end>
        <start>5063</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/cynthia-kroet/">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1487</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/esther-king/">
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2786</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/oliver-carroll/">
        <end>6660</end>
        <start>6646</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/why-putin-prefers-trump-democratic-national-committee-russia-us-elections/">
        <end>3236</end>
        <start>3222</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/russian-opposition-fights-for-survival-in-duma-vote-dmitry-gudkov-vladimir-putin-dmitri-medvedev/">
        <end>6900</end>
        <start>6866</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/russian-opposition-fights-for-survival-in-duma-vote-dmitry-gudkov-vladimir-putin-dmitri-medvedev/">
        <end>9276</end>
        <start>9260</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/oliver-carroll/">
        <end>6660</end>
        <start>6646</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/trump-in-hot-water-over-putin-embrace/">
        <end>9276</end>
        <start>9260</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/kristen-east/">
        <end>9321</end>
        <start>9309</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/vladimir-putin-to-skip-united-nations-general-assembly-sergey-lavrov-new-york/">
        <end>9276</end>
        <start>9260</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/author/vince-chadwick/">
        <end>9353</end>
        <start>9339</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/russian-opposition-fights-for-survival-in-duma-vote-dmitry-gudkov-vladimir-putin-dmitri-medvedev/">
        <end>9493</end>
        <start>9480</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.fontanka.ru/">
        <end>10624</end>
        <start>10616</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.eu/article/vladimir-putin-switches-chief-of-staff-sergei-ivanov-kremlin/">
        <end>11146</end>
        <start>11100</start>
    </links>
    <links>
        <end>11901</end>
        <start>11888</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>11/19/16, 3:14 PM CET BY Chris Spillane So is anti-establishment message of Nigel Farage, the Labour leader said. 11/19/16, 1:55 PM CET BY Sarah Wheaton Alumni of the Obama White House spent days mourning Trump’s win. Now they’re ready to fight. 11/19/16, 11:37 AM CET BY Chris Spillane Dick Schoof: ‘Chance of attack in the Netherlands is real.’ 11/19/16, 10:38 AM CET BY Chris Spillane Government could focus on starting the process of leaving the bloc sooner. 11/19/16, 10:13 AM CET BY Benjamin Oreskes Diplomats say the president-elect already has a playbook to undermine the global body. 11/19/16, 10:01 AM CET BY Michael Crowley and Nahal Toosi Flynn, Bannon represent ‘Islamophobic’ thinking of the type rejected by Bush and Obama, critics say. 11/19/16, 5:25 AM CET BY Michael Kruse The blue-collar workers who put Donald Trump in the White House are ready for him to deliver. How much time will they give him? 11/19/16, 5:20 AM CET BY Ryan Heath, Tara Palmeri, Harry Cooper and Quentin Ariès  11/18/16, 9:09 PM CET BY Harry Cooper A Polish political party’s links to a pan-European group raise questions about funding. 11/18/16, 6:31 PM CET BY Tom McTague Signs that Britain’s political class is coming to terms with June’s EU referendum. 11/18/16, 6:26 PM CET BY Hortense Goulard Conservative MEP denounced Juncker’s efforts to drum up support for Schulz as ‘outrageous.’ 11/18/16, 5:31 PM CET BY Ivo Oliveira Drawing the top stories around the globe. 11/18/16, 4:55 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Italians are likely to reject prime minister’s reform package in next month’s vote. 11/18/16, 4:48 PM CET BY Elana Schor, Kyle Cheney and Louis Nelson The president-elect starts building out his administration with loyalists. 11/18/16, 4:01 PM CET BY Nicholas Vinocur Left-wingers hope that by backing Alain Juppé, they will see off two political enemies. 11/18/16, 3:15 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Jens Stoltenberg did not mention the total number or reasons for the requests. 11/18/16, 3:02 PM CET BY Florian Eder and Janosch Delcker Wird Martin Schulz die SPD in den Bundestagswahlkampf führen? Oder schafft er es, doch noch einmal EU-Parlamentspräsident zu werden? Er muss sich bald entscheiden. 11/18/16, 2:34 PM CET BY Anthony Skinner Syrian refugees are pawns in Turkish president’s pursuit of power. 11/18/16, 2:33 PM CET BY Charlie Cooper Shadow Brexit secretary ‘seriously pissed off’ at colleague’s comments. 11/18/16, 2:33 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet German chancellor is ‘championing the interests of Europe,’ Witold Waszczykowski said. 11/18/16, 12:58 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Nikola Gruevski stepped down in January over a wire tapping scandal. 11/18/16, 12:48 PM CET BY Barbara Surk Jens Stoltenberg said he had a ‘good talk’ with the president-elect. 11/18/16, 12:35 PM CET BY Esther King Majority of those who failed to gain international asylum come from the Balkan states. 11/18/16, 11:48 AM CET BY Esther King Immigration is what keeps the country running, says pro-EU Lord. 11/18/16, 10:57 AM CET BY Esther King Conditions at offshore detention center for refugees are ‘cruel, inhuman and degrading,’ said François Crépeau. 11/18/16, 9:36 AM CET BY Esther King Foreign Minister Linas Linkevičius warned that Vladimir Putin could use transition period in Baltics, Syria. 11/18/16, 8:55 AM CET BY MADELINE CONWAY Former ambassador to the UN says there are ways of supporting the opposition that does not involve the use of American military force. 11/18/16, 8:39 AM CET BY Cristiano Lima Her presence is likely to raise fresh concerns about potential conflicts of interest. 11/18/16, 8:35 AM CET BY Bryan Bender The retired lieutenant general’s hardline views on Islam — as well as laudatory statements about Russia — have made him a lightning rod, as did his strident attacks on Hillary Clinton during the campaign. 11/18/16, 5:33 AM CET BY Nicholas Vinocur The center-right’s first ever presidential primary looked all over. Now it’s wide open. 11/18/16, 5:25 AM CET BY Tim King The Günther Oettinger controversies are tainting this European Commission by intimate association. 11/18/16, 12:17 AM CET BY Nahal Toosi Much of Europe is alarmed over what Trump’s presidency could augur. 11/17/16, 11:52 PM CET BY Shane Goldmacher and Andrew Restuccia ‘We feel way ahead of schedule and never in a rush to do the wrong thing,’ said campaign manager Kellyanne Conway. 11/17/16, 9:42 PM CET BY Jacopo Barigazzi Maltese interior minister not impressed with Bratislava’s migration plan. 11/17/16, 9:33 PM CET BY Edward-Isaac Dovere In Berlin, the president warned his successor that his divisive campaign style won’t wear well in the Oval Office. 11/17/16, 8:24 PM CET BY Janosch Delcker US President hopes Trump won’t ‘simply take a Realpolitik approach.’ 11/17/16, 8:21 PM CET BY Hortense Goulard European Parliament president will only accept foreign minister role if he is also the SPD candidate for the top job. 11/17/16, 8:18 PM CET BY Konstantin Richter Germans, of all people, are now called on to be bulwarks of democracy. 11/17/16, 8:06 PM CET BY Paul Dallison and Esther King Euroskeptic party stands accused of breaking rules on spending EU funds. 11/17/16, 7:16 PM CET BY Brent Griffiths  11/17/16, 6:31 PM CET BY Maïa de La Baume Brussels faults Ankara for ‘neglecting and undermining’ democracy and the rule of law. 11/17/16, 6:27 PM CET BY Louis Nelson  11/17/16, 5:47 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Jean-Marie Le Pen should receive €15,000 because he was prevented from carrying out his duties. 11/17/16, 4:57 PM CET BY Carter Stoddard Net debt has ballooned to £338 million, and currency fluctuations are partly to blame. 11/17/16, 4:34 PM CET BY Laurens Cerulus In finally passing her surveillance bill, Britain’s PM just made Brexit even more complicated. 11/17/16, 4:13 PM CET BY Hortense Goulard French prime minister called for more European integration amid rising nationalism. 11/17/16, 3:23 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Former European Council president joins forces with Flemish singer. 11/17/16, 2:53 PM CET BY Paul Dallison Corey Lewandowski said president-elect will work closely with Theresa May, with no need for UKIP leader as a go-between. 11/17/16, 2:37 PM CET BY Cynthia Kroet Freedom Party leader’s comments on Moroccans living in the Netherlands were ‘unnecessarily offensive.’ 11/17/16, 2:11 PM CET BY Esther King Nigel Farage’s party stands accused of breaking rules on spending EU funds. Cadets vote at a polling station. Vladimir Putin's United Russia party won a greater share of the vote than in 2011, with even less space in parliament for any real opposition party | Vasily Batanov/AFP via Getty Images By Oliver Carroll 9/19/16, 3:14 PM CET Updated 9/20/16, 6:08 AM CET MOSCOW — Two years of economic recession, Western sanctions and wars in Ukraine and Syria haven’t shaken Vladimir Putin’s grip on power. Instead, Sunday’s election to the Russian state Duma saw the president’s United Russia party win a greater share of the vote than in 2011, with even less space in parliament for any real opposition party. There was never any doubt about the outcome, and many Russians didn’t bother to turn out. Nationwide, only 48 percent voted compared to 60 percent in the previous elections for the lower house of parliament. The numbers were even worse in Moscow and St. Petersburg, bastions of the educated middle classes and traditionally more protest-oriented. This time, despite some reports of voter fraud, there were no signs of demonstrations. “They did everything [so] that people would ignore the elections, from holding them just after the summer break, to the most low-key election campaign I can remember,” said political expert Grigorii Golosov. On Monday, with 93 percent of the votes counted, United Russia had 54.2 percent of the vote, up from 49.3 percent five years ago. Russia’s new electoral system, a mix of party lists and single mandate districts, means that Putin’s party wins a huge constitutional majority of 343 seats in the 450-seat Duma — compared to 238 seats in 2011. With its super majority, United Russia will have free rein over parliament, dropping the need to bargain with friendly opposition parties. It can also change the constitution at will. In southern Russia a CCTV camera caught a polling official stuffing a ballot box. On the latest figures, the Communist Party will likely finish second, slightly ahead of the Liberal Democratic Party of Russia, with the center-left Just Russia fourth. They were all in the previous parliament, and traditionally support the government on many issues and refrain from attacking Putin. While there is some pressure for the Communists to be more independent— their leader Gennady Zyuganov at one point refused to recognize the results — all three can be expected to remain loyal. All in all, it was a terrible election for Russia’s liberal fringe, which now faces the prospect of obliteration. They’re down from one seat in the previous Duma to none. Their best hope, the liberal opposition Yabloko party, scored less than 2 percent of the vote, and will now lose out on government funding. The liberal-democratic PARNAS party failed to get 1 percent, and most of the candidates supported by exiled oligarch Mikhail Khodorkovsky were wiped out. Also On Politico Oliver Carroll Also On Politico Kristen East Also On Politico Vince Chadwick The centrist opposition also failed to break through in any of the single-mandate districts. The closest candidate, Yabloko’s Dmitry Gudkov, lost in the Moscow suburbs. As he faced defeat, Gudkov told POLITICO he had battled the full might of the government machine, but said that the result was ultimately down to the passivity of Russian democrats. “Voters didn’t turn up,” he said. “Russia’s middle class now is about to get what it deserves.” Only one independent and two right-wing populist candidates made it into the Duma, but they won’t give much support to the liberal opposition. One of the nationalist winners of the single-mandate run-offs was Vitaly Milonov, a former deputy of the St. Petersburg city government who has campaigned on an anti-gay rights platform. Although the outcome was never in doubt, the Kremlin made sure that the voting procedure was cleaned up from 2011, when voter fraud sparked anti-Putin protests. However, there were still questionable incidents, the most obvious being in Rostov in southern Russia where a CCTV camera caught a polling official stuffing a ballot box. In other places, voters were lured to the polls with free sausages and other goodies. Denis Korotkov, a correspondent for the St. Petersburg news portal Fontanka, managed to vote several times. He immediately wrote about the incident and brought it to the attention of the authorities. Law enforcement subsequently detained Korotkov — who is now threatened with prosecution for electoral violations. While the opposition faces being wiped out, the upshot for Putin is that his control of Russia is stronger than ever. He is likely to decide to run for a fourth term as president in 2018. As part of the preparations for yet another run, Putin recently reshuffled his closest advisers, weeding out those who might dare to challenge him and replacing them with lesser-known men completely dependent on his favor. The election also means there is likely to be little change in Russia’s policies on Ukraine and Syria, or in its economic program. “In practical terms, little will change with the new parliament,” wrote Capital Economics, an analysis firm, in a post-election note. “United Russia already held a majority in parliament, and didn’t face effective opposition. The strong showing for United Russia (and disappointing results for the opposition) suggests that the direction of policy will be largely unchanged.”  © 2016 POLITICO SPRL Log in to access content and manage your profile. If you do not have a login you can register here.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>39</end>
        <start>22</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>113</end>
        <start>40</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>135</end>
        <start>114</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>152</end>
        <start>136</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>245</end>
        <start>153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>268</end>
        <start>246</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>286</end>
        <start>269</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>346</end>
        <start>287</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>369</end>
        <start>347</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>387</end>
        <start>370</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>462</end>
        <start>388</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>485</end>
        <start>463</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>505</end>
        <start>486</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>592</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>615</end>
        <start>593</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>650</end>
        <start>616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>751</end>
        <start>651</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>773</end>
        <start>752</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>790</end>
        <start>774</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>918</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>940</end>
        <start>919</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1000</end>
        <start>941</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1001</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1023</end>
        <start>1002</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1039</end>
        <start>1024</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1040</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1149</end>
        <start>1128</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1164</end>
        <start>1150</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1247</end>
        <start>1165</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1269</end>
        <start>1248</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1289</end>
        <start>1270</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1381</end>
        <start>1290</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1403</end>
        <start>1382</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1419</end>
        <start>1404</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1461</end>
        <start>1420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1484</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1584</end>
        <start>1501</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1606</end>
        <start>1585</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1607</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1726</end>
        <start>1652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1748</end>
        <start>1727</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1768</end>
        <start>1749</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1769</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1878</end>
        <start>1857</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1895</end>
        <start>1879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1974</end>
        <start>1896</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1996</end>
        <start>1975</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2032</end>
        <start>1997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2196</end>
        <start>2033</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2218</end>
        <start>2197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2237</end>
        <start>2219</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2304</end>
        <start>2238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2326</end>
        <start>2305</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2344</end>
        <start>2327</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2416</end>
        <start>2345</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2438</end>
        <start>2417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2455</end>
        <start>2439</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2542</end>
        <start>2456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2565</end>
        <start>2543</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2582</end>
        <start>2566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2651</end>
        <start>2583</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2674</end>
        <start>2652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2690</end>
        <start>2675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2759</end>
        <start>2691</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2782</end>
        <start>2760</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2797</end>
        <start>2783</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2884</end>
        <start>2798</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2907</end>
        <start>2885</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2922</end>
        <start>2908</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2987</end>
        <start>2923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3010</end>
        <start>2988</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3025</end>
        <start>3011</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3137</end>
        <start>3026</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3159</end>
        <start>3138</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3174</end>
        <start>3160</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3283</end>
        <start>3175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3305</end>
        <start>3284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3324</end>
        <start>3306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3459</end>
        <start>3325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3481</end>
        <start>3460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3499</end>
        <start>3482</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3585</end>
        <start>3500</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3607</end>
        <start>3586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3623</end>
        <start>3608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3828</end>
        <start>3624</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3850</end>
        <start>3829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3870</end>
        <start>3851</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3958</end>
        <start>3871</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3980</end>
        <start>3959</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3992</end>
        <start>3981</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4091</end>
        <start>3993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4114</end>
        <start>4092</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4129</end>
        <start>4115</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4197</end>
        <start>4130</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4220</end>
        <start>4198</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4261</end>
        <start>4221</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4376</end>
        <start>4262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4398</end>
        <start>4377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4418</end>
        <start>4399</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4492</end>
        <start>4419</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4514</end>
        <start>4493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4537</end>
        <start>4515</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4652</end>
        <start>4538</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4674</end>
        <start>4653</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4693</end>
        <start>4675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4762</end>
        <start>4694</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4784</end>
        <start>4763</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4804</end>
        <start>4785</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4922</end>
        <start>4805</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4944</end>
        <start>4923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4966</end>
        <start>4945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5037</end>
        <start>4967</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5059</end>
        <start>5038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5092</end>
        <start>5060</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5165</end>
        <start>5093</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5187</end>
        <start>5166</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5206</end>
        <start>5188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5207</end>
        <start>5207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5229</end>
        <start>5208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5249</end>
        <start>5230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5336</end>
        <start>5250</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5358</end>
        <start>5337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5374</end>
        <start>5359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5375</end>
        <start>5375</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5397</end>
        <start>5376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5414</end>
        <start>5398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5510</end>
        <start>5415</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5532</end>
        <start>5511</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5551</end>
        <start>5533</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5638</end>
        <start>5552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5660</end>
        <start>5639</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5679</end>
        <start>5661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5774</end>
        <start>5680</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5796</end>
        <start>5775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5816</end>
        <start>5797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5900</end>
        <start>5817</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5922</end>
        <start>5901</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5939</end>
        <start>5923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6007</end>
        <start>5940</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6029</end>
        <start>6008</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6046</end>
        <start>6030</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6167</end>
        <start>6047</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6189</end>
        <start>6168</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6206</end>
        <start>6190</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6309</end>
        <start>6207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6331</end>
        <start>6310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6346</end>
        <start>6332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6422</end>
        <start>6347</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6642</end>
        <start>6423</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6660</end>
        <start>6643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6681</end>
        <start>6661</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6710</end>
        <start>6682</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6847</end>
        <start>6711</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7052</end>
        <start>6848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7486</end>
        <start>7053</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7694</end>
        <start>7487</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8034</end>
        <start>7695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8218</end>
        <start>8035</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8300</end>
        <start>8219</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8601</end>
        <start>8301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8794</end>
        <start>8602</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8965</end>
        <start>8795</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9259</end>
        <start>8966</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9276</end>
        <start>9260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9291</end>
        <start>9277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9308</end>
        <start>9292</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9321</end>
        <start>9309</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9338</end>
        <start>9322</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9353</end>
        <start>9339</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9704</end>
        <start>9354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9800</end>
        <start>9705</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10130</end>
        <start>9801</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10548</end>
        <start>10131</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10862</end>
        <start>10549</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11273</end>
        <start>10863</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11404</end>
        <start>11274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11780</end>
        <start>11405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11781</end>
        <start>11781</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11802</end>
        <start>11782</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11902</end>
        <start>11803</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico EU</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>7653</end>
        <start>7488</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9728</end>
        <start>9706</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9799</end>
        <start>9740</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11469</end>
        <start>11406</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11779</end>
        <start>11540</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8300</end>
        <start>8219</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Russia’s election: Free sausages and fraud allegations</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.eu/article/russias-election-free-sausages-and-fraud-allegations-parliament-vote/?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
