<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Republican vice presidential candidate Mike Pence said he was “so proud” of his running mate, Donald Trump, for “demonstrating restraint” during the first presidential debate Monday night by opting not to bring up former president Bill Clinton’s extramarital affairs. The vice presidential candidate told CBS This Morning that he was impressed that Trump held back after Clinton launched an “avalanche of personal insults” at him. Story Continued Below “Ninety minutes in a row of one insult after another and then Donald Trump, just completely open and transparent with the American people, said, ‘There’s things I could bring up, we all know what they are, we all lived through the 1990’s,’ and he just said ‘I’m not going to do it.'” Pence said. “I think there you saw in him the restraint and temperament that would make for a good president.” Trump hadn't always planned to refrain from using the former president’s scandals as a personal attack on Clinton, but after the debate told reporters he was glad he changed his mind. “I’m very happy that I was able to hold back on the indiscretions with respect to Bill Clinton,” Trump said. “Because I have a lot of respect for Chelsea Clinton and I just didn’t want to say what I was going to say.” He added that he was going to say “something extremely rough to Hillary and her family, and I said to myself, I couldn't do it. It's inappropriate. It's not nice.” Trump had also threatened last weekend to invite Gennifer Flowers, a woman Bill Clinton admitted to having an affair with decades ago, to the presidential debate.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>267</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>430</end>
        <start>268</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>452</end>
        <start>431</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>847</end>
        <start>453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1031</end>
        <start>848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1032</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1576</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>71</end>
        <start>63</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>136</end>
        <start>113</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>421</end>
        <start>392</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>735</end>
        <start>454</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>750</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1033</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1248</end>
        <start>1142</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1412</end>
        <start>1285</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Pence: Trump ‘demonstrated restraint’ in debate</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-first-debate-restraint-mike-pence-228787?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
