<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rick Britton</author>
    <links href="http://www.breitbart.com/tech/2016/09/21/northwestern-president-critics-of-safe-spaces-are-lunatics/">
        <end>211</end>
        <start>202</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://dailynorthwestern.com/2016/09/21/campus/schapiro-to-freshmen-people-criticizing-safe-spaces-drives-me-nuts/">
        <end>417</end>
        <start>395</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.northwestern.edu/president/biography/index.html">
        <end>478</end>
        <start>463</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>So I guess it is back to school for everyone.  I am not really too sure, as the last time I was in a classroom they actually taught curriculum that benefitted students.  I saw an interesting article in Breitbart today which read: “Northwestern President: Critics of Safe Spaces, Trigger Warnings are ‘Lunatics'”.   The article, which appeared in Northwestern University’s student rag newspaper, The Daily Northwestern, was based on a speech given by NU President Morton Schapiro.  I know that listening to libtards is enough to make any of my readers lose their lunch, so I will simply hit the high points.  In his speech Schapiro said: “The people who decry safe spaces do it from their segregated housing places, from their jobs without diversity — they do it from their country clubs. It just drives me nuts.” And about microaggression, what did this academic sainte have to say? “Microaggressions cut you to the core and aren’t easily forgotten…” Ok, first things first: According to his bio, Morton Schapiro has never worked a day in his life outside of academics.  While his resume might sound impressive it has all been in schools and colleges.  This is important because it means that he has nothing in common with the students that will eventually have to graduate his college and, gasp in horror, find a job. Dr. Schapiro told students that ““Look for those safe spaces. If you can’t find them, we will help you find them.”  Alright, call me a sadist, but I would love to be a fly on the wall when one of NU’s students goes into a job interview and starts talking about safe spaces.  Hey buttercup, the real world doesn’t have those!  What are you going to do, little snowflake, when you meet a co-worker or even a boss who says things that you consider “microaggressive”?  Are you going to run to your safe space and hide in your blanket fort whilst sipping a juice box?  Are you going to sit there in a boardroom during a meeting and cry because someone said something that goes against what you believe?  If you can answer yes to both of those questions then you will not be employed for too long.  To survive in the real world you need a level of self discipline and a really, really tough skin.  The working world is tough, it’s a lot tougher when you are a wuss. The whole purpose of college is to prepare its students for the real world not only by teaching them academics that can get them jobs, but also by preparing them for a tough, cold world.  Well, at least that use to be its purpose.  Now the purpose of college is to brainwash and coddle, making spineless wimps out out of the strong and airheads out of the smart.  Today’s colleges are run by administrators and teachers who have never worked a day in the private sector.  They teach theory, not reality.   Students come out with student debts in the hundreds of thousands without the skills necessary to survive in the working world.  I shudder to think that these entitled wusses will someday be running the country. I motion that Northwestern University change its name to Wussy U.  And, if you don’t like it, I will be in my blanket fort, sipping my juice box. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>314</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>636</end>
        <start>315</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>812</end>
        <start>637</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>950</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1318</end>
        <start>951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2278</end>
        <start>1319</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2996</end>
        <start>2279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3142</end>
        <start>2997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3143</end>
        <start>3143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>IPatriot</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>310</end>
        <start>231</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>811</end>
        <start>638</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>949</end>
        <start>884</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1432</end>
        <start>1352</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1780</end>
        <start>1765</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>812</end>
        <start>637</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The University of Wusses</title>
    <uri>http://ipatriot.com/the-university-of-wusses/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
