<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/racistft-620x326.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>What would you do if you were faced with an angry mob shutting down the stretch of road that you’re on? You approach the group and apply the brakes, wondering if they’ll move for you, but not only do they not make any effort to get out of your way, they start coming toward you. Remembering the Reginald Denny affair, you realize that you’re faced with two options: floor it and risk hurting one of the protesters, or stop and risk them hurting you, or worse.  What do you do? Maybe it was the way I was raised, but I learned that if you feel threatened and you feel as if it ultimately comes down to you or the person who you believe is planning to do you harm, the answer is absolutely, 100% self-preservation. Apparently, I’m not the only one with this set of beliefs. An incident took place on the campus of the Eastern Michigan University that proves that if you try to shut down a road in protest, you do so at your own risk. Watching the video below, you can see that black protesters have completely taken over the street. One small jeep, however, clearly has places to be that aren’t right there at that moment. The driver hits the gas pedal and speeds forward, bumping over a protester. Watch the video below:   In case you were wondering if they were upset about the Charlotte shooting, the answer is “no.” Instead, they were upset about the words “KKK” and “Leave N*****s” painted on the side of the school. The words were removed and the school issued an apology, but it was too late, BLM was outraged. Make no mistake, it’s better to be arrested for running over a protester than to be killed and/or have your property stolen by them because they think they’re entitled to it due to someone painting some mean words on the side of a building. “Better to be judged by 12 than carried by 6,” doesn’t only apply to protecting your home and family, but yourself as well. There is no good reason to stop while surrounded by irrationally angry people who just want violence to come to you and anyone else they deem “guilty” of whatever crime they’ve made up today. What would you do if you were in this situation? Would you stop, or would you put the pedal to the floor? </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>278</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>459</end>
        <start>279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>460</end>
        <start>460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>476</end>
        <start>461</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>712</end>
        <start>477</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>771</end>
        <start>713</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>931</end>
        <start>772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1196</end>
        <start>932</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1219</end>
        <start>1197</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1220</end>
        <start>1220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1221</end>
        <start>1221</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1515</end>
        <start>1222</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1756</end>
        <start>1516</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2072</end>
        <start>1757</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2178</end>
        <start>2073</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2179</end>
        <start>2179</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1316</end>
        <start>1313</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1363</end>
        <start>1360</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1383</end>
        <start>1370</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1802</end>
        <start>1758</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2030</end>
        <start>2024</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BlackLivesMatter Thugs BLOCK The Street – Regret It When One Car Drives RIGHT Over Them…VIDEO</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/blacklivesmatter-thugs-block-street-regret-one-car-drives-right-video/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
