<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1M75UbX">
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1254</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cNUAVf">
        <end>2366</end>
        <start>2345</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cFmFCe">
        <end>2469</end>
        <start>2448</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2czVUKc">
        <end>2553</end>
        <start>2532</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cPZqQm">
        <end>2631</end>
        <start>2610</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cjjFVC">
        <end>4066</end>
        <start>4042</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cnn.it/2czQezN">
        <end>4845</end>
        <start>4824</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cVJhfO">
        <end>5393</end>
        <start>5369</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/clk/313631530;141405222;h">
        <end>5603</end>
        <start>5522</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cjhwJX">
        <end>6631</end>
        <start>6607</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cvXEEd">
        <end>7350</end>
        <start>7329</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2clEhSa">
        <end>8384</end>
        <start>8362</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyp.st/2algwpl">
        <end>8539</end>
        <start>8518</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nydn.us/2b6YE1k">
        <end>8595</end>
        <start>8573</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nbcnews.to/2czVXp6">
        <end>8739</end>
        <start>8714</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cqVvvX">
        <end>8821</end>
        <start>8800</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://apne.ws/2cNET0i">
        <end>9266</end>
        <start>9244</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/trump2016?src=hash">
        <end>9374</end>
        <start>9364</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/9fHwog7ssN">
        <end>9401</end>
        <start>9375</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/DonaldJTrumpJr/status/778016283342307328">
        <end>9457</end>
        <start>9439</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d7Iav5">
        <end>10309</end>
        <start>10288</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2clJ7Pn">
        <end>10433</end>
        <start>10412</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cNFsqO">
        <end>11722</end>
        <start>11701</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cElVgE">
        <end>11991</end>
        <start>11967</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cUY0Yl">
        <end>12665</end>
        <start>12641</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://apne.ws/2d16COf">
        <end>13360</end>
        <start>13338</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cjh9yM">
        <end>13809</end>
        <start>13788</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://hrc.io/2cr2Rzs">
        <end>14188</end>
        <start>14167</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2cYLQMJ">
        <end>14241</end>
        <start>14219</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/clk/313631529;141405222;p">
        <end>14398</end>
        <start>14346</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cEcoml">
        <end>15105</end>
        <start>15081</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://wapo.st/2dcZ0F5">
        <end>15925</end>
        <start>15903</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bloom.bg/2cE7Nkc">
        <end>16439</end>
        <start>16416</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2dakhzf">
        <end>17211</end>
        <start>17189</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://nyti.ms/2d7Dc1x">
        <end>17336</end>
        <start>17314</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2cEoJu2">
        <end>18172</end>
        <start>18148</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d4J7Qn">
        <end>18246</end>
        <start>18225</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cnnmon.ie/2d7CvW1">
        <end>18694</end>
        <start>18670</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d19qLB">
        <end>19244</end>
        <start>19223</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2czUsHM">
        <end>19705</end>
        <start>19684</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cFda64">
        <end>20932</end>
        <start>20911</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cjiDJn">
        <end>21306</end>
        <start>21285</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2cFjESc">
        <end>21759</end>
        <start>21738</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://bit.ly/2d1difn">
        <end>21783</end>
        <start>21762</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://yhoo.it/1F9jFpf">
        <end>22693</end>
        <start>22671</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27e678973237540b2c24276ad69c745b973abd98144e0c210a">
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1254</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a2767f4940442aff97e7c066c727f9c20288dbf3b9a9c94af0b">
        <end>25044</end>
        <start>25020</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1OypFe9">
        <end>25088</end>
        <start>25064</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a274cd0c60878dc0107a2877730f30a3cf31907ea80300291ab">
        <end>25137</end>
        <start>25113</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1Nhtq5v">
        <end>25189</end>
        <start>25165</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27c2d30196dfdcef3b79d2e10c2707bcce21999529adf1def8">
        <end>25236</end>
        <start>25212</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/2bLvcPl">
        <end>25285</end>
        <start>25261</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://politi.co/1FZeLcw">
        <end>25332</end>
        <start>25308</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://go.politicoemail.com/?qs=85461d9f925c7a27f2079f7785f61ccb759e0f2b4aaa39da6b3d00c5a28d5b28">
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1254</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Politico POLITICO's must-read briefing on what's driving the day in Washington GOVT FUNDING UPDATE -- POTOMAC FEVER SETTING IN -- Earlier this month, Republicans and Democrats on Capitol Hill had a rosy prediction: They would be able to wrap up the fight over government funding this week and head home until after Election Day. But the optimistic outlook has collided with reality over the last few days. Senior aides on Capitol Hill now say the funding battle can easily stretch into next week because of disagreements over ancillary spending requests. Big deal? No, not really. They were always scheduled to be in session next week. But Congress would just prefer to get the hell out of D.C. and in front of their constituents. 49 DAYS until Election Day. Six days until the first presidential debate at Hofstra University on Long Island. Big thanks to Carleton College and POLITICO publisher and editor in chief John Harris for organizing a political discussion last night in Northfield, Minnesota. Harris moderated a conversation on Clinton, Trump and the media in 2016 before a packed house with Anna (a St. Olaf alum) and POLITICO alums and friends of Playbook, NYT’s JMart and WaPo’s James Hohmann. Story Continued Below **SUBSCRIBE to Playbook: http://politi.co/1M75UbX ATTN BROOKLYN -- TRUMP DISCUSSES DEBATE STRATEGY ON FOX NEWS -- Speaking with Bill O’Reilly last night, Trump gave a taste of his debate prep. How he plans to go after Clinton in the debates: “I can talk about her deleting emails after she gets a subpoena from Congress and lots of other things. I mean I can talk about her record which is a disaster. I can talk about all she’s done to help ISIS become the terror that they’ve become and I will be doing that. So I mean we’re going to go back and forth and she’s got a lot of baggage. I’ll tell you what.” On going after Bill Clinton’s infidelities: “I don’t think I’m looking to do that Bill. I don’t know what I’m going to do that exactly. It depends on what level she hits you with, if she’s fair, if it’s unfair, but certainly I’m not looking to do that.” His view of Lester Holt: “Lester is a professional, but we’ll see what happens … By the way, Lester is a Democrat. It’s a phony system. They are all Democrats. It’s a very unfair system. I’ve worked pretty well within the system.” Video of full interview http://bit.ly/2cNUAVf --CLINTON on “The Tonight Show” with Jimmy Fallon: Hillary Clinton on her health http://bit.ly/2cFmFCe … On “breaking barriers, fighting bigotry and debating Trump” http://bit.ly/2czVUKc … On “balancing seriousness with positivity as a woman” http://bit.ly/2cPZqQm PLAYBOOKING AND FOOD TRUCKING -- Want free breakfast? Nice. We want to give you some. Anna, Daniel and Jake have taken over a food truck for the week, and will be popping up at central locations Wednesday, Thursday and Friday to feed and caffeinate you. Why? Why not. Stay tuned for exact locations. #playbookEATS FROM BROOKLYN -- HOW ROBBY MOOK SAYS CLINTON CAN WIN -- by Gabe Debenedetti in New York: “‘Here’s the story that no poll can tell: Hillary Clinton has many paths to 270 electoral votes, while Donald Trump has very few. Hillary is nearly certain to win 16 ‘ blue' states, including Washington D.C., which will garner her 191 electoral votes,” writes Mook in the nearly 2,000-word memo that was blasted out [to donors, supporters and volunteers] in the early evening, and which was obtained by POLITICO. ‘If we add the five states that FiveThirtyEight.com gives Hillary a 70% or greater chance of winning (Michigan, Minnesota, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and Wisconsin), Hillary only needs 10 more electoral votes.’ ... “‘Put a different way, of these battleground states, Hillary can win just one (Florida, Ohio, or North Carolina) and win the presidency, which means the six additional states would only add more electoral votes to her total,” he writes. “Donald Trump, on the other hand, must win six of these seven states, including Florida, North Carolina, and Ohio — none of which he can lose.’” http://politi.co/2cjjFVC ADELSON PONIES UP -- “Adelson to spend at least $45 million on 2016 races in boost for GOP,” by CNN’s Teddy Schleifer: “The billionaire on Tuesday will disclose having given $20 million to the Senate Leadership Fund, a super PAC linked to George W. Bush hand Karl Rove and Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell. A check of a similar size is expected to go to the Congressional Leadership Fund, a similar super PAC focused on the House of Representatives. And to back Trump, a donation of at least $5 million is likely headed to the political operation helmed by the Ricketts family, who are expected to finally spend their fortunes on Trump as well. Other cash may be routed to Ricketts-led nonprofit groups that are not required to disclose the funders.” http://cnn.it/2czQezN -- “Schumer transfers millions to Dems in bid for Senate takeover,” by Burgess Everett and John Bresnahan: “The New York senator is transferring $1 million to Senate Democrats’ campaign arm on Tuesday. He’s also given $3.2 million to state parties over the past week, Democratic sources said. Earlier this month, Schumer shifted an additional $2 million from his campaign war chest to the [DSCC]. Altogether in September, Schumer has transferred $6.2 million of the $27 million he has on hand to help Democratic hopefuls.” http://politi.co/2cVJhfO **** A message from BP: Over the past 10 years, no energy company has invested more in the U.S. than BP – $90 billion in total. Take 90 seconds to see what else we’re doing to help keep America moving forward. ****** H.W. FOR HRC -- FROM DARREN SAMUELSOHN: “[Former President George H.W.] Bush, 92, had intended to stay silent on the White House race between Clinton and Donald Trump, a sign in and of itself of his distaste for the GOP nominee. But his preference for the wife of his own successor, President Bill Clinton, nonetheless became known to a wider audience thanks to Kathleen Hartington Kennedy Townsend, the former Maryland lieutenant governor and daughter of the late Robert F. Kennedy. In a telephone interview, Townsend said she met with the former president in Maine earlier today, where she said he made his preference known that he was voting for a Democrat. ‘That’s what he said,’ she told POLITICO. “Asked about Townsend’s [Facebook] post, George H.W. Bush spokesman Jim McGrath in an email replied, ‘The vote President Bush will cast as a private citizen in some 50 days will be just that: a private vote cast in some 50 days. He is not commenting on the presidential race in the interim.’” http://politi.co/2cjhwJX --QUICK THOUGHT: This is a man who is not only a former president, but a former Republican member of Congress, former chairman of the RNC, former ambassador under Gerald Ford and Richard Nixon, former CIA director under Ford and Ronald Reagan’s vice president. This should resonate with many on-the-fence Republicans. YOU’RE INVITED! -- Join us for Playbook Cocktails TOMORROW evening with civil rights icon, Rep. John Lewis (D-Ga.)! Our conversation comes during the opening week of the Smithsonian’s National Museum of African American History and Culture. We’ll talk about civil rights and explore Lewis’s extraordinary life. Doors open at 5:30 p.m. The W Hotel, 515 15th Street, NW. RSVP here http://bit.ly/2cvXEEd TERROR WATCH -- “Ahmad Rahami: Fixture in Family’s Business and, Lately, a ‘Completely Different Person,’” by NYT’s N.R. Kleinfeld: “He presided behind the counter of a storefront New Jersey fried chicken restaurant, making his home with his family in an apartment above it. To some of his friends, Ahmad Khan Rahami was known as Mad, an abridgment of his name rather than a suggestion of his manner, and they liked that he gave them free food when they were short on money. Beyond that, his other known obsession was souped-up Honda Civics that he liked to race. In recent years, though, some friends noticed a marked change in his personality and religious devotion after what they believed was a trip to Afghanistan, where he and his relatives are from. In fact ... Mr. Rahami had actually traveled to Pakistan, for three months in 2011 and, most recently, to Quetta, for nearly a year, where he stayed with family, returning to the United States in March 2014. While there, he is believed to have married.” http://nyti.ms/2clEhSa DRUDGE banner, “ISIS AMONG US” ... TAB COVERS -- N.Y. POST: “HE HATES AMERICA -- Bomber ‘hates gays, hates military, hates culture’” http://nyp.st/2algwpl … N.Y. DAILY NEWS: “MARTYR DUMB” http://nydn.us/2b6YE1k POLLS DU JOUR -- HILLARY CLINTON 50, DONALD TRUMP 45 in NBC News/Survey Monkey Weekly Election Tracking Poll (online) http://nbcnews.to/2czVXp6 … MONMOUTH: GEORGIA -- Donald Trump 43, Hillary Clinton 41. http://bit.ly/2cqVvvX SIREN -- AP: “524k Ohio absentee ballots requested, 40k more than 2012”: “State officials say more than 524,000 absentee ballots have been requested in Ohio this year -- an increase of 40,000 compared to the same period during the 2012 presidential election. Secretary of State Jon Husted says nearly 12,000 of the absentee ballot applications are from military and overseas voters. The rest are from in-state residents.” http://apne.ws/2cNET0i This image says it all. Let's end the politically correct agenda that doesn't put America first. #trump2016 pic.twitter.com/9fHwog7ssN — Donald Trump Jr. (@DonaldJTrumpJr) September 19, 2016 SKITTLES RESPONDS -- via the Hollywood Reporter’s Seth Abramovitch -- “Skittles are candy. Refugees are people. We don’t feel it’s an appropriate analogy. We will respectfully refrain from further commentary as anything we say could be misinterpreted as marketing.” PELOSI’S CASH DASH -- House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi is continuing her quest to fill the DCCC’s coffers with a luncheon Tuesday in New York City with Vice President Joe Biden. The push follows a bicoastal swing over the weekend that began with a trip to New York City followed by visits to Hartford, San Francisco, Sacramento and then Las Vegas. The aggressive dollar dash comes as the DCCC announced Monday it had outraised the NRCC by nearly $4 million in August, pulling in $11 million. --GABE FLEISHER, the 14-year-old proprietor of “Wake Up To Politics” (http://bit.ly/2d7Iav5), sends over an image of the “dramatic subject lines” he’s gotten from the DCCC in the last few days. http://bit.ly/2clJ7Pn HAPPENING TODAY -- Donald Trump is in High Point, North Carolina, at noon, and Kenansville, North Carolina, at the Duplin County Events Center for a 5 p.m. rally. Tim Kaine is in Reno, Nevada. BARACK OBAMA is addressing the U.N. General Assembly in the morning. He’ll then hold a meeting with Nigerian President Muhammadu Buhari, and calls with UN General Assembly President Peter Thomson of Fiji and UN Secretary General Ban Ki-Moon. Moon hosts Obama for lunch, and then Obama will attend a CEO roundtable, and a refugee summit. In the evening, Obama will speak at a reception for foreign heads of delegations to the U.N. He’s sleeping in New York. POTUS on the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette op-ed page, “Self-driving, yes, but also safe”: “[M]y administration is rolling out new rules of the road for automated vehicles – guidance that the manufacturers developing self-driving cars should follow to keep us safe. ... [T]echnology isn’t just about the latest gadget or app – it’s about making people’s lives better. That’s going to be the focus of the first-ever White House Frontiers Conference on Oct. 13. And what better place to hold it than Pittsburgh – a city that has harnessed innovation to redefine itself as a center for technology, health care and education.” http://bit.ly/2cNFsqO COMING TODAY -- “The Obama administration Tuesday will unveil its long-awaited guidance update for self-driving vehicles, outlining its expectations for automakers and tech companies, some of which are already bringing those cars to the road.” http://politi.co/2cElVgE BEING THERE -- “Millennials Go Mild For Hillary,” by Michael Grunwald in Philly: “In interviews at the event, many of her millennial supporters, especially the former Sanders revolutionaries, talked about her in the could-be-worse tone they might use to describe a boring but socially appropriate romantic partner. They used words like ‘capable,’ ‘well-informed,’ ‘responsible,’ and ‘qualified.’ They dutifully praised her positions on issues like abortion, student debt, mass incarceration, and climate change, while emphasizing the importance of stopping Trump and his inflammatory rhetoric. But most of them did not sound particularly inspired.” http://politi.co/2cUY0Yl TRUMP’S MONEY PLAY -- “Gold cards and red hats: A Trumpian approach to fundraising,” by AP’s Julie Bykowicz and Jeff Horwitz: “Donald Trump is underwriting his presidential bid by selling the Donald Trump lifestyle — and campaign finance records show it is working. For the low price of $25, you can snag a Trump Gold Card emblazoned with your name or join a campaign ‘Board of Directors’ that comes with a personalized certificate. For $30, there’s Trump’s signature hats — billed as ‘the most popular product in America.’ Supporters can elevate themselves to ‘big league’ by ponying up $184 for a signed, ‘now out of print’ copy of Trump’s book, ‘The Art of the Deal.’” http://apne.ws/2d16COf BERNIE SANDERS on the cover of The Nation, interviewed by Katrina vanden Heuvel and John Nichols: “The Democrats have got to open the door to young people. Welcome them in and understand that it will be messy, that many young people are not professional politicians. The Democratic Party is going to have to adjust itself to their reality, rather than force young people to be adjusted to the Democratic leadership’s reality.” http://bit.ly/2cjh9yM HILLARY’s open letter to Wells Fargo customers in the wake of the major scandal at the bank: “Executives should be held individually accountable when rampant illegal activity happens on their watch. Their compensation should take a hit if their companies pay major fines. And they must face appropriate legal consequences if they break the law.” The letter http://hrc.io/2cr2Rzs ... The latest on Wells Fargo http://nyti.ms/2cYLQMJ **** A message from BP: We’ve donated $147 million to U.S. community programs over the past five years. Check out the programs we support in your community. ****** HILL WATCH -- “Freedom Caucus stiffs GOP on campaign cash,” by Rachael Bade and Heather Caygle: “A bloc of conservatives is refusing to transfer cash to the National Republican Congressional Committee, convinced the committee is favoring moderate candidates over hard-line conservatives. Dozens of other Republican lawmakers also haven’t paid their expected party ‘dues,’ including several in tough primaries or general election races who figure they need the money for themselves. Several GOP sources told Politico that 3 in 10 members of the House Republican Conference are delinquent on their dues. And multiple senior Republicans said the shortfall exceeds $10 million.” http://politi.co/2cEcoml COMING ATTRACTIONS -- “Ed Gillespie favored in 2017 Republican primary for Virginia governor, poll finds,” by WaPo’s Laura Vozella: “In a crowded Republican field, strategist Ed Gillespie has the support of 19 percent of Virginia adults compared with 6 percent for Corey Stewart, who is chairman of Trump’s Virginia presidential campaign and the Prince William Board of County Supervisors. Gillespie’s closest competitor is the latest entrant to the GOP race: state Sen. Frank W. Wagner (Virginia Beach), who announced his candidacy in late August and drew the support of 11 percent in the poll. U.S. Rep. Rob Wittman had 8 percent ... “The poll, conducted Sept. 6 to 12 for the university by Princeton Survey Research Associates, found that 40 percent of Virginians have no preferred candidate.” http://wapo.st/2dcZ0F5 THE SECRET SAUCE -- “Bloomberg Politics will launch the ‘poll decoder’ -- a brand-new look inside major polling organizations’ numbers, broken down by race, gender, age, and education and then cross-referenced by those demographics' choice for president. Unlike other polling aggregators that provide one overall average poll number, news organizations gave Bloomberg Politics unique access to allow the poll decoder to show which candidate is winning which coalitions -- and by how much.” http://bloom.bg/2cE7Nkc TRUMP TRANSITION CHAIR UPDATE --“Chris Christie Knew About Bridge Lane Closings as They Happened, Prosecutors Say,” by NYT’s Kate Zernike in Newark: “Gov. Chris Christie of New Jersey knew that three of his top officials were involved in a plan to shut down lanes leading to the George Washington Bridge as it was happening and that the closings were intended to punish a local mayor for declining to support him, federal prosecutors said on Monday. The assertion was an unexpected and startling beginning to the trial of two former Christie administration officials charged with closing the lanes in 2013 and then covering it up. And it was a surprising claim because of the side of the courtroom it came from, as lawyers made opening statements.” http://nyti.ms/2dakhzf FOR YOUR RADAR -- Venezuela is in such bad shape that it is now importing oil from the United States. http://nyti.ms/2d7Dc1x MEDIAWATCH -- “Clinton press poolers clash with Egyptian leader's security,” by Halley Toosi in New York: “Reporters traveling with Hillary Clinton got a taste of the Egyptian security state on Monday -- and they didn't much care for it … According to the press pool report, upon reaching the hotel, the journalists were ordered to leave their bags, phones and computers with campaign staff ‘outside of the zone that had been deemed secure.’ ‘Reporters had to argue with Egyptian security to even carry recorders on their person,’ the pool report states. ‘There were also repeated arguments between Clinton campaign staff and the Egyptian security officials about how many reporters could enter the meeting despite having already reached an agreement with the country’s protocol officer prior to our arrival.’" http://politi.co/2cEoJu2 -- @ZekeJMiller: “Trump readout of el-Sisi meeting” http://bit.ly/2d4J7Qn -- “Joe Scarborough, Donald Trump look to repair relations,” by CNN’s Dylan Byers: “Last week, Scarborough and his ‘Morning Joe’ co-host, Mika Brzezinski, visited the Republican presidential nominee at Trump Tower to rekindle a once-rosy relationship that has turned bitter and adversarial ... The three also discussed the possibility of conducting an interview for ‘Morning Joe,’ though nothing was decided or finalized.” http://cnnmon.ie/2d7CvW1 --TV’S SLOW DEATH: “On the Eve of a New Broadcast Season, Emmys Ratings Drop to a Record Low,” by AdAge’s Anthony Crupi: “According to Nielsen live-plus-same-day data, ABC’s Sunday night presentation of the 68th Primetime Emmy Awards marked an all-time nadir for the ceremony, averaging 11.3 million viewers and a 2.8 rating among adults 18-49. While this marked a mere 5% decline versus the 11.9 million viewers Fox drew a year ago, the drop in the advertiser-coveted demo was much more steep -- down 22% compared with a 3.6.” http://bit.ly/2d19qLB --KEEP IN MIND: The four debate moderators are basically unknown to people 18-29, according to our recent Morning Consult poll. A plurality has not heard of a single debate moderator besides Anderson Cooper. OUT AND ABOUT -- POTUS and FLOTUS enjoying a dinner out last night at Cosme. Per our tipster: “Super trendy Mexican place ... on 21 St between Park and 5th. 3 blocks from the terrorist bombing on Saturday. Nypd seem psyched.” Menu http://bit.ly/2czUsHM SPOTTED: In addition to Speaker Paul Ryan, also spotted at Notre Dame over the weekend: Chief Justice John Roberts showing one of his children around the campus. The chief went to high school near Notre Dame in LaPorte, Indiana ... Sen. Marco Rubio in first class cabin of Acela yesterday afternoon from NYC to DC, on the same train as Sen. Elizabeth Warren, who was in the quiet car ... Virginia Sen. Mark Warner having drinks at The Gage on Michigan Ave in Chicago yesterday evening. The Senate was in session. ... Texas Rep. Roger Williams -- a candidate to be the next NRCC chairman -- at a restaurant at The Waldorf in New York. --The underground happy hour crew gathered at Bobby Vans on 15th Street to celebrate birthday week girl Jackie Stewart. SPOTTED: Megan McCafferty, Sara Skubikowski, Jackie Stewart, Joon Suh, Charlie Patterson, Brian Reardon, Elizabeth Brooks, Alex Ford. BETH WILKINSON, partner and co-founder at Wilkinson Walsh + Eskovitz, was inducted as a Fellow of the American College of Trial Lawyers this week … MELINDA HENNEBERGER has become a member of USA TODAY’s board of contributors … JOSH EARNEST stopped by the NowThis newsroom yesterday afternoon for a Facebook Live Q&amp;A. http://bit.ly/2cFda64 HAPPENING TONIGHT – Tonight is the first of the five-part BuzzFeed Brews series featuring politicians from both sides focusing on key issues in 2017. First up: Sens. Cory Booker and Mike Lee on criminal justice reform at 7 p.m. at the Newseum. LATE-NIGHT BEST – Stephen Colbert, “Did Trump End The Birther Controversy, Or Is That His Biggest Lie Yet?” http://bit.ly/2cjiDJn ENGAGED -- Kareem Dale and Natasha Burroughs were engaged at the Grand Hyatt over the weekend during the CBC conference -- where they first connected in 2012. Kareem is former special assistant to the president for disability policy in the White House and current director and senior counsel with Discover Financial Services. Natasha is a communications professional and cousin of Rep. David Scott, the Democrat from Georgia. Pics http://bit.ly/2cFjESc … http://bit.ly/2d1difn NEW POLITICO PRO hires – Marty Kady emails the staff: “Angela Greiling Keane is joining our team as deputy technology editor. Angela is a veteran of Bloomberg News, where she most recently served as a White House correspondent. ... Ted Hesson is joining the Labor and Employment team as a reporter. ... He’s been writing and editing immigration and economic stories for Vice, National Journal, and Upworthy for the past year. ... Adam Cancryn is joining the health care team on the providers beat. Adam was a senior reporter at S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence.” --HuffPost has hired Emily McCombs as their new Parents Editorial Director. She previously “served as Executive Editor at xoJane, the site she launched with Jane Pratt in 2011, and most recently was Executive Editor at Elite Daily.” BIRTHDAYS: Ashley Tate-Gilmore, director of White House Travel Office – Nedra’s 2013 profile http://yhoo.it/1F9jFpf … Keith Mason, former Clinton WH official and former COS to Georgia Gov. Zell Miller who is “still very close to both Clintons and raising $ for Hillary” (h/t Paul Begala) … digital media guru Joe Mansour, “leading the digital practice for @FP1Strategies by day. Whiskey lover &amp; dog owner by night,” per his Twitter ... Peter Flaherty ... Carter Lavin, membership coordinator of California Solar Energy Industries Association and proud resident of Oakland, Calif., is 28 ... Cathy Straight, managing editor of CNN Digital (h/ts Carl Lavin) ... Deborah Roberts is 56 ... Crystal Wallingford, marketing events coordinator at Norton Rose Fulbright US LLP and a Karen Hughes alum ... Alejandra Campoverdi, director of multicultural content at the L.A. Times and former White House deputy director of Hispanic media (h/t Ben Chang) ... Moira Bagley Smith ... WashTimes’ Rowan Scarborough ... Kristen Holmes of CNN ... Politico alum Shaun Waterman, now editor in chief of Fed Scoop … Politico alum Margaret Burge, events manager at Fed Scoop … NPR news editor and blogger Lauren Hodges … Bloomberg’s Drew Singer ... Douglas Sellers ... Aniello Alioto, global engagement manager at Greenpeace International ... Dan Henning, producer for Sirius XM Radio and a Bill Press alum ... Max Root is 21 ... Graham Vyse, politics editor of InsideSources ... … Van Jones, CNN commentator and co-founder of Rebuild the Dream ... NPR’s Neda Ulaby ... Marty Tolchin is 88 ... Melissa Jane Kronfeld ... Asher Allen, son of Jon ... Francesca Craig, social secretary at the French Embassy ... Maureen Shanahan, SVP at SKDKnickerbocker ... Valerie Lapinski, head of video for Guardian US and a Time alum ... former Rep. Walt Minnick (D-Idaho) is 74 … Adam Howard, COS for Rep. Mike Turner ... Terry “Big Guy” Gilfillan … Mark Mullery … Kenneth Maresco … Ashley O’Connor … Caitlin Blair … Sarah Hawkins ... Reena Flores, writer/video producer at CBS Politics ... Nancy Bocskor, an NRCC alum ... Sarah Hawkins Warren ... Riyad Hammad ... Sally Wendkos Olds ... Mardi O’Shaughnessy … Vanessa Kirsch ... Nancy Godfrey ... Carl Zichella ... Angie Schiavoni, the pride of Madison, Wisc. ... Sara O’Keefe ... John Judge ... Clay McClure (h/ts Teresa Vilmain) SUBSCRIBE to the Playbook family: POLITICO Playbook http://politi.co/1M75UbX ... New York Playbook http://politi.co/1ON8bqW … Florida Playbook http://politi.co/1OypFe9 ... New Jersey Playbook http://politi.co/1HLKltF ... Massachusetts Playbook http://politi.co/1Nhtq5v ... Illinois Playbook http://politi.co/1N7u5sb ... California Playbook http://politi.co/2bLvcPl ... Brussels Playbook http://politi.co/1FZeLcw ... All our political and policy tipsheets http://politi.co/1M75UbX</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>78</end>
        <start>9</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>730</end>
        <start>79</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1206</end>
        <start>731</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1228</end>
        <start>1207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1278</end>
        <start>1229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2366</end>
        <start>1279</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2631</end>
        <start>2367</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2945</end>
        <start>2632</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3659</end>
        <start>2946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4066</end>
        <start>3660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4845</end>
        <start>4067</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5393</end>
        <start>4846</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5610</end>
        <start>5394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6313</end>
        <start>5611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6631</end>
        <start>6314</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6949</end>
        <start>6632</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7350</end>
        <start>6950</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8384</end>
        <start>7351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8595</end>
        <start>8385</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8821</end>
        <start>8596</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9266</end>
        <start>8822</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9401</end>
        <start>9267</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9457</end>
        <start>9402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>9723</end>
        <start>9458</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10217</end>
        <start>9724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10433</end>
        <start>10218</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>10626</end>
        <start>10434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11083</end>
        <start>10627</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11722</end>
        <start>11084</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>11991</end>
        <start>11723</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>12665</end>
        <start>11992</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>13360</end>
        <start>12666</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>13809</end>
        <start>13361</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>14241</end>
        <start>13810</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>14405</end>
        <start>14242</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15105</end>
        <start>14406</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15741</end>
        <start>15106</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>15925</end>
        <start>15742</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>16439</end>
        <start>15926</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>17211</end>
        <start>16440</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>17336</end>
        <start>17212</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>18172</end>
        <start>17337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>18246</end>
        <start>18173</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>18694</end>
        <start>18247</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>19244</end>
        <start>18695</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>19452</end>
        <start>19245</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>19705</end>
        <start>19453</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20339</end>
        <start>19706</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20593</end>
        <start>20340</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>20932</end>
        <start>20594</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21176</end>
        <start>20933</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21306</end>
        <start>21177</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>21783</end>
        <start>21307</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22344</end>
        <start>21784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>22577</end>
        <start>22345</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24034</end>
        <start>22578</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>24920</end>
        <start>24035</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>25400</end>
        <start>24921</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1834</end>
        <start>1472</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2088</end>
        <start>1881</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2319</end>
        <start>2116</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2397</end>
        <start>2381</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2530</end>
        <start>2476</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2608</end>
        <start>2560</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3286</end>
        <start>3036</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3884</end>
        <start>3661</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4040</end>
        <start>3898</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4158</end>
        <start>4089</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4822</end>
        <start>4187</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4912</end>
        <start>4850</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>5367</end>
        <start>4954</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>6605</end>
        <start>5652</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>7456</end>
        <start>7368</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8360</end>
        <start>7484</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8414</end>
        <start>8401</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8516</end>
        <start>8446</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8571</end>
        <start>8560</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>8892</end>
        <start>8836</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9242</end>
        <start>8896</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9722</end>
        <start>9529</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10285</end>
        <start>10266</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>10362</end>
        <start>10340</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11166</end>
        <start>11134</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11699</end>
        <start>11170</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>11965</end>
        <start>11740</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12040</end>
        <start>12008</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12639</end>
        <start>12074</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12749</end>
        <start>12689</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>13336</end>
        <start>12793</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>13786</end>
        <start>13460</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>14154</end>
        <start>13904</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>14464</end>
        <start>14421</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15079</end>
        <start>14503</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15211</end>
        <start>15129</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>15901</end>
        <start>15239</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16414</end>
        <start>15947</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>16554</end>
        <start>16473</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>17187</end>
        <start>16590</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>17412</end>
        <start>17352</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18223</end>
        <start>17444</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18306</end>
        <start>18251</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18668</end>
        <start>18331</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>18788</end>
        <start>18715</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>19221</end>
        <start>18817</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>19677</end>
        <start>19548</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21283</end>
        <start>21213</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22343</end>
        <start>21839</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22576</end>
        <start>22437</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22846</end>
        <start>22787</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>22992</end>
        <start>22901</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>24476</end>
        <start>24469</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>9457</end>
        <start>9267</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Government funding battle could SLIP to next week -- Trump talks debate strategy with O’REILLY -- THE PLAYBOOK FOOD TRUCK -- MOOK MEMO: How we’ll win</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/tipsheets/playbook/2016/09/government-funding-battle-likely-to-slip-to-next-week-trump-talks-debate-strategy-with-oreilly-the-playbook-food-truck-mook-memo-how-well-win-216401?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
