<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kim Smith</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/hillary-acts-healthy-rally/">
        <end>158</end>
        <start>143</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wnd.com/2016/09/bill-clintons-longtime-pal-hillary-losing-her-mental-capabilities/?cat_orig=health">
        <end>504</end>
        <start>501</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/confused-hillary-benghazi-cant/">
        <end>691</end>
        <start>672</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/hillary-ushered-medical-episode/">
        <end>882</end>
        <start>864</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/new-national-poll-hillary-sicker/">
        <end>1755</end>
        <start>1741</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>One of former President Bill Clinton’s oldest friends has come forward and said what she believed was wrong with Democrat presidential nominee Hillary Clinton, and if she’s right, it could be detrimental to the former secretary of state. Dolly Kyle, author of “Hillary the Other Woman,” said Clinton has been “’cruisin’ for a bruisin’,” because she’s so angry and driven by rage. “People like that eventually break down, physically.” “Hillary Clinton is not physically fit to be president,” Kyle told WND. “Anyone who believes that she is has their eyes closed. If she was in a wheelchair or blind or something like that, she could still do the job. But she is losing her mental capabilities, she’s suffering from real cognitive impairment.” Kyle, an award-winning lawyer, also said Clinton is showing evidence of emotional instability, memory loss and difficulty carrying out tasks. These symptoms coupled with Clinton’s paranoia and desire to control could only result in a psychological disaster. “That paranoia, that tendency to be a control freak, has always been a part of her personality,” Kyle said, and it’s simply not a good combination for anyone — much less the president of the United States. Kyle said she wrote her book because she wanted everyone to know the truth about Hillary Clinton — and Clinton’s health was just one troubling aspect of a larger picture. Clinton is addicted to power, and will stop at nothing to get what she wants — even if it means jeopardizing her health and the Democrat party, according to Kyle. “She has been running for president ever since she took hold of Billy Clinton’s coattails so many decades ago in 1971,” the lawyer said. This was more bad news for Clinton, who has struggled to keep a positive image while deflecting scandals not only about her health but about her character and her ability to lead this country. Share this story and let us know what you think about Dolly Kyle’s claim that Hillary Clinton is losing her mental capacities. What do you think about Clinton's fitness for office? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>237</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>433</end>
        <start>238</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>741</end>
        <start>434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>883</end>
        <start>742</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>999</end>
        <start>884</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1205</end>
        <start>1000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1376</end>
        <start>1206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1539</end>
        <start>1377</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1676</end>
        <start>1540</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1869</end>
        <start>1677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1996</end>
        <start>1870</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2080</end>
        <start>1997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>285</end>
        <start>261</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>335</end>
        <start>310</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>432</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>489</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>740</end>
        <start>507</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1095</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1658</end>
        <start>1541</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Decades-Old Clinton Friend Comes Forward, Says She Knows What’s Happening to Hillary</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/clinton-friend-happening-hillary/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-21&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
