<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>New York Rep. Peter King rejected former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton’s focus on the need for law enforcement to do a better job of building trust with American Muslims. Instead, the 11-term congressman called for more surveillance within the community. “I disagree with her when she puts the emphasis on building trust with the Muslim community, they have no reason not to trust the police,” King said on MSNBC shortly after Clinton answered questions from the press on the weekend’s bombing in Manhattan. Story Continued Below King is not new to this topic. His insistence to hold hearings on homegrown radicalization within Islam drew comparisons to Sen. Joseph McCarthy’s infamous communist witch hunt. (King has said he considers such attacks on him a "badge of honor.") As she has before, Clinton called for an intelligence surge to thwart ISIL’s efforts to inspire terror, but cautioned against a broader offensive against a faith. But the only way to gather such intelligence, King said, is to step up surveillance. “So listen, it's not going to be the handshake of a friendship that's going to bring Muslim Americans outside,” King said. “To get more intelligence, you have to do that by surveillance, by undercovers. That’s what has been done with every other ethnic group in this country when there is crime, whether it's the Westies and the Irish, whether it’s the Italians and the mafia, that's how you do it. We shouldn't be pandering to political correctness."</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>259</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>512</end>
        <start>260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>534</end>
        <start>513</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>944</end>
        <start>535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1029</end>
        <start>945</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1481</end>
        <start>1030</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>397</end>
        <start>261</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1140</end>
        <start>1031</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Rep. Peter King: We shouldn't be 'pandering' to political correctness</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/peter-king-pandering-political-correctness-228356?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
