<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sonja Bochow</author>
    <links href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2016/09/18/officials-probe-bombings-stabbings-in-three-u-s-cities-in-12-hour-span.html">
        <end>68</end>
        <start>48</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ap_16262161072408_237b644b5d3f3387d64fcbb96ca12e2e.nbcnews-ux-2880-1000-e1474243189565.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>As far as terrorism is concerned, yesterday was a good and a bad day for Americans. In addition to a knife wielding Allah chanting attacker in a Minnesota mall, who injured 7 before being shot dead by an off duty police officer, there was an undetonated bomb found in Seaside Park in NJ and 2 bombs found in the Chelsea neighborhood of Manhattan, one undetonated and one detonated, which injured 29 people. At this juncture, police are saying that all three devices appear to have been made by the same person. It was a good day in that no intended victims died. And it was a bad day in that these incidents expose how vulnerable Americans are to these kinds of attacks, especially in urban areas with large numbers of people in them. Terrorists in America look like regular people. They are not wearing all black outfits and masks, or marching in groups down the middle of the street. They look like shoppers, coworkers and fellow subway riders. It is difficult to identify terrorists and that makes it difficult to discover their plans and stop therm. What we need to remember is this; these are not random attacks. They are, most times, planned out and carried out by radical Islamic terrorists who absolutely hate western civilization. When or if we see something odd or suspicious, we must say something. If a guy is standing in line at Walmart buying 4 pressure cookers, that’s something odd. We cannot assume that everyone around has our best interests in mind. If you see something, say something.  We need a President who will get serious about vetting immigrants, stemming the tide of refugees and illegal immigrants and keeping Americans safe. We know which person will do that if elected and it isn’t Hillary. If Hillary wins, she will bring more refugees in. She has said it. If Trump wins, he will put an end to our destructive immigration policy. And that is what he has said. The safety of Americans on our own soil must be paramount. It is time to get serious about which people we let in and which ones we don’t. There are 7 knife victims and 29 bombing victims who deserved better. They deserve a government that puts them first. While the knife attacker in the mall was thankfully taken out by an armed officer, New York City Police Commissioner James P. O’Neill said “I am concerned, we have a bomb that detonated and no one apprehended.” That’s right, the bomber is still out there. If you see something say something…before you can’t.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>736</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1507</end>
        <start>737</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1508</end>
        <start>1508</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1893</end>
        <start>1509</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2150</end>
        <start>1894</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2459</end>
        <start>2151</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2460</end>
        <start>2460</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2461</end>
        <start>2461</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2462</end>
        <start>2462</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2358</end>
        <start>2289</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>TERROR IN THE USA: Bombs Found In NY &amp; NJ Made By Same Person [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/terror-usa-bombs-found-ny-nj-made-person-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
