<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Doug Giles</author>
    <links href="http://web.archive.org/web/20040627142700/eastandard.net/headlines/news26060403.htm">
        <end>968</end>
        <start>948</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Please disable your Ad Blocker in order to interact with the site. Well THAT’S Weird. If the Birther movement is racist… does that mean that the person who wrote this had it in for Obama? What if that person is … Obama? Breitbart put this out, taken from the AP, entitled ““Kenyan-born Obama all set for US Senate” That was June 2004. Kenyan-born US Senate hopeful, Barrack Obama, appeared set to take over the Illinois Senate seat after his main rival, Jack Ryan, dropped out of the race on Friday night amid a furor over lurid sex club allegations. The allegations that horrified fellow Republicans and caused his once-promising candidacy to implode in four short days have given Obama a clear lead as Republicans struggled to fetch an alternative. As far as we know, Barack Obama never refuted this article. It’s still out there on the internet. Here’s a screen capture:  Here’s the bottom half of the same article with AP attribution.  And the link to the original. That’s not actually as weird as the one all the way back in 1991. That was Obama’s publicist. Here’s the quote: Breitbart News has obtained a promotional booklet produced in 1991 by Barack Obama’s then-literary agency, Acton &amp; Dystel, which touts Obama as “born in Kenya and raised in Indonesia and Hawaii.” The booklet, which was distributed to “business colleagues” in the publishing industry, includes a brief biography of Obama among the biographies of eighty-nine other authors represented by Acton &amp; Dystel. It also promotes Obama’s anticipated first book, Journeys in Black and White–which Obama abandoned, later publishing Dreams from My Father instead. If Obama is contradicting himself, the only real question is, which lie do we write of as him cynically manipulating an audience for personal gain? If his birth in America is valid — as we are led to believe? Why lie about it? Unless playing the ‘foreigner’ card gave him illegitimate access to preferential opportunities or tuition costs. In which case, he is a lying turd who cheated someone more deserving out of … whatever. A Harvard Education, possibly. Because if That WASN’T a lie… then something else MUST be. That ‘something else’ being his American birth and Citizenship. Which are prerequisites to his presidency. The quote can be read in context at Breitbart. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>66</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>187</end>
        <start>67</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>219</end>
        <start>188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>334</end>
        <start>220</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>550</end>
        <start>335</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>551</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>810</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>873</end>
        <start>811</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>874</end>
        <start>874</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>938</end>
        <start>875</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>939</end>
        <start>939</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>969</end>
        <start>940</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1035</end>
        <start>970</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>1036</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1277</end>
        <start>1082</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1483</end>
        <start>1278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1631</end>
        <start>1484</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1779</end>
        <start>1632</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2090</end>
        <start>1780</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2256</end>
        <start>2091</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2303</end>
        <start>2257</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Clash Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>313</end>
        <start>273</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1276</end>
        <start>1227</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>1317</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>810</end>
        <start>335</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1631</end>
        <start>1082</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>DEAR CNN: The AP, In 2004, Said Your Boy Obama Was BORN In This Particular Country</title>
    <uri>http://clashdaily.com/2016/09/dear-cnn-ap-2004-said-boy-obama-born-particular-country/?utm_source=referral&amp;utm_medium=facebook.com&amp;utm_campaign=lasmpfb</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
