<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rob Groce</author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/magazine/gallery/2016/03/foreign-cartoonists-trump-000621?slide=0">
        <end>781</end>
        <start>773</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2014/04/140413-total-lunar-eclipse-myths-space-culture-science/">
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>1280</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/magazine/gallery/2016/03/foreign-cartoonists-trump-000621?slide=0">
        <end>781</end>
        <start>773</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>All the excitement about the 2016 presidential election isn’t limited to the U.S. alone. Media from around the globe are covering this race, too. And just like U.S. media, so too is foreign press particularly keeping a watchful eye on – you guessed it – Republican frontrunner Donald Trump. He’s been a hot topic in international articles, editorials and broadcasts, and which pertain to everything from his bizarre and xenophobic statements to the violence at his campaign events. One particularly effective way that foreign media have been able to express their opinions on The Donald is through political cartoons. Those editorials of art can capture a lot more public attention, and often with a lot more punch. Like these 12 in particular (first collected by Politico): By Christo Komarnitski  by Petar Pismestrovic of Kleine Zeitung    By Micheal De Adder of the Halifax Chronicle Herald By Paresh Nath of The Khaleej Times This one isn’t against Trump alone, though. See what appears to be Hillary Clinton on the left? The cartoon insinuates that Trump is in the race just to make sure Clinton has an easy win in November. The phrase translates word-for-word to “Toward an eclipse of the moon” – or “Toward a lunar eclipse.” It seems to refer to legends about lunar eclipses (or “blood moons”) being bad luck, and how (at least) one culture would try to avoid that bad luck. In ancient Mesopotamia, a lunar eclipse was believed to indicate seven demons were coming to Earth to attack a king. In response, one commoner would falsely pose as the king – a body double who would take the harm in case the demons attacked. (And when the lunar eclipse was over, the pretend king would be killed.) In other words, then, this one implies that Trump is in the race only as a pretend candidate who could get Republican Party nomination, but who will only fall to Clinton in the general election. By Bryan Adcock of The Independent  By Emad Hajjaj By Dan Murphy    By Ramses Morales    By Joep Bertrams  Featured image clipped from political cartoon by Bryan Adcock of The Independent (Scotland), acquired from Politico </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>147</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>489</end>
        <start>148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>723</end>
        <start>490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>783</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>806</end>
        <start>784</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>807</end>
        <start>807</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>849</end>
        <start>808</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>852</end>
        <start>850</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>853</end>
        <start>853</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>906</end>
        <start>854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>942</end>
        <start>907</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1144</end>
        <start>943</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1413</end>
        <start>1145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1731</end>
        <start>1414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1926</end>
        <start>1732</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1961</end>
        <start>1927</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1962</end>
        <start>1962</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1978</end>
        <start>1963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1992</end>
        <start>1979</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1993</end>
        <start>1993</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1996</end>
        <start>1994</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2014</end>
        <start>1997</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2015</end>
        <start>2015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2018</end>
        <start>2016</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2036</end>
        <start>2019</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2037</end>
        <start>2037</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2154</end>
        <start>2038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2155</end>
        <start>2155</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <title>How The Rest Of The World Sees Donald Trump: 12 Foreign Political Cartoons</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/how-the-rest-of-the-world-sees-donald-trump-12-foreign-political-cartoons/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
