<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Amber</author>
    <links href="http://madworldnews.com/police-islamic-refugee/">
        <end>30</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.judicialwatch.org/blog/2016/06/islamic-refugee-gas-pipeline-plans-arrested-new-mexico-border-county/">
        <end>657</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.truthrevolt.org/news/islamic-refugee-gas-pipeline-plans-arrested-near-mexican-border">
        <end>1949</end>
        <start>1907</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.truthrevolt.org/news/islamic-refugee-gas-pipeline-plans-arrested-near-mexican-border">
        <end>2590</end>
        <start>2566</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>This actually happened in June, but is just as pertinent today, especially with 20,000 to 30,000 Syrian refugees due to arrive in the US next weekend. Police in New Mexico pulled over a woman driving a vehicle. The drive was an undocumented Muslim woman from the Middle East… that’s bad enough, but what is even worse is what she had in her car. The woman had plans for a gas pipeline with her. This just screams ‘terrorism’. I have no idea why they pulled her over, but it was a very good thing they did. It has been widely reported that hundreds, if not thousands, of Islamic illegal immigrants are trying to get across our southern border. Judicial Watch released a report last summer saying that Mexican cartels are smuggling foreigners from countries with terrorist links into the country. They furthermore released a second report just a few months ago saying that Islamic terror groups residing in Mexico have begun traveling to America in order to seek out potential targets. That border has now become a literal ticking time bomb of terrorism. It’s not ‘if’, it’s ‘when’ we get hit with a horrific terror attack that could kill thousands and it can all be laid at the feet of Barack Obama and the Marxists who are for open borders. They want America to be like Europe… Europe which is toast because of the Hijrah Migration and terrorism. No thanks. From Mad World News: Police in New Mexico recently pulled over a vehicle only to find that it was being driven by an undocumented, Middle Eastern woman. However, the situation got worse when they saw what she had in the car with her at the time – and now the surrounding area is on high alert. Judicial Watch indicates that a deputy sheriff in Luna County, New Mexico pulled over an unidentified “Islamic refugee” for an undisclosed reason. Luckily for everyone involved, the minor traffic infraction turned into so much more when the officer found plans for a gas pipeline in her possession. The pipeline is in Deming, New Mexico, and U.S. Border Patrol and the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s (FBI) Joint Terrorism Task Forces (JTTF) have been sent to the area to investigate. Unfortunately, the find could only be indicative of what is to come. Obama could bring in up to 250,000 Islamic refugees this next year. He is seeding them across America in conservative strongholds in an effort to change the voting demographic and terraform the US into an Islamic nation. Bringing in unvetted Islamists guarantees ISIS terrorists in their midst and Obama is good with that. What’s a few dead infidels to him? The plans this woman had in her possession include the region around the small town of Deming about 35 miles north of the Mexican border and 60 miles west of Las Cruces. Thanks to high unemployment, poverty, crime and a horrible public education system, Deming has been named No. 1 on a list of the “ten worst places” to live in New Mexico. The entire region is considered a High Intensity Drug Trafficking Area due to large amounts of meth, heroin, cocaine and marijuana smuggled through the state by Mexican traffickers. The brutal Juárez and Sinaloa cartels operate in that area. The media has swept this under the rug, but it is a severe national security threat. This election may pivot on it, especially if we get hit. Our leaders owe it to their constituents to put our safety first, lock down that border and vet these refugees and illegal immigrants. Before we lose countless Americans to terrorism that is.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>505</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>983</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1357</end>
        <start>984</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1378</end>
        <start>1358</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1651</end>
        <start>1379</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1950</end>
        <start>1652</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2207</end>
        <start>1951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2565</end>
        <start>2208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3148</end>
        <start>2566</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3482</end>
        <start>3149</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3483</end>
        <start>3483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3484</end>
        <start>3484</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1770</end>
        <start>1755</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2882</end>
        <start>2866</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1166</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>ALERT: Police Pull Over ‘Islamic Refugee,’ Horrified To See What Was In The Car</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/police-islamic-refugee-car/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
