<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Antiphon Freeman</author>
    <links href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/andrewkaczynski/mark-cubans-questions-if-trump-is-actually-a-billionaire?utm_term=.lgNBngMMw#.jeJgy3ZZK">
        <end>305</end>
        <start>298</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.gettyimages.com/license/457025958">
        <end>1779</end>
        <start>1767</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Dallas Mavericks owner Mark Cuban sat down with 88 WABC’s Bernie and Sid on Wednesday and questioned whether Donald Trump was even a billionaire. Talk about hitting the Donald where it hurts the most…. And – Cuban is even ‘willing to bet’ he knows how much cash Trump has on hand, while stating he’s a lot wealthier than him: “It’s not even close, I do,” Cuban said. “Before all the Trumpians jump on me on who has more money, the reason I know is when you file your federal election campaign reports, you have to list all your cash and liquid securities and bonds. You have to list them one by one. So we know without any question that as of May 27, Donald doesn’t have more than $165 million in cash and securities and bonds.” “And trust me, I’ve got a lot of more than that in cash, securities, and bonds,” he continued. “And so you know, I’m willing to bet dimes against dollars that that’s pretty much what he’s got.”  Cuban then went on to say he thinks Trump is acting like a ‘desperate’ man trying to make money by putting his name on anything and everything. “I asked, ‘what the hell are you doing?’ Are you that desperate for money?’ Seriously. So when you’re putting your name on steaks, and you’re putting your name on water, you’re putting your name on playing cards, you’re putting your name on all this nonsense, right? You’re not gonna make big bucks, no matter what. It’s not like Trump Steaks were gonna make him $100 million. It’s not like it was gonna make him $5 million.” Cuban does have a point. If Trump is really that successful at real estate, why then does he find himself needing to do all these other little things, half of which have gone bankrupt? Featured Image via Getty Images.  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>206</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>338</end>
        <start>207</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>753</end>
        <start>339</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>963</end>
        <start>754</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>964</end>
        <start>964</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1112</end>
        <start>965</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1207</end>
        <start>1113</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1562</end>
        <start>1208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1747</end>
        <start>1563</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1780</end>
        <start>1748</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1783</end>
        <start>1781</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>963</end>
        <start>339</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1562</end>
        <start>1113</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Mark Cuban: ‘Willing To Bet’ Trump’s Not A Billionaire – Here’s How Much Cash He Really Has…</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/mark-cuban-willing-to-bet-trumps-not-a-billionaire-heres-how-much-cash-he-really-has/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
