<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>A day after autocratic Egyptian leader Abdel Fattah al-Sisi said he had “no doubt” Donald Trump would make a strong leader, the Republican nominee returned the favor, praising Sisi as a “fantastic guy.” Sitting down with Fox Business’ Lou Dobbs, Trump touted the “chemistry” the two politicians shared during a special meeting on the sidelines of the United Nations General Assembly Monday. Story Continued Below “I thought it was very productive. He’s a fantastic guy,” Trump said of Sisi. “I thought it was a great meeting. We met for a long time, actually. There was a good chemistry there. You know when you have good chemistry with people. There was a good feeling between us.” Trump also praised the foreign leader’s handling of the Egyptian coup d’etat of 2013 that removed former President Mohamed Morsi from power, a bloody transition that saw thousands of dissidents and protesters killed. “He took control of Egypt. And he really took control of it,” Trump said. Days prior, Trump lavished Sisi with praise, expressing support for the leader’s “strong support for Egypt’s war on terrorism, and how under a Trump administration, the United States of America will be a loyal friend, not simply an ally, that Egypt can count on in the days and years ahead." Trump has faced heavy criticism for praising authoritarian leaders like Russia’s Vladimir Putin. In an interview with CNN Thursday, Sisi expressed confidence in Trump’s leadership in light of their recent meeting. Asked by host Erin Burnett whether he shared a similar positive outlook of Trump’s opponent, Hillary Clinton, Sisi showed similar confidence. “Political parties in the United States would not allow candidates to reach that level unless they are qualified to lead a country the size of the United States of America,” Sisi replied.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>202</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>390</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>412</end>
        <start>391</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>682</end>
        <start>413</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>899</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>973</end>
        <start>900</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1265</end>
        <start>974</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1362</end>
        <start>1266</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1621</end>
        <start>1363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1809</end>
        <start>1622</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>81</end>
        <start>73</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>201</end>
        <start>187</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>273</end>
        <start>264</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>469</end>
        <start>414</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>681</end>
        <start>492</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>960</end>
        <start>901</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1794</end>
        <start>1056</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump praises Egypt's al-Sisi: 'He's a fantastic guy'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-praises-egypts-al-sisi-hes-a-fantastic-guy-228560?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
