<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/15/news/companies/donald-trump-ford-ceo-mark-fields/">
        <end>86</end>
        <start>64</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/15/news/companies/donald-trump-ford-ceo-mark-fields/">
        <end>503</end>
        <start>491</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/15/news/companies/donald-trump-ford-ceo-mark-fields/">
        <end>738</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/15/news/companies/donald-trump-ford-ceo-mark-fields/">
        <end>948</end>
        <start>927</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.businesstrajectory.com/ford-says-will-fully-autonomous-car-2021/">
        <end>1756</end>
        <start>1737</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Earlier this week, as part of an interview he gave to Fox News, Donald Trump announced he had just learned that Ford Motor Company was about to “fire all their employees in the United States and…move to Mexico.” Trump went on to add that when he becomes President, Ford would have to pay a 35 percent tax on any car they send back to the United States for sale. Wow! That’s big news! It’s also, like 99.9 percent of what Donald Trump says, a gigantic lie, according to Ford CEO Mark Fields, who told CNN: “It’s really unfortunate when politics get in the way of the facts.” CNN host Poppy Harlow then asked Fields, would Ford cut any American jobs as part of its plans to build a new manufacturing plant in Mexico? To that, Fields replied: “Absolutely not. Zero. Not one job will be lost. Most of our investment is here in the US. And that’s the way it will continue to be.”   Ford has 85,000 workers in the United States, and that number has risen by 50 percent over the last five years. It currently employs 8,800 people in Mexico, and the new plant will create 2,800 additional jobs there. So once again we see that Donald Trump will say anything at all in order to muddy the waters and make it appear that he is the savior of the American economy. That’s a powerful message, especially in the industrial heartland–states like Michigan, Ohio, Pennsylvania, and Wisconsin–where Trump is hoping to score big on Election Day. But Trump has financially screwed over thousands of small businesses and vendors over the years to have any legitimate clout on the economic issue. All he offers is more tax cuts for the rich and empty words. And lies. Lots and lots of lies. Tax those and we could pay off the national debt. Featured Image Via Business Trajectory  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>363</end>
        <start>2</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>506</end>
        <start>364</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>575</end>
        <start>507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>741</end>
        <start>576</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>876</end>
        <start>742</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>877</end>
        <start>877</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>878</end>
        <start>878</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1094</end>
        <start>879</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1719</end>
        <start>1095</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1758</end>
        <start>1720</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1760</end>
        <start>1759</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Liberal America</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>210</end>
        <start>145</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>572</end>
        <start>506</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>873</end>
        <start>741</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Ford Motor CEO Says Trump Is Lying AGAIN! Company Is NOT Moving U.S. Operations To Mexico</title>
    <uri>http://www.liberalamerica.org/2016/09/17/ford-motor-ceo-says-trump-lying-company-not-moving-u-s-operations-mexico/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
