<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Blair Patterson</author>
    <links href="http://insider.foxnews.com/2016/09/18/judge-jeanine-pirro-anti-trump-hypocrisy-stunning-insists-creating-race-issues-hater">
        <end>2156</end>
        <start>2148</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Judge Jeanine Pirro has been outspoken against Hillary Clinton for some time, but never more so when the infamous “deplorable” comment was mentioned by ol’ Hillary. In Pirro’s most recent opening statement, she absolutely UNLOADED on Clinton, and it’s one you’re going to want to play on repeat. “This week, Hillary’s all better, and she and her surrogates call on all Americans—all but us ‘Deplorables’—to stand up and repudiate Donald Trump’s divisive rhetoric—through their own divisive rhetoric!” Pirro said in her Opening Statement. “Hillary is so desperate for the black vote that she insists on creating race issues,” she said, playing a clip of Clinton last week accusing Trump of “describ[ing] the black community in such insulting and ignorant terms.” “Isn’t Donald Trump speaking to the problems of the minority communities in inner cities? Maybe your recent health issues have prevented you from grasping the reality of inner city crime,” Pirro said, adding that her criticisms of Trump could easily be an indictment of her own actions. “You choose to create division—you look for a target: the police, Donald Trump, a common enemy. Then you promise the world and you have the gall to actually say “imagine someone who distorts the truth to fit a very narrow view of the world…who sees someone who doesn’t look like him and agree with him, and thinks that person must not be a real America.” “This is exactly what you said when you called us ‘deplorable’,” Pirro said. “I know you have double-vision and memory problems—documented by the FBI—but your hypocrisy is stunning. You’re the ‘hater’. You’re the one who said ‘we are above all that’.”  Hillary Clinton is the one that’s calling racism when it’s the Democrats, PROVEN by the DNC email leak, who are the true racists. They preach tolerance and equality, but they utilize that platform to keep minority populations at bay and not let them thrive. It’s absolutely appalling and we shouldn’t stand for it. This is just another nail in the political coffin for Clinton. Soon she’ll be gone from our minds and Trump will be president. You can make that happen this November. (Source: Fox News) </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>164</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>295</end>
        <start>165</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>537</end>
        <start>296</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>761</end>
        <start>538</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>762</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1403</end>
        <start>1049</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1480</end>
        <start>1404</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1655</end>
        <start>1481</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1656</end>
        <start>1656</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1971</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2138</end>
        <start>1972</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2157</end>
        <start>2139</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2158</end>
        <start>2158</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Yes Im Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>125</end>
        <start>115</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>499</end>
        <start>297</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>623</end>
        <start>539</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>760</end>
        <start>690</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>949</end>
        <start>763</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1402</end>
        <start>1050</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1467</end>
        <start>1405</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1654</end>
        <start>1482</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1655</end>
        <start>296</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Judge Jeanine Pirro Just Turned The Tables On Hillary Clinton</title>
    <uri>http://www.yesimright.com/judge-jeanine-pirro-just-turned-the-tables-on-hillary-clinton/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
