<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>ORLANDO — Tim Kaine and Mike Pence are both feeling more pressure to perform in their own vice presidential debate after Monday's caustic contest between Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton. Kaine spoke to Clinton shortly after, disclosing to a crowd at a Democratic field office here that his running mate's debate chops raise expectations for Kaine to match her. Story Continued Below "Man, you've really raised the bar. You put the kind of pressure on me that I like to really help my debate next Tuesday," Kaine recounted telling Clinton in a speech to field organizers here. Pence expressed similar sentiment, saying on Fox News he's been dusting off his Capitol Hill experience to get ready to go toe-to-toe with the Virginia senator. "Donald Trump raised the bar for his running mate last night,” Pence said. From there, however, the two vice presidential hopefuls' assessments diverged. Pence said that Trump took "command" of the stage while Kaine likened the GOP nominee to a heavyweight prizefighter on the verge of quitting. "If you're that rattled in the debate, try being president," Kaine said. "Donald Trump was up on the split screen like a boxer ready to go down on a TKO." Louis Nelson contributed to this report.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>187</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>361</end>
        <start>188</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>383</end>
        <start>362</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>576</end>
        <start>384</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>737</end>
        <start>577</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>812</end>
        <start>738</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1033</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1188</end>
        <start>1034</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1229</end>
        <start>1189</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Kaine, Pence both feel pressure after Monday's debate</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/tim-kaine-mike-pence-vice-presidential-debate-228778?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
