<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://www.tmz.com/2016/09/18/new-york-bomb-explosion-video-surveillance/">
        <end>307</end>
        <start>296</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/160918112909-11-chelsea-explosion-large-169.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/WireAP_bd83bb10ddc0456a9d2bec53de5b9f1f_16x9_1600.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/2016/09/17/explosion-new-york-chelsea-neighborhood/90605526/">
        <end>261</end>
        <start>257</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Footage of the explosion that took place in New York on Saturday night is now being shared across all social media sites. An explosion on Saturday night in what is known as New York’s “Chelsea neighborhood” left over 29 people injured. Mayor Bill de Blasio said that the explosion was definitely intentional, but as of now they do not believe it to be a specific terrorist threat. At a late night news conference after the explosion Blasio spoke saying that they are at full alert now. “There is no specific and credible threat to New York City from any terror organization. We believe at this point in time this was an intentional act. I want to assure all New Yorkers that the NYPD and … agencies are at full alert…Whatever the cause, New Yorkers will not be intimidated, they will not let anyone change who we are…”  The explosion on Saturday night wasn’t the only concern either. Authorities and examiners went searching the area on Sunday and found another explosive near the area of the explosion on Saturday night. A random pressure cooker was found about four blocks away from the site that the bomb went off. The police department tweeted around 2:30am stating that the device had been safely removed. “The suspicious device on West 27 Street in Chelsea has been safely removed by the NYPD Bomb Squad…”  New York Police Commissioner James O’Neill said that the explosion wasn’t a natural gas explosion but they also don’t have any other leads on the cause of the explosion either. They are treating the area as a crime scene in hopes to protect residents from harm. “The investigation is active and at this time an extensive search is being conducted. The area around the explosion site is being treated as a crime scene.” Watch the leaked video below, you can see the explosion and then you will see people running everywhere. This is so crazy!  Please pray for all of those who were injured….this has got to STOP!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>121</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>380</end>
        <start>122</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>485</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>818</end>
        <start>486</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>819</end>
        <start>819</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1117</end>
        <start>820</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1210</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1311</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1312</end>
        <start>1312</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1574</end>
        <start>1313</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1731</end>
        <start>1575</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1854</end>
        <start>1732</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1924</end>
        <start>1856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>205</end>
        <start>185</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>817</end>
        <start>487</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1310</end>
        <start>1212</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1730</end>
        <start>1576</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>818</end>
        <start>486</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1311</end>
        <start>1211</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1731</end>
        <start>1575</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Footage Leaked Of NYC Bombing, Watch Before It’s Deleted</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/news/breaking-footage-leaked-nyc-bombing-watch-deleted/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=nyc+bombing%2F9%2F19&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2Fnyc+bombing%2F9%2F19</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
