<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Zach Cartwright</author>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2016/09/20/you-can-sleep-tonight-knowing-the-klan-is-awake-fliers-like-these-are-showing-up-on-lawns-across-the-u-s/?tid=sm_fb">
        <end>403</end>
        <start>387</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.indystar.com/story/news/2016/07/24/fishers-residents-receive-pro-kkk-message-front-lawn/87503746/">
        <end>747</end>
        <start>714</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/intelligence-report/2016/year-hate-and-extremism">
        <end>1275</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The Ku Klux Klan — the most notorious white supremacist group in the country — is now advertising its presence with flyers and cryptic messaging. In the 15 months since white supremacist Dylann Roof’s mass shooting at the Emanuel AME church in Charleston, South Carolina, flyers promoting the Klan (KKK) have appeared in communities across the country. The Washington Post reported that flyers were seen in California, Indiana, Kansas, Michigan, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and other states. The flyers are often left on lawns inside plastic bags weighed down with rocks, along with various racist, Islamophobic, and anti-immigrant messages. One resident in Fishers, Indiana received a bag that included a KKK flyer along with a crudely written note bashing immigrants, minorities, and homosexuals. Ross Olsby told the Indianapolis Star he picked up approximately 200 bags on neighbors’ lawns so their children wouldn’t have to see them. “You think we made a lot of progress in the last 80 years, and I guess we have, but boy it’s 2016 and we still have work to do I guess,” Olsby said. Photo by Kaitlin Lange, Indianapolis Star The Southern Poverty Law Center (SPLC), which monitors and profiles hate groups across the US, said in their most recent “Year in Hate and Extremism” report that KKK groups have nearly tripled in size, suggesting racists have become more emboldened. In 2014, there were roughly 72 KKK affiliate groups in the US. By 2015, there were almost 200 KKK groups. 35-year-old Jaimi Hajzus, of Coudersport, Pennsylvania, said the ominous flyers started appearing in her neighborhood this past weekend. She told the Post that she’s worried Klan groups are trying to incite a race war with the incendiary flyers. “If this is actually a resurgence of a hateful and violent group, then we need to take a stance,” Hajzus said. KKK flyer, courtesy of Jaimi Hajzus for the Washington Post US Uncut’s attempts to call the “24-Hour Klanline” listed on the flyers were unsuccessful, and the mailbox associated with the number was full as of 12 PM Eastern on Wednesday afternoon.          </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>145</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>489</end>
        <start>146</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>935</end>
        <start>490</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1084</end>
        <start>936</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1126</end>
        <start>1085</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1482</end>
        <start>1127</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1728</end>
        <start>1483</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1839</end>
        <start>1729</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1899</end>
        <start>1840</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2086</end>
        <start>1900</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2088</end>
        <start>2087</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2089</end>
        <start>2089</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2091</end>
        <start>2090</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2092</end>
        <start>2092</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2093</end>
        <start>2093</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2094</end>
        <start>2094</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2095</end>
        <start>2095</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2096</end>
        <start>2096</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1071</end>
        <start>937</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1275</end>
        <start>1249</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1825</end>
        <start>1730</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1949</end>
        <start>1933</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>‘You can sleep tonight knowing the Klan is awake’: Ominous flyers appear across the US</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/can-sleep-tonight-knowing-klan-awake-ominous-flyers-appear-across-us/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
