<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.nationalreview.com/corner/440192/twitter-warns-against-andy-mccarthy-corner-post">
        <end>319</end>
        <start>265</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nationalreview.com/corner/440186/mulish-stupidity-clinton-obama-counterterrorism">
        <end>1607</end>
        <start>1603</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>An article by former assistant U.S. attorney Andrew C. McCarthy in National Review on Monday that is critical of Democrat Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton’s counterterrorism efforts has been censored by Twitter as being “unsafe” in their view. The article, titled “The Mulish Stupidity of Clinton-Obama Counterterrorism” when clicked on from Twitter, results in the following ominous-sounding warning:  Andrew McCarthy, who led the 1995 terrorism against  Sheikh Omar Abdel Rahman and eleven other radical Islamic terrorists, announced the censorship in a separate post on National Review on Monday evening. In the article, McCarthy makes the point that the today’s defenders of radical Islamic terrorism — progressive leftist Democrats — sound precisely like the attorney’s representing the Islamists in the cases he prosecuted in the 90’s. “As I have previously recounted, when I prosecuted the Blind Sheikh’s terrorist cell in the mid-Nineties, the defense lawyers for the jihadists – who sounded just like today’s anti-anti-terrorist progressives – claimed that their clients had been lured into terrorist activity by U.S. government policy and by the enticements of a government informant who spouted Islam-against-the-world rhetoric. In response to this fatuous contention, we put a very simple question to the jury: “What would it take to turn you into a mass-murderer?” What policy could be so bad, what rhetorical us-against-them flourishes so inspiring, that a person would join the terrorist cause and commit acts of barbarism?” Read more of the article that Twitter doesn’t want you to read HERE.  Email Subscribe</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>243</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>401</end>
        <start>244</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>402</end>
        <start>402</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>607</end>
        <start>403</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>841</end>
        <start>608</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1539</end>
        <start>842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1608</end>
        <start>1540</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1609</end>
        <start>1609</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1625</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politistick</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>227</end>
        <start>221</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>319</end>
        <start>265</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1376</end>
        <start>843</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1539</end>
        <start>842</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The hardest-hitting political news.</title>
    <uri>http://politistick.com/twitter-censors-national-review-article-critical-obama-hillary-unsafe/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
