<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matthew Dowd LZ GRANDERSON</author>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/issues/economic-growth.htm">
        <end>1628</end>
        <start>1613</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/issues/middle-class.htm">
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1783</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/chicago.htm">
        <end>2633</end>
        <start>2626</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>ABC News is bringing its original livestream series ‘Strait Talk with Matt &amp; LZ’ to the University of Detroit Mercy in front of a live audience on Monday, Sept. 19 at 7 p.m. ET for an open discussion about the biggest issues facing America this election cycle. ABC News Political Contributors Matthew Dowd and LZ Granderson, both Detroit natives, will be joined by Digital Host Amna Nawaz and ABC News Chief Political Correspondent Jonathan Karl as they talk with business leaders and community activists from the Motor City on key issues ranging from politics, race relations and law enforcement to religion and the economy. Dowd and Granderson opened up about the excitement behind bringing the show back to their hometown and why this conversation is needed right now.  "Then there are the topics that are important but not needle movers -- like gentrification. From New York to Los Angeles, the poor are being pushed out by rising rents and property taxes as developers reshape neighborhoods. Nestled in the shadows of the 'Detroit's recovery' narrative is the question of 'What will Detroit look like when it's over?' Take a look at Harlem: beautiful, yet void of the people and the history that made it an essential piece of Americana. Detroit is progressing toward that same fate and yet it cannot stay where it was. Solving this riddle is as important as creating jobs, whether it is on the news or not.” Dowd: “It's our birthplace and what formed us to a large degree as we went into our respective professions. Detroit really is the story of America. From modest beginnings on the frontier, to terrific economic growth from industrial revolution through mass production. Headquarters of the automobile, which symbolizes the freedom American's love. And the building of the middle class which really forms America in its unique position. And through the fall of Detroit because of loss of manufacturing, broken political governmental and corporate institutions. And now, rebuilding Detroit in whole new ways is taking place across America through entrepreneurs and innovation.”  "We are at a point of incredible disruption in all our institutions. And there is fear that our democracy might be broken and we can't do the things that need to be done. With two major party leaders distrusted and disliked by a majority of the country, and Americans facing this choice in a few weeks.” Granderson: “Politically Michigan is an important state and Detroit an important city because it really does capture the rural versus urban vote that can be found in numerous states. There is Miami and then there is Florida. There is Chicago and then Illinois. There is Detroit, then there are huge chunks of the state that couldn't be more different. Those differences are what both candidates are banking on and is a reason why neither is liked." "Honestly this cultural division has been going on for some time. Perhaps it's the personalities of the two doing the dividing that makes this year's campaign season particularly distasteful. But Detroit, a city that is 90 percent black, voted for a white mayor for the first time in decades. So once again Detroit can show the nation what happens when voters actively decide to shake up the status quo in the name of salvation.”   Jessica Care Moore | Poet, Detroit Advocate Ron Fournier | Associate Publisher, Crain’s Business Detroit Peter Cummings | Real Estate Developer Angie Reyes | Executive Director, Detroit Hispanic Development Corp Yusef Shakur | Neighborhood Activist Khaled Beydoun Associate Professor, University of Detroit Mercy Law Fatina Abdrabboh | Director, American Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee in Dearborn Chuck Stokes | Editorial &amp; Public Affairs Director, WXYZ-TV Ashley McGuire | Senior Fellow, The Catholic Association ‘Strait Talk with Matt &amp; LZ’ will be streamed live on ABCNews.com and on ABC News’ apps on mobile and OTT as well as ABC News’ Facebook page. Launched in September 2015, “Strait Talk with Matt &amp; LZ” is an original livestream series on politics and culture, hosted by ABC News Political Contributors Matthew Dowd and LZ Granderson. With over 30 shows to date, Dowd and Granderson host “Strait Talk” from ABC News Headquarters in New York and have brought the show to cities across the U.S, including Los Angeles, Austin and Detroit as well as Manchester for both of ABC News’ primary debates and Cleveland and Philadelphia for the 2016 conventions.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>625</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>771</end>
        <start>626</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>772</end>
        <start>772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1412</end>
        <start>773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2086</end>
        <start>1413</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2087</end>
        <start>2087</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2391</end>
        <start>2088</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2840</end>
        <start>2392</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3270</end>
        <start>2841</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3271</end>
        <start>3271</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3272</end>
        <start>3272</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3316</end>
        <start>3273</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3377</end>
        <start>3317</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3416</end>
        <start>3378</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3484</end>
        <start>3417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3521</end>
        <start>3485</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3589</end>
        <start>3522</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3674</end>
        <start>3590</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3734</end>
        <start>3675</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3791</end>
        <start>3735</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3933</end>
        <start>3792</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4439</end>
        <start>3934</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>ABC News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2088</end>
        <start>774</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4</end>
        <start>3</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>'Strait Talk with Matt &amp; LZ' To Stream Live from Detroit on Sept. 19</title>
    <uri>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/strait-talk-matt-lz-stream-live-detroit-september/story?id=42091125&amp;cid=abcnp_fb</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
