<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>eaglerising</author>
    <links href="http://dailycallernewsfoundation.org/2016/09/22/texas-school-our-teachers-are-armed-will-use-force-if-necessary/">
        <end>38</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/09/21/health/armed-teachers-sign-trnd/index.html?sr=twCNN092116armed-teachers-sign-trnd1122PMStoryLink&amp;linkId=29059181">
        <end>349</end>
        <start>342</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.ksat.com/news/medina-isd-warns-visitors-that-staff-may-be-armed">
        <end>741</end>
        <start>737</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.ksat.com/news/medina-isd-warns-visitors-that-staff-may-be-armed">
        <end>741</end>
        <start>737</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.ksat.com/news/medina-isd-warns-visitors-that-staff-may-be-armed">
        <end>741</end>
        <start>737</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>From the Daily Caller News Foundation: Teachers at a school in Texas might be armed and are willing to use whatever force needed to protect students, according to a sign posted outside the school district. Medina Independent School District placed a sign in front of one of its entrances Sept. 14 to warn people that teachers might be armed, reports CNN. “Please be aware that the staff at Medina ISD may be armed and will use whatever force is necessary to protect our students,” the sign says. The warning serves as a good way to drive away potential threats, according to the school’s superintendent. “I think that anybody who might have a thought about harming someone in mind might think twice about it,” Superintendent Penny White said, according to KSAT 12. “We’re 20 minutes or 25 minutes from Bandera. That’s our closest law enforcement.” White and Dr. James Lindstrom, a school board member, said no specific event spurred the sign, Lindstrom added it was posted due to the “the general environment nationally.” Jillian Sides, a mother with two sons at the school, thought the sign was a good way to keep away threats. “Schools have been a target for, for lack of a better word, crazy people, and I’m perfectly fine with it,” she told KSAT. Another mother disagreed, believing the sign could bring trouble. “I don’t know if that’s asking for trouble or not. I mean, you post a sign like that, it may bring trouble, unfortunately,” said Alisha Reagan, a mother of a third-grader. White would not name the teachers, if any, who are armed. The school plans to post two additional signs at other school entrances.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>38</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>205</end>
        <start>39</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>354</end>
        <start>206</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>495</end>
        <start>355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>603</end>
        <start>496</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>847</end>
        <start>604</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1021</end>
        <start>848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1128</end>
        <start>1022</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1250</end>
        <start>1129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1316</end>
        <start>1251</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1488</end>
        <start>1317</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1546</end>
        <start>1489</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1619</end>
        <start>1547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1620</end>
        <start>1620</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1766</end>
        <start>1621</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1840</end>
        <start>1767</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>479</end>
        <start>356</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>708</end>
        <start>605</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>846</end>
        <start>766</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1020</end>
        <start>985</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1234</end>
        <start>1130</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1439</end>
        <start>1318</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1802</end>
        <start>1790</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Texas School Arms Teachers: “Will Use Whatever Force is Necessary”</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36959/texas-school-arms-teachers-will-use-whatever-force-is-necessary/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
