<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/jim-carrey-episode-480x360.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/jim-carrey-girlfriend-cathriona-white-suicide.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Cathriona-White-Jim-Carrey-May-18-2015.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/1443621601036.jpeg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Jim Carrey might just be saying goodbye to his acting career, this is so crazy. Jim Carrey is one of the most well-known actors across the world. He is mostly known for his role in comedy films such as “Ace Ventura” and “Dumb and Dumber.” Unfortunately, the actor is in some trouble and it might just be the end for him.  Jim Carrey was hit with hard news last September when he found out that his 28-year-old girlfriend Cathriona White committed suicide. Apparently she had left a suicide note to Jim before overdosing. After finding out about her death he immediately released a comment sharing how shocked and heartbroken he was. “I am shocked and deeply saddened by the passing of my sweet Cathriona. She was a truly kind and delicate Irish flower, too sensitive for this soil, to whom loving and being loved was all that sparkled. My heart goes out to her family and friends and to everyone who loved and cared about her. We have all been hit with a lightning bolt.”  When the police showed up to investigate the crime scene they found 3 different prescriptions on White’s nightstand. Ambien (sleep aid), Percocet (painkiller), and Propranolol (blood pressure/heart). TMZ reported that all of the medications were prescribed by the same doctor but they were under the name Arthur King, which was Jim Carrey’s alias. This wasn’t Cathriona’s first time trying to kill herself. IT was reported that she attempted an overdose in 2012 after her father passed away. Now Carrey is being ACCUSED of supplying his ex with the pills that took her life. The lawsuit claims that Carrey gave the pills to Cathriona just 3 or 4 days before her death. It also states that Jim tried to cover up the fact that he gave her the pills by texting her asking her if she had taken them from his house. Not only that, but apparently she was already taking painkillers weeks before her death.  Of course, Carrey knew that she has struggled with depression and suicidal thoughts so it is crazy to think that he would actually give her the pills knowing her mental state. It was understood that the couple had broken up not long before Cathriona committed suicide and she even said that she couldn’t go on without him in her suicide note. “I’ve spent 3 days now in disbelief that you’re not here. I can go on brokenhearted and try to put the pieces back. I could, I just don’t have the will this time….I’m sorry you felt I wasn’t there for you. I tried to give you my best part. I don’t really know about burial or that sort of thing. You are my family so whatever you choose will be fine…Please forgive me. I’m just not for this world.”  This is so wild!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>79</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>320</end>
        <start>80</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>321</end>
        <start>321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>632</end>
        <start>322</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>971</end>
        <start>633</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>972</end>
        <start>972</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1320</end>
        <start>973</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1547</end>
        <start>1321</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1872</end>
        <start>1548</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1873</end>
        <start>1873</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2216</end>
        <start>1874</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2615</end>
        <start>2217</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2616</end>
        <start>2616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2633</end>
        <start>2617</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>214</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>237</end>
        <start>221</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>970</end>
        <start>634</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2614</end>
        <start>2218</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>971</end>
        <start>633</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2615</end>
        <start>2217</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Jim Carrey Facing Major Charges, He Could End Up In Prison</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/celebrity-news/breaking-jim-carrey-just-got-hit-with-career-ending-charges/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Jim+Carrey%2F9%2F20&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2FJim+Carrey%2F9%2F20</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
