<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Donald Trump called for a change Tuesday in how the U.S. handles the terror threat of the Islamic State, a shift away from President Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton's policies. “Crooked Hillary has been fighting ISIS, or whatever she has been doing, for years,” Trump tweeted Tuesday morning. “Now she has new ideas. It is time for change.” Story Continued Below Following a series of planted bombs in New York and New Jersey over the weekend and a stabbing in Minnesota, Trump on Monday hammered Clinton on her record amid increasing concerns regarding the terrorist network and the threat of domestic attacks. The real estate mogul again blamed Clinton and Obama for refusing to utter the words “radical Islamic terrorism” and accused them of emboldening terrorists across the globe. “Today, Hillary Clinton showed again that she will say anything — and blame anyone — to shift attention away from the weakness she showed as Secretary of State,” he said in a statement Monday, adding that terrorists are “hoping and praying that Hillary Clinton becomes President so that they can continue their savagery and murder.” Trump vowed to “bring an end to these senseless acts of violence” and condemned the White House, whose spokesman referred to the battle against the Islamic State as a “narrative fight.” “They are wrong to say that we’re in a fight about ‘narratives,’” Trump said. “These terrorists pose an existential threat to our country, our values, and our way of life.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>177</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>341</end>
        <start>178</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>363</end>
        <start>342</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>612</end>
        <start>364</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>786</end>
        <start>613</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1119</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1305</end>
        <start>1120</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1478</end>
        <start>1306</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>261</end>
        <start>179</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>340</end>
        <start>295</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>724</end>
        <start>699</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>947</end>
        <start>788</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1118</end>
        <start>1008</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1184</end>
        <start>1136</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1304</end>
        <start>1288</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1370</end>
        <start>1307</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1477</end>
        <start>1385</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump hits Clinton on Islamic State: ‘It is time for change’</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-islamic-state-clinton-228397?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
