<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tom Cahill</author>
    <links href="http://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/charlotte-shooting-video-footage-shows-fatal-encounter-between-police-keith-n653426">
        <end>237</end>
        <start>217</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjYvaSzhKbPAhXp7IMKHfjxDaEQqQIIHTAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2016%2F09%2F23%2Fopinion%2Frelease-the-charlotte-police-video.html&amp;usg=AFQjCNFVaJB3q87Y4DtaohII0cWyw_6a3w&amp;sig2=-DSXin8DR3pHqT1VthGm0Q&amp;bvm=bv.133700528,d.amc">
        <end>1342</end>
        <start>1312</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/heartbreaking-memory-for-mother-of-man-killed-by-charlotte-cop-keith-lamont-scott/">
        <end>1605</end>
        <start>1592</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>(EDITOR’S NOTE: This video contains graphic content that may be emotionally disturbing for viewers.) A video of Keith Lamont Scott’s final moments, filmed by Scott’s wife, Rakeiya, has been made public. In the video, obtained by NBC News, Charlotte-Mecklenburg (CMPD) police officers are seen approaching the car where Scott, a father of seven, was waiting for his child’s school bus to arrive. Rakeiya Scott is heard shouting, “Don’t shoot him! He has no weapon!” while police are heard in the distance shouting at Keith Scott to “drop the gun.” “He doesn’t have a gun… he’s not going to do anything to you guys. He just took his medicine,” Rakeiya Scott said.  After four shots were fired, Scott is heard repeatedly shouting, “Did you shoot him?” And runs over to her husband’s car. “He better not be fucking dead, he better not be fucking dead, I know that fucking much,” Scott said as officers ordered her to come to them. “We are at 9453 Lexington Court, and these are the police officers who just shot my husband,” Rakeiya Scott said. “He better live.” From the angle of the recording, it is unclear as to what led up to the killing of 43-year-old Keith Lamont Scott. As of this writing, CMPD officers have not released the body camera video of Scott’s death, despite calls from the community and even the New York Times editorial board to release it. Police were on the scene to search for a man with outstanding warrants, who was not Scott. However, Scott was nonetheless shot and killed by CMPD officers who allege he was brandishing a firearm. Scott’s mother, Vernita Scott Walker, told CBS News he was sitting in his car, waiting for his child’s school bus, and reading the Koran, which he did every day. “That’s a task for him every day, so he can be out there to get a special spot,” Walker said.”He sits in the truck and reads his book.”        </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>100</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>202</end>
        <start>101</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>546</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>661</end>
        <start>547</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>662</end>
        <start>662</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>784</end>
        <start>663</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>926</end>
        <start>785</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1058</end>
        <start>927</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1357</end>
        <start>1059</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1715</end>
        <start>1358</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1851</end>
        <start>1716</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1853</end>
        <start>1852</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1854</end>
        <start>1854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1855</end>
        <start>1855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1856</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1857</end>
        <start>1857</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1858</end>
        <start>1858</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1859</end>
        <start>1859</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>463</end>
        <start>429</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>545</end>
        <start>532</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>640</end>
        <start>548</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>747</end>
        <start>729</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>873</end>
        <start>786</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1019</end>
        <start>928</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1057</end>
        <start>1042</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1795</end>
        <start>1717</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Here’s the Video of Charlotte Police Shooting Keith Lamont Scott</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/black-lives-matter/video-shows-shooting-keith-lamont-scott/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
