<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2016/09/21/sheriff-arpaio-obama-birth-certificate/90770204/">
        <end>383</end>
        <start>363</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Even though Donald Trump finally acknowledged last week that President Barack Obama was born in the United States, one of the Republican nominee's most prominent allies in law enforcement is not dropping the case. “I don’t care where he’s from,” Joe Arpaio, sheriff of Maricopa County, Arizona, told the Surprise Tea Party Patriots group on Tuesday, according to The Arizona Republic. “We are looking at a forged document. Period.” Story Continued Below Arpaio also appeared to dismiss the notion that Trump's disavowal of his past birtherism played any role in his determination to keep investigating Obama's birth certificate, an inquiry that began in August 2011, four months after the White House released the document. “I know all the politicians say, ‘Sheriff, don’t talk about it,’” Arpaio said, according to the report. “But how can I back down when we started it? I’m not going to just forget it.” The Surprise Tea Party Patriots asked Arpaio to look into Obama's birthplace in August 2011. “I had nothing to do with Trump on the birth certificate,” Arpaio said. “We did it on our own, because of you guys.” Arpaio also added, "I’m not going to give up, and we’re looking into it ... I don’t know how it’s going to turn out.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>213</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>431</end>
        <start>214</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>453</end>
        <start>432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>723</end>
        <start>454</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>906</end>
        <start>724</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>999</end>
        <start>907</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1116</end>
        <start>1000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1234</end>
        <start>1117</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>244</end>
        <start>215</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>430</end>
        <start>386</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>788</end>
        <start>725</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>905</end>
        <start>829</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1057</end>
        <start>1001</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1115</end>
        <start>1073</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Sheriff Arpaio on Obama birth certificate: 'I'm not going to give up'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/joe-arpaio-obama-birther-228455?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
