<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Matt</author>
    <links href="http://louderwithcrowder.com/ahmad-rahami-sued-religious-persecution/#.V-BCvigrKUl">
        <end>725</end>
        <start>706</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>For a little over a decade today’s millennials have been described as being part of the “everyone gets a trophy generation.” Effort and standards are a thing of the past, so much so that even the standard to be a victim is at historic lows. Would you believe that the man behind Saturday’s NJ and NYC bombings once claimed to be a victim of “Islamophobia?” This was allegedly such a problem that the attacker Ahmad Khan Rahami and his father once sued the police in Elizabeth New Jersey for discrimination, and also accused other members of the community of discrimination based on religion. The journalists over at the Daily Mail did some digging into the lawsuit, and here’s what they found (courtesy of Louder With Crowder): The prime suspect in the New York and New Jersey bombings sued his local police force and claimed they were persecuting him for being a Muslim. Ahmad Rahami said in a lawsuit that cops in Elizabeth, New Jersey subjected his and his family to discrimination and ‘selective enforcement’ based on their religion. The family claimed that police tried to shut down their chicken restaurant, called First American, too early each night with ‘baseless’ tickets and summonses. Ahmad, 28, his father Mohammad Sr, 53, and his brother Mohammad, brought the lawsuit together and said that local residents also racially abused them and said: ‘Muslims don’t belong here’. The lawsuit was filed in 2011 and reveals that Ahmad has a long history of grievances with city officials, their local police force and people who lived close to them. No, you’re not living in an episode of the Twilight Zone right now, this is real life. Mayor Christian Bollwage insisted to The New York Times that there was no such discrimination. “It was neighbor complaints, it had nothing to do his with ethnicity or religion,” Bollwage said, adding, “It had to do with noise and people congregating on the streets.” Rahami’s family owns a fried chicken restaurant in Elizabeth, NJ called First American Fried Chicken. This is also the same town where five bombs were found at a train station Monday morning. His lawsuit went nowhere, so apparently his strategy in that particular case was that if you can’t beat them in the courts: bomb them instead. Welcome to Obama’s America – where even an Islamic terrorist can play the victim! How insane is this? Get the word out – share this post on Facebook and Twitter. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>240</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>591</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>727</end>
        <start>592</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1037</end>
        <start>728</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1385</end>
        <start>1038</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1553</end>
        <start>1386</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1640</end>
        <start>1554</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1907</end>
        <start>1641</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2242</end>
        <start>1908</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2324</end>
        <start>2243</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2404</end>
        <start>2325</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2405</end>
        <start>2405</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>123</end>
        <start>89</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>355</end>
        <start>342</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1737</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1906</end>
        <start>1843</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1210</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>NYC Terrorist Ahmad Rahami Sued Police Department for ‘Religious Persecution’ in 2011!</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/nyc-terrorist-ahmad-rahami-sued-police-department-religious-persecution-2011/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
