<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>iPatriot</author>
    <links href="http://ipatriot.com/leftwing-media-eat-american-journalism-dies/">
        <end>2076</end>
        <start>2030</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Matt Lauer is being skinned alive by the leftwingnut media for his honest presidential forum with Hillary and Trump. They are calling for his head on a platter for asking Hillary about her email crimes. The rightwing saw the interview as a surprise since leftists normally do their utmost to shield Hillary and avoid exposing her crimes. But then they saw that Lauer didn’t go into as much detail as they would have and that he did go after Trump, but not to the degree with which leftist fanatics would have and that has sent those leftwingnuts over the edge. In the coming debate between Trump and Hillary, they are calling on their moderators to “fact check” Trump, but not Hillary. The purpose of journalism is to inform you of events. You are then free to decide your opinion of those events. Opinions expressed in the media are supposed to be from either the public or the editors. But that is not what the leftist media practices today. Remember the 2nd Romney-Obama debate? The moderator took over debating Romney and backed Obama’s lie that he said the assassination of Ambassador Stevens was a terror attack. Even though she admitted she lied the next day the damage was done. I am not a journalist. I have a degree in journalism, but that doesn’t make me a journalist. I do not work for the media and I do not report the news. I am a blogger. I do not report events. I express my opinion of events. Before you read my articles I expect you to already know the ‘who, what, when, where, and how’ of events. If you are ignorant because you listen to the leftwingnut media spin then you will probably think my opinion is wrong because you think my facts are lies. There are leftwingnuts who have chastised bloggers as false because we express our opinions, as if by doing so that makes what we say not the truth. Expressing your opinion of an event does not make the facts of that event a lie – except in the narrow minds of ignorant liberals. I have also been chastised that I do not make good arguments because I am not… Read the rest of the story at www.iPatriot.com  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>202</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>685</end>
        <start>203</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1186</end>
        <start>686</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1950</end>
        <start>1187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2029</end>
        <start>1951</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2076</end>
        <start>2030</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2077</end>
        <start>2077</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2223</end>
        <start>2078</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2297</end>
        <start>2224</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>660</end>
        <start>650</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2259</end>
        <start>2247</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Liberals Call on Debate Moderator to “Fact Check” Trump, But Not Hillary</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37057/liberals-call-on-debate-moderator-to-fact-check-trump-but-not-hillary/</uri>
    <veracity>no factual content</veracity>
</article>
