<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.nbcnews.com/storyline/ny-nj-bombings/ahmad-rahami-identified-n-y-n-j-bombings-suspect-officials-n650306?cid=sm_tw">
        <end>471</end>
        <start>463</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Even as law enforcement continues to investigate a series of bombings over the weekend in and around New York City, President Barack Obama said Monday that military successes against the Islamic State have exposed the militant group “as the failed cause that it is.” The president declined to offer specifics of the investigation into the bombings, referring reporters to the FBI and other law enforcement agencies for updates. But as the president was speaking, NBC News and other media outlets began reporting that Ahmad Rahami, a man wanted in connection with the bombings, had been taken into custody. Story Continued Below Law enforcement has not publicly tied Rahami, a U.S. citizen of Afghan descent, to any terrorist group but in his public statement Monday, Obama spoke not just about the investigation into the weekend’s attacks but also the global fight to combat terrorist groups like the Islamic State and Al Qaeda. “We will continue to lead the global coalition on the fight to destroy ISIL, which is instigating a lot of people over the Internet to carry out attacks. We are going to continue to go after them. We're going to take out their leaders, we're going to take out their infrastructure,” the president said from New York, where he will attend the United Nations General Assembly meeting later this week. “As we take away more of their territory, it exposes ISIL as the failed cause that it is. And it helps to undermine their ideology which over time will make it harder to recruit and inspire people to violence.” Speaking specifically to the ongoing investigation into the bombings in New York and New Jersey, the president said he had been briefed by FBI Director James Comey and had spoken with New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo and New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie. The president also said that a “particularly high level of federal resources” were already in place in New York to assist with the UN General Assembly and that those resources would be able to assist in the investigations. Recalling his conversations with governors Cuomo and Christie, Obama praised New Yorkers and New Jerseyans for their toughness: “Folks around here, you know, they don’t get scared. They are tough. They are resilient. They go about their business every single day.” “That kind of toughness and resoluteness and a recognition that neither individuals nor organizations like ISIL can ultimately undermine our way of life. That's the kind of strength that makes me so proud to be an American,” the president said. “By showing those who want to do us harm that they will never beat us, by showing the entire world that as Americans we do not and never will give in to fear, that's going to be the most important ingredient in us defeating those who would carry out terrorist acts against us.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>266</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>605</end>
        <start>267</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>627</end>
        <start>606</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>928</end>
        <start>628</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1538</end>
        <start>929</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2008</end>
        <start>1539</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2273</end>
        <start>2009</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2796</end>
        <start>2274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>265</end>
        <start>234</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1210</end>
        <start>930</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1537</end>
        <start>1329</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1862</end>
        <start>1818</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2272</end>
        <start>2138</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2497</end>
        <start>2275</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2795</end>
        <start>2520</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama calls Islamic State a 'failed cause'</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/obama-islamic-state-failed-cause-228360?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
