<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/bomb-chelsea-575x372.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>I would say our President is useless, but really, this goes beyond useless and right into the realm of arrogance. He has done some pretty brain dead things in the past and has made some incredibly insensitive and idiotic statements but this? This is just tone deaf to the nth power.  I’m guessing that if you’re reading this right now, you keep up with the news, or at least have a tendency to follow breaking events. That being the case, you already know about the couple of bombings that happened in New York and New Jersey over the weekend, as well as the stabbing that occurred in St. Cloud, Minnesota. While you would think that this would be enough to prompt an immediate statement from our elected officials, you would be wrong. Surely you’d want to hear the man or woman you voted for stand in solidarity with the people against this kind of terrorism, especially on our own soil. Surely the men and women you elected would at least want to do that much, if not because they actually mean it, then for votes in the upcoming election. Well apparently your President doesn’t have any such feelings about the matter. In fact, not only did he not talk about the bombings while he was in New York, he ignored them in favor of speaking at a high-dollar fundraiser. Are you outraged yet? It gets better. In lieu of addressing the domestic terror that had just occurred, he lamented the “sexism” he says has been pushed by the likes of Rush Limbaugh and Fox News (who has more female faces than any mainstream media outlet I’ve ever seen, including MSNBC), claiming that they are the reason Hillary Clinton’s campaign is going down the tubes. He bashed Trump while lauding Hillary as some kind of savior, while never mentioning the men and women who were injured in explosions that officials agree were terror-related. Critics will say that he didn’t have enough information to make an informed statement at the time, but you don’t have to know every single detail to say “an explosion has taken place here in New York and I would like to take a moment to recognize the people injured and offer them my thoughts and prayers, and would ask you guys to do the same. I will be making a more in-depth statement later as I receive more details.” And then move on to the business of the hour. But no, he couldn’t even be bothered to do that. Disgusting. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>113</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>282</end>
        <start>114</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>283</end>
        <start>283</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>606</end>
        <start>284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>735</end>
        <start>607</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1041</end>
        <start>736</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1266</end>
        <start>1042</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1288</end>
        <start>1267</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1289</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1818</end>
        <start>1643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2286</end>
        <start>1819</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2347</end>
        <start>2287</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2348</end>
        <start>2348</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1394</end>
        <start>1388</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2239</end>
        <start>1973</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Obama’s Speech In New York Shocks Americans When He Says THIS About Attacks!</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/obamas-speech-new-york-shocks-americans-says-attacks/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
