<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tim Brown</author>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/70-of-arrested-protesters-in-charlotte-were-from-out-of-state/">
        <end>134</end>
        <start>13</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.americanthinker.com/blog/2016/09/why_are_outofstate_charlotte_rioters_not_being_prosecuted_for_crossing_state_lines_to_engage_in_destruction_and_rioting.html">
        <end>307</end>
        <start>301</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.fjc.gov/history/home.nsf/page/tu_chicago7_doc_11.html">
        <end>993</end>
        <start>982</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://uscode.house.gov/statviewer.htm?volume=62&amp;page=808">
        <end>3462</end>
        <start>3450</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/bdquery/L?d103:./list/bd/d103pl.lst:322(Public_Laws)">
        <end>3493</end>
        <start>3464</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://uscode.house.gov/statviewer.htm?volume=108&amp;page=2147">
        <end>3541</end>
        <start>3527</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/2383">
        <end>3551</end>
        <start>3545</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.americanthinker.com/blog/2014/08/the_anti_riot_act_one_more_law_unenforced_by_this_administration.html">
        <end>3804</end>
        <start>3799</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/obamas-doj-silent-new-black-panthers-leader-incites-violence-ferguson/">
        <end>3894</end>
        <start>3834</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://thewashingtonstandard.com/declaration-of-independence-do-our-rights-come-from-god-the-constitution-the-supreme-court-or-congress/">
        <end>4497</end>
        <start>4453</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://freedomoutpost.com/about-the-70-of-out-of-state-rioters-in-charlotte-why-is-the-obama-doj-not-charging-them-for-crossing-state-lines-to-riot-and-destroy/">
        <end>4544</end>
        <start>4499</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>On Friday, I reported that of those arrested in Charlotte, North Carolina, 70% of the provocateurs and rioters were from out of state. However, one writer is now questioning why they are not facing federal charges of crossing state lines in order to engage in rioting and destruction. James Lonstreet writes at The American Thinker that the Department of Justice has a “disinterest for certain laws” and it has engaged in “non-enforcement of the law has become sport in the past eight years.” Lonstreet says that the number of out of state rioters who have been arrested should pique the interest of the DOJ, but it doesn’t. Instead, the Justice Department has become so corrupt that it no longer seeks justice. He writes: Criminals disguised as protestors cross state lines to engage in destruction and rioting.  Has anyone heard of the statute that prohibits crossing state lines to engage in such behavior being enforced by federal authorities? From the Federal Judicial Center, 2101. Riots: (a) (1) Whoever travels in interstate or foreign commerce or uses any facility of interstate or foreign commerce or uses any facility of interstate or foreign commerce, including, but not limited to, the mail, telegraph, telephone, radio, or television, with intent – (A) to incite a riot; or (B) to organize, promote, encourage, participate in, or carry on a riot; or (C) to commit any act of violence in furtherance of a riot; or (D) to aid or abet any person in inciting or participating in or carrying on a riot or committing any act of violence in furtherance of a riot; and who either during the course of any such travel or use or thereafter performs or attempts to perform any other overt act for any purpose specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of this paragraph shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both. (b) In any prosecution under this section, proof that a defendant engaged or attempted to engage in one or more of the overt acts described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1) of subsection (a) and (1) has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or (2) has use of or used any facility of interstate or foreign commerce, including but not limited to, mail, telegraph, telephone, radio, or television, to communicate with or broadcast to any person or group of persons prior to such overt acts, such travel or use shall be admissible proof to establish that such defendant traveled in or used such facility of interstate or foreign commerce. There is a wisdom to such laws, one that predicts how local situations can blossom into much larger events when interlopers are allowed to exacerbate the situation.  These laws need to be enforced.  They are not.  It is fair to ask, “Why not?” Recall in Ferguson that the influx of non-residents (Revolution Club of Chicago, New Black Panthers, etc.) who came to join in the fray was noted by local authorities, yet there was no action from federal authorities regarding the enforcement of statues prohibiting the crossing of state lines to engage in such behavior. Whoever incites, sets on foot, assists, or engages in any rebellion or insurrection against the authority of the United States or the laws thereof, or gives aid or comfort thereto, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both; and shall be incapable of holding any office under the United States. (June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 808; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(L), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2147.)” source He then concludes, “There are two clarities. The administration has sympathies in one direction, and the Department of Justice has disinterest in another direction.” This is not the first time that Lonstreet has brought this issue up. In 2014, he wrote on the issue when it was the New Black Panthers stirring up rioting in Ferguson, Missouri. At that time, he cited the same law and wrote, “The proof is for all to see. The New Black Panthers once again are not prosecuted at the choice of federal authorities. (Recall Philadelphia polling incident.) Need we mention who those authorities are?” Picking and choosing which laws to enforce is problematic for sure. This administration not only often targets innocent Americans, but then allows the lawless to escape punishment. Perhaps it’s time the people brought justice upon their criminal representatives in DC and institute new government, as the Declaration of Independence advises us to do. Reposted With Permission From Freedom Outpost  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>284</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>492</end>
        <start>285</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>711</end>
        <start>493</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>722</end>
        <start>712</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>947</end>
        <start>723</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>994</end>
        <start>948</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1262</end>
        <start>995</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2527</end>
        <start>1263</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2771</end>
        <start>2528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3093</end>
        <start>2772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3551</end>
        <start>3094</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3717</end>
        <start>3552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4147</end>
        <start>3718</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4498</end>
        <start>4148</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4544</end>
        <start>4499</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4545</end>
        <start>4545</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4691</end>
        <start>4546</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4765</end>
        <start>4692</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>398</end>
        <start>370</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>491</end>
        <start>423</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2770</end>
        <start>2762</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3716</end>
        <start>3572</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4146</end>
        <start>3944</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3173</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2527</end>
        <start>995</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>3551</end>
        <start>3094</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4727</end>
        <start>4715</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Why Aren’t the Out-of-State Rioters Facing FEDERAL Charges?</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/37048/why-arent-the-out-of-state-rioters-facing-federal-charges/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
