<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>McIntosh</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ad_211867674.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3798328/Woman-urinated-war-memorial-jailed-seven-months.html#ixzz4KpIJ44e4">
        <end>700</end>
        <start>683</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/judge-382091.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It used to be in ancient times that soldiers that fought for their nations were respected. History doesn’t remember ancient hippies, or archaic anti-war activist groups…probably because they were all killed…anyways, today this kind of despicable behavior is the norm. It’s not uncommon to encounter these kinds of people in your everyday life. They saturate the planet. Of course none of them have ever served their country and most likely would rather sacrifice the life of a human being (not their own) over an animal (Harambe). Not to say that bad soldiers don’t exit. They do. There’s bad guys in every walk of life and that should be expected.  But what happens when you have a memorial monument dedicated to a major battle in your country’s history totally desecrated by a disgusting excuse for a human being? Kelly Martin, 42, incensed public decency when she desecrated, and that’s exactly the word needed here, the monument in broad daylight in Grays, Essex… first in April when there were still Remembrance wreaths that were set upon it. If that wasn’t bad enough, this beastly woman did it again back in June – the day before the 100th anniversary of the start of the Battle of the Somme. Martin, who looked as disheveled as ever, shouted ‘f*** this’ as she was led down to the cells at Basildon Crown Court, on her way to receive her sentence.  Judge John Lodge, the lucky duck that had the privilege of passing sentencing, said: ‘Each of these offences is so serious that only a custodial sentence is appropriate. The two cases of outraging public decency involve urinating on a war memorial…Inevitably war memorials were constructed at the center of towns and villages so on a daily basis people could be reminded of the sacrifices made by people who died…People use them as a place around which they congregate and that’s not wrong, but when people take that step further and abuse them by urinating on them that’s a matter the court needs to take very seriously indeed.’ Speaking to the piss monster herself, Judge Lodge said this: ‘What makes your case particularly bad is having been caught doing it one time, when the nation was commemorating the worst battle of the First World War you were caught doing it again in the middle of the day.’ Throw the book at her Judge. She obviously hasn’t learned to be a human being. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>648</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>649</end>
        <start>649</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>815</end>
        <start>650</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1047</end>
        <start>816</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1199</end>
        <start>1048</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1355</end>
        <start>1200</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1356</end>
        <start>1356</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1441</end>
        <start>1357</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1986</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2259</end>
        <start>1987</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2338</end>
        <start>2260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2339</end>
        <start>2339</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1986</end>
        <start>1442</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Jobless mom of 5 shouts ‘f*** this’ as she’s jailed for 7 months for urinating on war memorial twice</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/jobless-mom-5-shouts-f-shes-jailed-7-months-urinating-war-memorial-twice/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
