<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Charles Roberts</author>
    <mainText>A pregnant southern California woman was allegedly brutally attacked by someone who responded to a fake "rape fantasy" ad on Craigslist created by her husband's ex-girlfriend.  Ontario-based Michelle Suzanne Hadley, 29, was apprehended and jailed July 18 on a $1 million bond.  Hadley dated a U.S. Marshals Service agent between 2013 and 2015. Prosecutors say Hadley placed ads posing as her ex-boyfriend’s new wife to lure men into sexually attacking the woman, who was pregnant with the couple’s first child, reports KCBS. Hadley gave the couple’s Anaheim address to men who responded to the ad on Craigslist, asking them to drop by when she knew the victim would be home alone. Numerous men showed up, one of whom assaulted the pregnant woman. Fortunately, she managed to call for assistance.  The suspect was previously accused of threatening the same woman and her unborn baby. Although the pregnant woman filed a restraining order against Hadley on June 6, Hadley violated the order by stalking the victim and was arrested June 24, according to the Daily Mail.  Hadley was released on $100,000 bail, but prosecutors say she continued sending threatening emails and responding to the "rape fantasy" ads on Craigslist. “Hadley is accused of telling the responders that the victim wanted the responders to have forcible sexual intercourse with her, even if she screamed or resisted,” the Orange County DA said in a statement. “Several of the responders showed up at Jane Doe's residence with the intention of raping the victim but did not succeed.  “One responder arrived at Jane Doe's residence and physically attacked the victim before she was able to call for help and the man fled the scene.” The jilted lover is charged with stalking, stalking despite a restraining order, assault with the intent to commit a sexual offense during a first-degree burglary, and making criminal threats, plus six counts of attempted forcible rape. Hadley’s arraignment is scheduled for August 19. If convicted, she could face seven years to life in prison.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>176</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>277</end>
        <start>177</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>524</end>
        <start>278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>796</end>
        <start>525</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1067</end>
        <start>797</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1222</end>
        <start>1068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1428</end>
        <start>1223</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1551</end>
        <start>1429</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1699</end>
        <start>1552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1936</end>
        <start>1700</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2045</end>
        <start>1937</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>America Now</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1385</end>
        <start>1224</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1698</end>
        <start>1430</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Pregnant Woman Discovers Why Men Kept Coming To Her Home, Trying To Rape Her</title>
    <uri>http://www.americanow.com/story/society/2016/08/02/pregnant-woman-discovers-why-men-kept-coming-her-home-trying-rape-her?fb=rwn</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
