<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Cassy Fiano</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/Rusjacksbrook/status/780493842172764160">
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1437</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/BostonJerry/status/780520368855449600">
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1437</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LeBronJames?src=hash">
        <end>1785</end>
        <start>1773</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/aaronss101/status/780524206043783168">
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1437</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/nuffsaidNY/status/780495911071911936">
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1437</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Between the protests in Charlotte and athletes across the country refusing to stand for the National Anthem, the Black Lives Matter movement is getting a lot of attention. But not everyone is on board. Cleveland Cavaliers star Lebron James was giving a press conference, where he was asked for his opinion on athletes refusing to stand for the National Anthem in support of Black Lives Matter. And his response made liberals furious.   James began his statement by saying that while he respected Colin Kaepernick, he didn’t agree with the protest. “Me, standing for the national anthem is something I will do. That’s who I am,” he explained. “That’s what I believe in. But that doesn’t mean I don’t respect and don’t agree with what Colin Kaepernick is doing.” It was an exceedingly fair statement, but James wasn’t done yet. He continued, saying, “I’m not up here saying that all the police are bad, because they’re not. I’m not up here saying all kids are great and all adults are great, because they’re not. But at the same time, all lives do matter. It’s not just about black or white, it’s everyone.”   Well, James did himself in there, because “all lives matter”? That phrase is unforgivable to liberals. And they quickly began not only attacking James for his statement, they even accused James — a black man — of racism. No, really:  Lebron James better sit for the anthem or he a Uncle Tom — Black skip baeless (@Rusjacksbrook) September 26, 2016  "All Lives Matter" is a dog whistle, a thing racists say that doesn't sound racist at 1st glance but clearly communicates a racist idea. — Jerry Topsider (@BostonJerry) September 26, 2016  You can't expect some of these so-call athletes to take a stand with their own people. Money is the power to keep them neutral #LeBronJames — Aaron SpiveySorrells (@aaronss101) September 26, 2016   But not everyone was quick to slam him. Some people wisely remembered that James is much more of a friend to the minority community than Black Lives Matter activists are:  LeBron James just donated $41.8M to the University of Akron in Ohio, giving 1,100 kids a full 4-yr scholarship but y'all calling him a coon. — NUFF$AID (@nuffsaidNY) September 26, 2016   The Black Lives Matter movement doesn’t do much to improve things for inner-city kids or the minority community. LeBron James does. But hey, keep smearing him as a racist Uncle Tom because he said something you don’t agree with. Great idea. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>433</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>434</end>
        <start>434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>435</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>825</end>
        <start>436</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1105</end>
        <start>826</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1106</end>
        <start>1106</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1107</end>
        <start>1107</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1340</end>
        <start>1108</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1341</end>
        <start>1341</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1398</end>
        <start>1342</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1399</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1456</end>
        <start>1456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1593</end>
        <start>1457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1594</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1645</end>
        <start>1645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1785</end>
        <start>1646</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1841</end>
        <start>1786</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1842</end>
        <start>1842</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1843</end>
        <start>1843</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2014</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2015</end>
        <start>2015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2156</end>
        <start>2016</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2200</end>
        <start>2157</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2201</end>
        <start>2201</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2202</end>
        <start>2202</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2443</end>
        <start>2203</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2444</end>
        <start>2444</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>626</end>
        <start>549</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>759</end>
        <start>643</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1104</end>
        <start>849</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1167</end>
        <start>1151</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1455</end>
        <start>1342</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1644</end>
        <start>1457</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1841</end>
        <start>1646</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2200</end>
        <start>2016</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>VIDEO: LeBron James Says ‘ALL LIVES MATTER’ and the Left Goes SAVAGE! [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/black-lives-matter/video-lebron-james-says-lives-matter-left-goes-savage/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
