<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nicholas Wishek</author>
    <links href="http://www.theholocaustexplained.org/ks3/life-in-nazi-occupied-europe/controlling-everyday-life/the-nazis-seize-power/#.V-GSdWf2aUk">
        <end>137</end>
        <start>110</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hugo_Ch%C3%A1vez">
        <end>170</end>
        <start>146</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cis.org/Sanctuary-Cities-Map">
        <end>2621</end>
        <start>2591</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/house-charges-holder-with-contempt-of-congress-28-06-2012/">
        <end>3190</end>
        <start>3170</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-22529435">
        <end>3276</end>
        <start>3227</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://eaglerising.com/35789/did-obama-just-foreshadow-a-rigged-election-come-november/">
        <end>4330</end>
        <start>4272</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nationalreview.com/article/359967/">
        <end>4390</end>
        <start>4375</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Most Americans don’t realize that all revolutions aren’t the result of overt force. Hitler, for instance, was voted into power in Germany, as was Hugo Chávez in Venezuela. Currently in the United States we are in the process of such a revolution by the progressive controlled Democrat party – sadly too many Americans are oblivious to what is happening. It is impossible to know for sure whether this revolution is being orchestrated by a SPECTRE-like secret cabal, or is the result of years of progressive fellow travelers advancing similar goals. In either case what has resulted is in essence a coup. America’s progressive revolution is being fought with ballots rather than bullets, and the progressives are winning. In order to do this the progressive movement had to overcome traditional American values or they would never be successful electing their way to power. Seriously, if the Democrat Party had run with its present polices 60 years ago they would have not have come close to winning a single state. So how have they managed to get to where they are today? In the ‘60’s progressives, then called liberals started taking over the liberal arts departments of our colleges and universities. Those humanity majors they converted to their ideology went into journalism, education, and the entertainment media. Whether it was by plan or by inclination most of these liberal college grads joined the Democrat party. Since Kennedy every single Democrat nominee for president has championed the progressive ideology. You could argue that Lyndon Johnson and Bill Clinton who were more opportunists than true believers, but that didn’t stop them from supporting progressive goals. Today you’d have a tough time finding even a moderate Democrat candidate. Heck, nearly half of the party was fine with nominating a self-described socialist. Along with a news and entertainment media protecting Democrats, and the education system promoting the progressive ideology you have former and current Democrats in government sponsoring policies that garner still more votes and thereby gain more power. Does anyone honestly believe that a picture ID is that difficult to come by? Democrats are all for anything legal, quasi-legal, and some would say even illegal to recruit more voters. Immigrants and refugees are welcomed, given entitlements and are set to be Democratic voters as soon as possible. We all remember the ACORN voter fraud scandal, but if anyone seriously thinks that that was an isolated incident should really think again. The progressive revolution is ongoing. There are around 300 so-called sanctuary cities in the United States. These progressive cities refuse to obey the law of the land and have gotten away with it. Likewise whole states refuse to follow federal laws when they don’t agree with them. Worse, our current president, and cabinet officers, and whole departments in the federal government ignore their oaths to defend the Constitution. And, thanks to the timid establishment Republicans have done so with impunity. When the Attorney General of the United States Eric Holder lied to Congress without consequences – other than being found in contempt of Congress – we have a coup going on. When the IRS can use its power to punish political enemies of the administration going so far as to destroy evidence, that is a revolution. And certainly when former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton broke the law but is protected by the State Department, and the Department of Justice refuses to indict, we have a collapse of the rule of law. That is what happens in a coup. Certainly President Obama acts as if he doesn’t have to follow the Constitution. For now many of his more overt executive orders have been blocked by the courts, but as the progressive revolution grows in strength the Democrats appoint more and more judges who view the Constitution as a living document. It is doubtful that the progressive revolution is led by Obama or his handlers; they just take advantage of the increasing progressive power in the country. President Obama has an arrogance about him that drives him to foreshadow events like the IRS investigation, Hillary Clinton’s email investigation, and a possible rigging of the 2016 election. [Read Related Article: Did Obama Just Foreshadow a RIGGED Election Come November?] When he was elected he did the same thing. In 2008 he said, “We are five days away from fundamentally transforming the United States of America.” That is what he’s done and progressive will continue to try to do. Hillary, if elected will continue the progressive coup, possibly beyond our power to reverse. A Trump victory, like Ronald Reagan’s, will slow it down, but it must take a sustained effort to confront our loss of freedom.  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>353</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1014</end>
        <start>354</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1842</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2534</end>
        <start>1843</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3594</end>
        <start>2535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4248</end>
        <start>3595</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4331</end>
        <start>4249</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4765</end>
        <start>4332</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4766</end>
        <start>4766</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4912</end>
        <start>4767</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4986</end>
        <start>4913</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>4476</end>
        <start>4393</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>4948</end>
        <start>4936</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>The Progressive Takeover of America – We’re in the Midst of a COUP</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36948/the-progressive-takeover-of-america-were-in-the-midst-of-a-coup/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
