<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Victoria</author>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/judge-orders-release-of-internal-trump-university-documents/2016/05/28/2e960e5e-24f9-11e6-8690-f14ca9de2972_story.html?hpid=hp_rhp-top-table-main_trumpmanagement-256pm%3Ahomepage%2Fstory">
        <end>234</end>
        <start>213</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2016-election/donald-trump-hispanic-judge-trump-university-lawsuit-hater-n582066">
        <end>951</end>
        <start>932</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://news.groopspeak.com/gop-shocked-as-trump-campaign-admits-its-out-of-money-video/">
        <end>4216</end>
        <start>4203</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Trump currently has his hands full with the ongoing lawsuit against his company “Trump University”.  Now, a federal judge, the same one Trump insulted during a recent rally, has ordered that Trump University documents be released. Trump’s attorneys tried to avoid this outcome by claiming that the documents they were requesting included important trade secrets.  But that didn’t stop Judge Gonzalo Curiel. The result of this decision could certainly be damaging for the Trump campaign.  While Trump can brush many things off his back for some unknown reason, the idea of a fraud university that tricked college-aged students and put them into debt is rather disturbing. Furthermore, Judge Curiel stated that part of the reason he wanted the documents released is the public interest in Trump’s case. It’s clear that Trump has felt threatened by this whole ordeal.  For 12 whole minutes of a 58 minute speech, Trump insulted this judge and claimed he wasn’t playing fair.  Citing the fact that this judge was appointed by President Obama, and that he has made rulings against Trump, Trump claims he is biased. He also indirectly insinuated that the judge is biased because he is “Mexican” (which actually isn’t true at all, even if that mattered – he’s from the US). Trump University was started in 2004 as a firm to offer courses and workshops in entrepreneurship.  The University used the Trump brand and marketed it as an opportunity to be a apprentice of Trump himself.  Trump became a 93% owner of the enterprise and has benefitted from its profits. The problem is that many students believe they have not benefitted from the instruction.  The university is not accredited, you can’t earn a degree, and yet thousands of students took out tens of thousands of dollars worth of loans to attend.  Several lawsuits were placed against the “university” by its students. The state of New York even placed their complaints against Trump University.  The state filed a $40 million lawsuit saying the school gave “false promises”.  The New York State Board of Education claimed it was “misleading and even illegal” to call the firm a university. As a result, the name changed to the Trump Entrepreneur Initiative in 2010.  Around 80,000 people have been documented as attending free introductory seminars, while 9000 paid $1,500 for three-day seminars.  All of that doesn’t sound too bad, but take into account that 800 people paid around $35,000 for larger packages such as mentorship programs. In the lawsuit by the state of New York, under New York Attorney General Eric Schneiderman, it was alleged that Trump defrauded over 5,000 individuals. In a script only Trump could use, he claimed in marketing videos for the school that: “We are going to have professors and adjust professors that are absolutely terrific…and these are all people who are going to be handpicked by me.” Michael Sexton, one of the top executives of the institution, said himself that “none of the professors at the live events” were actually picked by Trump. The story and lawsuit of Trump University may just be one of the most symbolic things about the Trump candidacy and the man himself.  He uses his name recognition and the perception of wealth and success to further his interests.  It’s essentially “I’m rich because I’m rich, now give me more money/power because I’m rich”. By tagging his name along with the name of an unaccredited educational institution, thousands of people were duped into believing it would be worth their money. If Trump University had been named the Trump Entrepreneur Initiative all along, perhaps the allegations would seem more hollow.  After all, people pay for overpriced seminars and workshops all the time. However, naming the institution “Trump University” gives it the illusion that it is the kind of place a student could come to get a degree in lieu of another college.  That is just simply not the case. In the end, this lawsuit could end in Trump losing tens of millions of dollars, along with tens of millions of votes.  That’s a huge chunk of his fortune given that, depending on who listen to, some analysts estimate he is only worth between 20-70 million in terms of cash, assets and bonds. He himself claims he is worth several billion, but the truth is probably somewhere in-between.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>235</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>416</end>
        <start>236</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>681</end>
        <start>417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>682</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1128</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1295</end>
        <start>1129</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1585</end>
        <start>1296</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1908</end>
        <start>1586</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2190</end>
        <start>1909</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2544</end>
        <start>2191</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2696</end>
        <start>2545</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2782</end>
        <start>2697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2936</end>
        <start>2783</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3095</end>
        <start>2937</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3433</end>
        <start>3096</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3594</end>
        <start>3434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3798</end>
        <start>3595</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4005</end>
        <start>3799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4300</end>
        <start>4006</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4395</end>
        <start>4301</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Groopspeak</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>2936</end>
        <start>2783</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: Judge Over Trump’s Fraud Case Makes ‘Damaging’ Ruling – Could Cost Trump His Fortune</title>
    <uri>http://news.groopspeak.com/breaking-judge-over-trumps-fraud-case-makes-damaging-ruling-could-cost-trump-his-fortune/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
