<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/fox-news-sean-hannity-did-not-inform-us-he-was-making-trump-campaign-ad/">
        <end>690</end>
        <start>686</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/fox-news-sean-hannity-did-not-inform-us-he-was-making-trump-campaign-ad/">
        <end>988</end>
        <start>978</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/cheats/2016/09/20/sean-hannity-in-trouble-at-fox-after-participating-in-trump-ad.html?via=desktop&amp;source=copyurl">
        <end>1472</end>
        <start>1452</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Fake Fox News journalist Sean Hannity might be one of the golden boys at Fox News Channel, but he’s definitely going in the dog house after the stunt he pulled. Along with a handful of rednecks and hicks, Hannity and other conservative figures appeared in a ridiculously bad video called “#HEARTLAND4TRUMP.” The right-wing video was released on Trump’s official YouTube page over the weekend. “One of the reasons I’m supporting Donald Trump this year is, number one, he’s gonna put originalists on the Supreme Court, people that believe in fidelity to the Constitution, separation of powers, co-equal branches of government. He’s a guy who will vet refugees to keep Americans safe,” he says in the ad. And proving once again that he’s an ill-informed hack who sucks up to anyone willing to pay him to spew their fact free crap, Hannity offered full-throated support for Trump’s luxurious border wall (not going to happen). “And of course he’s going to build that wall,” Hannity continued. “He says he’s going to have Mexico pay for it, that’s fine, as long as we secure the country. And of course, we don’t want people competing for jobs.” It seems Hannity pissed off the higher-ups when he didn’t inform them that he was making a promotional video for the Donald Trump campaign. “We were not aware of Sean Hannity participating in a promotional video, and he will not be doing anything along these lines for the remainder of the election season,” Fox told the Daily Beast when they found out. We always deride Fox News for its ludicrous “Fair and Balanced” slogan, but never before have we seen propaganda quite like Hannity’s participation in the Trump campaign. Even Fox seems shocked by how obsessed their host is with Trump. When Fox is telling its pundits to cool it on the Trump worship, you know it’s reached embarrassing levels. Watch the ridiculous ad below: Featured image via screen capture  Someone gave us a visual for the ages. Now if we could just fill it up with kitty litter. Used kitty litter.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>161</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>393</end>
        <start>162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>702</end>
        <start>394</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>923</end>
        <start>703</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1140</end>
        <start>924</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1280</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1494</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1838</end>
        <start>1495</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1869</end>
        <start>1839</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1903</end>
        <start>1870</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1904</end>
        <start>1904</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2013</end>
        <start>1905</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>If You Only News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>306</end>
        <start>289</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>681</end>
        <start>394</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>968</end>
        <start>924</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1138</end>
        <start>990</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1281</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1556</end>
        <start>1539</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>701</end>
        <start>393</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1139</end>
        <start>923</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1493</end>
        <start>1280</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hannity Goes Rogue, Secretly Films Gushing Trump Ad – And Fox News Is PISSED</title>
    <uri>http://www.ifyouonlynews.com/politics/hannity-goes-rogue-secretly-films-gushing-trump-ad-and-fox-news-is-angry/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
