<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k0J_EKmvYZk">
        <end>79</end>
        <start>74</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/erik-wemple/wp/2016/09/20/fox-newss-sean-hannity-stars-in-trump-promotion/?utm_term=.d830ac14b6cf">
        <end>811</end>
        <start>796</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/06/sean-hannity-supports-trump-223763">
        <end>891</end>
        <start>879</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/on-media/2016/09/fox-news-to-host-trump-town-hall-228372">
        <end>1143</end>
        <start>1134</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>After Fox News host Sean Hannity appeared in a pro-Donald Trump political video over the weekend, the network will prohibit him from appearing in promotional political materials through the end of the election, a spokesperson said Tuesday. “We were not aware of Sean Hannity participating in a promotional video and he will not be doing anything along these lines for the remainder of the election season,” the spokesperson said in a statement to POLITICO. On Sunday, Trump’s presidential campaign uploaded an eight-minute video that showed a number of conservative figures expressing their support of the Republican candidate. One of those figures included the Fox News show host, who spoke for about 30 seconds expressing his support of the candidate. The Washington Post’s Erik Wemple was the first to report on the video. Hannity has been a long-time supporter of Trump, and said in June that he would be voting for the Republican nominee. But his appearance in the campaign video released Sunday was the first of its kind this election season. It’s unclear how the network will address Hannity’s appearance in the video during a town hall with Trump on the network Wednesday, which Hannity is scheduled to host. A spokesperson said at press time that there were no updates when asked about Hannity’s involvement in the town hall.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>239</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>456</end>
        <start>240</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>825</end>
        <start>457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1048</end>
        <start>826</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1334</end>
        <start>1049</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>405</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Fox News: Sean Hannity won’t appear in any more Trump ads</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/blogs/on-media/2016/09/fox-sean-hannity-wont-do-any-more-trump-ads-228437?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
