<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="http://www.dw.com/en/opinion-kerry-the-indefatigable-optimist/a-19067985">
        <end>64</end>
        <start>42</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/20/world/middleeast/syria-aid-john-kerry.html?ref=world&amp;_r=0">
        <end>809</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-believes-russia-bombed-syrian-aid-convoy-1474400403">
        <end>965</end>
        <start>959</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://foreignpolicy.com/2016/06/17/diplomats-dissent-bolsters-calls-for-u-s-assault-on-assad/">
        <end>4845</end>
        <start>4841</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/03/obama-kerry-syria-220526">
        <end>4944</end>
        <start>4936</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2015/06/john-kerry-iran-nuclear-deal-119562">
        <end>5635</end>
        <start>5625</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>NEW YORK — John Kerry has been called an "indefatigable optimist," the kind of guy determined to try, try again in spite of tough odds. It's a drive that helped him push through the Iran nuclear deal and keeps him searching for ways to solve the Israeli-Palestinian crisis. But the latest chaos in Syria has critics saying he may be trying too hard this time — looking weak in the process and undermining his own goal of a peace deal. Story Continued Below A Syrian cease-fire that Kerry announced less than two weeks ago is near collapse. The first big blow came Saturday after an apparently errant U.S. airstrike believed to have killed dozens of Syrian government soldiers instead of Islamic State terrorists not party to the truce. Then, on Monday, suspected Syrian government airstrikes hit an aid convoy, killing at least 12 people and infuriating moderate rebels already wary of making a deal with Syrian President Bashar Assad. And late on Tuesday, a report emerged that U.S. intelligence indicates that Russian forces actually carried out the strike. By any measure, the developments are a blow to the 72-year-old secretary of state. Still, on Tuesday on the sidelines of the U.N. General Assembly in New York, Kerry met yet again with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, Syria's de facto international representative, to see what could be done to salvage the cease-fire. "He seems unaware that it's simply impossible to win at the negotiating table what you do not win on the ground, and he seems to be unaware that he keeps getting outsmarted and outmaneuvered by Lavrov," Elliott Abrams, a former deputy national security adviser in Republican George W. Bush's administration, wrote in an e-mail to POLITICO. "His defenders say well, better to try than to give up, but that is wrong. He looks weak, and that makes the United States look weak." The argument to keep trying is compelling. An estimated half-million people have died in the Syrian civil war since March 2011, and millions more have been displaced from their homes. Syria's misery is likely to be the biggest stain on Kerry's legacy as secretary of state, not to mention Barack Obama's legacy as president. Kerry's defenders grouse that he is being unfairly criticized by detractors who fail to offer reasonable alternatives — scenarios that won't slip the U.S. into another war in the Middle East. And the secretary of state himself, wherever he goes, insists that the problem in Syria must ultimately be solved through a political, not military solution. "What he's trying to do on Syria isn't about his legacy — he doesn't view it in those terms," a State Department official told POLITICO. "Critics can claim all they want that he is being unrealistic, but they aren’t sitting in the room like the rest of us watching him work tirelessly to try to find a way through, leveraging every ounce of personal relationships he has to reach [an] accord. Never once have I heard him talk blindly about trust. It’s always been a sober assessment of the interests at stake and an honest effort to negotiate. The man knows people, and he knows how far he can take things." Added a former administration official of Kerry: "I just don't think he gives two thoughts to whether some wise guy in Washington believes he shouldn't have tried. He would want to hear their alternative." But the Russians, and for that matter the Syrians, have little incentive to acquiesce to an administration that's on its way out; and Moscow appears either unwilling or unable to rein in Assad. The Syrian dictator, bent on staying in power, appears impervious to criticism from enemies and pleas from allies. Robert Ford, a former Obama administration ambassador to Syria, said Kerry's tactics, not his intent, pose a risk. "I’m full of admiration for him for being willing to try. He’s not afraid to grapple with big issues, and I think he deserves some credit for that," said Ford, now at the Middle East Institute. "What’s not clear is whether his constantly going back to the Russians over and over again is helping or hurting his efforts to convince them. It's making him look weak. I don’t know that the Russians do things out of kindness or if instead they take advantage of weak players and weak countries." Part of the problem for Kerry, observers say, is that Obama appears to have zero interest in committing more military muscle to give his secretary of state leverage in the talks with Russia. "Time will prove that Kerry played a weak hand as good as he could," said Randa Slim, an analyst also with the Middle East Institute. "The blame for U.S. inaction in Syria and its consequences should rest on Obama's shoulders, not Kerry's." It also doesn't help that there are divisions within the Obama administration over what to do about Syria. More than 50 U.S. officials signed a memo leaked earlier this year that urges U.S. airstrikes on the Assad regime. Kerry himself is reported to have asked Obama to allow airstrikes on specific Syrian government targets to put Assad on notice, but Obama, wary of deepening the U.S. military role in the conflict, has declined. The recent bargain Kerry struck with Russia on Syria also has upset the Pentagon because it included coordination between Moscow and Washington on airstrikes against terrorist groups such as the Islamic State. Defense officials are extremely wary of sharing intelligence with Russia. Kerry's defenders insist he is not naive, despite his professed faith in the power of negotiations. For instance, at least twice during the marathon talks that led to the nuclear deal with Iran last year, Kerry reportedly became fed up with Iranian intransigence and threatened to quit the negotiations. In fact, Kerry's determination to get a deal with Tehran fueled similar questions last year about whether he was too eager for a legacy-making accomplishment. Kerry has spent most of his life in public service, but he's been dogged by criticism that he passed too few notable bills during his years as a lawmaker. He also failed to defeat Bush in the 2004 race for the White House. Another challenge Kerry has tried to solve repeatedly is the conflict between the Israelis and the Palestinians. After taking over as secretary of state in 2013, Kerry pushed the two sides to try once again to come to terms. But ultimately that effort sputtered. The Syria crisis is in many ways more complex than the decades old Israeli-Palestinian conflict. Not only is the carnage ongoing and on an extraordinary scale, the sheer number of Syrian groups involved and international actors taking sides makes three-dimensional chess look easy. The cease-fire currently on the brink in Syria isn't even the first one Kerry has helped devise. A truce reached in February kept hold for several weeks before eventually collapsing. Then, too, Kerry worked long hours to negotiate with the Russians to agree to the cease-fire. That was alongside on and off initiatives to bring Syrian rebel leaders and Assad's representatives to the bargaining table for a long-term deal. On Monday, following the airstrike on the U.N. aid convoy, senior administration officials briefing reporters had tough words for Russia, saying it was responsible for the Syrian government's actions. "The Russians have the responsibility certainly to restrain — refrain from taking such action themselves, but they also have the responsibility to keep the regime from doing it," one official said. "The burden is on the Russians to demonstrate ... quickly and in a significant way, that they are committed to this process, which — without which obviously we’re not going to be able to move forward with them." The administration's tone was more restrained following Tuesday's meeting between Lavrov, Kerry, and others involved in the Syrian peace effort. A readout from the State Department said participants decided they needed to meet again, but agreed that despite the violence, "there was still an imperative to pursue a nationwide cessation of hostilities." The shorter version? John Kerry is going to keep trying.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>273</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>434</end>
        <start>274</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>456</end>
        <start>435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1059</end>
        <start>457</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1384</end>
        <start>1060</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1859</end>
        <start>1385</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2184</end>
        <start>1860</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2534</end>
        <start>2185</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3142</end>
        <start>2535</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3348</end>
        <start>3143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3657</end>
        <start>3349</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4264</end>
        <start>3658</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4455</end>
        <start>4265</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4696</end>
        <start>4456</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>4803</end>
        <start>4697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5129</end>
        <start>4804</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5413</end>
        <start>5130</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>5717</end>
        <start>5414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6099</end>
        <start>5718</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6362</end>
        <start>6100</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>6644</end>
        <start>6363</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7067</end>
        <start>6645</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7268</end>
        <start>7068</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>7678</end>
        <start>7269</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8031</end>
        <start>7679</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>8088</end>
        <start>8032</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>Kerry's optimism is put to the test</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/john-kerry-syria-228405?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
