<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Capture.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/heroin2-e1474214716353.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://metro.co.uk/2016/09/18/ex-heroin-addict-shows-what-826-days-sober-will-do-to-you-6135888/#ixzz4KjgMwepJ">
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1489</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Anyone who has ever struggled with some kind of addiction knows that it is not easy to break the habit. Whether you’re addicted to nicotine, alcohol, meth or crack, even being 24-hours sober seems like a monumental achievement. One woman, an ex-heroin addict, showed Reddit what happens when you decide to turn your life around and free yourself from the clutches of addiction. You can’t argue with the results, either.  Addiction is a mental, physical, emotional and spiritual event, for want of a better term. Getting sober is tough for that very reason, but it’s necessary for the well-being of everyone involved, meaning the family and friends of the addict, as well as the addict themselves. The woman in question began a downward spiral into heroin addiction after her abusive boyfriend convinced her that it would make her feel better about the problems in her life, including losing custody of her daughter. She says that after 8 months of daily use and several failed attempts at getting sober, she finally told the judge in the case that she wanted to get clean. She was found in contempt of court and went to jail for 36 days before heading to rehab. As you can see in her mugshot, this woman – who is unnamed – was feeling the physical and emotional affects of her disease. When she finally became dedicated to getting clean, her whole life changed, as is evidenced in this “after” picture, where she is 826 days sober, and counting.  She added the following to the end of her Reddit post: ‘There are other addicts out there who are in the same circle of hell that I was in in that mug shot. So even if one of those people see this and get their sh*t together, then it was worth it.’ If you or someone you know is struggling with any kind of addiction, please know that it is okay to seek out help for them. You’re not intruding on their lives and while they may be furious with you for a period of time, they will come to see that you did what you had to do to make their lives better. There is no reason that someone should have to suffer from addiction for one more day. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>227</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>419</end>
        <start>228</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>420</end>
        <start>420</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>696</end>
        <start>421</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1161</end>
        <start>697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1285</end>
        <start>1162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1445</end>
        <start>1286</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1446</end>
        <start>1446</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1501</end>
        <start>1447</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1695</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2085</end>
        <start>1696</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2086</end>
        <start>2086</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>770</end>
        <start>765</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1695</end>
        <start>1502</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Ex-heroin addict shows what being clean for 826 days will do for you</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/ex-heroin-addict-shows-clean-826-days-will/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
