<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://www.youngcons.com/voters-believe-moderators-will-actively-try-and-help-hillary-during-debate-tonight/">
        <end>24</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Hillary-9-e1474907607651.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/elections/election_2016/voters_see_debate_moderators_giving_clinton_a_helping_hand">
        <end>797</end>
        <start>780</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/questions/pt_survey_questions/september_2016/questions_debate_moderators_september_20_21_2016">
        <end>1334</end>
        <start>1324</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/elections/election_2012/election_2012_presidential_election/september_2012/just_17_view_debates_as_very_important_to_how_they_will_vote">
        <end>1817</end>
        <start>1720</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/elections/election_2008/2008_presidential_election/most_voters_say_debate_moderators_are_biased">
        <end>1999</end>
        <start>1968</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/commentary_by_fran_coombs/this_race_is_down_to_the_debates">
        <end>2306</end>
        <start>2248</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/politics/elections/election_2016/white_house_watch_sep22">
        <end>2451</end>
        <start>2401</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Hillary1-5-e1474907649661.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>It would not surprise me in the least if the moderators in tonight’s debate help Hillary Clinton. In fact, I would bet on it. However… Trump is no wallflower or wilting lily. If the moderators are unfair to him, he’s going to come out and challenge them. There won’t be political niceties here. He’s a scrapper. I may not support the man, but trust me, I think he will mop the stage with these limp Marxists. That’s his brand. Hillary may think she has it in the bag and that the moderators will protect her and correct Trump at every turn, but not so fast. Trump has an unsettling effect on people. He’s known for throwing them off balance. And he loves the limelight… you don’t think for a moment that he will let someone like Clinton upstage him, do you? Don’t be silly.  From Rasmussen Reports: Voters are pretty convinced the moderators at the presidential debates scheduled to begin tonight will be helping Hillary Clinton more than Donald Trump. A new Rasmussen Reports national telephone and online survey finds that a plurality (46%) of Likely U.S. Voters believes most moderators will try to help Clinton in the upcoming debates. Only six percent (6%) think they will try to help Trump instead. Just 32% say most of the moderators will try to be unbiased, while 15% are undecided. (To see survey question wording, click here.) Seventy-eight percent (78%) of voters who support Trump think the moderators will try to help Clinton. Most Clinton supporters (56%) say the moderators will try to be unbiased, but 20% say they’ll try to help their candidate. Twelve percent (12%) of Clinton voters think the moderators will try to help Trump, compared to just two percent (2%) of Trump supporters who feel that way. Four years ago before the first debate between President Obama and Republican nominee Mitt Romney, 71% of Republicans and 56% of unaffiliated voters said debate moderators are biased, but Democrats by a 47% to 30% margin felt they were not biased. In 2008 before the first debate, 22% felt the first moderator, veteran PBS newsman Jim Lehrer, would try to help Obama, while six percent (6%) expected him to help GOP nominee John McCain. Forty-three percent (43%) though Lehrer would play a neutral role. This year’s debates are potentially a breakaway moment for either Clinton or Trump who have been running neck-and-neck for weeks in Rasmussen Reports’ White House Watch survey. Trump is ahead by five points in the latest survey, but it’s too early to say if he is gaining any traction over his rival. I consider everything out of both of their pieholes to be a lie, so I have no horse in this race. But, I am in it for the entertainment factor… sort of like eating popcorn during an apocalypse. Frankly, I think this is Trump’s to lose and I highly doubt he will. But I’m sure there are bookies out there laying odds on something going amiss with Clinton: a potty emergency, fainting spell, seizure, brain freeze, coughing fit… any of those and she is toast. Trump looks hale and hearty in comparison. This is the ultimate bread and circuses in America. Behold an election as reality TV. And Trump is known for saying, “You’re fired!” Clinton may very well exit the show stage left tonight.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>426</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>773</end>
        <start>427</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>774</end>
        <start>774</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>798</end>
        <start>775</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>952</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1336</end>
        <start>953</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1719</end>
        <start>1337</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2223</end>
        <start>1720</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2524</end>
        <start>2224</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3025</end>
        <start>2525</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3214</end>
        <start>3026</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3215</end>
        <start>3215</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3216</end>
        <start>3216</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>3157</end>
        <start>3144</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2524</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Right Before Tonight’s Debate Hillary Gets Good News – Moderators Accused Of…</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/donald-trump/right-tonights-debate-hillary-gets-good-news-moderators-accused/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
