<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>John Falkenberg</author>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/judge-hillary-mistake-benghazi/">
        <end>177</end>
        <start>169</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.newsmax.com/Newsmax-Tv/Benghazi-Hillary-Clinton-trust-attack/2016/09/20/id/749235/">
        <end>272</end>
        <start>265</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://conservativetribune.com/clintons-friends-turned-on-her/">
        <end>107</end>
        <start>92</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Ambassador Chris Stevens’ former fiancée, Lydie Denier, said that former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton resigned because she knew just how badly she had bungled the Benghazi debacle. “She was at the top at the time; she was the secretary of state,” Denier told Newsmax. “What I always wondered is suddenly she decided to quit her job as secretary of state earlier than people were expecting.” Denier addressed Benghazi and its aftermath in a new book, “A Voice for Ambassador J. Christopher Stevens,” commemorating the sacrifice of Stevens and the other Americans who died in the attack on the American diplomatic compound in September of 2012. She speculated as to the cause of Clinton’s departure from office: “Did someone tell her, ‘Listen, you made a big boo-boo and you have to get out?’ That subject has never been brought to the public.” Understandably, she said that Hillary Clinton can’t be trusted for the country — she certainly proved that she couldn’t handle the one situation that claimed the life of Denier’s fiancee. “If we cannot trust her for Americans, how can we trust her for the whole country? It doesn’t make sense. In my book, I do talk about that and about what happened … Chris was and knew, was extremely knowledgeable about Libya and what was going on. He should’ve been listened to,” said Denier. The book also took time to celebrate who Stevens was as a person. His fiancée understandably remembered him fondly. “The Chris Stevens I knew was fun and loving, caring, always putting others in front of everything instead of himself,” she said. Ultimately, Steven gave his life for his country — but he shouldn’t have had to. Please share this on Facebook and Twitter and let us know what you think of Stevens, Hillary Clinton and Benghazi. What do you think of Hillary Clinton's handling of Benghazi? Scroll down to comment below!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>186</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>396</end>
        <start>187</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>648</end>
        <start>397</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>848</end>
        <start>649</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1036</end>
        <start>849</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1329</end>
        <start>1037</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1445</end>
        <start>1330</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1575</end>
        <start>1446</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1656</end>
        <start>1576</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1771</end>
        <start>1657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1862</end>
        <start>1772</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Conservative Tribune</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>251</end>
        <start>188</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>395</end>
        <start>275</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>503</end>
        <start>457</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>847</end>
        <start>717</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1315</end>
        <start>1038</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1564</end>
        <start>1447</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Amb. Stevens’ Fiancee Releases Book, Levels Devastating Accusation at Hillary</title>
    <uri>http://conservativetribune.com/amb-stevens-fiancee-book/?utm_source=Facebook&amp;utm_medium=RightWingNews&amp;utm_content=2016-09-22&amp;utm_campaign=manualpost</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
