<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Rory Grant</author>
    <links href="http://ijr.com/2016/09/697400-hillary-tells-steve-harvey-shell-help-stop-police-shootings-by-speaking-directly-to-white-people/">
        <end>24</end>
        <start>16</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton appeared on Steve Harvey on Tuesday and expressed the feeling that she wanted to be instrumental in improving policing tactics in the United States. Specifically she was referencing the recent shooting of Terence Crutcher in Tulsa, Oklahoma by a white female police officer. It is now dominating the news as leftists and Black Lives Matter activists are simultaneously going crazy. She said, “How many times do we have to see this in our country? This is unbearable and it needs to be intolerable. Maybe I can, by speaking directly to white people [and] say, ‘Look this is not who we are.’ We’ve got to do everything possible to improve policing, to go right at implicit bias. We can do better. We have got to rein in what is absolutely inexplicable.” It is funny how she almost appears to be endorsing the idea that African American people are unjustly oppressed and discriminated against in the United States. Black people often say that one black person is not representative of the entire African American race. Yet, she thinks that as a white woman she can speak for all white people? That is pretty ignorant. Not even considering the fact that more people in her party like Senator Bernie Sanders than her. Crutcher’s family released the violent video of his death at the hands of a police officer on Tuesday. The Tulsa Police Chief said to the media during a press conference that no firearm was found at the scene of the shooting. The police officer indicated she shot Crutcher because he motioned his hand into the car as if to grab something which she had believed was a firearm. Which would seem to corroborate the belief that Crutcher was unarmed and not a danger to the police officers. To think that all one needs to do is “talk to white people” in order to quell the issue of systemic racism or brutality against African Americans is absolutely ludicrous. You would think that for a seasoned politician Clinton would understand that it is actions and not words that effect real change. But Clinton is usually all talk and no walk. Considering the fact she changes her opinions on issues as quickly as the cash from private lobbyists and Wall Street backers is created. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>164</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>397</end>
        <start>165</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>407</end>
        <start>398</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>767</end>
        <start>408</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1228</end>
        <start>768</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1715</end>
        <start>1229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2199</end>
        <start>1716</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2200</end>
        <start>2200</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>766</end>
        <start>409</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1774</end>
        <start>1754</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hillary Tells Steve Harvey She’ll Help Stop Police Shootings By Doing This To ‘White People’</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/hillary-steve-harvey-police-shootings-white-people/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
