<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Posted by Frank Wilkenmeyer on 25 Sep 2016</author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/780199873979219968">
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>1290</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>How can you tell when a man is so far gone that he’s obviously not fit to stand on a stage for 90 minutes? That opinion would likely differ from psychologist to psychologist, but certainly there are warning signs. Donald Trump has been running full-steam now for months. He’s constantly on the campaign trail, under the hot lights of the cameras with little time for rest. He’s a 70-year-old man and he refuses to let up. He’s been not only preparing for a debate with a world-class politician (no matter how much he denies it he knows the truth) and to “relax” he flies to Roanoke last-minute to hold a rally. It’s obviously catching up to him. Sunday night, less than 24 hours before he’s set to walk into the hall to get ready for the most important night of his life, Donald Trump is showing signs that he’s simply taken this thing too far and gone off the deep end. This incoherent tweet covers three topics that are completely unrelated. It shows that Trump’s mind is prone to wandering and while each topic by itself may have been a talking point used to pander to somebody, together it’s just gibberish: Five people killed in Washington State by a Middle Eastern immigrant. Many people died this weekend in Ohio from drug overdoses. N.C. riots! — Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) September 26, 2016  Just…what is he talking about? If you’re trying to court the people you want to scare into voting for you, you talk about terrorism. If you want to court moderates concerned that drugs are seeping into the middle-class like never before you talk about opioid deaths. If you want to pander to your low-hanging fruit and court the racists you talk about riots in North Carolina. Talking about them together shows just one thing: Trump is coming unhinged. He’s obviously not ready and maybe even unfit to debate Hillary Clinton. This could be the end of the line for the Trump train. Featured image from file</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>213</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>610</end>
        <start>214</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1111</end>
        <start>611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1252</end>
        <start>1112</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>1253</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1309</end>
        <start>1309</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1686</end>
        <start>1310</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1890</end>
        <start>1687</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1915</end>
        <start>1891</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Winning Democrats</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>560</end>
        <start>555</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>1112</start>
    </quotes>
    <title></title>
    <uri>http://winningdemocrats.com/donald-trump-goes-off-the-deep-end-may-be-unfit-for-debate/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
