<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>John Prager</author>
    <links href="https://www.facebook.com/RBReich/posts/1311195112226415">
        <end>462</end>
        <start>449</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>You’ve got to love Robert Reich. The former Secretary of Labor under future First Lady and former President Bill Clinton met a Trump supporter at a coffee shop and couldn’t resist stopping for a moment to ruin the poor guy’s week by introducing him to a concept that is foreign to him: facts. “I finally found a Trump supporter — this morning when I went to buy coffee. (I noticed a Trump bumper sticker on his car.),” Reich writes in a Facebook post that has gone viral since he posted it Monday morning. Then he completely dismantled Trump — politely — before the guy’s very eyes: “Hi,” I said. “Noticed your Trump bumper sticker.” “Yup,” he said, a bit defensively. “I hope you don’t mind my asking, but I’m curious. Why are you supporting him?” “I know he’s a little bit much,” said the Trump supporter. “But he’s a successful businessman. And we need a successful businessman as president.” “How do you know he’s a successful businessman?” I asked. “Because he’s made a fortune.” “Has he really?” I asked. “Of course. Forbes magazine says he’s worth four and a half billion.” “That doesn’t mean he’s been a success,” I said. “In my book it does,” said the Trump supporter. “You know, in 1976, when Trump was just starting his career, he said he was worth about $200 million,” I said. “Most of that was from his father.” “That just proves my point,” said the Trump supporter. “He turned that $200 million into four and a half billion. Brilliant man.” “But if he had just put that $200 million into an index fund and reinvested the dividends, he’d be worth twelve billion today,” I said. The Trump supporter went silent. “And he got about $850 million in tax subsidies, just in New York alone,” I said. More silence. “He’s not a businessman,” Reich concluded. “He’s a con man. “Hope you enjoy your coffee.” While it’s unlikely that Reich managed to change the Trump fan’s mind — or even reach him on a level that matters — he surely left the guy steaming more than a freshly-brewed cup of go-go- juice. Oh, to be a fly on the wall during that conversation! </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>298</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>600</end>
        <start>299</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>659</end>
        <start>601</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>698</end>
        <start>660</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>786</end>
        <start>699</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>945</end>
        <start>787</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1009</end>
        <start>946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1046</end>
        <start>1010</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1076</end>
        <start>1047</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1152</end>
        <start>1077</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1209</end>
        <start>1153</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1261</end>
        <start>1210</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1416</end>
        <start>1262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1554</end>
        <start>1417</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1696</end>
        <start>1555</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1729</end>
        <start>1697</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1815</end>
        <start>1730</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1829</end>
        <start>1816</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1934</end>
        <start>1830</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2193</end>
        <start>1935</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2194</end>
        <start>2194</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1828</end>
        <start>601</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Robert Reich Just Ruined A Trump Supporter’s Week With Facts</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/19/robert-reich-just-ruined-a-trump-supporters-week-with-facts/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
