<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Mr. Wendal</author>
    <links href="http://dailycaller.com/2016/09/23/mlb-player-gets-suspension-for-the-season-after-criticizing-obama-black-lives-matter/">
        <end>201</end>
        <start>185</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Doesn’t this piss you off, even just a little bit? All the garbage going down in the NFL with players and teams and now nationwide in highschools disrespecting the national anthem, FOR Blacklivesmatter. …and nothing happens to them, because it’s their right. Now another athlete speaks AGAINST BlackLivesMatter and he gets suspended…for an entire season? How do they figure? Seattle Mariners catcher Steve Clevenger has been suspended for criticizing Black Lives Matter and President Obama. “BLM is pathetic once again! Obama you are pathetic once again! Everyone involved should be locked behind bars like animals!” the backup catcher tweeted out about the riots in Charlotte. He also tweeted, “Black people beating whites when a thug got shot holding a gun by a black officer haha shit cracks me up! Keep kneeling for the Anthem!” The Mariners announced on Friday that he would be suspended for the rest of the season without pay. Clevenger will lose out on about $30,000 in salary according to ESPN reporter Darren Rovell. And of course…as always, the apology. Statement from Steve Clevenger “First and foremost I would like to apologize to the Seattle Mariners, my teammates, my family and the fans of our great game for the distraction my tweets on my personal twitter page caused when they went public earlier today. I am sickened by the idea that anyone would think of me in racist terms. My tweets were reactionary to the events I saw on the news and were worded beyond poorly at best and I can see how and why someone could read into my tweets far more deeply than how I actually feel. “I grew up on the streets of Baltimore, a city I love to this very day. I grew up in a very culturally diverse area of America and I am very proud to come from there. I am also proud that my inner circle of friends has never been defined by race but by the content of their character. Any former teammate or anyone who has met me can attest to this and I pride myself on not being a judgemental person. I just ask that the public not judge me because of an ill worded tweet. “I do believe that supporting our First Amendment rights and supporting local law enforcement are not mutually exclusive. With everything going on in the world I really just want what is best for everyone regardless of who they are. I like many Americans are frustrated by a lot of things in the world and I would like to be a part of the dialogue moving forward to make this a better world for everyone. ” I once again apologize to anyone who was offended today and I just ask you not judge me off of a social media posting. Thank you and God bless everyone.” Steve Clevenger While those in support of BlackLivesMatter continue to put our first responders in dangers, loot our businesses and beat up whoever they want…and still have DC releasing statement that support them.. like “we feel your pain” … This man gets severe consequences for simply unleashing his frustration in the form of words on social media. Sometimes I really hate this planet…and this is one of those times.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>258</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>374</end>
        <start>259</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>490</end>
        <start>375</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>677</end>
        <start>491</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>832</end>
        <start>678</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1025</end>
        <start>833</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1063</end>
        <start>1026</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1094</end>
        <start>1064</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2630</end>
        <start>1095</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2646</end>
        <start>2631</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2873</end>
        <start>2647</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2983</end>
        <start>2874</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3051</end>
        <start>2984</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>I Have The Truth</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>615</end>
        <start>492</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>831</end>
        <start>696</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2475</end>
        <start>1096</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2870</end>
        <start>2853</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1025</end>
        <start>375</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2646</end>
        <start>1064</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>36</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>MLB Player Gets Suspended For An ENTIRE Season After Criticizing Obama’s BlackLivesMatter…</title>
    <uri>https://ihavethetruth.com/2016/09/23/mlb-player-gets-suspended-for-an-entire-season-after-criticizing-obamas-blacklivesmatter/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
