<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Kat O'Kelley</author>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/original.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-22-at-8.35.01-AM.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>NASCAR is under fire like never before, quite like this nation. Earlier this week we reported that NASCAR was getting sued $500 million after being accused of having unfair advantages for race car drivers. Specifically white race car drivers. Terrance Cox III, who is the CEO of Diversity Motorsports, filed the racial discrimination claim due to minorities being denied basically any chance in the sport of NASCAR. NASCAR quickly came out with a statement explaining why all of that was wrong.  Here’s what Cox stated: “In 2016, motorsports remain the most racially segregated sport in the United States. [NASCAR has] been complicit in, and supportive of, the racially discriminatory environment that virtually excludes African Americans from meaningful participation in motorsports racing in the United States.” NASCAR however completely disagrees seeing that they have programs designed specifically to end racial discrimination in the sport. “Diversity both on and off the track continues to be a top priority for NASCAR and its stakeholders. We stand behind our actions, and will not let a publicity-seeking legal action deter us from our mission.” Whether we believe it or not, racial discrimination is still present here in America. NASCAR may not be guilty of it, but America as a whole is. Recently police in Charlotte, NC shot a black man and killed him. Keith Lamont Scott was approached by police when they were searching for a man under warrant. Scott was not the man they were looking for, but police stated that he appeared to be holding a gun. According to onlookers and family, Scott was reportedly holding a book that he was reading beforehand, and it looked like that was enough to lead policemen to believe it was a weapon.  Because of this act, people of Charlotte were completely outraged. They began protesting on that day and have not stopped protesting since. Just last night, protesters went wild and violent. One person was shot while multiple shops and buildings were looted. One of those buildings was the NASCAR Hall of Fame in Charlotte. They have closed down for now, according to Bob Pockrass, reporter at ESPN. “NASCAR has closed its Charlotte office for normal business today. During the unrest Wednesday night in Charlotte, windows were broken on the ground floor of the building tower where NASCAR offices occupy several floors.” Here’s a news video of the past 24 hours in Charlotte.  We are praying not only for the members of NASCAR but for this nation. That we would see the love of God prevail throughout these horrible times.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>63</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>242</end>
        <start>64</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>494</end>
        <start>243</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>495</end>
        <start>495</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>519</end>
        <start>496</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>520</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>945</end>
        <start>814</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1153</end>
        <start>946</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1298</end>
        <start>1154</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1743</end>
        <start>1299</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1744</end>
        <start>1744</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2003</end>
        <start>1745</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2144</end>
        <start>2004</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2366</end>
        <start>2145</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2421</end>
        <start>2367</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2422</end>
        <start>2422</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2568</end>
        <start>2423</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>812</end>
        <start>521</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1152</end>
        <start>947</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2365</end>
        <start>2146</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>813</end>
        <start>520</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1153</end>
        <start>946</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2366</end>
        <start>2145</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>BREAKING: NASCAR Shuts Down After Protests</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/sports/nascar/breaking-nascar-shuts-down-after-protests/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=nascar+closes%2F9%2F22&amp;utm_term=Right+Wing+News%2Fnascar+closes%2F9%2F22</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
