<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>The men and women on 2016’s Politico 50 list are some of the brightest, most provocative minds in American life. So what do they think about the pressing questions facing this country in 2016 and beyond? Where do they stand on Hillary Clinton vs. Donald Trump? Where would Barack Obama rank on an all-time list of presidents? What single word best describes the respective states of our two political parties? Of all the challenges facing America right now, which one is the biggest? And what issue is most likely to surprise us in 2017? We asked The Politico 50, and although they have very different ideas and backgrounds—from entertainers to academics to lawyers to professional agitators—there are areas where they agree. Ninety-eight percent, for instance, said that Russia is an international menace. Seventy-three percent said that, on balance, international trade deals help America. Fifty-three percent said that Bernie Sanders’ candidacy ultimately helped the Democratic Party. And The Politico 50, on average, are quite worried about the prospect of a Trump presidency. But there are many points of dispute across a broad swath of issues and interests, whether it’s the sleeper issue driving the election, Trump’s greatest strength as a candidate or Obama’s biggest piece of unfinished business in the White House. Here, their answers to our annual Politico 50 survey. (5W Infographics; illustrations by John Jay Cabuay)    Our guide to the thinkers, doers and visionaries transforming American politics.</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>203</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>537</end>
        <start>204</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1080</end>
        <start>538</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1379</end>
        <start>1081</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1431</end>
        <start>1380</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1432</end>
        <start>1432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1433</end>
        <start>1433</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1434</end>
        <start>1434</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1515</end>
        <start>1435</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <title>The 2016 POLITICO 50 Survey</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/09/2016-election-trump-clinton-obama-politico-50-survey-214232?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
