<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Sierra Marlee</author>
    <links href="http://www.bizpacreview.com/2016/09/26/high-school-teacher-sanctioned-calling-trump-supporting-students-racists-facebook-394215">
        <end>348</end>
        <start>331</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Veronic-Welsh-student-racist-gear-Trump-300x157.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.bizpacreview.com/2016/09/26/high-school-teacher-sanctioned-calling-trump-supporting-students-racists-facebook-394215">
        <end>822</end>
        <start>806</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Is it just me or has there been a rash of teachers behaving poorly across the nation? Maybe it’s always existed, but now because of social media, it comes out faster. Whatever the reason for the seeming increase of crappy educators, we can all agree that it’s NOT okay for anyone to call our kids “racists” for any reason. Period. End of discussion.  Veronica Welsh of Smithtown, NY called her students “racist” for doing absolutely nothing racist. They weren’t using racial slurs, they weren’t excluding minorities from their clubs, teams, groups, etc. They weren’t doing ANYTHING except, wait for it, wearing pro-Trump gear on USA day. These teachers are just part of a growing group of increasingly-liberal educators that have our children 7-8 hours a day. If this doesn’t frighten you, then you’re not paying attention. The Smithtown Superintendent called the act: “…An extremely unfortunate incident and these actions are not promoted by the Smithtown Central School District Administration and Board of Education, nor do they reflect the attitudes of our students and staff.” Of course when people get caught being jerks to others, they preach about their First Amendment rights and complain about the repercussions of their actions. Let’s not get into the fact that the First Amendment protects you from the government, not from being fired from your job for saying something outrageous. Are you being imprisoned? No? Alrighty then, you’re exercising your First Amendment rights and we’re exercising our right to hit back against your rhetoric. But let’s look into what punishment this teacher faced, because I think you might be surprised to hear what happened to her almost immediately after this nasty Facebook post hit the web. The Smithtown Superintendent said that Veronica Walsh has been sanctioned and “administratively reassigned.” Gotta love that karma bus. It’s going to be a difficult road trying to get another job in education with a history that is currently all over the news. </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>166</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>349</end>
        <start>167</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>350</end>
        <start>350</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>637</end>
        <start>351</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>823</end>
        <start>638</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>868</end>
        <start>824</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1239</end>
        <start>1082</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1551</end>
        <start>1240</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1738</end>
        <start>1552</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1847</end>
        <start>1739</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1999</end>
        <start>1848</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2000</end>
        <start>2000</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>305</end>
        <start>298</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>304</end>
        <start>298</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1080</end>
        <start>870</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1846</end>
        <start>1818</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1081</end>
        <start>869</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>High school teacher calls Trump-supporting students ‘racists’ on Facebook &amp; Gets Instant Karma</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/top-news/high-school-teacher-calls-high-school-teacher-calls-trump-supporting-students-racists-facebook-gets-instant-karmatrump-supporting-students-racists-facebook/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
