<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Charles Roberts</author>
    <mainText>A hardworking farmer went on ABC's reality show "Shark Tank" to pitch his product, which simply exists to improve the lives of other farmers, and was mocked for his lack of business expertise (video below). But by the end of his pitch, he had an investor and had won over the hearts of all the sharks on the panel. Johnny Georges, a farmer and the inventor of the Tree T-Pee, brought his invention to "Shark Tank," seeking an investment to help sell his product nationwide. As he explained his product to the panel of sharks and revealed that he had only sold within five counties of his Florida farm, the sharks were stunned. They began nearly mocking him for his lack of business experience and questioning how the company was expected to succeed.  Georges tried to explain that he wants to do what is right and to help other farmers, so he only makes $1 per Tree T-Pee. The judges were shocked he hadn't expanded his market or raised his prices, but he remained faithful to the greater cause. Finally, Georges' character won the hearts of the panel and John Paul DeJoria, co-founder of hair care product company Paul Mitchell, offered to give him exactly what he asked for. The moral of this story is certainly to stay true to who you are and what you believe in. Watch Georges' "Shark Tank" pitch below.  </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>314</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>473</end>
        <start>315</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>750</end>
        <start>474</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>995</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1176</end>
        <start>996</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1308</end>
        <start>1177</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1309</end>
        <start>1309</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>America Now</portal>
    <title>Naive Farmer Dismissed During 'Shark Tank' Pitch (Video)</title>
    <uri>http://www.americanow.com/story/society/2016/09/20/naive-farmer-dismissed-during-shark-tank-pitch-video?fb=rwn</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
