<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Stephen D Foster Jr</author>
    <links href="http://www.rawstory.com/2016/09/trump-loving-firefighter-canned-after-advocating-to-make-slavery-legal-again/">
        <end>558</end>
        <start>549</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.ksfy.com/content/news/Dell-Rapids-firefighter-relieved-of-duties-after-racist-comments-393919681.html">
        <end>826</end>
        <start>817</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton was absolutely right to call Trump supporters deplorable and this is why. In response to the expulsion of a Kansas State University student who said it “feels good to finally be a n*gga” in a photo of herself covered in L’Oréal facial cleansing mask, Dell Rapids, South Dakota firefighter John Nygaard literally called for bringing back slavery and endorsed Republican nominee Donald Trump. “Think we should make slaves again,” Nygaard wrote. “Vote Trump! Fuck these people.” Here’s a screenshot of his comments via Raw Story.  While that probably made Trump and his white supremacist supporters smile, the people of Dell Rapids were horrified by the remarks. “You’re a public servant and you’re putting stuff like that on Facebook, that’s not good,” resident William Dezee told KSFY. “There’s enough problems going on, we don’t need racial slurs or people wearing masks or saying something that’s what 160 years old, leave it alone. That’s the way it should be.” The outrage was enough for the Dell Rapids Fire Rescue to boot Nygaard off the squad and he has been terminated. “John is no longer a member of our volunteer organization,” the department said in a statement posted on Facebook. “Dell Rapids fire would like to apologize on behalf of our former member for his insensitive and narrow minded comments on Facebook. This is something we take very seriously and this type of thinking will not be tolerated by our members.” Here’s the report via KSFY.   People like Nygaard hurt the trust between the community and our first responders because you have to wonder if you are going to be helped or not depending on what color your skin is. A public service like fire rescue should work to help everyone regardless of race. But racists like Nygaard undermine that principle. Donald Trump has objected to his supporters being called deplorable. Well, if he really doesn’t think a racist who supports re-enslaving black people is deplorable, he has zero chance of getting a black person to vote for him, and he certainly shouldn’t get anyone else’s vote either. </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>89</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>413</end>
        <start>90</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>506</end>
        <start>414</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>559</end>
        <start>507</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>560</end>
        <start>560</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>692</end>
        <start>561</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1018</end>
        <start>693</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1131</end>
        <start>1019</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1493</end>
        <start>1132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1523</end>
        <start>1494</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1524</end>
        <start>1524</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1525</end>
        <start>1525</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1843</end>
        <start>1526</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2134</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2135</end>
        <start>2135</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <title>Deplorable Firefighter Fired After Calling For Bringing Back Slavery In Support Of Trump</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/19/deplorable-firefighter-fired-after-calling-for-bringing-back-slavery-in-support-of-trump/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
