<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Elvin Bartley</author>
    <links href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3359331/Angela-Merkel-promises-significantly-reduce-number-migrants-entering-Germany-response-growing-resentment-asylum-policies.html">
        <end>801</end>
        <start>791</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Germany’s chancellor Angela Merkel has been the biggest proponent of bringing in as many Syrian refugees as possible, adopting a literal open borders policy to bring in the migrants. This quickly turned into a horror show, as crime was unleashed onto German cities, with thousands of sexual assaults and other violent crimes were reported over the last year. The German people had apparently had enough of this rampant crime in Germany, because they just dealt a crushing blow to Merkel’s conservative Democrat party and voted them out by a large margin. Merkel then took to the stage to backtrack as much as she could, citing that the migrant crisis could have been avoided, and that she regrets the mistake she made, also referring to multiculturalism as a “living lie.”  According to the Daily Mail, Speaking to the party faithful at its annual conference, she repeated her catchphrase from throughout the migrant crisis, ‘we can do this’, but effectively admitted Germany could only cope if she wrestled back control of the influx. ‘A continuation of the current influx would in the long-term overwhelm the state and society, even in a country like Germany,’ she said. The leader, once known as the ‘Iron Chancellor’, won rapturous applause after announcing the volte face. However, she resisted calls to set a limit on the number of arrivals. ‘We want to, and we will, noticeably reduce the number of refugees,’ she told the conference in Karlsruhe. ‘With an approach focused on the German, European and global level, we will succeed in regulating and limiting migration.’ Mrs Merkel attempted to defend her August decision, which drew hundreds of thousands to Europe, claiming it was a ‘humanitarian imperative’. She appealed to the party’s sense of history, saying that the same strength that allowed it ‘to rebuild from the rubble of the war to create the economic miracle, and to go from division to a reunified country’ would get Germany through the crisis. She said she was banking on a multi-pronged approach to cut migrant numbers, urging bolstered protection for the bloc’s external borders, support for Turkey to host refugees long-term and a long-shot bid for a distribution scheme among EU member states. She also touted a range of measures already undertaken in Germany including speeding up the deportation of failed asylum applicants. Mrs Merkel, who has been the country’s leader for a decade, tried to paint an upbeat vision saying it was no longer the ‘sick man of Europe’ and ‘should be a country that is open, curious, tolerant and even exciting’.  It’s nice that she recognizes this, but it’s too little, too late. It came as no surprise to anyone voting Trump, but then again, it’s getting tiring to say “I told you so” so many times to so many different people. Hillary is still full-steam ahead on increasing the number of migrants into the country, so there’s no telling what can happen if she is allowed to win the election. We have to stop her in November by storming the voting booths and voting with our consciences. (Source: Daily Mail) </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>358</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>772</end>
        <start>359</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>773</end>
        <start>773</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>802</end>
        <start>774</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1035</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1172</end>
        <start>1036</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1347</end>
        <start>1173</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1577</end>
        <start>1348</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1967</end>
        <start>1578</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2221</end>
        <start>1968</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2572</end>
        <start>2222</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2573</end>
        <start>2573</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3050</end>
        <start>2574</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3071</end>
        <start>3051</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>3072</end>
        <start>3072</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Yes Im Right</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>771</end>
        <start>760</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2745</end>
        <start>2732</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2572</end>
        <start>803</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Angela Merkel Admits Bringing In Muslim Refugees Was A Big Fat Mistake</title>
    <uri>http://www.yesimright.com/angela-merkel-admits-bringing-in-muslim-refugees-was-a-big-fat-mistake/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly false</veracity>
</article>
