<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Tom Cahill</author>
    <links href="https://usuncut.com/class-war/elizabeth-warren-destroys-wells-fargo-ceo-video/">
        <end>167</end>
        <start>145</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/21/investing/wells-fargo-fired-workers-retaliation-fake-accounts/index.html">
        <end>990</end>
        <start>971</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/21/investing/wells-fargo-fired-workers-retaliation-fake-accounts/index.html">
        <end>1273</end>
        <start>1250</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/21/investing/wells-fargo-fired-workers-retaliation-fake-accounts/index.html">
        <end>1945</end>
        <start>1908</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/09/09/investing/wells-fargo-phony-accounts-culture/index.html?iid=EL">
        <end>2308</end>
        <start>2295</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://usuncut.com/class-war/wells-fargo-busted-scamming-customers/">
        <end>2475</end>
        <start>2448</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Roughly a half dozen Wells Fargo workers who tried doing the right thing about the bank’s scamming of customers were summarily fired. During his grilling in Washington earlier this week, Wells Fargo CEO John Stumpf testified that it was company policy to enable whistleblowers to speak out against unethical and fraudulent behavior at the bank. “Each team member, no matter where you are in the organization, is encouraged to raise their hands,” Stumpf said. However, Bill Bado, a former Wells Fargo banker in Pennsylvania, claims he had a different experience. Bado was given orders from his supervisors in September 2013 to enroll customers in phony accounts without their knowledge or consent. Bado not only refused, he called the company’s ethics hotline and contacted the bank’s human resources hotline to inform them of the scam. After Bado was let go, the bank’s official reason for his firing was “tardiness.” “I told them that’s not only unethical but illegal,” Bado told CNN Money. “They ruined my life.” A Wells Fargo human resources worker — who elected to remain anonymous to protect their career — also told CNN Money that the corporate headquarters put policies in place that were utilized to take revenge against whistleblowers, like firing them on the spot for showing up two minutes late. Former SEC chairman Harvey Pitt said that previous financial reform legislation, like the Dodd-Frank Act and the Sarbanes-Oxley Act codified protections for workers calling out illegal behavior at financial institutions. “It is clearly against the law for any company (or executives of such companies) to try to suppress whistleblowing,” Pitt told CNNMoney in an email. In early September, Heather Brock was fired from her position as a senior business banker at a Wells Fargo branch in Round Rock, Texas after she spoke up about the dubious sales practices she was asked to carry out. Brock said she endured textbook workplace harassment before eventually being fired. Sabrina Bertrand, who used to work for Wells Fargo in Houston, described pressure from her superiors to open the scam accounts was “unbearable.” “I endured harsh bullying … defamation of character, and eventually being pinned for something I didn’t do,”Brock told CNN Money. “I had managers in my face yelling at me,” Bertrand said. “They wanted you to open up dual checking accounts for people that couldn’t even manage their original checking account.” Wells Fargo was recently fined $185 million by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau for perpetuating an elaborate scam of opening credit card and checking accounts on behalf of customers who never signed off on them in order to drive sales numbers higher. While 5,300 low-level and mid-tier employees were let go after the scam was exposed, no senior management or compliance officials have been fired as of this writing, and CEO John Stumpf has not yet stepped down.        </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>133</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>344</end>
        <start>134</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>458</end>
        <start>345</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>917</end>
        <start>459</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1014</end>
        <start>918</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1527</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1676</end>
        <start>1528</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2121</end>
        <start>1677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2251</end>
        <start>2122</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2431</end>
        <start>2252</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2903</end>
        <start>2432</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2905</end>
        <start>2904</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2906</end>
        <start>2906</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2907</end>
        <start>2907</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2908</end>
        <start>2908</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2909</end>
        <start>2909</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2910</end>
        <start>2910</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2911</end>
        <start>2911</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>US Uncut</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>444</end>
        <start>346</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>916</end>
        <start>906</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>969</end>
        <start>919</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>993</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1643</end>
        <start>1529</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2120</end>
        <start>2109</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2229</end>
        <start>2123</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2293</end>
        <start>2253</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2430</end>
        <start>2311</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>I worked at Wells Fargo and blew the whistle on rampant fraud — then they fired me.</title>
    <uri>http://usuncut.com/news/wells-fargo-fired-whistleblowers/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
