<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <mainText>Hillary Clinton’s suggestion that Donald Trump’s rhetoric is treasonous and a recruiting tool for the Islamic State is beneath someone who’s running for the U.S. presidency, the Republican presidential nominee said Tuesday. “Her claim that my opposition to radical Islamic terrorism is a recruiting tool — what? How does that have to do with…” Trump began. “I’m being tough. Why is that a recruiting? I’m much tougher than her on this problem, this horrible situation, but she goes around saying it’s a recruiting tool.” Story Continued Below Clinton on Monday hinted that the real estate mogul may be committing treason by “giving aid and comfort to our adversaries” — the constitutional definition of the term — and said that he “is being used as a recruiting sergeant in and for the terrorists.” During a rally in High Point, North Carolina, on Tuesday afternoon, Trump suggested that Clinton was given her recruiting attack line by an advertising firm. “You know, somebody gave her that from Madison Avenue. You know what Madison — that’s advertising,” Trump said. “They gave her that from — they said let’s call it a recruiting tool. But why? Because I’m tough? It’s a recruiting tool?” Clinton’s rhetoric “demonstrates a level of ignorance about the terror threat,” Trump added. “That really is disqualifying for a person seeking the presidency. When she says my opposition to radical Islamic terror provides aid and comfort to the enemy, we know that Hillary Clinton has once again demonstrated that she’s really unfit for office. Her comments are not only reckless but beneath the dignity of the office that she seeks.”</mainText>
    <orientation>mainstream</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>223</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>520</end>
        <start>224</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>542</end>
        <start>521</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>798</end>
        <start>543</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>956</end>
        <start>799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1191</end>
        <start>957</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1627</end>
        <start>1192</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Politico</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>342</end>
        <start>225</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>519</end>
        <start>358</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>666</end>
        <start>625</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>797</end>
        <start>732</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1055</end>
        <start>958</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1190</end>
        <start>1070</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1270</end>
        <start>1212</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1626</end>
        <start>1286</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump hits back at Clinton for claiming he's a terrorist recruiting tool</title>
    <uri>http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/trump-clinton-terror-response-228416?cmpid=sf</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
