<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Terresa Monroe-Hamilton</author>
    <links href="http://www.infowars.com/clinton-responds-to-hillary-for-prison-shout-lets-make-it-happen/">
        <end>24</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://rightwingnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Hillary1-1.png">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Hillary just gets punked over and over again these days. Her latest embarrassment came at a rally where some guy yelled, “Hillary for prison!” To which Hillary replied, “Let’s make it happen!” The entire nation finally agrees with Hillary Clinton on something. But I’m sure she got confused (yet again) and didn’t mean to say that. She must have misheard the guy and thought that he said something like, “Hillary for president!” Funny and pathetic all at once. Not to be outdone, Elizabeth Warren posed for a selfie with someone she thought was a Hillary supporter… not so much. She got punked as well with the young man saying, “But you lied about your ethnicity!” He also said Hillary would lose to Trump which caused a back and forth. That just made it worse for Warren. Cringeworthingly humiliating. (Photo: Getty) From InfoWars: Hillary Clinton was caught in an embarrassing moment when someone at her rally yelled “Hillary for prison!”, to which the presidential candidate responded, “Let’s make it happen!”  The cringeworthy moment was captured on film. Given her now notorious propensity for being constantly “confused,” Hillary probably thought the man was saying “Hillary for president!,” but nothing could be further from the truth. The “Hillary for prison!” meme has been going on now for some time. Born out of a frustration that she has not been held accountable for even the slightest of her crimes, the slogan reflects the mood of America. And Trump has capitalized on it brilliantly. ‘Hillary for Prison 2016’ has become the theme of the Grand Old Party – Americans see what the Hildabeast is… the most corrupt politician to ever run for office in our country. Since the GOP convention, it has been the rallying cry of those who support Donald Trump and even those who don’t. Hillary’s own associates and friends say that she is corrupt beyond belief. Between the scandals plaguing Clinton and her severe health issues, Trump is now leading her in the polls. And with the renewed terrorism threats and the support of the police union, Trump is sure to surge even further ahead. Clinton looks frail, weak and tainted… if the country is besieged by terrorist attack after attack, they will turn to a strongman like Donald Trump and beg for his leadership. God help us. America is changing and not for the better. Be careful what you wish for, you may just get it.   </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>460</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>803</end>
        <start>461</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>818</end>
        <start>804</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>833</end>
        <start>819</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1013</end>
        <start>834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1014</end>
        <start>1014</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1060</end>
        <start>1015</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1243</end>
        <start>1061</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1500</end>
        <start>1244</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1868</end>
        <start>1501</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2283</end>
        <start>1869</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2378</end>
        <start>2284</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2379</end>
        <start>2379</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2380</end>
        <start>2380</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2381</end>
        <start>2381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Right Wing News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>141</end>
        <start>122</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>191</end>
        <start>170</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>427</end>
        <start>405</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>630</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>141</end>
        <start>122</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>191</end>
        <start>170</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1127</end>
        <start>1118</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1197</end>
        <start>1174</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>141</end>
        <start>122</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>407</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Clinton’s Response To “Hillary For Prison”?! “Let’s Make It Happen!” [VIDEO]</title>
    <uri>http://rightwingnews.com/hillary-clinton-2/clintons-response-to-hillary-for-prison-lets-make-it-happen-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
