<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Nancy Wells</author>
    <links href="http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/breaking-loretta-lynn-cancels-all-shows-after-devestating-health-news/">
        <end>399</end>
        <start>393</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Loretta-Lynn-630x420-2.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://cdn.newsbake.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/d52845833f5190637b483f66a92407ca.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Just a couple of weeks ago Loretta Lynn fell before a concert and doctors said that she would have to undergo surgery because of the injuries. Loretta Lynn was forced to postpone her upcoming concerts after the country legend fell before her big Labor Day Concert. The fall was a serious fall and Loretta was suffering from several injuries. Heartbroken that she couldn’t be with her fans she posted a thank you to everyone for their understanding. “I thank you all for coming, and I’m sorry I can’t be there with you. I’ve fallen, and I can’t get up. I injured my chest and can’t get a deep enough breath to sing, but I’ll update you Monday [Sept. 5] after I see the doctor.”  Unfortunately, things only got worse from there. Just a week or so ago Loretta Lynn announced that she was going to have to have surgery. Her website posted the update and fans were heartbroken that Loretta was going to have to go through all of this. “American country music legend Loretta Lynn is at home recuperating from a recent fall that left her unable to perform on Labor Day weekend at her ranch in Hurricane Mills, Tennessee. Although her injuries are not serious, she will be undergoing minor surgery and Loretta’s doctors have advised her to stay off the road until she’s made a full recovery.” NOW she just released another announcement and it was what fans never expected. Just a couple of months after her fall Loretta is going to be releasing her new Christmas album “White Christmas Blue”. The album is going to be a 12 track album that will also feature new studio performances of several classic Christmas songs.  Check out the songs below: 1. “White Christmas Blue” 2. “Country Christmas” 3. “Winter Wonderland” 4. “Away in a Manger” 5. “Blue Christmas” 6. “To Heck With Ole Santa Claus” 7. “Frosty the Snowman” 8. “Oh Come, All Ye Faithful” 9. “Jingle Bells” 10. “White Christmas” 11. “Silent Night” 12. “‘Twas the Night Before Christmas” We are so thrilled to hear that Loretta is going to be releasing a new album. It seemed like things were going downhill for the country singer, but thankfully now things are starting to look up! This is going to be so good! Please continue to pray for Loretta to have a quick recovery so she can be back out on the stage!  Congrats on your new album, WE LOVE YOU LORETTA LYNN!</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>142</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>448</end>
        <start>143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>676</end>
        <start>449</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>677</end>
        <start>677</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>929</end>
        <start>678</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1284</end>
        <start>930</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1609</end>
        <start>1285</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1610</end>
        <start>1610</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1637</end>
        <start>1611</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1937</end>
        <start>1638</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2161</end>
        <start>1938</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2259</end>
        <start>2162</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2260</end>
        <start>2260</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2314</end>
        <start>2261</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Newsbake</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>675</end>
        <start>450</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1283</end>
        <start>931</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1482</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1482</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1685</end>
        <start>1668</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1708</end>
        <start>1691</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1730</end>
        <start>1714</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1750</end>
        <start>1736</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1784</end>
        <start>1756</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1808</end>
        <start>1790</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1838</end>
        <start>1814</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1856</end>
        <start>1844</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1477</end>
        <start>1462</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1897</end>
        <start>1885</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1936</end>
        <start>1904</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>676</end>
        <start>449</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1284</end>
        <start>930</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Loretta Lynn’s Manager Just Announced Shocking Health News</title>
    <uri>http://newsbake.com/entertainment-news/music-entertainment/breaking-loretta-lynns-manager-announces-shocking-news/?utm_source=Right+Wing+News&amp;utm_medium=Loretta+Lynn%2F9%2F20&amp;utm_campaign=Right+Wing+News%2FLoretta+Lynn%2F9%2F20</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
