<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>FreedomDaily</author>
    <links href="http://www.theblaze.com/stories/2016/09/21/charlotte-police-chief-officers-warned-black-man-to-drop-gun/">
        <end>709</end>
        <start>701</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/jZPnOfSwvC">
        <end>1202</end>
        <start>1179</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KeithLamontScott?src=hash">
        <end>1220</end>
        <start>1203</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/UpzQj5qZwo">
        <end>1244</end>
        <start>1221</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/CNN/status/778590665974378496">
        <end>1276</end>
        <start>1258</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>America continues to be rocked by racial unrest and division, as the shooting of a black man in Charlotte, North Carolina sends folks into a frenzy of rioting and violence. Keith Lamont Scott was shot and killed by police yesterday, an incident about which race hustlers wasted no time in jumping to conclusions — and pushing narratives — particularly after the man’s daughter posted a video ranting that her father was disabled and unarmed. Police Chief Kerr Putney and his officers have a bit of a different take on the situation, however. They’ve just revealed the man was armed. Furthermore, Chief Putney says police gave him several warnings to drop the gun, which he refused to do. According to TheBlaze, Charlotte-Mecklenburg Police Chief Kerr Putney said during a news conference Wednesday morning that officers were searching for a suspect Tuesday when they saw 43-year-old Keith Lamont Scott exit a vehicle with a handgun. He says the officers told him to drop the gun and that he got out of the vehicle a second time still carrying the gun. He says the man was shot because he posed a threat. Charlotte Police Chief: Officers gave loud, clear commands before shooting https://t.co/jZPnOfSwvC #KeithLamontScott https://t.co/UpzQj5qZwo — CNN (@CNN) September 21, 2016  “It’s time to change the narrative, because I can tell you from the facts that the story’s a little bit different as to how it’s been portrayed so far, especially through social media,” he said. His comments were an apparent reference to a profanity-laced, hourlong video that a woman claiming to be Scott’s daughter posted to Facebook soon after the shooting, saying that her father had an unspecified disability and was unarmed. In it, she appears to be at the shooting scene, which is surrounded by yellow police tape, as she yells at officers. The woman did not respond to Facebook messages, and her claims could not immediately be verified by The Associated Press. It also was not clear if she witnessed the shooting. As of now, the facts surrounding this case are still coming in, so it’s difficult to make a final judgment on the whole situation. If Scott was indeed armed and refused to comply with police officers, then those on the scene had no choice but to use force to neutralize the threat posed by the suspect. What’s unfortunate is that so many folks in Charlotte — and across the nation — have jumped to conclusions, buying into the narrative that police officers are somehow a corrupt institution looking for new and creative ways to exterminate blacks. Our nation is in desperate need of healing along racial lines, but this will never happen as long as folks believe a false narrative they’re being spoon fed by liberals who want nothing more than to keep minorities enslaved to the Democratic Party. [Note: This article was written by Michael Cantrell] </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>172</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>441</end>
        <start>173</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>687</end>
        <start>442</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1103</end>
        <start>688</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1244</end>
        <start>1104</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1276</end>
        <start>1245</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1277</end>
        <start>1277</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1472</end>
        <start>1278</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1825</end>
        <start>1473</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2000</end>
        <start>1826</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2131</end>
        <start>2001</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2303</end>
        <start>2132</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2549</end>
        <start>2304</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2798</end>
        <start>2550</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2851</end>
        <start>2799</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2852</end>
        <start>2852</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1462</end>
        <start>1279</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>557</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>JUST IN: Charlotte police reveal what they said to black man MOMENTS before shooting…</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/just-charlotte-police-reveal-said-black-man-moments-shooting/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
