<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Vera</author>
    <links href="http://www.rawstory.com/2016/09/trump-endorsing-police-union-turns-on-him-for-saying-cop-choked-in-tulsa-shooting/">
        <end>201</end>
        <start>180</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>While giving a speech at a church rally in Cleveland, Donald Trump confused everyone by actually siding with a victim of police brutality instead of law enforcement – and it’s gotten him in trouble with America’s largest police union. In speaking to the rally goers in Cleveland, Trump strayed from his normal, pro-cop rhetoric to say a few unflattering words about Betty Shelby, the Tulsa police officer who shot an unarmed black man. Clearly worried about how horrendously his attempts to reach black voters have failed, Trump gave an unusually thoughtful response to a group of African American pastors, in which he suggested that Shelby had ‘choked’: “Now, did she get scared? Was she choking? What happened? But maybe people like that, people that choke, people that do that, maybe they can’t be doing what they’re doing, okay? They can’t be doing what they’re doing. I watched the shooting in particular in Tulsa. And that man was hands up. That man went to the car, hands up, put his hand on the car. I mean, to me, it looked like he did everything you’re supposed to do, and he looked like a really good man.” Trump made these comments just five days after the Fraternal Order of Police (FOP), which has 330,000 members, endorsed him. But after hearing Trump criticize the Tulsa police officer, FOP executive director Jim Pasco is livid and thinks Trump’s comments were inappropriate. Pasco said that Trump “must be mindful of the due process rights and presumption of innocence accorded to all, including police officers.” Now, no one should be proud or relieved that Trump finally decided to acknowledge police brutality victims – he’s been known to pander to whatever audience he is in front of at any given moment, and is notorious for flip-flopping almost instantly. This speech was easy for Trump to say in front of black pastors – I doubt he would have dared to say this in front of a predominately white audience. Trump also knows he is struggling tremendously with the minority vote, which may very well determine this election. Trump will say whatever he needs to win – but this time, he lost a major support group. Here’s the clip that got Trump in trouble with the police union:  </mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>240</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>664</end>
        <start>241</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>892</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1142</end>
        <start>893</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1564</end>
        <start>1143</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2174</end>
        <start>1565</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2241</end>
        <start>2175</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2242</end>
        <start>2242</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2243</end>
        <start>2243</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Addicting Info</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>1141</end>
        <start>665</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Trump Loses Support Of Police Union After Saying Tulsa Shooting Cop ‘Choked’ (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://www.addictinginfo.org/2016/09/22/trump-loses-support-of-police-union-after-saying-tulsa-shooting-cop-choked-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mixture of true and false</veracity>
</article>
