<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>FreedomDaily</author>
    <links href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/1809088/minnesota-knife-attack-the-somali-isis-fanatic-dahir-a-adan-who-went-on-mall-knife-rampage-after-checking-whether-victims-were-muslims/">
        <end>756</end>
        <start>751</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.morningnewsusa.com/jason-falconer-st-cloud-mall-attack-hero-photos-facts-23106027.html">
        <end>947</end>
        <start>940</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.allenbwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/jason.jpg">
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/latest-claims-responsibility-minnesota-attack-42173338">
        <end>1272</end>
        <start>1239</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.michelehickford.com/">
        <end>1961</end>
        <start>1945</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>via Allen West: When tragic mass attacks occur, the media generally focuses on the attacker, making the victims anonymous factors in the body count. Can you name one victim of the Orlando Pulse Nightclub attack? No of course not, but you surely know the killer. The attacker in the St. Cloud Mall this weekend has been identified as a 22-year-old Somali man and “solider of ISIS.” But let’s ignore him for a moment and focus on the hero who brought him down – because you can be quite certain the liberal media doesn’t want you to know ANYthing about him. His name is Jason Falconer, an off-duty police officer and firearms instructor who owns a gun range. Falconer happened to be at the mall when the terrorist began carrying out his attack. The Sun says, Falconer opened fire as the suspect lunged towards him. He got up and continued his terrifying assault each time he was shot until he was eventually fatally wounded. Morning News USA reports, “His (Falconer’s) goal is to teach individuals the mindset, knowledge and skills needed to be successful with firearms in order to secure their personal safety or that of their family, at home or in public,” said Tactical Advantage, the off-duty police officer’s company website.  Falconer told the Minneapolis Star Tribune that he’s “been trying to stay away from it all, for the time being.” He told the newspaper he wasn’t hurt and declined to talk further, citing the ongoing investigation for not saying more. Well, we’d like to give Officer Falconer a really big shout-out and thanks. He’s once again proven the best way to stop a bad guy with a knife is a good guy with a GUN. This isn’t the ending liberals want to the story. They also don’t want you to know the attacker was asking victims if they were Muslims before stabbing them. And they certainly don’t want to know an armed citizen was the one who stopped further horror. Facts are nasty things. [Note: This article was written by Michele Hickford] </mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>261</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>555</end>
        <start>262</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>656</end>
        <start>556</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>812</end>
        <start>657</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>922</end>
        <start>813</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1228</end>
        <start>923</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1229</end>
        <start>1229</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1463</end>
        <start>1230</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1632</end>
        <start>1464</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1885</end>
        <start>1633</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1909</end>
        <start>1886</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1962</end>
        <start>1910</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1963</end>
        <start>1963</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Freedom Daily</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>379</end>
        <start>363</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1155</end>
        <start>950</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1341</end>
        <start>1284</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>12</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Hero who stopped ISIS mall attacker is making liberals CRAZY</title>
    <uri>http://freedomdaily.com/hero-stopped-isis-mall-attacker-making-liberals-crazy/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
