<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author></author>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Emmys?src=hash">
        <end>1648</end>
        <start>1642</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/jimmykimmel">
        <end>1662</end>
        <start>1650</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/DxE9JEoINP">
        <end>1752</end>
        <start>1729</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://t.co/vZ6gNe5HnL">
        <end>1779</end>
        <start>1753</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/THR/status/777662618781650945">
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1808</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Jimmy Kimmel had an opportunity to bash Donald Trump in front of an audience of millions at the Emmys and he did not disappoint. He even went after Trump’s enablers who were sitting in the audience. Kimmel opened the ceremony by poking fun of Hollywood’s elite and making several sarcastic but pointed jokes about diversity. “This year’s nominees are the most diverse ever. And here in Hollywood, the only thing we value more than diversity is congratulating ourselves on how much we value diversity. The Emmys are so diverse this year, the Oscars are telling people we’re one of their closest friends.” Kimmel sarcastically riffed about the existence of television making it possible for such self-aggrandizing and bombastic egotists like Trump to thrive. “If it weren’t for television, would Donald Trump be running for president? No. He would be at home right now quietly rubbing up against his wife Malaria, while she pretends to be asleep.” And when it came to who was responsible for creating the five-alarm dumpster fire that is Donald Trump’s presidency, Kimmel singled out Mark Burnett, the brainchild behind Celebrity Apprentice. “That’s right. That guy. Mark Burnett, the man who brought us ‘Celebrity Apprentice. Thanks to Mark Burnett, we don’t have to watch reality shows anymore, because we’re living in one. Thank you, Mark.” Perhaps only the guy who invented the infomercial is responsible for more suffering than Mark Burnett. That’s why Kimmel nominated Burnett to be the first one tossed over Trump’s wall, should Trump convince enough deplorables to vote against their economic self-interests. Watch the segment below:   #Emmys: @JimmyKimmel blames Mark Burnett for Donald Trump during his opening monologue https://t.co/DxE9JEoINP pic.twitter.com/vZ6gNe5HnL — Hollywood Reporter (@THR) September 19, 2016  Featured image via Getty  Leading Republican candidate, Ben Carson, abandons the Constitution and admits he wants to fully embrace Fascism if elected president.</mainText>
    <orientation>left</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>0</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>199</end>
        <start>1</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>325</end>
        <start>200</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>604</end>
        <start>326</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>757</end>
        <start>605</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>946</end>
        <start>758</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1140</end>
        <start>947</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1342</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1615</end>
        <start>1343</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1642</end>
        <start>1616</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1780</end>
        <start>1643</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1827</end>
        <start>1781</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1828</end>
        <start>1828</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1853</end>
        <start>1829</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1854</end>
        <start>1854</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1989</end>
        <start>1855</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>If You Only News</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>602</end>
        <start>326</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>944</end>
        <start>758</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1340</end>
        <start>1141</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>603</end>
        <start>325</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>945</end>
        <start>757</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1341</end>
        <start>1140</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1826</end>
        <start>1642</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>21</end>
        <start>-1</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>Emmy Host Kimmel Calls Out Dude Who Made Trump A Reality TV Star For Helping Destroy America (VIDEO)</title>
    <uri>http://www.ifyouonlynews.com/humor/emmy-host-kimmel-calls-out-dude-who-made-trump-a-reality-tv-star-for-helping-destroy-america-video/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
