<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Philip Hodges</author>
    <links href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/hillary-clinton-emails-fbi-228607">
        <end>374</end>
        <start>361</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/obama-weighs-in-hillary-clinton-private-emails/">
        <end>1727</end>
        <start>1700</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>The FBI just released its second batch of documents Friday, including notes from their various interviews with State Department officials, such as Hillary’s closest aides Huma Abedin and Cheryl Mills. According to these newly-released documents, President Obama used a pseudonym when communicating by email with Hillary Clinton when she was Secretary of State. From Politico: In an April 5, 2016 interview with the FBI, Abedin was shown an email exchange between Clinton and Obama, but the longtime Clinton aide did not recognize the name of the sender. “Once informed that the sender’s name is believed to be pseudonym used by the president, Abedin exclaimed: ‘How is this not classified?'” the report says. “Abedin then expressed her amazement at the president’s use of a pseudonym and asked if she could have a copy of the email.” The State Department has refused to make public that and other emails Clinton exchanged with Obama. Lawyers have cited the “presidential communications privilege,” a variation of executive privilege, in order to withhold the messages under the Freedom of Information Act. The State Department hasn’t released the contents of the emails between the President and Secretary of State. The one that was shown to Abedin had the subject heading ‘Re: Congratulations.’ It was dated June 28, 2012. Politico speculates that it could have been in reference to the Supreme Court ruling on a particular part of the Obamacare law. Interestingly, President Obama had told reporters a little over a year ago that he had no idea the former Secretary of State used a private email server for official matters (even though he had been emailing her private address under a pseudonym). He said he learned about it “the same time everybody else learned it through news reports.” What do you think Obama’s pseudonym was?    The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>200</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>375</end>
        <start>201</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>553</end>
        <start>376</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>833</end>
        <start>554</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1105</end>
        <start>834</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1451</end>
        <start>1106</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1791</end>
        <start>1452</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1832</end>
        <start>1792</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1834</end>
        <start>1833</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1835</end>
        <start>1835</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1981</end>
        <start>1836</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>2055</end>
        <start>1982</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>690</end>
        <start>555</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>832</end>
        <start>710</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>996</end>
        <start>958</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1790</end>
        <start>1729</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1105</end>
        <start>376</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>2017</end>
        <start>2005</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>FBI: Obama Used Pseudonym in Emails With Hillary</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36997/fbi-obama-used-pseudonym-in-emails-with-hillary/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
