<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
    <author>Campus Reform</author>
    <links href="http://www.cornellbigred.com/news/2014/2/26/FB_0226145647.aspx">
        <end>10</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </links>
    <links href="https://twitter.com/coachistvan">
        <end>144</end>
        <start>139</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://thetab.com/us/cornell/2016/09/21/cornell-football-coach-under-fire-for-cultural-appropriation-tweet-3584">
        <end>839</end>
        <start>829</start>
    </links>
    <links href="http://www.campusreform.org/?ID=8155">
        <end>1207</end>
        <start>1164</start>
    </links>
    <mainText>Roy Istvan, Cornell Football’s offensive line coach, was forced to issue a public apology in response to student outrage over a picture he tweeted showing two players wearing large sombreros. Istvan said he regrets his “cultural insensitivity,” but explained that the team awards sombreros to “team members who represent the best teamwork and winning spirit on and off the field.” A Cornell University football coach has been forced to issue an apology for the “cultural insensitivity” of tweeting a photo of two players wearing sombreros. Cornell Football’s offensive line coach Roy Istvan came under fire for a tweet sent out Tuesday morning, now deleted, captioned “Eman &amp; Fosta! THE BIG SOMBRERO!” with a picture of two football players each wearing a big sombrero.  The University retweeted Istvan’s tweet, and Istvan later apologized for the photos over Twitter when the attention sparked outrage among students. “I am truly sorry for the cultural insensitivity and understand how our expression of pride came at the expensive of others in the Cornell community,” Istvan said in a Tweet. Ivstan also explained the original pictures in another tweet, saying… Read the rest of the story at Campus Reform  The views expressed in this opinion article are solely those of their author and are not necessarily either shared or endorsed by EagleRising.com Get your daily dose of Eagle Rising by entering your email address below.</mainText>
    <orientation>right</orientation>
    <paragraph>
        <end>191</end>
        <start>0</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>380</end>
        <start>192</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>539</end>
        <start>381</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>769</end>
        <start>540</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>770</end>
        <start>770</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>918</end>
        <start>771</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1093</end>
        <start>919</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1163</end>
        <start>1094</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1207</end>
        <start>1164</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1208</end>
        <start>1208</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1354</end>
        <start>1209</start>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph>
        <end>1428</end>
        <start>1355</start>
    </paragraph>
    <portal>Eagle Rising</portal>
    <quotes>
        <end>243</end>
        <start>220</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>379</end>
        <start>294</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>242</end>
        <start>220</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>700</end>
        <start>669</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1068</end>
        <start>920</start>
    </quotes>
    <quotes>
        <end>1390</end>
        <start>1378</start>
    </quotes>
    <title>“Cultural Insensitivity”: Cornell Football Coach FORCED to Apologize for Players Wearing SOMBREROS</title>
    <uri>http://eaglerising.com/36916/cultural-insensitivity-cornell-football-coach-forced-to-apologize-for-players-wearing-sombreros/</uri>
    <veracity>mostly true</veracity>
</article>
